<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>quotes on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/quotes/</link>
      <description>Recent content in quotes on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 14:29:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/quotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/ea7eb9ef2a85d61d55d44918252a52d8/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 14:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/ea7eb9ef2a85d61d55d44918252a52d8/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do not be dismayed by the brokenness of the world. All things break. And all things can be mended. Not with time, as they say, but with intention. So go. Love intentionally, extravagantly, unconditionally. The broken world waits in darkness for the light that is you.&amp;ldquo;&lt;!--sep--&gt;&amp;ndash; L. R. Knost&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/1365276093977038852/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 12:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/1365276093977038852/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is grief if not love preserving&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/512f30a007215436724cc156c524ff00/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 02:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/512f30a007215436724cc156c524ff00/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let everything happen to you: beauty and terror.
Just keep going.
No feeling is final.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Rainer Maria Rilke, &amp;ldquo;Go to the Limits of Your Longing&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Quotes!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/quotes/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 07:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/quotes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I used to collect quotes a lot. Maybe I still do. Here are a couple of collections I&amp;rsquo;ve posted online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/quotes/tic/&#34;&gt;Tang In Cheek&lt;/a&gt; - a list of quotes (allegedly by me)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/quotes/sig/&#34;&gt;Email signatures&lt;/a&gt; - a list of quotes I used as a pool to randomly select an email signature from. I rarely send email these days, and when I do it&amp;rsquo;s usually web-based, so I can&amp;rsquo;t use these anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s probably a better way to organize these. I mean, I kind of want some kind of upvoting system like they have at bash.org (to see which quotes the three readers of this blog like), but that&amp;rsquo;s a side project for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also a list page at &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/quotes/&#34;&gt;/quotes/&lt;/a&gt; which maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll add to the menus somewhere? For fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: There is also a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/quotes/&#34;&gt;quotes tag&lt;/a&gt;, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t been maintaining it too well.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1223113973559521282/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 05:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1223113973559521282/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The wave returns to the ocean. What the ocean does with the water after that is anyone&amp;rsquo;s guess.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Three Hearts
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/three-hearts/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/three-hearts/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;h3 id=&#34;shogun&#34;&gt;Shogun&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a quote I like from &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/shogun-and-the-rest-of-james-clavells-asian-saga/&#34;&gt;James Clavell&amp;rsquo;s novel Shogun&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It&amp;rsquo;s a saying they have, that a man has a false heart in his mouth for the world to see, another in his breast to show to his special friends and his family, and the real one, the true one, the secret one, which is never known to anyone except to himself alone, hidden only God knows where.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel implies this was a Japanese saying, which may not be accurate, Clavell &lt;a href=&#34;https://japanese.stackexchange.com/questions/18973/question-about-supposedly-a-japanese-proverb&#34;&gt;probably based it on Jesuit writings from that era&lt;/a&gt;. That being said, I like this quote because I think it&amp;rsquo;s applicable to all people, not just the Japanese, especially in this modern age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;unlimited-hearts&#34;&gt;Unlimited Hearts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often we are not even limited to three &amp;ldquo;hearts&amp;rdquo;. Other people can see and bear witness to your life, but they only see a sliver, a fraction of what it is to be you, and only what you choose to let them see. How other people experience you varies for each group. You have your set of high school friends, who know of your early days of hijinks, your work friends who know how you react to stress and how you unwind, your relatives who know how you are during the holidays in the face of family turmoil, and so on. None of them know the real you, not completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;true-heart&#34;&gt;True Heart&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can&amp;rsquo;t be helped that the &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; version of each person is known only to that person alone. No one else lives the same life exactly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider myself. I write a lot about what&amp;rsquo;s going on in my life, whether through social media or through this blog. I strive to be open and honest and true in my dealings with other people, and I am almost always willing to offer up my thoughts without filter, if asked. But despite that, the picture I present to the world is still always incomplete. There are things I omit and things I hold back and things I don&amp;rsquo;t like to talk about. It&amp;rsquo;s something I have since learned to respect in other people as well, despite my inquisitive nature: to hold back when they obviously don&amp;rsquo;t want to talk about something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Don&amp;rsquo;t worry I haven&amp;rsquo;t secretly committed any heinous crimes.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;public-facing&#34;&gt;Public-facing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reminded of this quote only because I was reading some discussion about private content on the internet. In general, if I post something on the internet, I don&amp;rsquo;t expect it to be private, not completely. Otherwise, why post it on the internet at all? Anything on the internet has the chance to be exposed later, one way or another, and we should be careful accordingly. And &amp;ldquo;on the internet&amp;rdquo; here isn&amp;rsquo;t even limited to websites and blogs and social media. &amp;ldquo;Private&amp;rdquo; communications are a weak point too, as anyone can capture a screenshot anytime. If you want to keep secrets, then don&amp;rsquo;t put them on a network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three can keep a secret if two of them are dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;black-mirror&#34;&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a Black Mirror episode where the personality of a human who passed away is recreated based on his social media postings and what not. Because of the nature of humans, I don&amp;rsquo;t believe this process can ever be 100% accurate. What you will get is a shadow of the original human, an approximation of who he chose to present himself as. His true self will have been forever lost.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>In Search of Knowledge
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/in-search-of-knowledge/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/in-search-of-knowledge/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are, finally, all wanderers in search of knowledge. Most of us hold the dream of becoming something better than we are, something larger, richer, in some way more important to the world and ourselves. Too often, the way taken is the wrong way, with too much emphasis on what we want to have, rather than what we wish to become.”
— Louis L’Amour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swiss-miss.com/2019/05/in-search-of-knowledge.html&#34;&gt;swissmiss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Langston Hughes: The Dream Keeper
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/langston-hughes-the-dream-keeper/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/langston-hughes-the-dream-keeper/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring me all of your dreams,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You dreamer,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring me all your&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heart melodies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That I may wrap them&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a blue cloud-cloth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Away from the too-rough fingers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Langston Hughes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Churchill on Giving In
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/churchill-on-giving-in/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/churchill-on-giving-in/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Never give in, never, never, never–never, in nothing, great or small, large or petty. Never give in except to convictions of honor and good sense.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Churchill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persistence is a virtue, except when it isn&amp;rsquo;t - there is some amount of good sense necessary to discern when one should just give in. As in most things, a balance is required. Unfortunately, good sense is not always in abundance in today&amp;rsquo;s world.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Learning from failure
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/learning-from-failure/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/learning-from-failure/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success is not final, failure is not fatal: it is the courage to continue that counts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Winston Churchill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already typed the above quote into the post, then realized I had already &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/dealing-with-failure/&#34;&gt;used it before&lt;/a&gt;. Whatever, just goes to show, I&amp;rsquo;m no stranger to failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reminded of this quote because recently I prepared a demo for a project that didn&amp;rsquo;t push through. At first I was annoyed at the wasted effort, but I realized that I had wisely taken the demo project as an opportunity to learn/sharpen some skills. Specifically, I used it to study the Django Rest Framework (for the backend API), and a little bit of VueJS (for the frontend), which means that even if the project isn&amp;rsquo;t going anywhere, I was at least able to hone some technical skills. The advantage of always looking to try new things is that your worst case scenario still leads to some self-improvement.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Ship of Theseus
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/the-ship-of-theseus/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/the-ship-of-theseus/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I found myself poring over the Wikipedia entry for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ship_of_Theseus&#34;&gt;the Ship of Theseus&lt;/a&gt; the other day. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a thought experiment along the lines of &amp;ldquo;if a given ship&amp;rsquo;s parts are replaced at every port it visits, and eventually none of the parts are from the original ship, is it still the same ship?&amp;rdquo; The thought experiment questions the meaning of identity of a whole composed of many individual parts, such as a ship, or even a human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about this while I was &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/digging-through-time/&#34;&gt;digging through time&lt;/a&gt; (read: old posts) the other day. In all these years I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging, I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve fundamentally changed, I still feel like I&amp;rsquo;m the same person I was back then writing those posts, and yet at the same time I know I&amp;rsquo;ve grown and adapted in many different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People change over time of course, but in terms of identity I tend to think of it as something like a codebase that undergoes version control. At any given point of time there is a version of you, slightly different from who you were yesterday or who you will be tomorrow, but still fundamentally the same. As time passes, the person you are adapts to the path and circumstances you travel, resulting in the next versions. All of this reminds me of this quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No man ever steps in the same river twice, for it&amp;rsquo;s not the same river and he&amp;rsquo;s not the same man.&amp;rdquo; - Heraclitus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>It is necessary to be lost
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/it-is-necessary-to-be-lost/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/it-is-necessary-to-be-lost/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is necessary to be lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a simple logic to this. You cannot find yourself without first being lost. You cannot catch what you do not drop. You have to open your fist and let what you are clenching fall.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Cary Tennis @ Salon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;https://karigee.com/blog/2015/3/3/it-is-necessary-to-be-lost&#34;&gt;karigee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Find the others
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/find-the-others/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/find-the-others/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Admit it. You aren’t like them. You’re not even close. You may occasionally dress yourself up as one of them, watch the same mindless television shows as they do, maybe even eat the same fast food sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it seems that the more you try to fit in, the more you feel like an outsider, watching the “normal people&amp;rdquo; as they go about their automatic existences. For every time you say club passwords like “Have a nice day&amp;rdquo; and “Weather’s awful today, eh?&amp;rdquo;, you yearn inside to say forbidden things like “Tell me something that makes you cry&amp;rdquo; or “What do you think deja vu is for?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Face it, you even want to talk to that girl in the elevator. But what if that girl in the elevator (and the balding man who walks past your cubicle at work) are thinking the same thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who knows what you might learn from taking a chance on conversation with a stranger? Everyone carries a piece of the puzzle. Nobody comes into your life by mere coincidence. Trust your instincts. Do the unexpected. Find the others…&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Timothy Leary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swiss-miss.com/2019/03/find-the-others.html&#34;&gt;swiss-miss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Hemingway on Superiority
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/hemingway-on-superiority/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/hemingway-on-superiority/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is nothing noble in being superior to your fellow man; true nobility is being superior to your former self.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Ernest Hemingway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Eternal Struggle
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/the-eternal-struggle/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/the-eternal-struggle/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If the world were merely seductive, that would be easy. If it were merely challenging, that would be no problem. But I arise in the morning torn between a desire to improve the world and a desire to enjoy the world. This makes it hard to plan the day.&amp;rdquo; - E.B. White&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am fortunate that with my flexible working schedule I get to choose whether to derp around or to be productive every day. Though I must confess, derping around wins more often, maybe.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Different is not necessarily better
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/different-is-not-necessarily-better/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/different-is-not-necessarily-better/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#bfa90b7a5eef745feb866e8b272b2828-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/different-is-not-necessarily-better/different-better_hue8779adf69f8a8c81705ab160cc2853f_723186_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;bfa90b7a5eef745feb866e8b272b2828-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/different-is-not-necessarily-better/different-better.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;8 Mar 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;8 Mar 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/GetMotivated/comments/axy274/image_perspective/&#34;&gt;r/GetMotivated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s fun to think about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/it-might-have-been/&#34;&gt;what might have been&lt;/a&gt;, but often regret is tinged with optimism - the optimism that given another chance, we might have made different decisions and obtained better outcomes. But different doesn&amp;rsquo;t always mean better, so such visualizations are often pointless speculation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/different-is-not-necessarily-better/different-better_hue8779adf69f8a8c81705ab160cc2853f_723186_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Whatever doesn&#39;t kill you
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/whatever-doesnt-kill-you/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/whatever-doesnt-kill-you/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Whatever doesn&amp;rsquo;t kill you, only makes you stronger.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nietzche&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked this quote a lot when I was younger and more gung-ho, especially about things like work. In fact, I may have considered it as a bit of a defining quote back then. I guess the idea was &amp;lsquo;ok, we&amp;rsquo;ll rush in and try anything, at worst we learn a lesson and be better for next time&amp;rsquo;. I think it&amp;rsquo;s kind of the naive optimism that can only come with youth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve grown older my views on things like self-care and burnout have evolved, and the quote seems a bit silly to you know. I mean, we all know there are things that won&amp;rsquo;t kill you but can make you weaker, like depression or getting disabled or yes even burnout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And frankly, there are more important things than being stronger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: Hey, I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/whatever-doesnt-kill-you-only-makes-you-stronger/&#34;&gt;posted about this quote before&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>It might have been
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/it-might-have-been/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/it-might-have-been/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Of all sad words of tongue or pen, the saddest are these, &amp;lsquo;It might have been.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;― John Greenleaf Whittier, Maud Muller - Pamphlet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is human nature perhaps, to think about those alternate realities that might have come from different decisions or different dispositions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I was braver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I was more decisive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I didn&amp;rsquo;t have something holding me back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I knew what I knew now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I had fought harder for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I could speak to her again one last time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I realized what it all meant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While unavoidable, best not to linger in these alternate worlds too long. Regret is a trap that takes us away from the present. Learn what we can from our mistakes, and move on.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>There&#39;s no time for anything else
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/theres-no-time-for-anything-else/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/theres-no-time-for-anything-else/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“None of us are getting out of here alive, so please stop treating yourself like an after-thought. Eat the delicious food. Walk in the sunshine. Jump in the ocean. Say the truth that you’re carrying in your heart like hidden treasure. Be silly. Be kind. Be weird. There’s no time for anything else.&amp;rdquo;
— Keanu Reeves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swiss-miss.com/2019/02/there-is-no-time-for-anything-else.html&#34;&gt;swissmiss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Debt
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/debt/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/debt/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;For my first few years in elementary school, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get any pocket money. Instead I&amp;rsquo;d have a couple of sandwiches and a thermos of water. So I wasn&amp;rsquo;t used to handling money. One time while waiting for the school bus, I was a bit thirsty but my thermos was already out. For some reason, I decided to borrow five pesos from a classmate to buy a coke from the canteen. This gave me a bit anxiety on the ride home. It meant I had to ask my parents for money so I can pay back the guy! I had never asked for money before. I didn&amp;rsquo;t mention it when I got home. The next day, the guy asks to be paid back, and I put him off til the next day. This went on for a couple of days until I got the nerve to ask my parents for money and it turned out to be no big deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remembered this today because I was wondering why now as an adult I&amp;rsquo;m extremely averse to debt. This incident isn&amp;rsquo;t probably all there is to it, but it was the earliest and only time I can ever remember being in debt. I dislike owing other people, whether it be money or other things. I try avoid borrowing money as much as possible, and even when I end up having to (usually due to something silly like forgetting my wallet or something), I&amp;rsquo;ll pay it back as soon as possible. I don&amp;rsquo;t take out loans to make large purchases, I wait until I have enough money available for all of it. I use credit cards, but only for convenience. I pay off each bill in full immediately so I don&amp;rsquo;t accrue debt and/or interest. If I buy something on installment, in my head and in my accounting that is money already spent in full. To this day, I am primarily a creditor, not a debtor. I am the one other people owe money to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand that debt can be a powerful instrument for things like investments and businesses as such, but I just dislike the idea of it. This might be one of the reasons why I can&amp;rsquo;t be an entrepreneur - I would be very averse to for example taking out a loan to fund a business. In spite of that, I think it&amp;rsquo;s a net positive overall. (Although certainly, I can say this because I enjoy a certain level of privilege in life.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>This too shall pass
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/this-too-shall-pass/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/this-too-shall-pass/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is said an Eastern monarch once charged his wise men to invent him a sentence, to be ever in view, and which should be true and appropriate in all times and situations. They presented him the words: And this, too, shall pass away. How much it expresses! How chastening in the hour of pride!how consoling in the depth of affliction!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://quotationsbook.com/quote/44524/&#34;&gt;Abraham Lincoln&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More quotes! I like ones that have a level of ambiguity, a meaning that changes depending on situation. &amp;ldquo;This too shall pass&amp;rdquo; teaches us to hope in times of desperation, and encourages temperance in times of plenty. Hope is a good thing, especially in times like these when many problems plague the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also reminds me of Shelley&amp;rsquo;s sonnet &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ozymandias&#34;&gt;Ozymandias&lt;/a&gt;, which reminds us that even the greatest of empires fade away:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And on the pedestal these words appear:
&amp;lsquo;My name is Ozymandias, king of kings;
Look on my works, ye Mighty, and despair!&amp;rsquo;
Nothing beside remains. Round the decay
Of that colossal wreck, boundless and bare
The lone and level sands stretch far away.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Be excellent to each other, and party on, dudes
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/be-excellent-to-each-other-and-party-on-dudes/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/be-excellent-to-each-other-and-party-on-dudes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#ece114fafc526b73c9b858e6e11a3e95-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/be-excellent-to-each-other-and-party-on-dudes/be-excellent_hu7e3233b1eb981efa89f666137af55032_58005_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;ece114fafc526b73c9b858e6e11a3e95-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/be-excellent-to-each-other-and-party-on-dudes/be-excellent.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Feb 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;18 Feb 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quote is from the 1980s cult classic &lt;em&gt;Bill and Ted&amp;rsquo;s Excellent Adventure&lt;/em&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t include this movie in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/&#34;&gt;my top 10 movies post&lt;/a&gt;, but it and the sequel &lt;em&gt;Bill and Ted&amp;rsquo;s Bogus Journey&lt;/em&gt; are still among my childhood faves. These wise words are give by the Wyld Stallyns band composed of the epnoymous Bill and Ted, and form the philosophical basis of the future utopian civilization inspired by their music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this quote because it&amp;rsquo;s simple and comprises two principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be good to other people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enjoy life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, what more is there? And maybe I&amp;rsquo;m reading too much into it, but it has a profound kind of balance too: each principle holds the other in check: you should enjoy life, but not by hurting other people; and you should help other people, but not to your own detriment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(A third movie, &lt;em&gt;Bill and Ted Face the Music&lt;/em&gt; has been greenlighted and might come as soon as end of 2019!)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/be-excellent-to-each-other-and-party-on-dudes/be-excellent_hu7e3233b1eb981efa89f666137af55032_58005_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Life Isn&#39;t Fair
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/life-isnt-fair/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/life-isnt-fair/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Quote 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The world isn&amp;rsquo;t fair Calvin&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know Dad, but why isn&amp;rsquo;t it ever unfair in my favor?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Bill Watterson, &amp;ldquo;Calvin and Hobbes&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quote 2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you expect the world to be fair with you because you&amp;rsquo;re fair to them, its like asking a lion not to eat you because you don&amp;rsquo;t eat lions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Unknown source)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We accept that the natural order of the world is inherently unfair. There are stronger creatures and weaker creatures, there are predators and there are prey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But does it follow that because the natural world is unfair, that human society must also be unfair?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/1088642083320139778/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 03:37:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/1088642083320139778/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Productivity is what makes things fun, that&amp;rsquo;s why humans go to work.&amp;rdquo; - Raymond Holt&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Price for Being the Best
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/the-price-for-being-the-best/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/the-price-for-being-the-best/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The price for being the best is always&amp;hellip; having to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; the best.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terry Pratchet, &lt;em&gt;Lords and Ladies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favorite quotes. For context: in the story, one of the characters has a special talent that he can shoe anything anyone gives him (like when you put horseshoes on a horse). And Granny Weatherwax tells him that the price he pays for that talent is that when someone brings him something to shoe, no matter how wild or ridiculous the request, he has to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In real life of course, the literal interpretation is ridiculous. You are not obligated to do something just because you are the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; at that something. But being the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; at something implies two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People are more inclined to come to you whenever they need help or advice with what you&amp;rsquo;re best at.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to keep being the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; at that thing, you have to keep doing it, and you have to keep surpassing yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a variant of this quote that I used a lot in a previous job, where people often came to me with their technical problems and asked me for help in solving them, so a lot of my time was taken up by helping solve other people&amp;rsquo;s problems. I would jokingly complain &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ang hirap talaga maging magaling!&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s hard being so good! - implying that being &lt;em&gt;magaling&lt;/em&gt; gave me so much additional work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you put yourself in a position of leadership in your field, there will be pressure to maintain that position by constantly improving and learning and showing your skills by helping other people. Humility disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not claiming to be the best software developer by any stretch, it was probably more of a big fish in a small pond scenario. But the quote above is a reminder for me that pursuing excellence has a price often unmentioned, and you have to be sure you are willing to pay that price, and that it&amp;rsquo;s worth it for you.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/10157057506758912/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/10157057506758912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;“It is only with the heart that one can see rightly; what is essential is invisible to the eye.” — Antoine de Saint-Exupery&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/09/10156944714508912/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 22:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/09/10156944714508912/</guid>
            <description>
            
            


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/09/10156944714508912/_hu5c12cb92109adc83d65bfa16f381f660_15356_50998bb448a02327fce0feb0c2e2dbde.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;&#34;If you want to test your memory, try to recall what you were worrying about one year ago today.&#34; – E. Joseph Cossman&#39; on /r/quotes at https://reddit.com/r/quotes/comments/97s3uv/if_you_want_to_test_your_memory_try_to_recall/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/08/e4bs9hp/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:57:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/08/e4bs9hp/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;&amp;#34;If you want to test your memory, try to recall what you were worrying about one year ago today.&amp;#34; – E. Joseph Cossman&amp;#39; on /r/quotes at https://reddit.com/r/quotes/comments/97s3uv/if_you_want_to_test_your_memory_try_to_recall/:

            &lt;p&gt;facebook.com/onthisday&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/05/10156668630063912/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 22:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/05/10156668630063912/</guid>
            <description>
            
            


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/05/10156668630063912/_hub4df19861347c43aad03732e0503574e_45981_d324b33d7cf959b33e0218c5390c202e.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/02/968394318707703808/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 07:56:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/02/968394318707703808/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;“I wish life was not so short,&amp;rsquo; he thought. &amp;lsquo;Languages take such a time, and so do all the things one wants to know about.” ― J.R.R. Tolkien&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/12/10156294616568912/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 02:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/12/10156294616568912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;“Everything ends and it&amp;rsquo;s always sad, but everything begins again, too. And that&amp;rsquo;s always happy. Be happy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Doctor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/11/10156167338153912/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 21:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/11/10156167338153912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;“I’m bored’ is a useless thing to say. You live in a great, big, vast world that you’ve seen none percent of. Even the inside of your own mind is endless. It goes on forever, inwardly - you understand? The fact the you’re alive is amazing. So you don’t get to be bored.” - LOUIS C.K.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/921815425112870912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 19:08:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/921815425112870912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;“The world is chaos. Be kind.” - Patton Oswalt’s late wife&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from GreatestQuotes https://twitter.com/GreatestQuotes/statuses/915974178427277312/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/915974684868362240/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 16:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/915974684868362240/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from GreatestQuotes https://twitter.com/GreatestQuotes/statuses/915974178427277312/:
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Self-praise is for losers. Be a winner. Stand for something. Always have class, and be humble.&amp;rdquo; - John Madden&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/10155991095293912/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 23:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/10155991095293912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;“There has to be a balance, Vin,” he said. “Somehow, we’ll find it. The balance between whom we wish to be and whom we need to be.” He sighed. “But for now,” he said, nodding to the side, “we simply have to be satisfied with who we are.”&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/10155968386438912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 23:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/10155968386438912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Life is short
and the world is at least half terrible
and for every kind stranger,
there is one who would break you,
though I keep this from my children.
I am trying to sell them the world.
Any decent realtor,
walking you through a real shithole,
chirps on about good bones:
This place could be beautiful, right?
You could make this place beautiful.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Good Bones by Maggie Smith&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/895432195036200960/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 23:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/895432195036200960/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you went back and fixed all the mistakes you&amp;rsquo;ve made, you erase yourself&amp;rdquo; - Louis C.K.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/10155929302568912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 08:52:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/10155929302568912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Rick: &amp;ldquo;To live is to risk it all; otherwise you&amp;rsquo;re just an inert chunk of randomly assembled molecules drifting wherever the universe blows you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/05/10155654402758912/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 18:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/05/10155654402758912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frodo: I can&amp;rsquo;t do this, Sam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam: I know. It&amp;rsquo;s all wrong. By rights we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t even be here. But we are. It&amp;rsquo;s like in the great stories, Mr. Frodo. The ones that really mattered. Full of darkness and danger, they were. And sometimes you didn&amp;rsquo;t want to know the end. Because how could the end be happy? How could the world go back to the way it was when so much bad had happened? But in the end, it&amp;rsquo;s only a passing thing, this shadow. Even darkness must pass. A new day will come. And when the sun shines it will shine out the clearer. Those were the stories that stayed with you. That meant something, even if you were too small to understand why. But I think, Mr. Frodo, I do understand. I know now. Folk in those stories had lots of chances of turning back, only they didn&amp;rsquo;t. They kept going. Because they were holding on to something.  Frodo: What are we holding onto, Sam?  Sam: That there&amp;rsquo;s some good in this world, Mr. Frodo&amp;hellip; and it&amp;rsquo;s worth fighting for.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/05/10155654402758912/10155654420888912/18700244_10211742221185040_7552413497350204723_n_hu719ba1a49cd9ab650fc346e7e670d62c_5913_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/10155482897228912/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 14:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/10155482897228912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;h2 id=&#34;sometimes-you-have-to-wonder-if-were-living-in-a-douglas-adams-novel&#34;&gt;Sometimes you have to wonder if we&amp;rsquo;re living in a Douglas Adams novel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;On its world, the people are people. The leaders are lizards. The people hate the lizards and the lizards rule the people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Odd,” said Arthur, “I thought you said it was a democracy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I did,” said Ford. “It is.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So,” said Arthur, hoping he wasn’t sounding ridiculously obtuse, “why don’t the people get rid of the lizards?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It honestly doesn’t occur to them,” said Ford. “They’ve all got the vote, so they all pretty much assume that the government they’ve voted in more or less approximates to the government they want.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You mean they actually vote for the lizards?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh yes,” said Ford with a shrug, “of course.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But,” said Arthur, going for the big one again, “why?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Because if they didn’t vote for a lizard,” said Ford, “the wrong lizard might get in.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Source: HHG2G)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/10155452138493912/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 03:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/10155452138493912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Let me never fall into the vulgar mistake of dreaming that I am persecuted whenever I am contradicted. — Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/836620010726412288/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 16:52:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/836620010726412288/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I love deadlines. I love the whooshing noise they make as they go by.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;― Douglas Adams, The Salmon of Doubt&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/10155332846438912/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 22:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/10155332846438912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The meaning of life is just to be alive. It is so plain and so obvious and so simple. And yet, everybody rushes around in a great panic as if it were necessary to achieve something beyond themselves. To have faith is to trust yourself to the water.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alan Watts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/826422318956105729/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 13:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/826422318956105729/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The winner of the game is the player who makes the next-to-last mistake.&amp;rdquo; - chess grandmaster Savielly Tartakower&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/10155269161388912/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 10:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/10155269161388912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Fear is a strange soil. Mainly it grows obedience like corn, which grows in rows and makes weeding easy. But sometimes it grows the potatoes of defiance, which flourish underground.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small Gods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from lenirobredo https://twitter.com/lenirobredo/statuses/814401606527647744/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/814428035558436864/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 11:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/814428035558436864/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from lenirobredo https://twitter.com/lenirobredo/statuses/814401606527647744/:
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I’m sorry you were not truly loved and that it made you cruel.&amp;rdquo; - Warsan Shire&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/10155226663398912/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 08:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/10155226663398912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;“Anyway, George comes up to me the first day of filming and he takes one look at the dress and says, &amp;lsquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t wear a bra under that dress.&amp;rsquo; So, I say, &amp;lsquo;Okay, I&amp;rsquo;ll bite. Why?&amp;rsquo; And he says, &amp;lsquo;Because&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s no underwear in space.&amp;rsquo; I promise you this is true, and he says it with such conviction too! Like he had been to space and looked around and he didn&amp;rsquo;t see any bras or panties or briefs anywhere. Now, George came to my show when it was in Berkeley. He came backstage and explained why you can&amp;rsquo;t wear your brassiere in other galaxies, and I have a sense you will be going to outer space very soon, so here&amp;rsquo;s why you cannot wear your brassiere, per George. So, what happens is you go to space and you become weightless. So far so good, right? But then your body expands??? But your bra doesn&amp;rsquo;t- so you get strangled by your own bra. Now I think that this would make a fantastic obit- so I tell my younger friends that no matter how I go, I want it reported that I drowned in moonlight, strangled by my own bra.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;― Carrie Fisher, Wishful Drinking&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/805306362460663809/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2016 07:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/805306362460663809/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Millions long for immortality who do not know what to do with themselves on a rainy Sunday afternoon.&amp;rdquo;  - Susan Ertz&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/10155076007533912/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 23:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/10155076007533912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;It is said an Eastern monarch once charged his wise men to invent him a sentence, to be ever in view, and which should be true and appropriate in all times and situations. They presented him the words: &amp;ldquo;And this, too, shall pass away.&amp;rdquo; How much it expresses! How chastening in the hour of pride! How consoling in the depths of affliction!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/796006567225135104/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 15:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/796006567225135104/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Those who cannot remember the past are condemned to repeat it.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ndash; George Santayana&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>