<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>mcu on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mcu/</link>
      <description>Recent content in mcu on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 02:15:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mcu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Spider-Man: Far From Home spoiler-free review!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home-spoiler-free-review/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 02:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home-spoiler-free-review/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;- I watched Far From Home while I was&amp;hellip; far from home.&lt;br/&gt;- great movie, lots of fun, and the stakes are a lot higher than the Vulture just stealing some tech off Tony Stark&lt;br/&gt;- basically a story of Peter Parker the high school student trying to juggle his Spider-Man problems with his high school life, which was one of the best eras of comic book Spider-Man&lt;br/&gt;- the movie gives us a look at what the world looks like post-Endgame and how weird it is for everyone&lt;br/&gt;- if you&amp;rsquo;ve seen the trailers, you know who the &amp;ldquo;villain&amp;rdquo; is and you have certain expectations coming in. I was worried this would be a problem but it worked out fine, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a problem and was handled well&lt;br/&gt;- There is a mid-credits scene, possibly one of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, in terms of how it changes the entire tone of the movie. There is also a post-credits scene, the implications of which are still unclear and will leave the fanbase speculating for a while&lt;br/&gt;- Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Possibly! There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of &amp;ldquo;cute&amp;rdquo; Peter Parker high school moments she&amp;rsquo;d probably like, and the plot and action aren&amp;rsquo;t too hard to follow&lt;/p&gt;


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Captain Marvel spoiler-free review!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/captain-marvel-spoiler-free-review/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 15:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/captain-marvel-spoiler-free-review/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movie was pretty good, no major issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doesnt follow the typical MCU origin story ‘formula’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some weird pacing issues in a few places, but that just might be because of the chosen story direction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lots of little call-outs and tie-ins to the other MCU movies (although I feel like they could have done a bit more in some spots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am not a cat person. But if you are a cat person, you might like this: there is a cat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s some parts that made it obvious they were aiming for that Wonder Woman audience, so the movie may be better for you if you’re in that demo (but I think WW was a better movie overall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imax was pretty good, nothing too excessive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Midcredits scene, and postcredits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni mama? Possibly! Also, its a good idea to bring little girls to watch this movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>