<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>RoyWantsMeat on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/source/roywantsmeat/</link>
      <description>Recent content in RoyWantsMeat on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/source/roywantsmeat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Moved again...
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2006/02/moved-again/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2006 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2006/02/moved-again/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Hopefully for the last time ^_^&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://roytang.net&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://roytang.net/blog&#34;&gt;http://roytang.net/blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Farewell blogger!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Users don&#39;t know what they want.
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2006/01/users-don39t-know-what-they-want/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2006 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2006/01/users-don39t-know-what-they-want/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dilbert.com/comics/dilbert/archive/dilbert-20060129.html&#34;&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s Dilbert &lt;/a&gt;takes the old programming truism to an extreme &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Users don&amp;rsquo;t know what they want.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>How to Organize a Cluttered Mind?
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2006/01/how-to-organize-a-cluttered-mind/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2006 07:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2006/01/how-to-organize-a-cluttered-mind/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Yeah, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been posting lately. I still have a lot of thoughts running around my head, and often throughout the day I find myself thinking, &amp;ldquo;I should post an entry about this.&amp;rdquo; But at the end of the day, I&amp;rsquo;m tired and I&amp;rsquo;m exhausted from thinking about two hundred different issues and juggling twenty different priorities, so I don&amp;rsquo;t post about it. I note it somewhere and sooner or later it becomes irrelevant and I forget why I wanted to post it in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remarked to one of my coworkers that I often find myself remembering dozens of things in my head simultaneously and he of course reminded me of the popular notion that human beings can only remember seven things at any one time. It&amp;rsquo;s the concept of limitation in humans&amp;rsquo; short-term memory or RAM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably mostly true, but as I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten more and more used to this multitasking mode of mine, I&amp;rsquo;ve found that the seven most important things stay on top, but the rest don&amp;rsquo;t really disappear. They fall away for a while, swallowed into your subconscious, only to rear their ugly head again later once you have some free RAM again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current role at work forces me to be locked in this mode for most of the day. As one of the senior technical guys, I typically field dozens of technical questions from junior developers during a single day and when somebody&amp;rsquo;s problem can&amp;rsquo;t be solved quickly I physically get up from my desk and go walk them through it. And that&amp;rsquo;s just the queries regarding concerns outside my own project. Aside from that I often have to worry about scheduling, technical risks, physical designs and of course the occasional invitation to go down and buy some food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developer multitasking is generally looked-down upon in the tech world I know; people are encouraged to work directly on one task at a time to give them focus. Maybe most people have some short period of time at the start of the day to reply to emails and address issues raised by other people. I wish I could have that sort of luxury, but it seems to me that every issue or problem raised to me needs to be resolved five minutes ago. People can&amp;rsquo;t continue coding unless I help them. Schedules can&amp;rsquo;t be finalized until I give my input. Developers can&amp;rsquo;t write program specifications until I hand in the database design. I literally have dozens of dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how do I cope? Simple, I cope the only way I know how. By instinct. This would be a terrifying revelation to anyone I actually work with, but during working hours I&amp;rsquo;m typically buried under so many issues, my only recourse is to dismiss as many as I can as quickly as possible, and that requires a whole lot of working from my gut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, my gut has gotten really good at this. But I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure all the people who are incredibly organized and have moleskin notebooks and stuff would tear their hair at such an unorganized method (or is it madness?). And I know, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to get organized, I really am. I have to-do lists, a couple of dozen that tell me what I should be doing. I have log files that theoretically tell me what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing all day. I try to turn off my email client sometimes, even though I will inevitably have people coming up to me and asking if I&amp;rsquo;d seen the mail they just sent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I can&amp;rsquo;t help it. That&amp;rsquo;s the role I play. People expect me to help them, to provide them guidance. I&amp;rsquo;ve projected myself as being open to consultations, and the company and all of my coworkers appreciate that. And even then I still have my own tasks to perform. I&amp;rsquo;m considering suggesting to the company that I never be considered working on a project for more than a 50% allocation. The other 50% should be allocated to my on-the-fly firefighting tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, especially during the past couple of weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself mentally exhausted. I have a very easy time separating work from personal life, because by the time I step into the elevator after logging out I&amp;rsquo;m already too tired to even think about work issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that I have a bad job, mind you. It&amp;rsquo;s awesome. But I guess sometimes I toss myself into it a bit too much. When my personal load is light, I can easily handle everything tossed at me and people go &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re awesome!&amp;rdquo; and I nod and address the next crisis. But when my load is heavy, well, then things really get exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I forgot what my point was now, as I unconsciously launched into a narrative of how my typical day goes. I&amp;rsquo;m still getting by with my gut, but I know from experience that gut instinct only gets you so far. Sooner or later, something&amp;rsquo;s gonna give and I&amp;rsquo;ll need to find some way to make sure I can carry this level of awesome-ness to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and yeah I changed layouts.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Adventures in Linux Land, Part 1
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2006/01/adventures-in-linux-land-part-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2006/01/adventures-in-linux-land-part-1/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So yeah, out of a strange mix of adventurism, inertia, coincidence and plan old boredom, I decided to install linux on this machine. At first I just wanted to see how easy the install would be, but after I nuked my Windows XP install I sort of had no turning back. (-_-!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I went for a dual boot of Windows XP and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kubuntu.org/&#34;&gt;Kubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, supposedly an easy-to-use Linux distro. So yeah, I even watched this &lt;a href=&#34;http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-6104490811311898236&amp;amp;q=ubuntu+dual+boot&#34;&gt;video online&lt;/a&gt; that showed how to do the installs. (The video shows two guys doing the dual boot install with XP and Ubuntu, same difference.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m cool. I do the install and woohoo, I boot into Kubuntu, I&amp;rsquo;m awesome, yeah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But my Kubuntu has no internet. :( It seems to have some sort of namespace resolving problem. I asked around on the kubuntu channel at irc.freenode.net and on the kubuntu forums, some nice guys gave me some stuff I could try, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try again maybe tomorrow if I don&amp;rsquo;t get home too late. (Can&amp;rsquo;t right now as my bro is playing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dota-allstars.com/&#34;&gt;DoTA&lt;/a&gt; and his internet goes down if I reboot&amp;hellip; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(To be continued&amp;hellip; )&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>I Wasn&#39;t Planning On Making Resolutions
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2006/01/i-wasn39t-planning-on-making-resolutions/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 08:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2006/01/i-wasn39t-planning-on-making-resolutions/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; but what the hell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will try more new things this year.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>I Wish I Had Something Snazzy To Say About The New Year
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2006/01/i-wish-i-had-something-snazzy-to-say-about-the-new-year/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 07:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2006/01/i-wish-i-had-something-snazzy-to-say-about-the-new-year/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; but I just want to see what happens now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transition from the last year felt a bit strange to me. Usually, the new year is a time for letting go of the past, and looking ahead to a whole new future. That so perfectly described the end of the last year, as things changed around me and just naturally fell into positions where I would be able to leave them behind. Things changed, things I had known for a long time and taken from granted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to the coming year. A new beginning I suppose. I hope it&amp;rsquo;s interesting at least.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Games -- Civilization 4
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/12/games-civilization-4/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2005 00:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/12/games-civilization-4/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Sid Meier&amp;rsquo;s Civilization &amp;ndash; one of the most highly-acclaimed strategy game series in existence. Any serious gamer worth his salt knows about it &amp;ndash; whether he plays turn-based strategy games or not. And the fourth installment was eagerly awaited in our home &amp;ndash; two out of four brothers were eager to play the latest update.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And Civ4 is in many ways the same game all over again. The basic premise is still there &amp;ndash; explore, build cities, research technologies, kick other civivlizations while they&amp;rsquo;re down, race to space, etc. But several other new features have kicked in, many of them adding a new layer of management complexity to the already complex strategy game. Great Persons, National Wonders, cultural expansion, luxury resources&amp;hellip; well, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if some of these are new since Civ3 &amp;ndash; I didn&amp;rsquo;t play that one much. The most important change has to be the streamlining of the interface such that it becomes easy to tell at a glance what a city is building and how long it takes for it to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, as expected, the game is still incredibly engrossing. I sat down yesterday morning to &amp;ldquo;just give it a try&amp;rdquo;, and after what seemed like a few short turns found myself contemplating whether to nuke the Arabians in the early 17th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, awesome Civ4 gameplay, as expected. I finished two games in short order, one took me 4 hours because the silly Germans and Spanish kept trying to declare war on me, and I had to be satisfied with a Time Victory. The second took less than two hours &amp;ndash; full peace/diplomacy, science/culture all the way, never entered a state of war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m not playing it again. Why? Because the game&amp;rsquo;s performance is crap-tastic! You can play smoothly found maybe 5-10 minutes before the game starts slowing to a crawl. Going to the lowest possible settings and quitting all running programs doesn&amp;rsquo;t help at all. Apparently I&amp;rsquo;m not alone, as I&amp;rsquo;ve seen numerous message board posts lambasting Firaxis for the terrible performance of the game regardlesss of the system running it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a testament to both the addictiveness of the gameplay and how much patience I&amp;rsquo;ve gained recently that I was able to finish two games at all. But as it is, I&amp;rsquo;m not playing it again until some radical performance improvment happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I can still find a copy of Civ3&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>How Would It Feel to Be A Developer-Slave?
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/12/how-would-it-feel-to-be-a-developer-slave/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2005 12:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/12/how-would-it-feel-to-be-a-developer-slave/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;As I watched my brother playing the latest incarnation of EA&amp;rsquo;s FIFA game, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but consider that there must be a staff of developers over at EA dedicated solely to the task of churning away to release updates to EA&amp;rsquo;s flagship lines of sports games year after year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder how fulfilling that kind of job actually is&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Games -- I Give Up On Dragon Quest VIII
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/12/games-i-give-up-on-dragon-quest-viii/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2005 04:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/12/games-i-give-up-on-dragon-quest-viii/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Not that it&amp;rsquo;s a bad game mind you. From the ten or so hours I&amp;rsquo;ve played it&amp;rsquo;s definitely a lot better than the previous game in the series. And the voice acting is really great this time, with a bunch of British people doing the over-the-top voices. The battle system is still a bit simplistic, and the main quest seems very straightforward. From what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, it&amp;rsquo;s probably an above average game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the problem. I don&amp;rsquo;t have time for above average games. It was okay when I was still in school and had tons of free time, I could afford to waste my time with midcarders like Legend of Legaia or Wild Arms, but these days there are so many things competing for my attention (thanks DSL), and work sched is a lot more tight than school, so I have to be a LOT more selective in my choice of distractions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &amp;ldquo;above-average&amp;rdquo; just doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the cut anymore.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Moving Things Around A Bit
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/12/moving-things-around-a-bit/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2005 16:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/12/moving-things-around-a-bit/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I was getting a bit bored with the place, so I spruced it up a bit, switched some colors, moved stuff around. You know, just to pretend something&amp;rsquo;s happening. And to showcase my sorely lacking UI design skills. :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screenshot captured for posterity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/uploads/2005/layout20051211.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also cleaned up some of the global files that were being accessed from fateback, since I will eventually drop that host completely. Right now, the external files used by this site are hsoted on my geocities account (which I should also organize/clean up in some way.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the curious, this site is maintained in several layers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the blogger template &amp;ndash; ideally, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to change this too often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an external javascript file &amp;ndash; ideally, if I want to do small changes to the site, I&amp;rsquo;ll just modify this and use DHTML to do it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an external stylesheet &amp;ndash; ideally, if I want to make changes to layout, I just adjust this one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while back I was also wondering if it was viable to use XSL transformations for a blogger blog&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;m too lazy to try to figure it out now.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Music - Ultraelectromagnetic Jam
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/12/music-ultraelectromagnetic-jam/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2005 09:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/12/music-ultraelectromagnetic-jam/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no music critic; often I can&amp;rsquo;t even carry my own tune. But I do know what I like, and I know I like the Eraserheads&amp;rsquo; music. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know who the ‘heads are, they&amp;rsquo;re basically the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eraserheads&#34;&gt;Beatles of the Philippines&lt;/a&gt;, galvanizing the local music industry and serving as an example and inspiration to numerous other bands that followed after them. It&amp;rsquo;s only fitting then that many of the current crop of Filipino performers pay tribute to them in the form of Ultraelectromagnetic Jam. This fantastic album features several artists performing their own versions of some of the Eraserheads best hits, namely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alapaap by 6-Cycle Mind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alcohol by Radioactive Sago Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ang Huling El Bimbo by Rico J Puno&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard to Believe by Cueshé&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huwag Kang Matakot by Orange and Lemons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huwag Mo Nang Itanong by MYMP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ligaya by Kitchie Nadal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magasin by Paolo Santos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maling Akala by Brownman Revival&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overdrive by Barbie Almabis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pare Ko by Sponge Cola&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoliarium by Imago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Superproxy by Francis M.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tikman by Sugarfree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Torpedo by Isha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Para sa Masa by all of them!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to comment on each track separately, but I&amp;rsquo;m too lazy :p They&amp;rsquo;re all pretty good, mostly because the originals were great in the first place. Paolo Santos carried Magasin surprisingly well, and Superproxy was just the right track for Francis M. Radioactive Sago&amp;rsquo;s Alcohol is hilarious, and I like the way Orange and Lemons mixed a little bit of Julie Tearjerky and Tikman in Huwag Kang Matakot. I also think I actually like Cueshé&amp;rsquo;s version of Hard To Believe better than the original. My least favorite track on the album is Kitchie Nadal&amp;rsquo;s Ligaya, (cute laugh on the &amp;ldquo;inaahit&amp;rdquo; bit notwithstanding) as I really prefer the more upbeat original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish more bands had contributed to the effort though, as the ‘heads probably deserve it. According to my brother, the participating artists were all from the same recording studio (I don&amp;rsquo;t really pay attention to studios, so yeah I&amp;rsquo;ll just agree here.) Still, it would&amp;rsquo;ve been nice to hear some renditions from ‘heads contemporaries like Rivermaya and Parokya ni Edgar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, awesome album. If you have listened to the Eraserheads music at one time or another, go find a way to get it.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Left Half of My Mouth is Numb, Thanks
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/12/the-left-half-of-my-mouth-is-numb-thanks/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2005 05:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/12/the-left-half-of-my-mouth-is-numb-thanks/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I had three teeth taken out today, all of them deep in the bottom-left part of mouth. One of them was apparently a wisdom tooth that had lodged itself in a peculiar angle. That one required surgery (and was not covered by my health card).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re there, even when your mouth is numb, even if you&amp;rsquo;re not really scared or anything, once you start to feel that pressure on your jaw, you can&amp;rsquo;t help but be at least a little bit anxious. It&amp;rsquo;s not so much whatever pain gets through the anesthesia that&amp;rsquo;s annoying. It&amp;rsquo;s the fact that you&amp;rsquo;re mentally anticipating that pain. When you start to feel the dentist pushing and pulling at your tooth, you can&amp;rsquo;t help but worry that somewhere, some resilient little nerve of yours has avoided the anesthesia and is just waiting to send you into a world of pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, not only is my dentist very good, but I&amp;rsquo;m quite comfortable with her, despite the often corniness of her jokes :p&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Random Java Programs
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/12/random-java-programs/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 15:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/12/random-java-programs/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So, my brother needed to present 20 java programs for school. He didn&amp;rsquo;t have to make them himself, he said. Just to print them out and submit them. (What kind of ridiculous compsci teacher asks for hardcopies of source instead of softcopies?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I said, sure. I&amp;rsquo;ll make some, it&amp;rsquo;ll be easy. After all, trivial programs shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take me more than 5 minutes each right? It was true, each one didn&amp;rsquo;t take long. But I spent quite some time thinking about what I would actually code. The usual suspects are there &amp;ndash; Hello World, prime factors, factorial, simple arithmetic, palindromes. It was just harder than I thought making up twenty diverse trivial java programs to write. I&amp;rsquo;m not a teacher after all :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, in case someone in the world finds these examples useful: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geocities.com/zroytang/RandomJavaProgs.zip&#34;&gt;Twenty random java programs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDIT 2020: Since the above link is no longer accessible, I&amp;rsquo;ve just uploaded the twenty programs as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roytang/RandomJavaProgs&#34;&gt;github repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Comics -- Batgirl
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/12/comics-batgirl/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 15:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/12/comics-batgirl/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Cassandra Cain was raised as an assassin. Growing up, her father never taught her to read or write, only to fight. She grew up knowing only one language &amp;ndash; body language. Her mind processes human motions as fluently as ordinary people speak their native tongue. She can see moves before they happen or read a person&amp;rsquo;s intentions simply by following their movement patterns. She was an experiment to create the ultimate human fighting machine. At the age of eight, she made her first kill. Then she ran away. She wound up in Gotham, under the tutelage of the Dark Knight. She has become Batgirl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read through the current 70 issues over the weekend. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. Batgirl almost always faces up against normal people &amp;ndash; goons, thugs, mafia and whatnot. She&amp;rsquo;s not metahuman either, but her superior abilities allow her to dodge bullets and kill with her bare hands (Not that she does kill mind you, but she CAN.) The fact that she&amp;rsquo;s illiterate and basically ignorant of how to interact with the rest of society makes the comic all the more interesting and provides a lot of room for her to grow as a character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing I don&amp;rsquo;t like about trying to follow a single comic series &amp;ndash; crossovers. You read an issue, and suddenly there&amp;rsquo;s several other comics you need to read to get the whole picture. I can see why they do it.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Yeah, I&#39;m Not Gonna Make It
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/11/yeah-im-not-gonna-make-it/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2005 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/11/yeah-im-not-gonna-make-it/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;(Cross-post from &lt;a href=&#34;http://roynano.blogspot.com/2005/11/yeah-im-not-gonna-make-it.html&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#aed0d9ac2ca8b8a2d96eb4e37bce6e06-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2005/11/yeah-im-not-gonna-make-it/nano_huaeeb8801bb31003898722958cd54067e_12683_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;aed0d9ac2ca8b8a2d96eb4e37bce6e06-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2005/11/yeah-im-not-gonna-make-it/nano.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;27 Nov 2005 2:30pm&#34;&gt;27 Nov 2005 2:30pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I would&amp;rsquo;ve had a good chance to make it if I had started on time though. :(&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not gonna stop though, I think I&amp;rsquo;ll finish this novel.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;An excerpt:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;“I really should organize my stuff more. You’d think someone living alone deep in the woods would have a lot of time to organize, but no, there’s always one thing or another. Squirrels, usually. Silly things keep insisting their friends are nuts! Or the nuts are their friends, something like that; I never was very good at understanding their chitter-chatter, most of it is about nuts anyway. I think they have like two hundred different sounds to represent nuts, did you know that? It’s funny too how they attach the same meaning to the term “nuts” as humans do. How do you suppose they picked that up? I hope it’s not me, I don’t think I have a tendency to say people are nuts. Aha there it is!”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2005/11/yeah-im-not-gonna-make-it/nano_huaeeb8801bb31003898722958cd54067e_12683_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Are Filipinos the Next American Minority After Blacks?
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/11/are-filipinos-the-next-american-minority-after-blacks/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2005 17:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/11/are-filipinos-the-next-american-minority-after-blacks/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;One of the panels from Marvel&amp;rsquo;s House of M (second issue) made me think so&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#0687d692f7fb730c426dd80c0f652031-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2005/11/are-filipinos-the-next-american-minority-after-blacks/house_of_m_hu1e45c35c5ae512af4925df66f5ba26e3_411380_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;0687d692f7fb730c426dd80c0f652031-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2005/11/are-filipinos-the-next-american-minority-after-blacks/house_of_m.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;20 Nov 2005 5:03pm&#34;&gt;20 Nov 2005 5:03pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing or a bad thing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;Context: Mutant scientist Hank McCoy and human scientist Henry Pym were discussing the moral issuess surrounding Henry&amp;rsquo;s isolation of the mutant gene.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2005/11/are-filipinos-the-next-american-minority-after-blacks/house_of_m_hu1e45c35c5ae512af4925df66f5ba26e3_411380_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Stand Tall, Shake The Heavens
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/11/stand-tall-shake-the-heavens/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2005 14:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/11/stand-tall-shake-the-heavens/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Sometimes I can&amp;rsquo;t help but look back on the story so far and wonder where the hell I&amp;rsquo;m going. I&amp;rsquo;m in a pretty good place right now I guess, compared to a majority of people in this country. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a good job with a more than decent salary that lets me consume the mythical three-square-meals-a-day and pile on a bit of luxury on top of that.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But sometimes you stop and think to yourself, is this all there is to life? Slaving away as some company&amp;rsquo;s employee, getting promotions and raises, then retiring to watch your kids grow up? Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I love my job and the company I work for is great, very responsive to its employees. And I&amp;rsquo;m sure retiring and raising kids is a worthy goal for some people. But I highly doubt I&amp;rsquo;m that sort of person.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I get antsy sometimes, I often tell some people at work that I think of resigning at least once a week. The thing is, I don&amp;rsquo;t really know where to go or what to do if I resigned. All I know is at some point I would like to be doing something else with my life, something other than a regular nine-to-five (well in my case more of eight-to-seven) job, something that leaves a mark on the world. &lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;Stand tall and shake the heavens&lt;/span&gt;, I always like to say to myself.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My biggest problem right now is fear - fear of burning bridges. There was this awesome article somewhere by this shareware guy about how to start your own indie business (I&amp;rsquo;ll credit him sometime when I remember), and I remember one of the things he said that struck me the most: Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to burn bridges.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;But I am afraid, and with good reason. Like I said, I&amp;rsquo;ve got a good job, it&amp;rsquo;s decent pay and I even enjoy the work a good percentage of the time. And of course, I&amp;rsquo;m also providing &lt;a href=&#34;http://clair.pinoyweb.net/?p=467&#34;&gt;financial support for the rest of the family&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It becomes more frightening when I take into consideration what my passions are. The main ones right now are: gaming and web development. Taken together, it points in one direction: I should work on a web-based game. But the size of this task at this point is too huge for me to imagine, and the risks far too obvious. It would be very hard and it may take years to turn a profit, I would need some considerable financial base before doing this. And I would also need an idea of what game to do&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The second problem is focus. I lack focus. This I&amp;rsquo;ve known for a long time. Even if I decide on one course of action, I&amp;rsquo;m never sure that I would have the will to carry it on until the end. I can have focus and determination in the short term, i.e. a task that takes a week or so I can easily focus on. But the sort of life-changing ambitions I&amp;rsquo;m considering right now can&amp;rsquo;t be done in a week, and I fear that I will run out of steam half-way through and all will be for naught.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I need to overcome these problems. I need to overcome fear. Well, now that I think about it, it would be far easier to overcome fear if I knew that I had focus and determination. I need to be become stronger than I currently am.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Yay For Default Blogger Templates!
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/11/yay-for-default-blogger-templates/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2005 08:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/11/yay-for-default-blogger-templates/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Temporarily shifted to one after someone reported some javascript redirecting to a porn site. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen on my machine though. Sheesh, now I have to debug a non-replicable bug on my blog. And I didn&amp;rsquo;t even get any porn :p&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Update: Moved now to roywantsmeat.blogspot.com&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Why Do I Blog?
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/11/why-do-i-blog/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2005 23:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/11/why-do-i-blog/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;girl from work (10:19:57 AM): may blog ka ba roy?&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:20:18 AM): haha bakit mo natanong?&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:21:04 AM): nagbabasa kasi ako ngayon blogs ng high school friends ko e&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:21:11 AM): e ikli lang :D&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:21:28 AM): I have one with entries dating back to 2002 :p&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:21:49 AM): tlga... updated?&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:22:01 AM): minsan&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:22:24 AM): may icky luv stuff dun? &gt;:)&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:23:15 AM): haha maybe, maybe not&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:24:46 AM): haha :))&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:26:30 AM): sometimes you write something and later, you think, &#34;maybe I shouldn&#39;t have written that&#34;; you look back at it later and think &#34;what the hell was I thinking&#34;, but you should keep it up anyway, so you remember what it was like at that time :D&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:27:23 AM): hehe oks lang yan... alam ko yan... nagligpit lang kami last week dito sa house... and i saw an old journal from 1996 pa :))&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:27:50 AM): except yours is not in public for people to find by accident :p&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:28:06 AM): hehe yep :p&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:28:21 AM): anu isearch ko to find ur blog by accident &gt;:)&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:29:00 AM): ask and I will tell you; I have nothing to hide :D tsaka mostly boring stuff lang naman un, kailangan mo isaisahin yung posts to find anything remotely interesting&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:29:31 AM): sige... something to read while i wait for breakfast :)&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:29:49 AM): 10:30 is not a time for breakfast&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:30:20 AM): brunch :D&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:30:51 AM): I am thinking if it is a good idea...nobody else at work knows the url, and I am not sure if I have written anything stupid about work haha&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:31:14 AM): haha... baka may mga ***** sucks ba :))&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:31:23 AM): no, of course not&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:31:41 AM): if I give you the url, you must give me something interesting to read in return :D&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:31:54 AM): hindi akin na blog pwede? :))&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:32:08 AM): mas maganda kung iyo hehe&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:32:37 AM): haha... sabi ko nga wag mo na ko bigyan ng url e :))&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:33:03 AM): haha bat ayaw mo&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:34:02 AM): I am thinking if it is a good idea...nobody else at work knows the url, and I am not sure if I have written anything stupid about work haha&lt;br /&gt;girl from work (10:34:10 AM): familiar ba? :))&lt;br /&gt;zroytang (10:34:47 AM): :p&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;(Edited to remove the name of my company, and keep the name of the person I&#39;m chatting with anonymous. Not that I have anything to hide, but more because it feels like the right thing to do.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sometimes I wonder why I do. When I started keeping a website for myself back in &#39;02, it was more because I wanted to experience having to maintain one, and to sharpen my HTML skills (I&#39;m pretty good at it now I think, although my web design still sucks); When Blogger started becoming prominent, I figured, might as well convert to a blog to take advantage of automatic archiving and stuff, as it was becoming tedious to update a website by hand.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Even now, I&#39;m not sure why I go on, when I&#39;m not even sure if any people read this (I am aware that there are some that probably do, though they usually remain quiet :D) I&#39;m not sure why, but I guess I feel a need to maintain an online &#34;presence&#34; as it were. Part-time therapy, part-time boredom, part-time egotism perhaps?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Why then am I hesitant to let a coworker (who is also a friend) know the url? Like I said, I don&#39;t have anything to hide (and I&#39;m pretty sure I haven&#39;t said anything stupid about my work, mostly because, hey I like my work!). If I had anything to hide, why blog in public at all? You could always hide behind Livejournal&#39;s protected system (they have one of those right?) or use an anonymous name.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I don&#39;t have an answer. But if she (or anyone else) asks again, I will give the url. :D


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Bible Promotes Capitalism
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/11/the-bible-promotes-capitalism/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2005 20:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/11/the-bible-promotes-capitalism/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;At least, that&amp;rsquo;s what I was thinking when I was listening to today&amp;rsquo;s Gospel regarding the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parable_of_the_talents&#34;&gt;parable of the talents&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bsically, I think the gist of it is: God gives us talents, we should do the best we can; if we don&amp;rsquo;t, how can we complain when others do better?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yeah, I pay attention in Church. Go me!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>What I&#39;m Worth
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/11/what-im-worth/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2005 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/11/what-im-worth/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Apparently, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.humanforsale.com&#34; title=&#34;How much am I worth?&#34;&gt;I am worth $1,758,066 on HumanForSale.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also, I don&amp;rsquo;t why but&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;border: 1px solid #cccccc; background-color: white; width: 115px; text-align: center; padding: 0 0 10px 0;&#34;&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;margin: 0&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://static.flickr.com/23/25822676_789bf55448_t.jpg&#34; style=&#34;border:0;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;   &lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 11px;&#34;&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;http://roytang.sinfree.net/meat&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; is worth &lt;b&gt;$1,693.62&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-size: 10px;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.business-opportunities.biz/projects/how-much-is-your-blog-worth/&#34;&gt;How much is your blog worth?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://technorati.com/pix/tech-logo-embed.gif&#34; style=&#34;border: 0px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I wish someone would send me that cash, I could use it.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Nanowrimo...Why The Hell Not?
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/11/nanowrimo...why-the-hell-not/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2005 23:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/11/nanowrimo...why-the-hell-not/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I was introduced to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nanowrimo.org/&#34;&gt;nano&lt;/a&gt; a few years back when some fanfiction writers I knew online told me about it. I&amp;rsquo;ve attempted it every year, and failed each time. I just don&amp;rsquo;t have the drive.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I figured I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t start this year. After all, here I am, it&amp;rsquo;s the ninth of November, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything, prepared or otherwise, why fight a losing battle right?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you think I don&amp;rsquo;t fight losing battles, you don&amp;rsquo;t know me very well. Who knows, I may catch up and might actually make it this time.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;ll write in public too. I have no title, so bear with it &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;http://roynano.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;roynano&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Games - GameFAQs Top 100 Games (User Picks)
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/11/games-gamefaqs-top-100-games-user-picks/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2005 17:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/11/games-gamefaqs-top-100-games-user-picks/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;For it&amp;rsquo;s 10-year anniversary, GameFAQs has released the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamefaqs.com/features/top10/top10_100.html&#34;&gt;top 100 games&lt;/a&gt; as chosen by its&amp;rsquo; users during their anniversary contest.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To give you an idea of the general composition of the GameFAQs populace, 15 of the top 100 are Squaresoft games (including every single US-released main-series Final Fantasy), 17 are Nintendo games (5 Zelda, 7 Mario, 3 Metroid plus a couple more). Only 11 are PC games, 4 of which are from Blizzard.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And poor Megaman didn&amp;rsquo;t make it into the list. Good old Street Fighter II actually did better, coming in at 47.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Long Weekend (or lack thereof) and Open Source Code
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/11/the-long-weekend-or-lack-thereof-and-open-source-code/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2005 14:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/11/the-long-weekend-or-lack-thereof-and-open-source-code/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Filipinos traditionally take the weekend of All Saints/All Souls Day off, to rest and to visit their dearly departed. Westerners, particularly Americans, treat this time, specifically All Hallow&amp;rsquo;s Eve, as a children&amp;rsquo;s holiday. Given GMA&amp;rsquo;s penchant for holiday economics, it was evident we would get at least Monday and Tuesday off, and they were indeed declared as holidays, so Filipinos got a respite shortly before the much-dreaded EVAT implementation.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Not me, though. I had to work. Funny how the demo projects always manage to get me during times of extended holidays. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet had the benefit of a weekend - I spent most of Saturday through Wednesday in the office. Yesterday, I was able to negotiate that I be allowed to take today (Thursday) off; Seeing as how Nov. 4 was also an RP holiday (celebrating the end of Ramadan) and they were asking me to come in anyway, they gladly agreed to swap my holiday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anyway, the project I was working on at least proved to be slightly interesting. It was a popular open-source ERP software that we were customizing for the client. Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve never delved far into open source code before (although I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted do), so I daresay I hope the quality of other open-source code out there is at least better than this one. It may be a popular open-source business package, but the codebase seemed incredibly messy to me, and hard to pickup without having to go through traces and stuff. I don&amp;rsquo;t know, maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just demanding.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Sunday Work and Naruto Fillers
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/10/sunday-work-and-naruto-fillers/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2005 22:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/10/sunday-work-and-naruto-fillers/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I have to work today :( And probably tomorrow and the day after as well, although both are local holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On what may very well become one of the company&amp;rsquo;s biggest projects I might add, if we get the contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On an unrelated note, these filler Naruto episodes are just silly. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense that Raiga, one of the Seven Shinobi Swordsmen, can be defeated by Naruto and Lee (no matter how drunk Lee is); Raiga is supposedly on par with his former comrade Kisame, who was easily able to take on two of Konoha&amp;rsquo;s jounins. There should be a big gap in power levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what&amp;rsquo;s up with Lee and Naruto pretty much shock-resistant?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Games -- Walk of Game
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/10/games-walk-of-game/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2005 17:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/10/games-walk-of-game/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Voting for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.walkofgame.com/&#34;&gt;Walk of Game&lt;/a&gt; is up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My votes were: Starcraft, Civilization, Final Fantasy and Street Fighter II. Also Sid Meier and the Pac-man guy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: After some thought, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of silly to have a poll where you could vote everyday. There&amp;rsquo;s no chance for Pac-man to beat Final Fantasy here, as FF has an army of fanboys willing to vote everyday, and Pac-man&amp;hellip; well, a lot of his fans might vote once buy many won&amp;rsquo;t even realize or care that they can vote again.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>I Am Selling An Old Monitor
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/10/i-am-selling-an-old-monitor/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2005 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/10/i-am-selling-an-old-monitor/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ebili.com/product.asp?itemId=107167&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: Sold for the low, low price of P1500!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>SessionSaver Firefox Extension and Page State
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/10/sessionsaver-firefox-extension-and-page-state/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2005 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/10/sessionsaver-firefox-extension-and-page-state/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A post I made today had a 23-Oct timestamp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some investigation, I determined it was because I had left the create post screen open in a firefox tab last 23-Oct, then closed my browser. On my next launch of firefox, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/extensions/moreinfo.php?id=436&#34;&gt;SessionSaver&lt;/a&gt; extension automatically reloaded my previous session, but the create post screen still had the 23-Oct date. I had to manually change the date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note to self: Refresh the create post screen always.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>World of Warcraft -- Gorilla press!
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/10/world-of-warcraft-gorilla-press/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2005 12:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/10/world-of-warcraft-gorilla-press/</guid>
            <description>
            
            


&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2005/10/world-of-warcraft-gorilla-press/wow_gorilla_press_hu9b2b9438664b43abc8d27f3ee2821946_110447_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>When Are You Sick Enough to Call In Sick?
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/10/when-are-you-sick-enough-to-call-in-sick/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2005 03:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/10/when-are-you-sick-enough-to-call-in-sick/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m never really sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up this morning with a slight headache, compounding my annoying cough and colds. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I would have been able to make it to work and put on a whole day&amp;rsquo;s work, albeit probably at a less productive level. But then again, if I rest today, I may be able to put in a 110% productive day tomorrow, whereas not resting might cause me to be unproductive for more than one day.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>I Have A Phone! (Nokia 6020)
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/10/i-have-a-phone-nokia-6020/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2005 09:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/10/i-have-a-phone-nokia-6020/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After seemingly being the last man in the Philippines without a cellphone for so long, I broke down and bought one a couple of weeks ago. I&amp;rsquo;d post a picture, but I can&amp;rsquo;t find the digicam, and the phone can&amp;rsquo;t take a picture of itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 6020 itself seems pretty okay, although as a phone newbie I really have not much of a basis for comparison. The camera is nifty, but it took me a while to find a data cable for the phone. And now I can annoy people by SMS! (Not that I do, just that I can.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am of course fairly good with technical stuff, but also a newb with regards to phones. Being so, I have had trouble setting up things like MMS/GPRS/Email using the phone. I did have the GPRS up the other day, but then I downloaded some setting using Nokia&amp;rsquo;s service, and I lost it. Oh yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m on Globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Globe, is their customer support service really so bad? In this internet day and age, why do I have to call a hotline or go to a Globe store to get help in setting up my phone service settings? Their forums are a mess, their website looks terribly messy, and any setup info I could get from their website doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, I have a phone, and I&amp;rsquo;m whining already.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Idyllic Sundays
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/10/idyllic-sundays/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2005 08:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/10/idyllic-sundays/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It nevers fails, every week, around 1-2pm on a Sunday. For some unexplainable reason, an overpowering drowsiness steps in, and I must sacrifice 2-3 hours of my time to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not a normal sleep either, it&amp;rsquo;s the kind of sleepm that&amp;rsquo;s very hard to break. You wake up it&amp;rsquo;s 4pm, and think &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s some stuff I have to do,&amp;rdquo; but by 5pm you&amp;rsquo;re still happily sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only happens when I&amp;rsquo;m at home though (which is most Sundays), and not just to me. Every member of the household seems to take a siesta on Sundays.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>On Journalling, or How Hard It Is to Keep Up a Blog
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/10/on-journalling-or-how-hard-it-is-to-keep-up-a-blog/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2005 10:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/10/on-journalling-or-how-hard-it-is-to-keep-up-a-blog/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;In my line of work, which is to say &amp;ldquo;large-scale database systems&amp;rdquo;, there&amp;rsquo;s always the idea of &amp;ldquo;journalling&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;audit trail.&amp;rdquo; Basically, it means that for every transaction of significance, a record is kept of that transaction, stored in a log somewhere, so that should something malefic happen, the logs can be parsed and the trail can be followed, blame can be assigned and countermeasures can be taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, that&amp;rsquo;s not really limited to large-scale database systems. Any nontrivial software system should have some sort of journalling scheme involved, as printlogging is usually part and parcel of the development process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, I would wish that life too had a journalling system, one more reliable and less arcane than that gift humans call memory. I sometimes have trouble remembering what I had for breakfast this morning. Okay, that&amp;rsquo;s a lie, I seldom forget about meals less than a week old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I do have a tendency to forget other things. Tasks to do, people I&amp;rsquo;ve met, appointments I&amp;rsquo;ve set. A Saturday or so (I forget when), I had set a training meeting at 10am. Of course, my job does not require me to be in the office before noon on Saturdays, so I conveniently forgot about the meeting while playing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.worldofwarcraft.com/&#34;&gt;World of Warcraft&lt;/a&gt;, recalling such appointment only while taking a bath at 10:30am. (Luckily they didn&amp;rsquo;t mide me re-scheding to 11:30)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, frail as our memories are, we resort to other things to keep us on track. Paper, notebooks, to-do-lists, organizers, calendars, cellphones, PDAs, sticky notes and every so often, the proverbial rubber-band-around-the-finger. (Yes, I have done that, and yes I did forget what the rubber band stood for.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging, is of course, one of those outlets, one of those forms of introspection so commonplace on the web nowadays. I started quite some time ago, on another server, and have kept up, a bit sporadically if I might add. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been entirely too sure of my own reasons for blogging. Some parts ego, some parts experimentation, some parts therapy, perhaps some part exhibitionism? In any case, though I have considered several times to abandon this practice, especially when I have been too lazy to pursue it for months on end, I find myself giving it another go eventually. Because life should have an audit trail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shall I offer some excuse of why I have been so long without an entry? Some vague representations of WoW addiction, business at work or general laziness? I just did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, our story continues&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Final Fantasy VII -- Advent Children
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/09/final-fantasy-vii-advent-children/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2005 16:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/09/final-fantasy-vii-advent-children/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A friend of mine said, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s for die-hard fans only.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s right. Luckily, there are roughly seventy trillion die-hard FF7 fans. And I doubt they will be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advent Children is a DVD-movie about the events that happen two years after the events of the game. Some of the story-related parts might get you a bit sleepy, especially if you weren&amp;rsquo;t particularly fond of the whole Reunion/Jenova/planet thing from Final Fantasy VII, but that&amp;rsquo;s okay because&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; the actions scenes are flat-out spectacular! Seriously, the fight scenes from the trailer were incredibly cool, but the ones that you see in the movie itself, wow. It&amp;rsquo;s a good thing Square is really good at CGI, there&amp;rsquo;s no way those scenes could have been done with live action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of CGI, the quality of their work has definitely improved since Spirits Within. (Red XIII could use some work though.) I wish Spirits Within had had this level of awesomeness, but Advent Children has the advantage of a whole game of backstory with which the audience is already assumed to be familiar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for those skeptics who question how Cloud could possibly swing around that big-ass sword of his, better not watch this one as Cloud now fights with a big-ass sword in each hand!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are an FF7 fan of any sort, watch it. There are torrents all around, with subtitles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Books -- Neverwhere
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/09/books-neverwhere/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2005 07:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/09/books-neverwhere/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never really read much Neil Gaiman before — I&amp;rsquo;m not a particular fan of the Sandman series, for which he is most known. But I know some people who are big fans, so I respect his work at least. Neverwhere is only the second Gaiman book I&amp;rsquo;ve read (well, third maybe, I think I read that thing he co-wrote about the apocalypse), and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty much satisfied so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neil Gaiman does fantasy. Not medieval fantasy or sci-fi or anything like that, but fantasy in modern-day settings. Neverwhere takes place in London, a place with which the author seems intimately familiar. Except that his fictional London is divided into two cities &amp;ndash; London Above, which is the normal everyday London, and London Below, a temming network of underground locations where people fall through cracks and disappear. Something like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our protagonist is an ordinary guy, who meets a resident of London Below, and is thereupon plunged into it&amp;rsquo;s mad, mystical world, where the familiar laws of reality seldom seem to apply. The plot is nothing extraordinary, one you may have read in some form or other: Our intrepid hero meets an interesting cast of unlikely allies and they band together on a quest, ultimately saving the universe. Something like that. It&amp;rsquo;s Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s writing that stands out though; his flowery prose and florid descriptions brings the fantasy world of London Below to life, presenting a striking contrast to the protagonist&amp;rsquo;s boring life in London Above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, a good read. Nothing extraordinarily deep, but enough to make me interested in reading more Gaiman.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Manny Pacquiao
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/09/manny-pacquiao/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2005 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/09/manny-pacquiao/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I saw an interview with Manny Pacquiao on Rated K, apparently after his celebrated win last Sunday. Korina referred to him as a millionaire because of his share from the match, but Manny said he&amp;rsquo;s going to be giving a lot of it away. People told him to donate to Katrina, but he says there are also a lot of needy people in his own country so he&amp;rsquo;s giving to them first. He&amp;rsquo;s giving away food and stuff to poor people in his hometown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man, that guy&amp;rsquo;s got heart. No wonder he&amp;rsquo;s a local hero.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Looking for a phone and finding bad webapps
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/09/looking-for-a-phone-and-finding-bad-webapps/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2005 11:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/09/looking-for-a-phone-and-finding-bad-webapps/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Sorry about the title. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any succinct way to put it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, yeah. I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to be trying to get a phone. People have been harassing me for years about the fact that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a phone. Since my vacation is already half-wasted already, I figure I&amp;rsquo;d go online and get some info on what phone I&amp;rsquo;d buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, bear with me a bit, I&amp;rsquo;m really stupid when it comes to phones, since I&amp;rsquo;ve practically never owned one. If there&amp;rsquo;s any better way or better place to look for the info than the way I describe here, tell me about it. 😀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, to find out what are the available phones and their features, I check the website of one of the major providers to see what handsets they list, since supposedly this tells me what models are available locally. FYI, I chose to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smart.com.ph/SMART/Catalog/Handsets/&#34;&gt;Smart&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, this helps me find phones which have features I like. But the Smart website only gives me prices offered by Smart when the phone is tied to one of their plans. Let&amp;rsquo;s assume I want a bit more flexibility and don&amp;rsquo;t want to be tied to the plan. I have no idea where to check the prices though, so I hit two auction sites instead: &lt;a href=&#34;http://ebili.com&#34;&gt;ebili&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://bidshot.com&#34;&gt;bidshot&lt;/a&gt;, so I can get some idea what people are willing to pay for these models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy enough right? Check the features, cross-check the prices, choose a phone. Some notes on these websites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart: Why the hell is the list of phones not sorted in any logical order? None that I can see anyway. When I see a cheap, er, reasonably-priced phone on the auction sites, I want to check the features of that phone on the Smart website but it takes me a while to find it. Some sort of search feature would have been nice. (Or maybe there is one and I missed it?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ebili/Bidshot: Why the hell is the search result list not sortable in any way? If you have a grid of search results, I don&amp;rsquo;t see how difficult it is to implement sortable columns; every single webapp I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on has this feature! I was almost tempted to send them an email offering my services as a freelancer to implement reasonable searching features such as sorting and filtering. These are NOT difficult things to implement, I don&amp;rsquo;t know why we don&amp;rsquo;t see them in all websites; I can understand the performance concern if you&amp;rsquo;re potentially returning millions of hits (i.e. Google), but these searches have hits ranging in dozens, sorting performance hit should be minimal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is all, just wanted to rant. And no, I have not chosen a phone yet.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Games -- World of Warcraft
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/09/games-world-of-warcraft/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2005 00:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/09/games-world-of-warcraft/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It may very well have been a mistake. Buying and installing World of Warcraft on the first day of my leave, that is. Now I spend some 3-4 hours daily on the addictive beast. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to stop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard, World of Warcraft is Blizzard&amp;rsquo;s MMORPG take on it&amp;rsquo;s famous RTS series, and it&amp;rsquo;s one helluva good game. It looks excellent, the gameplay is terrific, people don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be assholes, etc. The only real downside is that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to stop playing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blizzard seems to have hit the sweet spot of the mythical RPG spiral: you always have that urge to go for one more creep, one more quest, one more level, and it repeats ad infinitum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to get bored with the game, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re a true-blue follower of the Warcraft series. You get to immerse yourself in famous locations and meet characters and heroes from the RTS games. You get to do quests, literally dozens of quests throwing themselves on you. You get to customize your character. You get to wander off to gather obscure ingredients. You get to interact with other players, challenge them, fight alongside them, raid whole cities with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a few other MMOs before, and none really struck me so hard as WoW&amp;hellip; other games get you hopelessly stuck in the levelling &amp;ldquo;grind&amp;rdquo;, but WoW throws so much stuff to do at you that it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to forget about that level bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend the game to any serious gamer, even to those who primarily like single-player RPGs. Because honestly, you can play WoW just like a single-player RPG with a vast multitude of quests (except that you occasionally get some other characters helping you out randomly). I&amp;rsquo;ll play again in a short while :p&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Good, The Bad and the Ugly
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/09/the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2005 02:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/09/the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to do during this hiatus was to watch more movies — we&amp;rsquo;ve got a ton of DVDs downstairs I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen yet. Since I had just finished the &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2005/09/books-dark-tower-v-wolves-of-the-calla/&#34;&gt;fifth book of Stephen King&amp;rsquo;s western fantasy&lt;/a&gt;, I started this task with Sergio Leone&amp;rsquo;s western opus, The Good, The Bad and The Ugly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched many westerns before. This is probably the first one I completed. And you know what it reminds me of? Dragonball. Ages of staring at each other, hands hovering over your guns, ending in two seconds of gunfire. I know they&amp;rsquo;re a lot more speak-y in Dragonball, but it gave me the same feeling&amp;hellip; the anticipative build-up and the big, explosive finish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God, that was a long movie. I think it clocked in at 2:45 or so. It was mistake to watch this movie in late afternoon, as I started getting drowsy towards the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen Clint Eastwood this young before! But he reminds me of how I usually visualize Roland of Gilead. And the impossibly good shooting in the movie seems characteristic of Roland&amp;rsquo;s gunslingers as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good movie, though longish.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Books: Dark Tower V -- Wolves of the Calla
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/09/books-dark-tower-v-wolves-of-the-calla/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2005 04:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/09/books-dark-tower-v-wolves-of-the-calla/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;There will be water if ka wills it.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Roland of Gilead&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a Powerbooks gift certificate the other week, and the Powerbooks at Megamall happened to have a sale, so I took a look around. And lo, I was lucky enough to find a copy of the fifth book of Stephen King&amp;rsquo;s epic western fantasy, The Dark Tower. It was a huge book, larger than my copies of the first four, but with the same cover style and by the same publisher, so it was the copy I wanted. I spent less than a hundred pesos on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it was that I once again journeyed into the world/s of the Dark Tower, following the path of Roland of Gilead and his ka-tet of gunslingers along the path of the Beam, heading inexporably towards the Dark Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dark Tower series has always been a weird sort of hybrid. Primarily a western, set in a fantasy multiverse which intersects with multiple versions of our own reality, Roland and his posse find themselves facing robots, bears, wizards, psychotic trains, undead and such. This time they face &amp;ldquo;Wolves&amp;rdquo;, an unknown new enemy who plague a farming community along the path of the Beam. Like any good RPG-party, the gunslingers decide to offer aid to the people of the Calla, though not all would accept their help. In exchange, they are granted the power to travel back to New York, the nexus of all New Yorks, where they must protect the Rose, an incarnation or manifestation of the Dark Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing I did not like about this copy: It had illustrations. Normally, that would be a good thing, but I find I did not really want to know what Roland of Gilead looked like, even to another person, as it spoiled my own vision of what the book tells me. That&amp;rsquo;s how good the series is — it&amp;rsquo;s the type of series where you form your own version of it in your head and you are completely drawn into its saga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, the book is dark and compelling. Despite the hectic work schedule last week, I finish the thick book in less than four days, and the volume ends in cliffhanger, as the ka-tet is broken. Two more books to go before the end of their quest; I can only hope the last two come out in my preferred format soon.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The A-Team!
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/09/the-a-team/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2005 03:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/09/the-a-team/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My hiatus involves quite a bit of TV of course, especially since I get some idle time while waiting for installations/formatting/downloads to finish. Today, for the first time in maybe twenty years, I saw an exciting action-packed episode of the A-Team!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those not in the know, the A-Team was a bunch of rogue ex-commandos who usually acted as mercs, fighting for good, beating bad guys and saving the day. In the parlance of Roland of Gilead, gunslingers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The A-Team TV series was most famous for having as one of its cast the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mrtvseverything.com/&#34;&gt;now-popular-on-the-internet&lt;/a&gt; tough-talking, fool-pitying &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mr._T&#34;&gt;Mr. T&lt;/a&gt;. I also particularly like the antics of their resident screwball flyball, &amp;ldquo;Crazy Man&amp;rdquo; Murdock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember that Marvel even had an A-Team comic book out when I was a kid; I had an issue or two. I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to go out and look for copies of those now. 😀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a good episode too, but ended with a cliffhanger. It&amp;rsquo;s a good thing I&amp;rsquo;m free to watch the next episode tomorrow. 😀&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Total Hard Drive Space: Tripled!
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/09/total-hard-drive-space-tripled/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2005 03:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/09/total-hard-drive-space-tripled/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Bought a brand-spankin&amp;rsquo; new 160GB hard drive yesterday. Seagate Barracuda 7200. Yessir, ups the total hard drive capacity at home to 240 gigs, I hope we don&amp;rsquo;t fill it up too fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moved the 40GB hard drive on the primary computer to the secondary (for a total of 80 on the secondary), and installed the new one on the primary. My brother Alvin was working with me on this, and it took us a better part of three hours to get the connection right (one of the casings wasn&amp;rsquo;t very agreeable)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installed a fresh XP on the primary, that took a while. Almost immediately after setting up the network/internet the first time, got smacked by a couple of trojans and a virus, seemed to have lost some important system files as everything went wonky. Lesson learned, I reinstalled XP clean and this time, I installed my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.free-av.com/&#34;&gt;free antivirus package of choice&lt;/a&gt; before starting the internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned something new today. It seems the OS has some sort of limit on the partition size? It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t let me install it as a single 160Gb partition, so I had to settle for a 128 gig main partition and a 21 gig secondary (the unfortunately uneven division due to my not knowing how to handle the situation correctly during the initial install). Ten gigabytes lost, bummer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything seems fine now. Took me most of the night (up to 2AM) to transfer the files from the old hard drive (across the network cable). On hindsight, next time I should try to see if some disk-imaging utility would be better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes for next time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure all the installers are handy before starting. We were pretty lucky this time. 😀&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently, the order in which the hard drives are connected on the IDE cable does matter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divide the partitions neatly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install antivirus before opening internet connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See if a disk-imaging utility can be used to transfer the files/OS/settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is all.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Two Weeks of Freedom
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/09/two-weeks-39a-freedom/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2005 03:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/09/two-weeks-39a-freedom/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Freedom from work at least. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to take a two-week leave since late last year, but never found a chance. Now is the perfect time, just before I jump full-swing into the next large project (which may or may not be confidential in nature)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, no thinking about work for two weeks, unless they call me in for an emergency :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What stuff do I have planned? I&amp;rsquo;m not skipping town or anything. As I keep telling people, if I plan it, it&amp;rsquo;s not free time! But I do have some stuff I want to get around to, I&amp;rsquo;ll let you in if anything&amp;rsquo;s interesting :p&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Google Talk
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/08/google-talk/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2005 16:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/08/google-talk/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;As you may have heard, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/talk/index.html&#34;&gt;Google Talk&lt;/a&gt; is up. The client looks neat and all, but there&amp;rsquo;s not much reason for most people to start using it. Sure, the voice chat thing is neat, but I know that Yahoo Messenger supports it, and probably some of the others do? Otherwise, the client seems awfully thin. Simple, like Google, but it needs to be a lot more than that to make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting thing about the service itself is, it&amp;rsquo;s actually seems to be just a server running the open source jabber protocol. Since it&amp;rsquo;s jabber, you can have more than one client on without knocking the other offline. (Am running both google client and GAIM right now) This means, if you leave your PC on at home all day for some reason, at work you can still log in to Google Talk without knocking the home login off the server.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Webhosting?
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/08/webhosting/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2005 15:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/08/webhosting/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of getting some webhosting. Not that I&amp;rsquo;m unsatisfied with my free webhosting and Blogger mind you, but sometimes I just get the urge to do some server-side chicanery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mandatory:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PHP/mySQL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good service, tech support, fast response time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No-hassle payments (which means I prefer local, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to pay through credit cards or anything)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Of course, a good deal on space, bandwidth, reliability, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optional:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tomcat/JSP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not ploghost though. :(&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Pop Ratio
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/08/pop-ratio/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2005 15:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/08/pop-ratio/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve known of Markku Seguerra&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://rebelpixel.com&#34;&gt;rebelpixel&lt;/a&gt; website for a while, having enjoyed his constant stream of &lt;a href=&#34;http://lyrics.rebelpixel.com&#34;&gt;OPM-friendly lyrics section&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I came upon &lt;a href=&#34;http://rebelpixel.com/archives/2005/08/11/pop-ratio-originals/&#34;&gt;his blog post&lt;/a&gt; about his band with some Pisay 96 batchmates. Their band is Pop Ratio, and he&amp;rsquo;s made available some original tracks and also some covers on his website. They&amp;rsquo;re pretty okay, you might want to listen to a few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know some of my own batchmates are active in bands, I wonder if I can get any (free) samples of their music?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>A hundred pirated games
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/08/a-hundred-pirated-games/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2005 09:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/08/a-hundred-pirated-games/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My brother estimates we have at least a hundred pirated copies of PS2 games. (Please don&amp;rsquo;t lecture me in any way on piracy, I&amp;rsquo;ve said &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2005/02/some-thoughts-on-piracy/&#34;&gt;my piece&lt;/a&gt; before.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, we have spent at least ten thousand pesos (roughly two hundred american) on pirated PS2 games. And out of those hundred copies, some games we have two or three copies of (due to the problems generally associated with illegal copies); Out of all those pirated games, I&amp;rsquo;d make a conservative estimate that at least 20 games were actually playably good. We got good playing time out of them, and it was a good experience overall. So the effective cost per good game comes out to around five hundred pesos (roughly ten american dollars). This number is important, because this magic number is the price at which it becomes worthwhile for us to buy an original game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I make a game, I will price it in this range.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>HTML/CSS Trickery
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/08/htmlcss-trickery/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2005 08:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/08/htmlcss-trickery/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The whole web developer thing was boring me for a while. But last week I got to help on some preliminary webpage design for one of the projects, so my interest in HTML/CSS/Javascript is a bit tweaked. (Hence the slightly updated stylesheet — try changing font sizes now.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://roytang.net/sandbox/&#34;&gt;some HTML/CSS trickery&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll add stuff here as I try them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re using IE, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t appreciate it much.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>I&#39;m Back. And I&#39;m 27.
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/08/i39m-back-and-i39m-27/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2005 08:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/08/i39m-back-and-i39m-27/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Yeah, so there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an impromptu hiatus anyway. Unplanned and whatever. Work has been hell lately. Not a tedious kind of hell though. Just the sort that sucks up a lot of time. I spent more than 15 hours in the office on my birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty-seven huh? I wish I had more to say, but birthdays seem to matter less and less as I get older. I&amp;rsquo;m in a good place right now, but I&amp;rsquo;m still not where I ultimately want to be. I have a long road ahead of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe someday I&amp;rsquo;ll get around to it.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Linux is shareware?
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/07/linux-is-shareware/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2005 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/07/linux-is-shareware/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Or so the paper says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Philippine Daily Inquirer had an article today about Oracle targetting local SMEs. Apparently they have an advantage because they use &amp;ldquo;the Linux shareware.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too bad I can&amp;rsquo;t find the article online.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>