<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>vpdebates on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/vpdebates/</link>
      <description>Recent content in vpdebates on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 11:05:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/vpdebates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Vice Presidential Debate
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/04/vice-presidential-debate/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 11:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/04/vice-presidential-debate/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Commentary thread for the vice presidential debate today&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[18:55] Leni doing well. Calm, composed yet striking hard. Marcos following Binay strategy: deny deny deny #vpdebates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:05] Apc asking opponents for a plan but when asked to elaborate on their plans: gagalingan lang namin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:09] Omg this debate. So many savage burns&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:12] APC really hates BBM. Sya kasi ang kaagaw sa duterte supporters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:15] So far APC, Trillianes, Leni doing well. Chiz and Gringo weak answers. BBM lol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:21] Leni not shying away from traffic problems. Hits her strong points emphasizing she&amp;rsquo;s a commuter and taga province&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:38] APC coming out strong on traffic/transpo. Leni answered well, not denying delays in infra. Would&amp;rsquo;ve been better if she came out vs Abaya&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:46] Leni wasted a lot of time describing the internet problems. APC hitting OFW and oligarchy notes popular with duterte supporters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:52] APC doing much better than his presidential candidate, always hitting the political will notes whenever infra is discussed and focusing on anecdotal stories of ordinary folk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:55] Bakit ang sleep inducing ng boses ni Chiz? Parang mas ok na mag orate si Grace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[20:15] Grabe chiz wth were you even talking about. Parang estudyante na pinipilit punuin yung 2 page na essay, kulang na lang lakihan yung font&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[20:17] Leni and BBM gave good answers to the cabinet position question. BBM speaks well (like his father) except when trying to defend his family&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[20:19] Closing statements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leni: Among the 6 of us, may the best woman win &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chiz: did he actually say anything? Parang estudyante na pinipilit mapuno yung 2 pages na essay. Kulang na lang lakihan yung font size&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;APC: All-in na kami dun sa 3-6 months!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[20:33] I think Leni and APC performed best in this debate. BBM speaks well but as expected unable to defend his family/martial law. Trillianes medyo ok. Chiz and Gringo weak&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/04/vice-presidential-debate/10154524365523912/12963585_10154053530203926_1036088610432699325_n_hud62f4a523a18e6da566bbe5286afd037_2675_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>