<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>regret on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/tags/regret/</link>
      <description>Recent content in regret on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/tags/regret/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Different is not necessarily better
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/03/different-is-not-necessarily-better/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/03/different-is-not-necessarily-better/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/uploads/2019/different-better.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/GetMotivated/comments/axy274/image_perspective/&#34;&gt;r/GetMotivated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s fun to think about &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/02/it-might-have-been/&#34;&gt;what might have been&lt;/a&gt;, but often regret is tinged with optimism - the optimism that given another chance, we might have made different decisions and obtained better outcomes. But different doesn&amp;rsquo;t always mean better, so such visualizations are often pointless speculation.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>It might have been
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/02/it-might-have-been/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/02/it-might-have-been/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Of all sad words of tongue or pen, the saddest are these, &amp;lsquo;It might have been.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;― John Greenleaf Whittier, Maud Muller - Pamphlet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is human nature perhaps, to think about those alternate realities that might have come from different decisions or different dispositions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I was braver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I was more decisive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I didn&amp;rsquo;t have something holding me back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I knew what I knew now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I had fought harder for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I could speak to her again one last time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If only I realized what it all meant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While unavoidable, best not to linger in these alternate worlds too long. Regret is a trap that takes us away from the present. Learn what we can from our mistakes, and move on.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>&#34;Choose without Regret&#34; and the Fear of Missing Out
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2018/11/choose-without-regret-and-the-fear-of-missing-out/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2018/11/choose-without-regret-and-the-fear-of-missing-out/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;With the rise of social media, we get to see a lot of things our friends are doing or buying or places they&amp;rsquo;re going to, and this has led to the rise of the phenomenon called FOMO or Fear of Missing Out. It&amp;rsquo;s a type of envy of other people&amp;rsquo;s lives and as a type of envy it&amp;rsquo;s also a form of regret for our own life choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOMO is rightly called a fear, and like all irrational fears, it should be dismissed as soon as one recognizes it. I had the draft of the first part of this post for a while, but after revisiting it, I realized how much it applied to one of my own decisions I&amp;rsquo;m faced with right now. I&amp;rsquo;ve already evaluated the decision and have made a rational assessment, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2018/11/two-pronged-decision-making/&#34;&gt;my irrational subconscious&lt;/a&gt; is giving me some hesitation. I realize now that the hesitation comes from a place of fear, specifically a fear of missing out on opportunities and experiences by giving up on the other choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can&amp;rsquo;t live our lives with the fear of regret or missing out, that can only lead us to indecision and paralysis. I try to live without FOMO and one of my own personal life tenets is to &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2017/03/paella/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Choose without regret&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. As long as I made the best decision I could given the information I had at the time, I will not have any regrets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Pretty sure an attitude of FOMO is one of the main reason social media use can lead to depression too!)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>