<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>wheel of time on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/tags/wheel-of-time/</link>
      <description>Recent content in wheel of time on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/tags/wheel-of-time/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Wheel of Time: Eye of the World
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/05/wheel-of-time-eye-of-the-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/05/wheel-of-time-eye-of-the-world/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Continuing with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/05/wheel-of-time-new-spring/&#34;&gt;Wheel of Time re-read&lt;/a&gt;! I devoured Eye of the World much more quickly than I expected, finishing the book in less than 3 days. It helps that I had already read it before of course, but I think there&amp;rsquo;s also a part of me that enjoys escaping into this fantasy world when the &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/05/ph-elections-2019-otso-diretso-compromises-lesser-evils/&#34;&gt;real world outlook seems dire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the book shows a lot of Tolkien-esque plot influence, especially near the start: Some kids from a backwater village are visited by a magic user and after some troubles are forced on the run from black riders? Sounds familiar. Not only that, but you can even map the characters somewhat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emond Field kids -&amp;gt; Hobbits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moiraine -&amp;gt; Gandalf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lan -&amp;gt; Aragorn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thom -&amp;gt; Okay, LoTR didn&amp;rsquo;t have a bard, but he does take the role of sacrificing himself while the kids run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s even a location called the Mountains of Dhoom, which is a riduclous name!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s fine. I remember back when I read this series the first time I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much patience for Jordan&amp;rsquo;s prose where he describes everything in so many words including the food being eaten, the clothes worn, the crowds, the buildings and so on; I was always hungry for the plot so I tended to skim a lot of the background noise. This time I made more of an effort to appreciate the prose and the settings, since I already knew most of the plot. It is not as boring as I feared it would be, and perhaps my imagination is more enriched because of it. The characters certainly look a bit different in my head now than they did before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the book does take its time. After Shadar Logoth, the party gets split up and it takes them forever to be reunited. It isn&amp;rsquo;t until 85% through the book that everyone gets back together and Moiraine concludes that they have to go visit the titular Eye of the World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Nynaeve and Lan relationship wasn&amp;rsquo;t built up very well either I think. It seems they just were suddenly affectionate near the end, after barely anything more than longing looks and barely any conversations for most of the book. Also, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the WoT TV series if only to learn how to properly pronounce &amp;ldquo;Nynaeve&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book ends with a victory for the good guys. Not THE victory, as some of them think, but it is a victory. But it is also a strange place, as Rand discovers what he can do and decides to leave the group for a while. The next book takes them to Ilian for the Great Hunt I believe, and I seem to recall that it may be a long time before the Emond Fielders are together in the same place again. Onwards!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Wheel of Time: New Spring
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/05/wheel-of-time-new-spring/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/05/wheel-of-time-new-spring/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Since I was going to be taking a long trip in a month, I was looking for some books to read on the plane and in airports and whatnot while waiting. I settled on a re-read of Robert Jordan&amp;rsquo;s Wheel of Time series, a pretty good time for it since by next year we may have a TV series from Amazon (hopefully better than Game of Thrones). Side note: Wheel of Time is also why I&amp;rsquo;m not optimistic that GRRM can finish ASoIaF in just two more books - Jordan took forever and died before he could finish WoT and even Sanderson who took over needed an additional three books to finish the saga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I read any of the books - I bought and read the final book &lt;em&gt;A Memory of Light&lt;/em&gt; when it came out, so that was around 2013. That means I followed the series for around two decades - I remember borrowing &lt;em&gt;Eye of the World&lt;/em&gt; from a friend maybe around late high school/early college (circa mid 90s) and quickly going through the books until I was caught up. Wheel of Time was my first real epic fantasy series - I only read Tolkien later on and before that most of my fantasy exposure was limited to TV and movies. I enjoyed the first half of the 14-book series, then got &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2005/05/wheel-of-time-10-crossroads-of-twilight/&#34;&gt;annoyed by the pacing in the second half&lt;/a&gt;, and was relieved when Sanderson managed to satisfactorily land the plane with &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/41200573244/so-i-finished-reading-a-memory-of-light-today&#34;&gt;Memory of Light&lt;/a&gt;. My annoyance with the later books may have been due to the fact that I had to wait for each one in turn to be released - it will be interesting to see how the series holds up for me now that I can read all the books in succession. I also like to think I&amp;rsquo;ve matured as a reader since then and will be able to appreciate the books differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also well behind my book reading target for this year, so doing a re-read of a long series gives me a good bump. Also, since the books have been out forever, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to bother to mark spoilers when I&amp;rsquo;m discussing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am however starting with a book I haven&amp;rsquo;t read yet - &lt;em&gt;New Spring&lt;/em&gt; is a prequel novel that I never bothered to read before. The story takes place 20 years before &lt;em&gt;Eye of the World&lt;/em&gt;, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story follows the PoV of two characters introduced in &lt;em&gt;Eye of the World&lt;/em&gt; - Moiraine Damodred, starting out as an Accepted with future Amyrlin Siuan Sanche at the White Tower in Tar Valon, and Lan Mandragoran, fresh off the tail end of the Aiel War and how their paths eventually intersect. Given the two main characters future, we can anticipate that the novel will end with them forming the Warder bond. The book is short - about half as long as &lt;em&gt;Eye of the World&lt;/em&gt; - but as is typical of Robert Jordan, it takes a long time to get there, as most of the first half of the book centers around Moiraine and Siuan navigating the intrigues of the White Tower as the search for The Dragon Reborn begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pace picks up a bit once Moiraine manages to leave the tower and crosses path with Lan and they realize the existence of the Black Ajah searching for the Dragon Reborn. Yes, reading this book before the rest means you are already aware the Black Ajah exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given how at the start of this book Lan is openly disdainful of getting caught in Aes Sedai problems and how tight Moiraine and Lan are by the time of &lt;em&gt;Eye of the World&lt;/em&gt;, I assumed there would be some big life-changing event near the end of the book that would cause him to change his mind and allow the Warder bond, but I was a bit whelmed by how it happened. One would think losing his oldest bondsman to the Black Ajah would Lan more wary of Aes Sedai, but all it took was a quick reminder from Moiraine about the stakes and he easily acquiesed to the bond. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished the book in 3 days (as I said, quite short), but the other books in the series are at least twice as long, and there are 14 more books to go, so I think there should be plently leftover by the time the trip rolls around.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>So I finished reading A Memory of Light today (last Wheel of Time book)
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2013/01/so-i-finished-reading-a-memory-of-light-today-last-wheel-of-time-book/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 16:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2013/01/so-i-finished-reading-a-memory-of-light-today-last-wheel-of-time-book/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a satisfyingly good ending. The book is action-packed, with 80-90% of the book just bloody, bloody fighting, and very little of the whiny manipulative bitchiness that characterized some of the weaker books in the series. As far as I can tell most of the dangling points are wrapped up neatly, many characters get to be heroes and die, etc. Part of me wonders whether I&amp;rsquo;d be this satisfied if Jordan had managed to finish everything himself.&lt;/p&gt;


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Wheel of Time 10 -- Crossroads of Twilight
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/05/wheel-of-time-10-crossroads-of-twilight/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2005 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/05/wheel-of-time-10-crossroads-of-twilight/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Haven&amp;rsquo;t read Robert Jordan in a while. Someone gave me Crossroads of Twilight as a gift, so I read it and hope that his pacing has improved. It has not. He writes well enough, dialogue is nice, descriptions are more than adequate, but I expect some things to happen in his books! He has so many plots running at once, he should at least resolve two or three per book. Perrin, Mat and Elayne get a lot of chapters, but they barely get anything done. Rand al&amp;rsquo;Thor himself barely gets one chapter, and I&amp;rsquo;m thinking it was just put in &amp;lsquo;cause people would be pissed if he didn&amp;rsquo;t actually appear in the book. Egwene at least had the good sense to go out and try to do something. Not that she got anywhere sensible of course&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swear, with so many things going on, it will take him forever to wrap up this series. And while that may be good for him, I wonder how many people will bother following the books for so long? Especially when they&amp;rsquo;re more of the same&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>