<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Roy Tang::</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/</link>
      <description>Recent content on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
        
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1379041002778984448/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 11:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1379041002778984448/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some kind of yoga pose #sketchdaily 95/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1379041002778984448/1_1379041002778984448_EyNWeiFUYAEE5EL_hu40ce2adc15a6a7bf9d6c44c881f6376f_59242_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Reviews: Guards! Guards! and Men at Arms by Terry Pratchett
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/book-reviews-guards-guards-and-men-at-arms-by-terry-pratchett/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 08:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/book-reviews-guards-guards-and-men-at-arms-by-terry-pratchett/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So after reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/neuromancer/&#34;&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/a&gt; last month, I was looking for a bit of lighter fare, so I decided to work on some Discworld books and started with the first book of the City Watch subseries, &lt;em&gt;Guards! Guards!&lt;/em&gt;. I was already quite a bit in when I was like &amp;ldquo;why does all of this seem so familiar? Are Discworld books really so same-y that it feels like I&amp;rsquo;ve read this before?&amp;rdquo; The good news is that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t true, Discworld books aren&amp;rsquo;t super-samey; I have read it before, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/805050532834353152/&#34;&gt;way back in 2016&lt;/a&gt; in fact. And I also found out that I had &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/equal-rites/&#34;&gt;done this in 2016 with another Discworld book as well&lt;/a&gt;! Ok, so I guess that means they are a bit same-y, but on the other hand I am getting better at retention because I actually recognized it this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I went ahead and completed the re-read and proceeded to the next City Watch book, &lt;em&gt;Men at Arms&lt;/em&gt;. And this one was totally new to me, for sure. So, this is a bit of a double review. And maybe a review of the Discworld series as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Guards! Guards!&lt;/em&gt; we get Pratchett&amp;rsquo;s treatment of common fantasy tropes such as dwarves, dragons that can&amp;rsquo;t possibly be flying, and unknown heroes becoming king by slaying evil dragons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have the effrontery to be squeamish, it thought at him. But we were dragons. We were supposed to be cruel, cunning, heartless, and terrible. But this much I can tell you, you ape—the great face pressed even closer, so that Wonse was staring into the pitiless depths of his eyes—we never burned and tortured and ripped one another apart and called it morality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Terry Pratchett, &lt;em&gt;Guards! Guards!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Men at Arms&lt;/em&gt;, Pratchett expands on the cast of the City Watch subseries, explores the guild structure of the city of Ankh Morpork, and expands the lore of races such as dwarves and trolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take boots, for example. He earned thirty-eight dollars a month plus allowances. A really good pair of leather boots cost fifty dollars. But an affordable pair of boots, which were sort of OK for a season or two and then leaked like hell when the cardboard gave out, cost about ten dollars. Those were the kind of boots Vimes always bought, and wore until the soles were so thin that he could tell where he was in Ankh-Morpork on a foggy night by the feel of the cobbles.
But the thing was that good boots lasted for years and years. A man who could afford fifty dollars had a pair of boots that’d still be keeping his feet dry in ten years’ time, while a poor man who could only afford cheap boots would have spent a hundred dollars on boots in the same time and would still have wet feet.
This was the Captain Samuel Vimes “Boots” theory of socioeconomic unfairness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Terry Pratchett, &lt;em&gt;Men at Arms&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yes, the Discworld books are maybe kind of same-y, but that&amp;rsquo;s kind of a good thing? You usually know what to expect. They&amp;rsquo;re light reading, they&amp;rsquo;re funny in a dry British humor kind of way, and Pratchett likes to attack and parody and deconstruct common fantasy tropes. I like the books, despite their sameyness, although I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll ever be able to work my way through the entire series.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>books</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to bloodyvints&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/bloodyvints/statuses/1378940700780195841/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1378942372751417350/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 05:27:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1378942372751417350/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to bloodyvints&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/bloodyvints/statuses/1378940700780195841/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bloodyvints/&#34;&gt;@bloodyvints&lt;/a&gt; What series and issue is this from?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1378926899255123970/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 04:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1378926899255123970/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Open tomb #sketchdaily 94/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1378926899255123970/1_1378926899255123970_EyLusv2VIAAlOWj_hu423beb4ad258905d22baabf6507689e4_213742_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2021-04-04
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/weeknotes-2021-04-04/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 07:23:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/weeknotes-2021-04-04/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s April! Or as it&amp;rsquo;s otherwise known, March 2020 month 13. As is usual, we are suffering the sweltering summer heat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, it&amp;rsquo;s Easter Sunday, if that means anything to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world&#34;&gt;The world:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surprising almost no one, the PH government extended the ECQ lockdown in the NCR+ bubble. Anyone with half a brain could have told you that the one week ECQ was no way going to be enough, given what we know about the virus&amp;rsquo; life cycle. Meanwhile, we continued to hit record numbers of new cases, our 7-day rolling average now the highest in SEA since the pandemic began. It&amp;rsquo;s like we&amp;rsquo;re in the same situation we were in last year, except the numbers are much, much higher. And yet our leadership is like &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/inquirerdotnet/status/1377810270500790274&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not so bad, even France has lockdowns!&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;. Sigh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-of-interest&#34;&gt;Links of interest:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Austin Kleon reminds us that we all need &lt;a href=&#34;https://austinkleon.com/2018/01/19/something-to-look-forward-to/&#34;&gt;something to look forward to&lt;/a&gt;. (Arbitrary stupid goals!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was fascinated by this &lt;a href=&#34;https://theconversation.com/the-man-with-no-plot-how-i-watched-lee-child-write-a-jack-reacher-novel-51220&#34;&gt;article about how Lee Child writes Jack Reacher novels on the fly&lt;/a&gt;, mainly because that seems like the sort of &amp;ldquo;less work&amp;rdquo; approach I&amp;rsquo;d prefer when writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a curiosity: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benford%27s_law&#34;&gt;Benford&amp;rsquo;s Law&lt;/a&gt;, or the law of anomalous numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://newrepublic.com/article/161106/defense-nothing&#34;&gt;In defense of doing nothing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spent a long time working with Java projects, so &lt;a href=&#34;https://advancedweb.hu/a-categorized-list-of-all-java-and-jvm-features-since-jdk-8-to-16/&#34;&gt;this long list of new features from Java 8 to 16&lt;/a&gt; was interesting to me. After reading this, I asked my old workmates what version of Java they were now using, and they were still on Java 8, the same version as when I left there 6 years ago! Time flows differently in the enterprise universe I guess.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My friends were amazed I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6-1Ue0FFrHY&#34;&gt;Long, Long Man japanese commercials&lt;/a&gt; before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enjoyed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Peu6lw0nido&#34;&gt;this case study by Elsa Charretier of a Hawkeye comic book panel by David Aja&lt;/a&gt;. Probably helpful in my own sketching! Subscribed to her channel as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sony announced that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ign.com/articles/playstation-store-shut-down-ps3-vita-psp&#34;&gt;they will be shutting down the PS3, Vita and PSP stores&lt;/a&gt;. End of an era really. A lot of people are complaining about content that will be forever lost, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure that there are people working to archive this stuff and make it available through other means. &lt;em&gt;Wink wink&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-stuff&#34;&gt;My stuff:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook/&#34;&gt;Still sketching&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a person with comorbidities (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/05/hypertension/&#34;&gt;hypertension&lt;/a&gt;), I&amp;rsquo;m in vaccine priority group A3, right after senior citizens (A2s). And since the stock of AstraZeneca is limited, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/QCGov/status/1377997094431129606&#34;&gt;QC is now allowing A3s to go ahead of A2s&lt;/a&gt;, so I was able to book a vaccine appointment on the 27th. Its a ways off, but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that means they&amp;rsquo;ve learned to streamline their on-site processes by then, so hopefully things go smoothly. It&amp;rsquo;s weird to have booked a schedule even before the more at-risk parents though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a bid to minimize having to go outside, we decided to try ordering groceries online via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.metromart.com/&#34;&gt;Metromart&lt;/a&gt;. The first-time experience wasn&amp;rsquo;t great; we had to buy from a different grocery (since our usual one wasn&amp;rsquo;t available), not all the regular items we needed were there, and some items were way more expensive. And worst of all, I ordered Tostitos cheese dip and they bought spinach dip instead!! The weird thing is, there were some other items that were out of stock that they called me about (even though I explicitly set that if there were missing items, just don&amp;rsquo;t buy them??), yet for the dip, they just went ahead and bought a different flavor. I ended up having a long convo with their customer support about how disappointed I was, and somehow despite saying there&amp;rsquo;s nothing they could do, they later ended up offering me P100 store credit as compensation. I guess it will be useful if ever we decide to try this again. Anyway, we ended up doing a supplementary grocery run yesterday to cover the items the online delivery didn&amp;rsquo;t get (and the cheese dip!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only one movie watched this week, continuing the James Bond run: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1a1ab3ad610478ba3b672b0a89c26333/&#34;&gt;On Her Majesty&amp;rsquo;s Secret Service (1969)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supergirl&lt;/strong&gt; has started up again, carrying over baggage from the cut-short previous season, same as Flash. The writing was marginally better though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Falcon and Winter Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; was pretty good, though I still found Wandavision more exciting overall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I tried grinding to Master Rank in Eternal on the last day of the month, but I ran out of time with half a level to go. Sigh. Arena I didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother and ended the month in platinum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played a couple of Civ6 games, mostly achievement hunting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played a bit more &lt;strong&gt;Iris and the Giant&lt;/strong&gt;, now down to 1 achievement remaining, but it requires going through all the secret levels, I think?? That might take a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s multiplayer games with friends: Blood Rage, Sentinels of the Multiverse, Root, and Orcs Must Die 2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;: Finished reading Discworld&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Men at Arms!&lt;/strong&gt;, maybe I can write book review(s) this week. Need to find a new book to read, probably a nonfiction one this time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This was the second Holy Week in a row where we were just stuck at home all day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-coming-week&#34;&gt;This coming week:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new Falcon and Winter Soldier, Invincible, One Piece, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>philippines</category>
                        
            <category>covid19</category>
                        
            <category>weeknotes</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1378608294454046720/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 07:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1378608294454046720/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Fried egg. #sketchdaily 93/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1378608294454046720/1_1378608294454046720_EyHM7uDUcAAS8Io_hu1f31c27815912b00ae3c57851c27f1f9_55915_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1a1ab3ad610478ba3b672b0a89c26333/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 06:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1a1ab3ad610478ba3b672b0a89c26333/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 6: On Her Majesty&amp;rsquo;s Secret Service (1969). Only Lazenby appearance. He was fine, I suppose. Tracy probably best Bond girl so far. I liked the ski scenes more than Thunderball&amp;rsquo;s underwater scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--sep--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loose continuity. Was confused by Blofeld not recognizing Bond after they already met in the previous movie. Apparently, the novel order was reversed. Also, did Bond just leave him stuck in a tree assuming he was dead after hunting him relentlessly?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1378238889853284355/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 06:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1378238889853284355/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Darkseid is. #sketchdaily 92/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1378238889853284355/1_1378238889853284355_EyB89auU8AE7I5X_hu56dfda20a70ceaf4e6b439ab7a87993b_182663_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>A categorized list of all Java and JVM features since JDK 8 to 16
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/a-categorized-list-of-all-java-and-jvm-features-since-jdk-8-to-16/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 03:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/a-categorized-list-of-all-java-and-jvm-features-since-jdk-8-to-16/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://advancedweb.hu/a-categorized-list-of-all-java-and-jvm-features-since-jdk-8-to-16/&#34;&gt;A categorized list of all Java and JVM features since JDK 8 to 16&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>In Defense of Doing Nothing
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/in-defense-of-doing-nothing/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/in-defense-of-doing-nothing/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://newrepublic.com/article/161106/defense-nothing&#34;&gt;In Defense of Doing Nothing&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Benford&#39;s law
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/benfords-law/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/benfords-law/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benford%27s_law&#34;&gt;Benford&amp;#39;s law&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1377639106516189187/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 15:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1377639106516189187/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I guess this is supposed to be a joke but TBH it hits a bit too close to home. #DutertePalpak&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/comics/comments/mhrvkl/just_a_little_joke/&#34;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/comics/comments/mhrvkl/just_a_little_joke/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1377639106516189187/1_1377639106516189187_Ex5bTtHUUAEVLC5_hub5462d801fd3a7c1d012c816c789a1fc_280489_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>DutertePalpak</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1377633231311372288/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 14:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1377633231311372288/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Mac and cheese #sketchdaily 91/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1377633231311372288/1_1377633231311372288_Ex5WHexVcBEO_2n_hu44cc6c7064c5af5abb3f74b4d0d8d651_146583_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to zaaaldehyde&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/zaaaldehyde/statuses/1377553777566228485/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1377556584780361732/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 09:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1377556584780361732/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to zaaaldehyde&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/zaaaldehyde/statuses/1377553777566228485/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zaaaldehyde/&#34;&gt;@zaaaldehyde&lt;/a&gt; Food deliveries are allowed past the curfew time&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1377336527374622722/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 19:06:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1377336527374622722/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Lion #sketchdaily 90/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1377336527374622722/1_1377336527374622722_Ex1IQUsVgAQzQXP_hudc29fab7bb697702f9f6372ce6203f28_363788_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The man with no plot: how I watched Lee Child write a Jack Reacher novel
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/the-man-with-no-plot-how-i-watched-lee-child-write-a-jack-reacher-novel/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 17:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/the-man-with-no-plot-how-i-watched-lee-child-write-a-jack-reacher-novel/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://theconversation.com/the-man-with-no-plot-how-i-watched-lee-child-write-a-jack-reacher-novel-51220&#34;&gt;The man with no plot: how I watched Lee Child write a Jack Reacher novel&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Something to look forward to
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/something-to-look-forward-to/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 04:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/something-to-look-forward-to/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://austinkleon.com/2018/01/19/something-to-look-forward-to/&#34;&gt;Something to look forward to&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1377093864771612674/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 03:02:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1377093864771612674/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Boat #sketchdaily 89/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1377093864771612674/1_1377093864771612674_ExxrkBAUcAEmBcu_hub7fdbf74f5cf7cbc50bb715259b1ba89_178160_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to mlq3&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/mlq3/statuses/1376776949792567301/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376777097453072386/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 06:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376777097453072386/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to mlq3&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/mlq3/statuses/1376776949792567301/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mlq3/&#34;&gt;@mlq3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rocketkeis/&#34;&gt;@rocketkeis&lt;/a&gt; Noted. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to rocketkeis&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/rocketkeis/statuses/1376768860091609095/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376775457153019905/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 05:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376775457153019905/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to rocketkeis&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/rocketkeis/statuses/1376768860091609095/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rocketkeis/&#34;&gt;@rocketkeis&lt;/a&gt; what is it supposed to mean?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376590449364754432/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 17:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376590449364754432/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Loxodon Hierarch #sketchdaily #mtg 88/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376590449364754432/1_1376590449364754432_ExqhthkVcAEKRJg_hufdd5bbd6d2e492a85e2fbb6c38032b73_218737_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376585657523441664/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 17:22:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376585657523441664/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Zangief #sketchdaily 87/365&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The prompt was actually for &amp;ldquo;worst movie you&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen&amp;rdquo;, but my excuse is that the campy live action Street Fighter movie was one of my favorite &amp;ldquo;worst movies&amp;rdquo; ever, and Zangief was one of the funniest characters there.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376585657523441664/1_1376585657523441664_ExqdWj9UUAM2_Cl_hu718715df39d128b810b58cd8afe7885c_233210_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to anthony_siy&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/anthony_siy/statuses/1376488004194197507/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376494924409933826/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 11:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376494924409933826/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to anthony_siy&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/anthony_siy/statuses/1376488004194197507/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/anthony_siy/&#34;&gt;@anthony_siy&lt;/a&gt; what does service contracting mean here sir?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to Wizards_MagicEU&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/Wizards_MagicEU/statuses/1376178644217909251/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376179123924598786/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 14:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376179123924598786/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to Wizards_MagicEU&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/Wizards_MagicEU/statuses/1376178644217909251/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Wizards_MagicEU/&#34;&gt;@Wizards_MagicEU&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mtgjp/&#34;&gt;@mtgjp&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;All around the world&amp;rdquo;? What about in southeast asia?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376175428121939970/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 14:12:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376175428121939970/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;This one is my favorite so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/ponettplus/status/1375675902185594880&#39;&gt;ponettplus&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    don&amp;rsquo;t worry everyone, help has arrived
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376175428121939970/1_1376175428121939970_Exdh49KWUAAqNJw_huf559a5835d9d4cf5699c7b6d3c70bd5b_414937_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376175428121939970/2_1376175428121939970_Exdh585XEAMvpP8_hu55dd5829bba8cb208bb30d4c53c78f07_76699_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376097405498617858/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 09:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376097405498617858/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Jeez, sorry for trying to use a more secure password&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1376097405498617858/1_1376097405498617858_ExjhPtrVgAEwASr_hu40c08ca638446be87c1ea7dab8bc04cd_1857_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Write Simply
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/write-simply/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 04:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/write-simply/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://paulgraham.com/simply.html&#34;&gt;Write Simply&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Douglas Adams&#39; note to self reveals author found writing torture
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/douglas-adams-note-to-self-reveals-author-found-writing-torture/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 04:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/douglas-adams-note-to-self-reveals-author-found-writing-torture/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/mar/22/douglas-adams-note-to-self-reveals-author-found-writing-torture&#34;&gt;Douglas Adams&amp;#39; note to self reveals author found writing torture&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>30 covers that are better than the originals
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/30-covers-that-are-better-than-the-originals/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 04:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/30-covers-that-are-better-than-the-originals/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nme.com/photos/30-covers-that-are-better-than-the-originals-1405281&#34;&gt;30 covers that are better than the originals&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2021-03-28
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/weeknotes-2021-03-28/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 04:14:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/weeknotes-2021-03-28/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the last weekend of March. It feels like the month went by quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world&#34;&gt;The world:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local covid response: The government introduced the concept of an &amp;ldquo;NCR Plus&amp;rdquo; bubble last Monday, restricting travel in and out of the NCR and adjacent provinces, in response to the rising cases. Still, the daily counts kept rising, hitting record highs of almost 10k cases daily. Even before the dust has settled on the bubble response, they decided to announce last night a reversion to the stricter ECQ. Shades of last year, during the run up to the first lockdown announcement: rumors circulated via chat groups about the impending lockdown before the government finally made their announcement. As can be expected, memes quickly circulated about how we came back to ECQ more than a year after the first lockdown. The lockdown is imposed only for one week, during the Holy Week period, presumably to take advantage of the two holidays in the week to minimize economic impact. The fact that they imposed two different levels of responses one after another &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375737016407625729/&#34;&gt;reeks of poor planning and analysis&lt;/a&gt;, as if they were just making all this up as they go along, which might not be far from the truth. What happens if the case counts continue to rise until next Sunday?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a bit of economically-devastating-yet-unintentionally-hilarious world news: a very large container ship, the MV EVER GIVEN, ran aground in the Suez Canal, blocking passage, and has been stuck there since Tuesday-ish, clogging up global shipping trade through the canal. Apparently losses are at the order of $400M per hour or something? IDK, I&amp;rsquo;m not an economist. All I&amp;rsquo;m sure of is the internet almost immediately produced a &lt;a href=&#34;https://nypost.com/2021/03/25/the-best-suez-canal-memes-the-stuck-ship-ever-given-inspired/&#34;&gt;bunch of memes&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;a href=&#34;https://jezebel.com/yes-people-are-writing-horny-fanfic-about-the-suez-can-1846562940&#34;&gt;horny fanfic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-of-interest&#34;&gt;Links of interest:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read this interesting post about &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.ayjay.org/blogging-and-the-blogosphere/&#34;&gt;blogging and the blogosphere&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something that interested me mostly for trivia purposes: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nme.com/photos/30-covers-that-are-better-than-the-originals-1405281&#34;&gt;30 covers that are better than the originals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/mar/22/douglas-adams-note-to-self-reveals-author-found-writing-torture&#34;&gt;Douglas Adams&amp;rsquo; note to self reveals author found writing torture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul Graham reminds us to &lt;a href=&#34;http://paulgraham.com/simply.html&#34;&gt;write simply&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-stuff&#34;&gt;My stuff:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook/&#34;&gt;Sketching, sketching&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuing my run on the Bond movies with &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/fb71576d1974213ea471b5cda8a20948/&#34;&gt;You Only Live Twice (1967)&lt;/a&gt;. Secret volcano lair!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also managed to convince myself to sit down and watch &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/snyder-cut/&#34;&gt;Zack Snyder&amp;rsquo;s Justice League&lt;/a&gt;. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t manage to sit down for four hours straight, so it was two sittings over two days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second episode of The Falcon and the Winter Soldier last Friday. Still a bit meh, mostly because there hasn&amp;rsquo;t been anything I haven&amp;rsquo;t expected yet. But that&amp;rsquo;s bound to change as I think all the content from the trailers have been shown by now. Some good acting by Sebastian Sean though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished watching &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek The Animated Series&lt;/strong&gt;, Star Trek TV series completion!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First 3 episodes &lt;strong&gt;Invincible&lt;/strong&gt; have dropped on Prime Video. Most of the first episode is good, clean superhero fun, but by the end of the episode you are dissuaded of that notion. Pretty good pacing, seems mostly accurate to the source material, looking forward to the rest of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also been rewatching The Office as my background watching, mostly because I listened to a podcast of Office trivia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second Fire Emblem Three Houses run: Still ongoing, somehow. It feels like I&amp;rsquo;m doing these in real time, only advancing one week of the game per week of real life. At that rate, I should be done in like six months lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After five years of playing Street Fighter V, I managed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374367400276025345/&#34;&gt;dig myself out of the pits of the bronze ranks and hit silver&lt;/a&gt;! Surprisingly, on the next two days after this, I had trouble finding ranked matches again. I took that as a sign to take a break before attempting to climb up to gold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final Civ6 NFP drop came out as expected. Not super hyped, but I have started a Portugal game already, they seem really strong especially on island maps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strixhaven official previews kicked off, and I&amp;rsquo;m really hyped for the set, mostly because I really &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375147827110629379/&#34;&gt;like the Mystical Archive cards&lt;/a&gt;. Collecting all of them on Arena is gonna be a challenge though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supposedly Magic Arena is now available &amp;ldquo;everywhere&amp;rdquo; on mobile, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/magicTCG/comments/mdf9dp/androidios_versions_not_available_in_southeast/&#34;&gt;not in Southeast Asia though&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books:&lt;/strong&gt; I mentioned last week that I started reading the Discworld book &amp;ldquo;Guards! Guards!&amp;rdquo;, but for some reason everything seemed so familiar, and soon I realized it was because I had &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/805050532834353152/&#34;&gt;already read it back in 2016&lt;/a&gt;. Doh! I was enjoying it anyway, so I finished the re-read and will probably publish a review, since I didn&amp;rsquo;t have one in 2016. But I&amp;rsquo;ll finish the next City Watch book first: Men at Arms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AboutQuiz this week a bit better than last week, but I still miss the other trivia groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374212757189369861/&#34;&gt;I hit the 800-day streak on Duolingo&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-coming-week&#34;&gt;This coming week:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New FatWS episode, etc etc. I presume new Invincible episode as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe the world will miraculously be better next week? IDK, one can always hope right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Holy Week! Normally a big deal for the RC faithful in this country, but this time everyone has to stay at home for the second year in a row.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ECQ! Well, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect me much, though there are now some errands that we have to push back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/weeknotes-2021-03-28/thanos_ecq_hubf4d701baf9e23055cf1311d5ccc9528_421385_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>philippines</category>
                        
            <category>covid19</category>
                        
            <category>weeknotes</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375821511601258499/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 14:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375821511601258499/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Snow leopard #sketchdaily 86/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375821511601258499/1_1375821511601258499_ExfmWsxVcAYCkN4_hu18b0896cadb43d000ea64f657e3528b5_314582_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to paulcatiang&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/paulcatiang/statuses/1375729594020466688/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375787410055827462/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 12:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375787410055827462/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to paulcatiang&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/paulcatiang/statuses/1375729594020466688/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/paulcatiang/&#34;&gt;@paulcatiang&lt;/a&gt; Alt + 0151 — use the numpad&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to SaffronOlive&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/SaffronOlive/statuses/1375776619143565319/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375783440952397832/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 12:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375783440952397832/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to SaffronOlive&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/SaffronOlive/statuses/1375776619143565319/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SaffronOlive/&#34;&gt;@SaffronOlive&lt;/a&gt; Wait, are bolt counterspell and swords allowed in historic brawl then?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375737016407625729/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 09:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375737016407625729/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Planning for a stricter lockdown less than a week after starting this ridiculous bubble, without even waiting to see the effects, reeks of making shit up as they go along, just reacting to the numbers without any real analysis or planning.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375636032448696323/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 02:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375636032448696323/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;It always feels weird for me when the PH president exercises a line item veto, since presumably Congress has balanced the bill as a whole. This is an unusual power, Wikipedia only lists 3-4 countries that allow line item vetoes &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Line-item_veto&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Line-item_veto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/manilabulletin/status/1375431491417612289&#39;&gt;manilabulletin&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    READ: President Duterte vetoed nine items in CREATE law, including hike in VAT threshold on real property sale, redundant incentives for domestic enterprises; automatic approval of incentive application (📷: Roque) | &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GenKabiling/&#34;&gt;@GenKabiling&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the PH isn&amp;rsquo;t one of those listed in the Wikipedia article! I think I&amp;rsquo;ll attempt to edit Wikipedia today.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375636032448696323/1_1375636032448696323_ExaDom8U8AUfmqt_hu320acbd6ec46337cc3304f9d6c6b19a2_167309_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375636032448696323/2_1375636032448696323_ExaDonNUYAYO1g4_hu9f2c1ef0c801ec27b196b3e118d0e76e_164192_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375636032448696323/3_1375636032448696323_ExaDonlVoAQqedu_hu8c7fd6c6b33ec339c872b07d9a5be19b_128697_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375636032448696323/4_1375636032448696323_ExaDooAVIAExvUQ_hu755a427ac3a895f0ea4b00675e943dbf_119477_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375538318578966528/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 20:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375538318578966528/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Winter Soldier #sketchdaily 85/365 #procreate #Marvel #comicbooks&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375538318578966528/1_1375538318578966528_ExbkzONUUAAI_qQ_hu83ea29aca341da3c6d37364b92ef02bd_142859_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
                        
            <category>procreate</category>
                        
            <category>Marvel</category>
                        
            <category>comicbooks</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by lynnfyr on &#39;Android/iOS versions not available in Southeast Asia?&#39; on /r/magicTCG at https://reddit.com/r/magicTCG/comments/mdf9dp/androidios_versions_not_available_in_southeast/gs982db/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/gs98o1v/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 04:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/gs98o1v/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by lynnfyr on &amp;#39;Android/iOS versions not available in Southeast Asia?&amp;#39; on /r/magicTCG at https://reddit.com/r/magicTCG/comments/mdf9dp/androidios_versions_not_available_in_southeast/gs982db/:

            &lt;p&gt;So what does that mean? Are we never getting iOS/Android versions in SEA? Will they (Tencent) release it later? Or there&amp;rsquo;s no word at all?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>magicTCG</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/mdf9dp/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 03:02:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/mdf9dp/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;h4 id=&#34;posted-on-rmagictcg-androidios-versions-not-available-in-southeast-asiahttpsredditcomrmagictcgcommentsmdf9dpandroidios_versions_not_available_in_southeast&#34;&gt;Posted on r/magicTCG: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/magicTCG/comments/mdf9dp/androidios_versions_not_available_in_southeast/&#34;&gt;Android/iOS versions not available in Southeast Asia?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has anyone in SEA been able to get the mobile versions? I&amp;rsquo;m from the Philippines, me and my friend in Singapore both can&amp;rsquo;t find the app on the stores. Even when using a direct link, the stores will just say Arena isn&amp;rsquo;t available in the country/region. Any others from SEA countries have any luck?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have they released any official word on this? Or is there any WOTC staff here who can shed some light on why it&amp;rsquo;s not available in SEA?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So annoyed that the MTG twitter accounts have the audacity to claim Arena is now available &amp;ldquo;everywhere&amp;rdquo; on mobile when it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>magicTCG</category>
                        
            <category>reddit_submission</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375147827110629379/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 18:09:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375147827110629379/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Both the normal and alt art Strixhaven mystical archive treatments are probably my favorite “expedition” -style treatments of all time. Glad these are coming to #magicarena #mtg&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375147827110629379/1_1375147827110629379_ExWBp7vVgAUkE5V_hu1e481a2e8c549a25298d8ddee1d562ef_39940_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375147827110629379/2_1375147827110629379_ExWBp7vVcAUW9VH_huddb88528358cb7f186d43bb50023f68d_114246_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375147827110629379/3_1375147827110629379_ExWBp7vU4AE9-5I_hubf892cc2d8535e72c3f42dd9137465fa_174099_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375147827110629379/4_1375147827110629379_ExWBp7vVgAcksr-_hu415660d0e0fd0cb2f21f1f27779bc88a_200468_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to mtgcolorpie&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/mtgcolorpie/statuses/1375144243463790595/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375144979174019072/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 17:58:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375144979174019072/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to mtgcolorpie&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/mtgcolorpie/statuses/1375144243463790595/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mtgcolorpie/&#34;&gt;@mtgcolorpie&lt;/a&gt; I would guess Negate more likely than Mana Leak&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>blogging and the blogosphere
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/blogging-and-the-blogosphere/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 15:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/blogging-and-the-blogosphere/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.ayjay.org/blogging-and-the-blogosphere/&#34;&gt;blogging and the blogosphere&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375110861237325824/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 15:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375110861237325824/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MTG_Arena/&#34;&gt;@MTG_Arena&lt;/a&gt; why isn&amp;rsquo;t your iOS app available in my region? #mtgarena&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>mtgarena</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375104128427302913/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 15:15:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375104128427302913/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Just a panda #sketchdaily 84/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375104128427302913/1_1375104128427302913_ExVZ6J3VoAACfyz_hu2e548afd50c8b59e643c950a5a39dfb8_110033_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375004320916144133/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 08:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375004320916144133/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Moonlit masquerade #sketchdaily 83/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1375004320916144133/1_1375004320916144133_ExT_IoMVoAIa4vx_hu9eac7612eccbcf0647445dacd257b29b_289743_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/fb71576d1974213ea471b5cda8a20948/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 08:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/fb71576d1974213ea471b5cda8a20948/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 5: You Only Live Twice (1967). Such Japan. Much wow. Cringe at trying to pass Bond off as Japanese. Introduction of secret volcano lair trope. Ninjas with guns! First screen appearance of the head of SPECTRE, inspiration for Dr Evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--sep--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That endgame scene of ninjas invading the secret volcano lair reminded me of the Simpsons episode &lt;em&gt;You Only Move Twice&lt;/em&gt;. Bond&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;wife&amp;rdquo; never named despite being only Bond girl to survive the movie.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374385938273476623/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 15:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374385938273476623/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Why it&amp;rsquo;s hard to trust either the Chinese government or Sinovac, exhibit 22,316&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/rthk_enews/status/1374314806484688899&#39;&gt;rthk_enews&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    The #HongKong government stops a doctor from giving out #COVID19 jabs after he allegedly told people that the BioNTech vaccine has a much better reputation than the one made by China&amp;rsquo;s Sinovac. &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.rthk.hk/rthk/en/component/k2/1582148-20210323.htm&#34;&gt;https://news.rthk.hk/rthk/en/component/k2/1582148-20210323.htm&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>hongkong</category>
                        
            <category>covid19</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374380033117016075/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 15:18:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374380033117016075/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Petra (from Fire Emblem Three Houses) #sketchdaily 82/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374380033117016075/1_1374380033117016075_ExLHWe5VkAEc0Cf_hu2fba7fd367aa75a74bca9bb8f4c3dfbc_140183_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374367400276025345/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 14:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374367400276025345/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After five years of languishing in the bronze ranks of Street Fighter V, I somehow managed to break through to silver!! #gaming&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374367400276025345/1_1374367400276025345_ExK7tkOVkAEUEVX_huc60d383cf676f0b9a1cd01dc4697676c_124448_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374367400276025345/2_1374367400276025345_ExK71sXVkAcQKpo_hu37c3947ab3c62218993f81c24b28853f_12615_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>gaming</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374267414192353281/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 07:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374267414192353281/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Give people aid so they can stay at home, you cowards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/philippinestar/status/1373474758080172032&#39;&gt;PhilippineStar&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    READ: Amid rising COVID-19 cases, NEDA acting secretary &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/_karlchua/&#34;&gt;@_karlchua&lt;/a&gt; says the issue now is the total health of the people, including hunger and other sickness apart from COVID-19. Localized lockdowns and managing risks should be the focus. | &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/maureensimeon/&#34;&gt;@maureensimeon&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374267414192353281/1_1374267414192353281_Ew-P7AvUcAM3cHY_hufe5778a879134d2329b842d9148eb07c_157659_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374264516414894085/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 07:39:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374264516414894085/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Whenever I deliver any software to clients I should go “Please enjoy the gifts from me, please make a commitment that you will take care of this code, you will take car of this database, you will take care of these bugs..”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/paulcatiang/status/1374239680951033859&#39;&gt;paulcatiang&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Managed to get the receipt for the crass display by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DOTrPH/&#34;&gt;@DOTrPH&lt;/a&gt;. Remember, the people&amp;rsquo;s taxes paid for those and continue to put food on your tables, you ungrateful public servants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, we&amp;rsquo;ve lost so many hours in traffic thanks to your incompetence. Umayos nga kayo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1374264516414894085/1_1374264516414894085_ExJHtNWUcAE9ubH_hu7a40907e264292b631407bf0c73c000d_144544_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>