<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Roy Tang::</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/</link>
      <description>Recent content on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
        
    
        <item>
            <title>52 things I learned in 2020
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/52-things-i-learned-in-2020/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 08:40:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/52-things-i-learned-in-2020/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/fluxx-studio-notes/52-things-i-learned-in-2020-6a380692dbb8&#34;&gt;52 things I learned in 2020&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-12-27 Season Finale
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-27/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-27/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I started doing these weeknotes at &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/weeknotes-01-12/&#34;&gt;the top of 2020&lt;/a&gt;, so this one signals one complete year of doing my weekly reviews/notes in public. I thought it appropriate for a review!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did it turn out to be a good practice? I think for me yes! Not necessarily for anyone following the blog (all 3 of you), since a lot of the weeknotes stuff might seem boring or irrelevant to you. But for me, forcing me to publicly write some thoughts about the past week has been good for my own self-awareness and keeping me writing regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned this in the first weeknotes linked above, but I used to do private weekly reviews before this. I haven&amp;rsquo;t found much need to supplement the public weeknotes with private ones over the year, but that&amp;rsquo;s basically because (a) my other tracking systems have evolved this year to better capture more data, so less review was actually needed; and (b) this silly pandemic keeping me at home most of the year means there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much to report most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I&amp;rsquo;ll be carrying the weeknotes practice into 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the past week, it was of course Christmas week, which went about as expected. Noche buena night was just me and the folks at home, although the brothers and their families did pass by for a short while on the morning of that day for some gift exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world was relatively quiet. Well, there&amp;rsquo;s finally a post-Brexit trade deal, and Trump seems to be screwing over everybody as expected, and there&amp;rsquo;s a new Covid19 variant, and our government is still being dumb. So, same old same old?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good chunk of my week went towards playing &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1340074409961222146/&#34;&gt;Fire Emblem Three Houses&lt;/a&gt;. As is typical of JRPGs, the startup is a bit slow, but once you get into the whole Persona-like loop of tasks and battles, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty addictive. Pretty sure this will take a while to finish though!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steam Christmas Sale is still ongoing. Thinking of actually getting Hades, because of all the GOTY accolades it&amp;rsquo;s getting. On the other hand, Fire Emblem&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regular weekly gaming with friends: Root, Sentinels of the Multiverse. I also played a couple more Civ6 games for achievement hunting purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new Jeopardy eps on Netflix ran out quickly. Haven&amp;rsquo;t really started on anything seriously yet, though I did watch first episodes of The Expanse S5 and Kimetsu no Yaiba, but I&amp;rsquo;m not feeling like binging either series yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of cramming a few more movies into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;2020 movies list&lt;/a&gt; this week, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if I get around to it or just play more Fire Emblem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To whoever is reading this: despite everything about this year, I hope you somehow managed to have a good holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This coming week: end of year stuff!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>weeknotes</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to Westraid&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/Westraid/statuses/1342836060884140034/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1342836877942931456/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 14:17:15 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1342836877942931456/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to Westraid&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/Westraid/statuses/1342836060884140034/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Westraid/&#34;&gt;@Westraid&lt;/a&gt; Merry Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Christmas Traditions
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/xmas-traditions/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/xmas-traditions/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This was the year when a lot of Christmas traditions were broken, due to the pandemic. There are &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/xmas-ph/&#34;&gt;cultural/country-specific Christmas traditions&lt;/a&gt; of course, but usually each person or family also has their own personal traditions that they do every Christmas. Here are some of mine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christmas Eve dinner, or as it&amp;rsquo;s popularly known here in the Philippines, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/nochebuena&#34;&gt;noche buena&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growing up, our immediate family/household unit usually celebrates Christmas Eve with a late noche buena, an extra meal that happened after dinner and starting at around midnight. Then we&amp;rsquo;d open presents, usually with one of the uncles taking the role of &amp;ldquo;Santa Claus&amp;rdquo; and giving out gifts. And as kids, it was one night of the year where we were allowed to stay up late and play with the presents for a while. As we grew older, this usually meant playing video games for a few hours in the early morning!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typical noche buena food: some kind of bread, some kind of ham, some quezo de bola, some kind of pasta. Sometimes there&amp;rsquo;s other stuff too like barbecue or soup, but those seem to be the mainstays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We kept this tradition when we moved out of my grandparents&amp;rsquo; house. This tradition only started changing recently, when my brothers all got married and moved out in the past 10 years. They still come to visit with the kids on Christmas eve, but we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have the noche buena very late anymore, because they would need to drive back home, and some of the kids had early bedtimes. So the noche buena kind of got merged into the Christmas dinner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usually we&amp;rsquo;d all be dressed in red and take a family photo in front of the Christmas tree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This year, as you can imagine, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have that dinner together. Instead, my brothers came out on the morning of the 24th and we exchanged presents outdoors. It was the first time for the folks to see their grandkids in person a long while! We still had noche buena early (during dinner time), despite there only being three of us at home to celebrate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My mother&amp;rsquo;s side extended family usually has a reunion on Christmas day itself, the one time of the year we all get together.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re talking a few dozen people (best estimate, the number grew a lot over the years, as some of my cousins were very, um, productive). When we used to live at my grandparents&amp;rsquo; house, it was easy, because everyone else came to us. When that house was sold, one of my other uncles/aunts/cousins usually hosted (our house was way too small), but that usually involved driving out to some far corner of the Metro. Far for us, at least. (Driving across the Metro on Christmas day was tough, and there were some years where some of us had to get a taxi, that always took forever).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the get-together itself, there&amp;rsquo;s usually dinner, then some kind of party games or some cousins might be asked to perform, then presents exchange. We used to do the Santa Claus thing where one person stands in front of the tree and goes through the presents one by one and calls them out and the recipient comes forward and so on. But this didn&amp;rsquo;t really scale as the extended family grew and grew. Later on, the present exchange became more &amp;ldquo;underground&amp;rdquo;, with each household going around giving gifts to the others throughout the night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A tradition started by my grandfather was the &amp;ldquo;pasabog&amp;rdquo; where there would be a surprise throwing of money (usually coins or small bills) over the party area and everyone scrambled to grab some. My uncles carried on this tradition when my grandfather passed away, and in recent years my dad and I have been doing the pasabog ourselves (since at this point all of my uncles have passed away as well).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We do a big family photo in this gathering too, but it&amp;rsquo;s usually much more challenging since there&amp;rsquo;s way more people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obviously this year, the get together could not happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was also thinking the other day about how the people we greet on Christmas Eve/Day has evolved with technology.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I was young, we could only greet those people in our immediate household and sometimes the neighbors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When cellphones became popular, people greeted each other through those. Usually people had limited SMS, so they&amp;rsquo;d only pick and choose who they could greet. And during those days in particular, network congestion was so bad, it would sometimes be hours before your messages got through. I got a cellphone late and was never much into SMS, so this period didn&amp;rsquo;t last long for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the ubiquity of instant messaging these days, people just send greetings online, mostly to group chats and some to specific people (who are probably more &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; for you&amp;rdquo;). At least this is one tradition the pandemic can&amp;rsquo;t take away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, our government manages to get its act together and get this pandemic under control as soon as possible, so we can resume our Christmas traditions next year!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to wrongwaygoback&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/wrongwaygoback/statuses/1342405268890677248/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1342417270094479360/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 10:29:52 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1342417270094479360/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to wrongwaygoback&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/wrongwaygoback/statuses/1342405268890677248/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wrongwaygoback/&#34;&gt;@wrongwaygoback&lt;/a&gt; the token can&amp;rsquo;t be used for quick draft or for arena cube&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;When a new set comes out you can upgrade your common and uncommon wilds!&#39; on /r/MagicArena at https://reddit.com/r/MagicArena/comments/kj7j72/when_a_new_set_comes_out_you_can_upgrade_your/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/ggvzbuq/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 18:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/ggvzbuq/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;When a new set comes out you can upgrade your common and uncommon wilds!&amp;#39; on /r/MagicArena at https://reddit.com/r/MagicArena/comments/kj7j72/when_a_new_set_comes_out_you_can_upgrade_your/:

            &lt;p&gt;For people like me who dislike watching videos: Before you start drafting a set, craft all the common/uncommon cards from the new set, so that each common/uncommon you open in draft adds to the vault percentage.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>MagicArena</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>My favorite essays of life advice
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/my-favorite-essays-of-life-advice/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 11:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/my-favorite-essays-of-life-advice/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.benkuhn.net/weeklyessays/&#34;&gt;My favorite essays of life advice&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1342078964311834627/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 12:05:34 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1342078964311834627/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;We’re doing #nochebuena early this year. Merry Christmas everyone!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1342078964311834627/1_1342078964311834627_EqAFsl1UwAAitKs_hu6530370d1fecb4bbaa0b6a31d1274dce_193890_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>nochebuena</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1341952566423273473/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 03:43:18 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1341952566423273473/</guid>
            <description>
            
            


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1341952566423273473/1_1341952566423273473_Ep-SqCYVEAAXhDz_hu5b3107488983b79b4d0009ec3ca97c10_43501_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1341491804571455490/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 21:12:24 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1341491804571455490/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This has to be one of my most satisfying Words with Friends plays&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1341491804571455490/1_1341491804571455490_Ep3vrn6UwAAf2aR_hu162566edfc6392643d48e5b68b36946d_159891_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>“Turn your audience into a business”
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/turn-your-audience-into-a-business/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 12:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/turn-your-audience-into-a-business/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://rubenerd.com/turn-your-audience-into-a-business/&#34;&gt;“Turn your audience into a business”&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>This used to be our playground
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/this-used-to-be-our-playground/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 12:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/this-used-to-be-our-playground/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://colly.com/articles/this-used-to-be-our-playground&#34;&gt;This used to be our playground&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1341090027996999680/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 18:35:53 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1341090027996999680/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I bet I could make an earthquake detection machine where all it does is check PH twitter for &amp;ldquo;lindol&amp;rdquo; tweets&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from HHFlashbacks https://twitter.com/HHFlashbacks/statuses/1340865921779265536/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1340868417394331648/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 03:55:17 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1340868417394331648/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from HHFlashbacks https://twitter.com/HHFlashbacks/statuses/1340865921779265536/:
            &lt;p&gt;Kung akala mo ay walang kinalaman ang administrasyon na &amp;lsquo;to sa pagpatay ng isang pulis sa mag-inang walang laban, isa kang hangal.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to mlq3&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/mlq3/statuses/1340866545614897153/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1340868156378660864/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 03:54:15 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1340868156378660864/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to mlq3&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/mlq3/statuses/1340866545614897153/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mlq3/&#34;&gt;@mlq3&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pnppio/&#34;&gt;@pnppio&lt;/a&gt; what would this effort have entailed?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>HTML Tags Memory Test
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/html-tags-memory-test/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 16:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/html-tags-memory-test/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://codepen.io/plfstr/full/zYqQeRw&#34;&gt;HTML Tags Memory Test&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-12-20
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-20/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-20/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the penultimate week of the year, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not the only who&amp;rsquo;s had enough of this accursed year and looking forward to moving on to the next one. I know that&amp;rsquo;s silly since the world won&amp;rsquo;t magically become better when the calendar flips over to January the first, but I think it helps our mental health to have this sort of &amp;ldquo;fresh start&amp;rdquo; mentality, even if it&amp;rsquo;s on an arbitrarily chosen date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holiday season continues to be weird, thanks to the pandemic. My brothers and I have been trying to hash out how to have the usual holiday gift exchange among the four households. In theory nobody will be coming inside the house, just parking outside and dropping off and picking up gifts, but they need to coordinate since they also need to exchange gifts with each other. They&amp;rsquo;re trying to see if they can synchronize their visits so that the exchanges can happen, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if that works out. Meanwhile, the usual family and extended family reunions will probably happen on Zoom, like many of my friends&amp;rsquo; recent company Christmas parties. Hopefully they go smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the pandemic and the holiday, cases continue to rise locally. This trend will probably carry on into January as a result of holiday gatherings. In pandemic related government screwups recently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;requiring face shields everywhere in public, even for joggers or bikers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a pilot for face to face classes in January because the education secretary says they are more likely to get infected at home anyway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apparently we could have had vaccines as early as the first quarter of 2021, but the health secretary dropped the ball during negotiations with pfizer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I guess they were working with some sort of backlog due to the holiday sales, but my local gaming store took an entire week to ship me my copy of Fire Emblem Fates. It finally arrived last Friday so yay! I haven&amp;rsquo;t started playing yet, beyond opening the package and checking that the cartridge works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead this week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a bit of achievement hunting in Civilization VI, since a new patch with balance updates dropped last week. I also tried resuming my Wasteland 2 game. It took me a while to get my bearings, but the game just seems so fiddly, I have a hard time getting into it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG: Kaldheim previews started this week! We don&amp;rsquo;t get any more until January though. The metal-themed previews reminded me of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1339627168947601408/&#34;&gt;something from 10 years ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finished The Big Bang Theory rewatch, I totally did not almost tear up at Sheldon&amp;rsquo;s speech in the finale. TBBT gets a lot of flak for being terrible, but I think it holds up reasonably well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caught up with Mandalorian and Discovery. Discovery was so-so, but wow, the Mandalorian. What a fantastic season finale. I watched it around half a day after the episode dropped and I was very happy I wasn&amp;rsquo;t spoiled by the internet. The team behind the show are doing a great job with the Star Wars franchise. After the problematic sequel trilogy (which I still enjoyed), maybe the real future of the franchise is on episodic TV. Looking forward to all the new Star Wars content next year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New background binge watching: There&amp;rsquo;s new episodes of Jeopardy on Netflix! Not a lot, but more trivia is always fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, most of my time was again spent on digging through and sorting old files. Additionally, one of my old external hard drives had also started getting errors, so I ordered and got a new 1tb one, and spent some time trying to move old backup files across from the old drive to the new one. It was annoying because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t play any games that use a controller while this was happening, for fear of disturbing the long file transfers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m kind of looking forward to doing my year in review blog post for this strange and accursed year.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>weeknotes</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Beat&#39;s list of the 50 best comics of 2020 includes titles by seasoned creators and up-and-coming talents.
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/the-beats-list-of-the-50-best-comics-of-2020-includes-titles-by-seasoned-creators-and-up-and-coming/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 17:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/the-beats-list-of-the-50-best-comics-of-2020-includes-titles-by-seasoned-creators-and-up-and-coming/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.comicsbeat.com/the-50-best-comics-of-2020/&#34;&gt;The Beat&amp;#39;s list of the 50 best comics of 2020 includes titles by seasoned creators and up-and-coming talents.&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1340074409961222146/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 23:20:11 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1340074409961222146/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A new thing arrived! #pickups&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1340074409961222146/1_1340074409961222146_EpjmkpXVgAAnQTe_hu5c89b7563a3d69b115791db177b22ee1_219668_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>pickups</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1340072060886765568/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 23:10:51 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1340072060886765568/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Props to all the people I follow who didn&amp;rsquo;t spoil The Mandalorian ending for me lol. That was wild&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1339627168947601408/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 17:43:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1339627168947601408/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;The metal Kaldheim previews reminded me of my favorite Lotus Cobra is Evil comic: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mtgcolorpie.com/2010/09/26/lotus-cobra-is-evil-rock-on/&#34;&gt;https://mtgcolorpie.com/2010/09/26/lotus-cobra-is-evil-rock-on/&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/houseofsixten/&#34;&gt;@houseofsixten&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mtgcolorpie/&#34;&gt;@mtgcolorpie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;“The current estimated mutant population on Earth is around 100,000 [and growing]...” (House of X #5)&#39; on /r/comicbooks at https://reddit.com/r/comicbooks/comments/kebntc/the_current_estimated_mutant_population_on_earth/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/gg2qxa4/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 05:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/gg2qxa4/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;“The current estimated mutant population on Earth is around 100,000 [and growing]...” (House of X #5)&amp;#39; on /r/comicbooks at https://reddit.com/r/comicbooks/comments/kebntc/the_current_estimated_mutant_population_on_earth/:

            &lt;p&gt;Did this population number only happen during Hickman&amp;rsquo;s run? I forget if there was a mass resurgence of mutants post-decimation&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>comicbooks</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Facebook Is a Doomsday Machine
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/facebook-is-a-doomsday-machine/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 16:11:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/facebook-is-a-doomsday-machine/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2020/12/facebook-doomsday-machine/617384/&#34;&gt;Facebook Is a Doomsday Machine&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;Opismeyts: Patawad&#39; on /r/Philippines at https://reddit.com/r/Philippines/comments/kdtisn/opismeyts_patawad/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/gfyytvp/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 06:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/gfyytvp/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;Opismeyts: Patawad&amp;#39; on /r/Philippines at https://reddit.com/r/Philippines/comments/kdtisn/opismeyts_patawad/:

            &lt;p&gt;Both the site (&lt;a href=&#34;https://patawadpatawad.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;https://patawadpatawad.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;) and the qr code are valid, props for that!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>Philippines</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1338981232621703168/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 22:56:17 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1338981232621703168/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://asiatimes.com/2020/12/duterte-fatally-misplays-philippines-vaccine-diplomacy/&#34;&gt;https://asiatimes.com/2020/12/duterte-fatally-misplays-philippines-vaccine-diplomacy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i would be infuriated but at this point I&amp;rsquo;m just tired&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>How Not to Mentor Software Developers
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/how-not-to-mentor-software-developers/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/how-not-to-mentor-software-developers/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve talked a bit about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/mentoring-in-software-development/&#34;&gt;mentoring in software development&lt;/a&gt; before, and how early on I used to get feedback about me being &amp;ldquo;intimidating&amp;rdquo;. I never got any concrete feedback regarding that, so I don&amp;rsquo;t know what problems I had specifically. Though I was recently reminded of one particular incident that was a bit cringey for me personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a bit more than 10 years ago I think. I was usually assigned to mentor new hires, which means fresh graduates who usually needed guidance with a Java (which was our primary programming language at that time) and with our in-house web framework, which could be a bit challenging to work with. That means a lot of my days are spent answering questions or guiding newbies through more complicated tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incident I remember was with one particular newbie. After they completed a particular task, they asked me to check their work and everything was fine. I don&amp;rsquo;t have the actual wording of what I said but recall making an offhand in-jest remark congratulating them on getting an entire thing done with zero questions and no actual issues. I remember thinking almost immediately afterwards that it was a terrible thing to say since it implies that asking questions might be frowned upon. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of like the difference between just saying &amp;ldquo;Good job&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Good job, you didn&amp;rsquo;t screw this one up!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might have been overthinking it a bit back then as I don&amp;rsquo;t remember any actual negative reaction to that particular remark. That&amp;rsquo;s not really a good metric though, especially when you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with newbies on their first job. There&amp;rsquo;s power dynamics to consider, so they may not think it appropriate to complain even if something makes them feel bad or uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a mentor, it&amp;rsquo;s important to actually encourage the mentees to ask questions when things are unclear or to raise conceerns when there are problems. It&amp;rsquo;s an essential communication skill that all developers (maybe arguably all people) should have. And it&amp;rsquo;s not enough to say &amp;ldquo;Hey, you can ask me questions any time&amp;rdquo;, but you also have to reflect that openness in your actions, your feedback, and your comments.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>software development</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from theskinsensei https://twitter.com/theskinsensei/statuses/1338326582700621825/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1338707102395584512/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 04:46:59 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1338707102395584512/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from theskinsensei https://twitter.com/theskinsensei/statuses/1338326582700621825/:
            &lt;p&gt;Cancel niyo na muna:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❌Pagpunta sa gym, coffee shop, indoor resto, mall, masisikip na lugar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;❌Pakikipagkita sa jowa, barkada, kamag-anak&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Celebrate at home kung ayaw niyong may magkasakit o malagas sa pamilya niyo. Kahit may pera kayo kung puno ang ospital, di kayo magagamot.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to rovietoosin&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/rovietoosin/statuses/1338391308210040835/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1338398359619469314/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 08:20:09 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1338398359619469314/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to rovietoosin&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/rovietoosin/statuses/1338391308210040835/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rovietoosin/&#34;&gt;@rovietoosin&lt;/a&gt; naku madaming pera jan ano lol&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to rovietoosin&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/rovietoosin/statuses/1338389067218620416/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1338390255959883777/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 07:47:57 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1338390255959883777/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to rovietoosin&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/rovietoosin/statuses/1338389067218620416/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rovietoosin/&#34;&gt;@rovietoosin&lt;/a&gt; San ka na lumipat?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1338064928628871168/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 10:15:13 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1338064928628871168/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;700! #Duolingo&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1338064928628871168/1_1338064928628871168_EpHC9gkU0AI0f18_hua1919070a76d8a285ef91f6d118fb840_30501_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>Duolingo</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-12-13
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-13/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-13/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Time passes yet again. I think I have to get used to not having much personal stuff to report in the weeknotes on certain weeks (aside from the watching/gaming parts), especially given the pandemic where I&amp;rsquo;m at home 90% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the pandemic, the UK started vaccinations last week, and the US FDA approved the Pfizer vaccine as well, so hopefully this is where things start to turn around. Sadly, it may be a while before vaccinations get widespread, especially here in the Philippines. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping things clear up by mid next year for us here, but I&amp;rsquo;m not optimistic about it. It would be really sad if the pandemic restrictions reach next year&amp;rsquo;s holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that people here seem to realize there&amp;rsquo;s still a pandemic going on, if pictures coming out of Divisoria are any indication. I get that not everyone has access to online shopping, but are there no other options for holiday gift shopping than walking through such dense crowds? This may be one instance where our generous gift-giving culture is bad for us, since people are still out trying to buy gifts when the pandemic is a perfectly good excuse for scaling back on the shopping. Capitalism ho!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The saddest part of this pandemic for me has that my brothers and their families can&amp;rsquo;t come over to visit, which means my parents don&amp;rsquo;t get to see their grandkids (and I don&amp;rsquo;t get to see the pamangkins). Sometimes we push back a bit on that envelope, but it&amp;rsquo;ll be a while before we all really get to see each other and enjoy company in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I managed to finish Batman Arkham Knight! The main story at least. Achievement completion seems unlikely, given the multiplayer achievements, and even some of the single-player ones seem a bit too challenging. I was able to enjoy the game despite the graphical issues I encountered early on. Lowering the settings helped a lot I think, though things still weren&amp;rsquo;t 100% good. I really take to these style of games where there&amp;rsquo;s an open world and you have a lot of things to collect and such.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ordered Fire Emblem Fates for the Switch yesterday! I was also considering Paper Mario Origami King, but that had some mixed reviews, so holding off for now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt; Currently doing a binge re-watch of The Big Bang Theory as my background watching, I&amp;rsquo;m up to season 7 at the moment. I think the show holds up better than some of its contemporaries such as How I Met Your Mother. I know the geek portrayals can be a bit exaggerated or patronizing, so a lot of geeks don&amp;rsquo;t like it, but for me it&amp;rsquo;s fine. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of doing a bad comic book movie marathon sometime this month, covering the ones I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother watching, stuff like Ben Affleck Daredevil, Michael B Jordan Fantastic Four, and the recently released New Mutants. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if I get around to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just under two weeks until Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>weeknotes</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1337969729902821376/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 03:56:56 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1337969729902821376/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;RTing so I know to clean up my mac later&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/lorenb/status/1337832978253230081&#39;&gt;lorenb&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So it turns out that Google Chrome was making everything on my computer slow &lt;em&gt;even when it wasn’t running&lt;/em&gt;, because it installs something called Keystone which is basically malware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a website because this shouldn’t happen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://chromeisbad.com&#34;&gt;https://chromeisbad.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from NonTrotski https://twitter.com/NonTrotski/statuses/1337428335824080899/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1337453916162703360/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 17:47:16 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1337453916162703360/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from NonTrotski https://twitter.com/NonTrotski/statuses/1337428335824080899/:
            &lt;p&gt;Thread! Author &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sparrowtrooper/&#34;&gt;@sparrowtrooper&lt;/a&gt; and I are giving away 3 signed copies &amp;amp; 5 eBook copies of her book! &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/David__Cage/&#34;&gt;@David__Cage&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ChrisTheHoff/&#34;&gt;@ChrisTheHoff&lt;/a&gt; and I were quoted on the back! It&amp;rsquo;s wild. RT this for a chance to win! Winners will be selected after this tweet gets 100 retweets &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/How-Games-Get-Made-Stories/dp/1636765483/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=&amp;amp;sr=&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/How-Games-Get-Made-Stories/dp/1636765483/ref=tmm_pap_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=&amp;amp;sr=&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1337327864992055304/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 09:26:24 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1337327864992055304/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Every new &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MTG_Arena/&#34;&gt;@MTG_Arena&lt;/a&gt; patch brings new gifts&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1337327864992055304/1_1337327864992055304_Eo8kTvNUcAAiVWe_hu6c3c96244c1dd44425d9fe1735ecae11_179777_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1337181083952017412/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 23:43:08 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1337181083952017412/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Star Wars looking to overtake Star Trek in number of TV series within the next two years&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to Westraid&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/Westraid/statuses/1336730436815499269/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1336743110601162752/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 18:42:47 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1336743110601162752/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to Westraid&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/Westraid/statuses/1336730436815499269/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Westraid/&#34;&gt;@Westraid&lt;/a&gt; Why do you want to work holidays?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1336703174711803906/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 08:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1336703174711803906/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;The internet needs to stop telling me things about Tom Holland&amp;rsquo;s 3rd spider-man movie :/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the last time a live action Spider-Man movie tried to tell us there was a multiverse&amp;hellip; well you know what happened there&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1336584083476946944/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 08:10:52 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1336584083476946944/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I made the most of 2020 by learning Spanish on Duolingo. Check out my progress! #Duolingo365 &lt;a href=&#34;https://2020.duolingo.com/share.html?rid=BDHTZTB5CWWKTAN665AG5I7KBY&#34;&gt;https://2020.duolingo.com/share.html?rid=BDHTZTB5CWWKTAN665AG5I7KBY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>Duolingo365</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-12-06
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-06/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-06/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This week felt like another set of those moments-in-between, where not much seemed to happen, but it somehow still went by quickly anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the household and the family has slowly gotten used to the idea that any big Christmas celebration isn&amp;rsquo;t happening. My niece&amp;rsquo;s birthday was last weekend, so we sent her gifts via Grab delivery instead of being able to get together. Most likely something similar&amp;rsquo;s going to happen for gift exchanges on Christmas. We&amp;rsquo;re still trying to figure out what we can do in the meantime. The extended family has proposed a zoom call on the day of, instead of our traditional annual get-together, I&amp;rsquo;ll let them manage the logistics of that, they have a lot of digital natives to figure it out I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past couple of weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve made improvements to one of my side projects which is an app I use for personal data tracking. Improvements to that app&amp;rsquo;s feature set meant I could also take the time to do some digital housekeeping. That mostly means digging into a whole bunch old files to process their contents and possibly extract them the tracking app. Also regular maintenance things like backing up what needs backing up, deleting what can be deleted. It feels appropriate as a near-year-end activity to be going through junk from the past. (Although I should get started on going through actual physical junk as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;: In the never-ending quest to defeat the  gaming backlog, I started working on Arkham Origins. I believe I&amp;rsquo;ve had  my Steam copy for years now, well before I finished Arkham Knight, and  never got around to it. It&amp;rsquo;s not a particularly new game, so I figured  my five-year old PC could handle it fine. However I&amp;rsquo;m experiencing graphical  slowdowns, especially when dealing with bug groups of enemies. I&amp;rsquo;ve  already tried turning the graphics down to minimum settings, but still  experiencing some issues. My suspicion is that it may have something to  do with me currently using an AMD graphics card (the game does say it&amp;rsquo;s  optimized for NVidia when starting up). So maybe I should have gotten  around to it before my old GeForce card started having trouble. It&amp;rsquo;s  still mostly tolerable, and I did manage to get through some of the  quick-time event sections despite framerate drops. I&amp;rsquo;ll stick with it a  bit to see if I can crawl my way to the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt; Finished the binge watch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/perfect-strangers/&#34;&gt;Perfect Strangers&lt;/a&gt;, and have caught up with Mandalorian and Discovery. I also blazed through S4 of My Hero Academia. I&amp;rsquo;d read the manga already, so just skipped ahead through the boring parts. I kind of want them to catch up with the current manga arc, as I want to see some of the more recent fights animated, but I guess that&amp;rsquo;s going to take a while. I also started rewatching The Big Bang Theory as my background show of choice, it&amp;rsquo;s aged reasonably well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned recently that I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write more, and I did manage to churn out one blog post per day last week! Maybe I went overboard? And that says nothing about their quality of course. Still, writing more + going through the past should help me focus my thoughts to help me figure out what I want for the upcoming year (aside from the to-be-expected wish for the end of the pandemic of course.) I&amp;rsquo;m not committed to daily posting, but let&amp;rsquo;s see if I can keep up the writing pace.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>weeknotes</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Perfect Strangers
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/perfect-strangers/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 12:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/perfect-strangers/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;While digging through some old stuff recently I found a copy of the late 80s/early 90s US sitcom &lt;em&gt;Perfect Strangers&lt;/em&gt; and decided to binge through all 8 seasons of it (really more like 6 and a half, since seasons 1 and 8 were an abridged 6 episodes each).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up watching this series, on live tv even, before we had cable or Netflix or anything like that. During the binge-watch I remember a good number of the episodes from the first season all the way up to the end of season 7, which implies almost all of it was broadcast on local TV, kind of a rarity I think? Of course, given the primitive nature of broadcast tv (i.e. needing to be there at the time the show is on), a lot of the episodes were new to me too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, the premise of the show is simple: Balki Bartokomous, an immigrant from the small Mediterannean island-nation of Mypos, comes to America to pursue his dreams and somehow convinces his distant-cousin-that-he-has-never-seen-before Larry Appleton, who himself has just moved to the windy city of Chicago, to take him in and let him live with him. The series largely relies on the contrast between the two leads for its humor: Balki is portrayed as a naive, unassuming foreigner, honest and open and prone to hugging strangers, while &amp;ldquo;Cousin Larry&amp;rdquo; sees himself as this street-wise, savvy guardian who must introduce Balki to the realities of modern American life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, Larry is actually terribly neurotic, deceptive and manipulative, even to his closest friends. He often gives Balki advice that gets both of them into trouble; he typically overreacts to the situations they find themselves in; he is prone to being taken over by his greed when the opportunity presents itself. And when he does get the two of them into some trouble, his first instinct to try to lie and cheat his way out of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember enjoying the series a lot when I was young, and have a fond recollection especially of the theme song, which I consider one of the best TV show theme songs of all time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8vbnLYROCj8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, the show isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly deep, as can easily be seen during a binge-watch. Most episodes will have a plot along the lines of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balki says/does something naive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larry says &amp;ldquo;Balki, Balki, Balki&amp;rdquo; and gives some advice or some other action that gets them into trouble&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hijinks ensue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optionally: Larry overreacts to the hijinks and lies or something getting them into even deeper trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d say Larry is at fault maybe 80% of the time, though he does have some good/redeeming moments too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show&amp;rsquo;s overall story arc follow the two cousins as they grow both in terms of careers and relationships; they start out working as clerks in a used furniture store, and later move on to jobs at the presitigious Chicago Chronicle. Along the way, they form relationships with a pair of flight attendants (with decidedely 80s hair) who live in their apartment building, whom they eventually marry and have kids with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last part is a bit problematic for me, as I feel like Larry&amp;rsquo;s fiancee and eventual wife Jennifer deserves much better; Larry constantly lies to her and have put their group in mortal danger more than once. Although, once they are married, Jennifer does exhibit many of the same neurotic behaviors Larry has, including trying to lie her way out of bad situations, so maybe they deserved each other. I would guess this character arc is largely a product of its time, a time when society (and thus TV shows) focused on values such as building a career and a stable relationship and eventually a family (as opposed to the Friends era, where the characters would often be jumping across relationships constantly.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I did learn during this binge-watch run (and the accompanying Wikipedia check) is that &lt;em&gt;Perfect Strangers&lt;/em&gt; spawned a spin-off show, &lt;em&gt;Family Matters&lt;/em&gt;, that went on to be one of the longest-running shows on US tv. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that show ever aired on local tv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, it was a reasonable binge-watch, good enough for watching in the background while doing other stuff. My nostalgia is not damaged, I never assumed it was a deep show. The best part remains the theme song, which I still somehow feel compelled to sing out loud with each episode.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>tv</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to visakanv&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/visakanv/statuses/1335151586473984000/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1335170496153841664/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 10:33:47 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1335170496153841664/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to visakanv&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/visakanv/statuses/1335151586473984000/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/visakanv/&#34;&gt;@visakanv&lt;/a&gt; It kind of bothers me that the first tweet in that thread says “2019 tweets”. I know that refers to the quoted 2019 thread, but you otherwise typically start your threads with context for the rest of the thread&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1335170496153841664/1_1335170496153841664_Eod6fOHVgAA7S_C_hu19b3aa51c9e6de953e72c1a5f981828c_82325_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Dress Codes
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/dress-codes/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/dress-codes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A while back someone I know went from working as a developer to working at a senior/management type position at a bank, and that new job came with the corresponding dress code, which meant he was now going to work in long sleeves or barongs. That kind of thing is not for me - back when I still considered a regular office job, one of the fastest ways to get me to run away from an &amp;ldquo;opportunity&amp;rdquo; would be an overly stringent and/or formal dress code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reminded of this because a few days ago, I read an article titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/latimes/status/1251152944717639680&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enough with the WFH sweatpants. Dress like the adult you&amp;rsquo;re getting paid to be.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;, which is like a hilariously bad take. (The account&amp;rsquo;s social media editor &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/latimes/status/1251175728940343298&#34;&gt;immediately followed up disavowing the tweet and admitting to working from home in his pjs&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s understandable if your job involved salesmanship or meeting with clients and such, but not for ordinary office work. I can fix bugs as easily in a t-shirt and jeans as I can in a suit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind of elitist too. Fancy clothes impractical for commuting or for tropical heat. Reinforces existing power structures. Obsolete signals/ideas of status/power/affluence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not saying you can&amp;rsquo;t dress up if you want, but maybe don&amp;rsquo;t judge others for not doing so, or otherwise require them to dress up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand the line needs to be drawn somewhere, but why does the line have to be something impractical and not simply comfortable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/06/casual-fridays/&#34;&gt;Previously.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Ephemeral Echoes
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/ephemeral-echoes/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/ephemeral-echoes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Last week, Twitter added Fleets, their own version of stories (short-lived posts). As could be expected, it&amp;rsquo;s not something I can relate to. I did post one (saying &amp;ldquo;This is dumb.&amp;quot;) just to see what the interface was like, but that&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about writing a blog post about how I dislike this sort of ephemeral social media, but it turns out that &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/ephemeral/&#34;&gt;something I&amp;rsquo;d already written about before&lt;/a&gt;. Things don&amp;rsquo;t change I guess, and they just come around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still can&amp;rsquo;t relate to this kind of thing, since I really prefer having a record of things I&amp;rsquo;ve posted for future reference. It&amp;rsquo;s generally my favorite feature of social media platforms; even when I was winding down my usage of Facebook, I was still using it regularly for the &amp;ldquo;On This Day&amp;rdquo; feature. And I even put an &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/onthisday/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;On this day&amp;rdquo; feature&lt;/a&gt; on this very site as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People do seem fond of this kind of thing though, a lot of my Twitter follows are already posting fleets. I don&amp;rsquo;t mind looking through other people&amp;rsquo;s fleets or stories, there&amp;rsquo;s some fun stuff there sometimes. So this might be the sort of feature we can expect social media platforms to keep putting out in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>tech life</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1334095939020046336/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 03:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1334095939020046336/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;This is how my year sounded on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Spotify/&#34;&gt;@Spotify&lt;/a&gt;. Get your 2020 Wrapped now #2020Wrapped &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/wrapped/share-fdd70c18adb14e70a29521ce4fc85e96-1080x1920?lang=en&amp;amp;si=Wrpf3LjSQl2kQ6vLM3Olpw&#34;&gt;https://open.spotify.com/wrapped/share-fdd70c18adb14e70a29521ce4fc85e96-1080x1920?lang=en&amp;amp;si=Wrpf3LjSQl2kQ6vLM3Olpw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Spotify/&#34;&gt;@Spotify&lt;/a&gt; basically exactly the same as last year&amp;rsquo;s lol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/1202523947289337858&#39;&gt;roytang&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    This is how my year sounded on Spotify. Get your 2019 Wrapped #spotifywrapped &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/wrapped/ddf3e4a1ee43a067d9e011917a96978cb404b9e4&#34;&gt;https://open.spotify.com/wrapped/ddf3e4a1ee43a067d9e011917a96978cb404b9e4&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>2020Wrapped</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game Review: Super Mario Odyssey
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After playing through &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/mario-3d-all-stars/&#34;&gt;Super Mario 3D All Stars in October&lt;/a&gt;, I borrowed a copy of Super Mario Odyssey for the Nintendo Switch from my brother and played through it for most of November. Odyssey was the main reason I actually got a Switch; I played through a few worlds at a friends house during a single session and loved it, so I had been meaning to get the console just for Odyssey alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game deviates a bit from the formula established by Mario 64, Sunshine and Galaxy; Instead of a single hub that leads to small mission worlds, there are a number of different kingdoms, each of which have different residents. The plot is standard Mario fare; Bowser kidnaps Peach because he wants to marry her against her will (and apparently there&amp;rsquo;s nothing she can do about it?! You can say no girl!) You visit each kingdom in turn as you chase Bowser across the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each kingdom is a self-contained &amp;ldquo;open world&amp;rdquo; where there are many challenges you can complete to advance the story. Completing challenges earns you Power Moons (the analogue to 64/Galaxy&amp;rsquo;s stars and Sunshine&amp;rsquo;s shines) which ostensibly power your ship, the Odyssey. Examples of the Kingdoms are the Metro Kingdom featuring New Donk City, whose mayor is the girl you rescued from Donkey Kong so long ago; the Woodland Kingdom is populated by flower-growing robots; the residents of the Seaside Kingdom are slugs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  




&lt;a href=&#34;#0e296a63e8c5317e383ba1adf72d06a3-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/new-donk-city_hud58de80b5c48a33903c4e78adf89972c_330126_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;It&amp;#39;s so weird when you&amp;#39;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&#34; title=&#34;It&amp;#39;s so weird when you&amp;#39;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so weird when you&amp;rsquo;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;0e296a63e8c5317e383ba1adf72d06a3-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/new-donk-city.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s so weird when you&amp;#39;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#e484a0deecbc15a71ffd6173d9c64579-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/woodland_hu39148852bfe8193ef55eed0344c3d387_349647_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is the woodland kingdom&#34; title=&#34;This is the woodland kingdom&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;This is the woodland kingdom (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;e484a0deecbc15a71ffd6173d9c64579-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/woodland.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is the woodland kingdom&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#84526be5a48128edac1b70b29da91719-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/beach_hucc1160ff1649688cbfe46fb4ddd33ef0_299952_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&#34; title=&#34;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Mario wearing a parka at the beach (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;84526be5a48128edac1b70b29da91719-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/beach.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually finished the main story after around a week of play. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly straightforward, not especially challenging.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#7ba08eb041f1571ff133f4ee17ae133b-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/credits_hub108851206b98ce5466a0d64971ceaa1_272556_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&#34; title=&#34;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;7ba08eb041f1571ff133f4ee17ae133b-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/credits.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is however, a lot of post-game and completion stuff to do, that took me another couple of weeks and change. Odyssey&amp;rsquo;s completion revolves around collecting a rather large number of Power Moons. A good chunk of them are only available after beating the main story, though I did try to get as many as I could even before beating Bowser. And some worlds like Peach&amp;rsquo;s Mushroom Kingdom and the more challenging Dark Side/Darker Side of the Moon are available only in the post-game.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#313a380fa8b81e6d69b10f94691c3c60-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/mushroom-kingdom_hu0d6d184ea89cff2c96204967b79d565d_305312_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&#34; title=&#34;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;313a380fa8b81e6d69b10f94691c3c60-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/mushroom-kingdom.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite parts of the game are these segments where Mario becomes a 2D Mario and you have to play 2d Mario stages in 8-bit style, they appear in the open world as murals, often hidden, and they&amp;rsquo;re really nice throwbacks. They even made 8-bit versions of each Mario costume!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completion is a real challenge. There are much more difficult platforming challenges involved, and some moons like the Koopa racing ones will require you to master advanced moves and jumps to beat them. There&amp;rsquo;s also a whole lot of minigames to complete, moons hidden using art-based clues, and a whole lot of collectibles (including hats and costumes for Mario) that you can purchase from stores using coins and regional currency that you collect. I played most of the game in handheld mode, but there are some moons that are easier to get using motion controls, which requires you detach the joycons, so that&amp;rsquo;s something I sometimes had to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  




&lt;a href=&#34;#afa7f811401cc0b4aa2ed14482ff2296-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/clue_hu5c03d63d75cc02a67f36228a0ae744c9_163462_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;There&amp;#39;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&#34; title=&#34;There&amp;#39;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;afa7f811401cc0b4aa2ed14482ff2296-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/clue.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#8743a48562a1c5ef53ff66112e0af0d2-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/space-koopa_hu5a04ad347ee2589302cf1ada3c228395_130058_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mario doesn&amp;#39;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&#34; title=&#34;Mario doesn&amp;#39;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Mario doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;8743a48562a1c5ef53ff66112e0af0d2-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/space-koopa.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mario doesn&amp;#39;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#cf3c150025add34858ebdc88dd0872a9-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/hats_hu0fc2897e727a2efd79695b17b87b2564_246730_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Maybe there&amp;#39;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&#34; title=&#34;Maybe there&amp;#39;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team? (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;cf3c150025add34858ebdc88dd0872a9-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/hats.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maybe there&amp;#39;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get all but 7 of the unique 880 collectible moons. The 7 I missed were 5 for minigames (100 jumps in jump rope, 100 volleys in beach volleyball, and 3 bound bowl races) and 2 stage moons (for Breakdown Road in Dark Side). While none of these seem impossible to do, they all seem like they require much more patience than I am willing to give, so I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with this completion rate for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  




&lt;a href=&#34;#97e0ebef995f25880cec449204a6d666-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/874-moons_huac9045153cdd9a41641854a98f87ad17_219394_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;It&amp;#39;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&#34; title=&#34;It&amp;#39;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;97e0ebef995f25880cec449204a6d666-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/874-moons.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#3116ac381049afd75bad589d6cc5a45d-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/thank-you_hu7f88aae91c13a4ffff71119166449a0c_73671_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&#34; title=&#34;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;3116ac381049afd75bad589d6cc5a45d-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/thank-you.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only complaint is that at some point I found going for completion to be super tedious, especially with those last few moons. 880 moons is a ridiculous number, compare that to a paltry 240 stars in Galaxy. This might be a case of there just being too much stuff? I realize this is a weird thing to complain about. Overall it&amp;rsquo;s still a fun and engaging game, though I&amp;rsquo;m waffling over whether this one or Galaxy is the better game. (I probably still like Super Mario 3D World over either though!)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/874-moons_huac9045153cdd9a41641854a98f87ad17_219394_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;amp;rsquo;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/beach_hucc1160ff1649688cbfe46fb4ddd33ef0_299952_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/clue_hu5c03d63d75cc02a67f36228a0ae744c9_163462_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;There&amp;amp;rsquo;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/credits_hub108851206b98ce5466a0d64971ceaa1_272556_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/hats_hu0fc2897e727a2efd79695b17b87b2564_246730_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Maybe there&amp;amp;rsquo;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/mushroom-kingdom_hu0d6d184ea89cff2c96204967b79d565d_305312_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/new-donk-city_hud58de80b5c48a33903c4e78adf89972c_330126_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;amp;rsquo;s so weird when you&amp;amp;rsquo;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/space-koopa_hu5a04ad347ee2589302cf1ada3c228395_130058_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Mario doesn&amp;amp;rsquo;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/thank-you_hu7f88aae91c13a4ffff71119166449a0c_73671_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/woodland_hu39148852bfe8193ef55eed0344c3d387_349647_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;This is the woodland kingdom&lt;/p&gt;
    



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>gaming</category>
                        
            <category>nintendoswitch</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1333994890338832384/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 04:42:20 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1333994890338832384/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s only the 1st week of December and we&amp;rsquo;re already getting &amp;ldquo;best of 2020&amp;rdquo; lists. The year isn&amp;rsquo;t up yet, who knows what surprises await!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Rhythm of War by Sanderson, Brandon
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/rhythm-of-war/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/rhythm-of-war/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Rhythm of War is book four in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s epic fantasy Stormlight Archive series. Goodreads tells me I read the prior book Oathbringer back in Nov 2017, but didn&amp;rsquo;t bother writing a review, so I had to make sure I&amp;rsquo;d write one now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book&amp;rsquo;s launch day kind of caught me a bit unexpectedly so I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother doing a re-read of the previous three books. Which given an epic fantasy series of this scope might have been a mistake, but watch me do it again for book five. No review meant while reading every so often I&amp;rsquo;d stop and be like &amp;ldquo;Who is this character again, and why is she here?&amp;rdquo; Which is to be expected for this kind of thing, probably if GRRM ever manages to bring out Winds of Winter that&amp;rsquo;ll be a thing again. It&amp;rsquo;s a whole big sprawl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got this book on launch day last Nov 17. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/01/words-of-radiance/&#34;&gt;review for the second book Words of Radiance&lt;/a&gt; tells me it took me three weeks to get through it, so I was kind of expecting I might take until 2021 with this one. It only took me a around eight days, with the last third of the book taking me a single read in one long night. So, that says a lot about how good the book is and how the pacing is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a really fun book actually, things are happening, and there&amp;rsquo;s character growth and everything, and I feel like this one touched a lot more on the cosmere stuff. Or maybe I was just notificing more things because no review meant I was reading the wiki more. (Don&amp;rsquo;t worry I managed not to spoil myself!). It&amp;rsquo;s great that Sanderson manages to just put in a lot of stuff and give all of the lead characters significant things to do and character arcs and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s some happenings near the end that turn around some things the characters thought they knew about their history; not as big as the one in Oathbringer, but that&amp;rsquo;s always fun. And some things happen where I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how the next book is going to handle it, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to that. (Trying not to be too spoilery here of course!) At Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s rate, it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be at least 3 years before book 5 comes out, and even after that, the series is expected to have a second 5-book arc, plus there&amp;rsquo;s some side books that I feel like I should read because they introduce some relevant characters (Edgedanger, etc) so there&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of Stormlight Archive to look forward to!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>books</category>
                        
            <category>stormlight archive</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1333407638336532480/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 05:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1333407638336532480/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Streaming some Kaladesh Remastered draft! Watch me be terrible &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt; #mtg #magicarena #twitch #mtgkld&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As predicted; I was indeed terrible. Draft seemed to go well enough, but I made too many mistakes I guess? Seems like this format is not for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YT: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S15AgtyStzw&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S15AgtyStzw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1333407638336532480/EoFUiNeUcAIrNwi_hu6f1189614c9a3bd6b07a786db4b1a506_87449_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>twitch</category>
                        
            <category>mtgkld</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>We Shouldn&#39;t Need Heroes
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/we-shouldnt-need-heroes/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/we-shouldnt-need-heroes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s National Heroes Day over here, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about heroics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In software development, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.c2.com/?HeroicProgramming&#34;&gt;Heroic Programming&lt;/a&gt; can have a negative connotation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HeroicProgramming is often the only course of action left when poor planning, insufficient funds, and impractical schedules leave a project stranded and unlikely to complete successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;rsquo;s not just in software development either. Many times heroics are an indicator of failed systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonifacio and other Philippine heroes were needed because Spanish colonialism had failed the Filipino people, necessitating a revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this pandemic, we hail the medical workers and other frontliners as heroes for their sacrifices during the pandemic, but they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to do so if we had better health care systems and the government had made better planning early on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whistleblowers are hailed as heroes, but it would be better if instead the people in charge knew better than to do the bad things that would need whistleblowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever there&amp;rsquo;s an election, we look among the candidates, searching for a hero who will fix all our problems and save our country, but a few good politicians won&amp;rsquo;t be enough, what we need are systems and institutions that work to serve the citizenship and can survive even bad leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will always be exceptionalism, and heroics always make for great stories, but there&amp;rsquo;s also something to be said for just having normal, working systems, institutions, and communities that don&amp;rsquo;t need heroes to keep going. We should celebrate our heroes and be grateful for their heroics, but even better would be a world where we need less heroes; a society that functions normally without people having to make sacrifices.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1333200765167366144/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:06:46 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1333200765167366144/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Last minute mythic on #magicarena. Also hit master on Eternal last week, so it&amp;rsquo;s my first double month! #mtg&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1333200765167366144/1_1333200765167366144_EoB64zwVEAAxDsI_hu11ee7da40519a76f2646bc9b13077d79_64227_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>