<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Roy Tang::</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/</link>
      <description>Recent content on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
        
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-22 The Moments In Between
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-22/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-22/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This week felt weird. It kind of went by quickly for me, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like anything important really happened. Its kind of like those moments in-between other events, where you&amp;rsquo;re just coasting along and waiting for the more significant things to happen. My country is still recovering from the storms of the past few weeks, Trump is still flailing around trying to overturn democracy, and our own president is still insecure when someone gets more attention than him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These moments feel fleeting, but they&amp;rsquo;re a pretty good time for some self-reflection. I probably need a bit more of that, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found my mind has been wandering through parallel universes lately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I pushed the post-game completion on Super Mario Odyssey, but I might just be at my limit. I have 7 moons remaining, and 5 of those are for minigames, and the last 2 are for the super frustrating Breakdown Road stage. All of these probably require a great deal more patience than I have available, so that might be it for me. Still, it was a great ride, and I&amp;rsquo;m proud I can even get this far given I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself great at platformers nowadays. Still looking around for a new single-player game to dig into, not sure if I want to do another platformer or look for an RPG or such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magic:&lt;/strong&gt; Still been drafting a bit of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgkld/&#34;&gt;Kaladesh Remastered&lt;/a&gt;, although it seems the draft format doesn&amp;rsquo;t like me very much. I&amp;rsquo;ve gone a single 5-3 and three 0-3s, so it&amp;rsquo;s pretty bad! Still, I can keep doing at least one draft a week until Kaldheim comes out next year I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Rhythm of War&lt;/em&gt;, fourth book in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s Stormlight Archive came out this past week! I got a Kindle copy off Amazon and have been reading a few chapters every night. I&amp;rsquo;m about a third of the way through I think. The problem with this book is I didn&amp;rsquo;t do a re-read of the previous books (they&amp;rsquo;re pretty long!) so every few chapters I&amp;rsquo;m like &amp;ldquo;Who is this person again and why is she here?&amp;rdquo;. This is a typical problem for epic fantasy series like this, so I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have this same problem if/when GRRM manages to get &lt;em&gt;Winds of Winter&lt;/em&gt; out. (I think these two are the only unfinished fantasy series I&amp;rsquo;m still following.) I will say that Sanderson still writes quite well, and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this gets me back into the habit of reading regularly again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I caught up with the Mandalorian, pleasant surprise to see Katie Sackhoff around, apparently playing a character she voiced in Clone Wars (which I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen). Since I caught up with both Mandalorian and Discovery mid-season, now I have to wait every week for new episodes, like some kind of peasant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For my background binge watching, I found some old copies I had of Perfect Strangers, so I&amp;rsquo;ve burned through a few seasons of that already. I loved this series when it was on TV back when I was young. It&amp;rsquo;s not particularly deep; most episodes have the same plot of &amp;ldquo;Balki does/says something naive and/or Larry overreacts and gets them into trouble and hilarity ensures&amp;rdquo;, but it&amp;rsquo;s still fun, and has probably one of the best ever TV show opening themes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;hellip; don&amp;rsquo;t know? US thanksgiving is next week, which is mainly relevant for me because there&amp;rsquo;s usually a bunch of gaming sales at the time, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in yet. There&amp;rsquo;s also some family events coming up (my eldest niece&amp;rsquo;s birthday), but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to get excited about those since we can&amp;rsquo;t actually get together.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>weeknotes</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1330113747550134277/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 11:40:04 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1330113747550134277/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been binging Perfect Strangers. Fun show (and maybe best theme song), but 80% of the eps are like &amp;ldquo;Balki says/does something naive, Larry overreacts and gets them into trouble, but it all works out in the end&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1330094403378163713/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 10:23:12 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1330094403378163713/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Kaladesh Remastered draft really doesn&amp;rsquo;t like me; I thought this deck was pretty good, but it was yet another 0-3. D: At least I didn&amp;rsquo;t waste gems this time. #mtg #magicarena #mtgkld&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1330094403378163713/1_1330094403378163713_EnVxoixXUAU03qr_hu1d69d4f33e2eded9691a5141e132c239_109212_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>mtgkld</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1329868993600004096/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 19:27:30 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1329868993600004096/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Wasting time wandering through parallel universes&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1329022017753001988/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 03:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1329022017753001988/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Streaming some more Kaladesh Remastered draft (ep 2) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt; #mtg #magicarena #twitch #mtgkld&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, internet was too poor again tonight for streaming :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, I went ahead and did two drafts which was a terrible idea because I did very poorly both times. (Didn&amp;rsquo;t bother getting a screenshot of the second result, they were the same!) Sigh, this format is tough. Hopefully I figure it out by next time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1329022017753001988/EnG4qJrVgAASHg6_hu1e9a988a7db3ad80c7aa09ea890c9a7e_168007_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1329022017753001988/EnG4qKIUcAIR0y__hub7a8e13c6776e94e03849f7610728e51_101410_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1329022017753001988/EnG4qKYVoAEWq2Q_hu578a9590ac4da5b585724c2c66753dc4_94931_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>twitch</category>
                        
            <category>mtgkld</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1328773621007876096/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 18:54:53 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1328773621007876096/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fantasy, but I&amp;rsquo;m kind of hoping &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/inquirerdotnet/&#34;&gt;@inquirerdotnet&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PhilstarNews/&#34;&gt;@PhilstarNews&lt;/a&gt; manages to put the word &amp;ldquo;Meltdown&amp;rdquo; somewhere on their front page for Nov 18 #DuterteMeltdown&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>DuterteMeltdown</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from ChappellTracker https://twitter.com/ChappellTracker/statuses/1328104778954575873/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1328358247061831680/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 15:24:20 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1328358247061831680/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from ChappellTracker https://twitter.com/ChappellTracker/statuses/1328104778954575873/:
            &lt;p&gt;Okay I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to explain this, so bear with me. On Tiktok, an entire community has come together to create Ratatouille the Musical. What seemed like a joke has become an incredible undertaking. Or not? Here&amp;rsquo;s how it started, with a call:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&#39;320&#39; height=&#39;568&#39; controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#39;https://video.twimg.com/ext_tw_video/1328104736529264640/pu/vid/576x1024/Dx5FqLWTqS9BBJJL.mp4?tag=10&#39; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
    &lt;/video&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-15 Winds and Rain
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-15/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-15/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Weather this past week was very bad for those of us in Metro Manila (and many other places in Luzon). Howling winds and strong rains dominated for 2-3 days of the week due to typhoon Ulysses. This typhoon wasn&amp;rsquo;t as strong as Rolly a couple of weeks ago, but it seems that it brought a lot more rains, causing flooding and loss of power in a whole lot of places. Metro Manila was hit quite badly, even drawing comparisons to Ondoy back in 2009. Even up to today I&amp;rsquo;m still reading about a ton of people who need assistance, relief or rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fortunately got off relatively unscathed. The howling winds and pouring rain meant it was heard to sleep at some point, but we experienced no other bad effects and in fact were a bit more comfortable due to lower temps. Oh, and we still don&amp;rsquo;t have cable service until today, a minor inconvenience. A lot of my friends lost power and some in the more Northern provinces were subject to severe flooding as well. It also took us a couple of days to get in touch with some relatives on the southern side of Luzon, but it seems they are fine, power issues notwithstanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; Still playing Super Mario Odyssey, hopefully to completion. Although given how difficult some of these minigames are for me, I&amp;rsquo;m not optimistic. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how close I can get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magic:&lt;/strong&gt; Kaladesh Remastered is out on Arena! I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten started on a sealed and a draft, you can follow along via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgkld/&#34;&gt;MTGKLD tag&lt;/a&gt;, if you&amp;rsquo;d like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Boys S2: Surprisingly the Boys kind of got a &amp;ldquo;good ending&amp;rdquo; this time, although there are still threats lurking around. I went back and reread the first Omnibus of the comic book after finishing the season, and the differences are really stark, as in the comics Butcher is really portrayed as a bastard, maybe even as much as Homelander, while in the series they&amp;rsquo;re pretty tame by comparison. Somehow a lot of the issues raised in this season feel topical too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Trek Discovery S3: Season isn&amp;rsquo;t done yet, but I went ahead and got this started. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a trip. Discovery is charting an unknown future now in the Star Trek timeline, and there are a lot of fun moments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Queen&amp;rsquo;s Gambit: This Netflix limited series has been getting a lot of buzz so I decided to give it a go. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly good, in a sports anime kind of way.  It&amp;rsquo;s a testament to how good and realistic the portrayal of the 1960s chess scene is that for a while I thought it was based on a real-life chess prodigy. Apparently, the show is based on a novel instead, a well-researched one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Misc:&lt;/strong&gt; In the starting-yet-another-side-project department, I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with this library called the Dragonruby Game Toolkit, which I got from the itch.io Racial Justice bundle a while back. I tried building a simple platformer using a Kenney asset pack that I also got from the bundle. Here&amp;rsquo;s the WIP: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MDRShB4psyU&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MDRShB4psyU&lt;/a&gt;. I like that I can work with the framework using only my text editor (as compared to some big bulky IDE like Unity), and it&amp;rsquo;s fairly quick to start up, as it makes a lot of assumptions for you so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about things like screen resolution, screen coords, fps, etc. I don&amp;rsquo;t doubt that using Unity might have made the platforming physics a bit easier, but I did enjoy figuring things out on my own. Not sure if this is going anywhere, I&amp;rsquo;m mostly just dabbling with it at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trivia:&lt;/strong&gt; we actually won an online quiz this past week! Amazing. We had so much fun, we even went ahead and had our own internal 2-hour trivia quiz right after: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=no0sYBcU5LA&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=no0sYBcU5LA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; I just found out that the next book in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Stormlight Archive&lt;/em&gt; is coming out next week! That&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a huge book, hopefully I can manage to finish it before year-end (so that I can at least get my books read stat for the year up a tiny bit)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>weeknotes</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1327853276302217223/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 05:57:46 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1327853276302217223/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;[Team Camote] - Post-Trivia Trivia ni Seresa &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=no0sYBcU5LA&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=no0sYBcU5LA&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/YouTube/&#34;&gt;@YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1327606340764766209/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 05:36:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1327606340764766209/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Kaladesh Remastered draft ep 1 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt; #mtg #magicarena #twitch #mtgkld&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, internet wasn&amp;rsquo;t too good so I just cut the stream short. Too bad, so sad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draft didn&amp;rsquo;t feel super good, but I managed to break even in the games. No video because no stream. (In hindsight I could have just recorded locally!) Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll try streaming a draft again early next week.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1327606340764766209/EmyxfHaVcAICSj5_hufc111c56ebd91b4df3e5e2b9d267ccc4_86824_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1327606340764766209/Emyxj_ZVoAIDXO8_hu9b28843a38c2bd0992ba255d5fd26d76_167218_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>twitch</category>
                        
            <category>mtgkld</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to amirrajan&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/amirrajan/statuses/1327107332275376129/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1327111324728393728/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 04:49:31 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1327111324728393728/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to amirrajan&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/amirrajan/statuses/1327107332275376129/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/amirrajan/&#34;&gt;@amirrajan&lt;/a&gt; i dont have much other gamedev experience other than playing with unity a bit, but: I like that I can do most of the work in my text editor, and I like that it simplifies a lot of the work by making assumptions (like the 1280x720 resolution etc) so I can just focus on what I want&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1327110978798907392/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 04:48:08 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1327110978798907392/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Decided to try a Kaladesh Remastered sealed before diving into draft. Didn&amp;rsquo;t do particularly well, but at least I got a feel of what the Kaladesh limited format is like (again) #mtg #magicarena #mtgkld&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1327110978798907392/1_1327110978798907392_EmrX1EHUwAAeTu5_hu1a59db29feea89f384398c688c99b9f9_99591_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1327110978798907392/2_1327110978798907392_EmrX1zMVgAIgBej_hu2af7164ad559f2018ffd6cb08637cc67_200602_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>mtgkld</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1326919888472956928/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 16:08:49 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1326919888472956928/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with this thing called Dragonruby Game Toolkit + some Kenney assets I got from the itch Racial Justice bundle. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MDRShB4psyU&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MDRShB4psyU&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1326760344644059136/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 05:34:50 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1326760344644059136/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Need to complete de-googlification in 4 years&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1326760344644059136/1_1326760344644059136_EmmZcSFWMAIPhRx_huc6fc37ff0af683a258e3e354c7f57e36_21807_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from lenirobredo https://twitter.com/lenirobredo/statuses/1325772716599775232/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1325797474070523904/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 13:48:44 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1325797474070523904/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from lenirobredo https://twitter.com/lenirobredo/statuses/1325772716599775232/:
            &lt;p&gt;lols&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1325797474070523904/1_1325797474070523904_EmYXQWVVcAAqCtc_huc6936e7d598a7b104775b95a31176158_91342_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from Loeybug https://twitter.com/Loeybug/statuses/1324954849394495489/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1325354399493877761/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 08:28:07 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1325354399493877761/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from Loeybug https://twitter.com/Loeybug/statuses/1324954849394495489/:
            &lt;p&gt;This is genuinely the funniest piece of media I’ve ever seen in my life and should absolutely be what is shown to explain the 2020 election for generations to come&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&#39;320&#39; height=&#39;568&#39; controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#39;https://video.twimg.com/ext_tw_video/1324954810009923584/pu/vid/576x1024/DpwFx1uapuoEladb.mp4?tag=10&#39; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
    &lt;/video&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-01 A Collective Sigh of Relief
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-08/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-08/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The World&lt;/strong&gt;: Somehow the week seemed to go by both quickly and agonizingly slowly, mostly because of the US presidential elections held this week. Slowly because after the initial burst of results on Tuesday night (US time), the remaining states&amp;rsquo; results trickled in very slowly. Quickly because much time was spent doomscrolling and refreshing election-related updates. I think the world collectively breathed a sigh of relief this weekend as the US networks finally called the race for former VP and now president-elect Joe Biden. Celebrations on the streets in many cities in the US, notably New York and Philadelphia. Trump still won&amp;rsquo;t concede and vows legal action, but that seems unlikely to go anywhere except make him look immature and pathetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biden isn&amp;rsquo;t even the best or most exciting candidate, and it&amp;rsquo;s still to be seen how he handles crises like the BLM and police brutality stuff and even healthcare, but at the very least the US will now have a coherent leader and hopefully will be able to address the pandemic better. I would guess that Harris as VP will ultimately end up the more historic win. But I imagine the celebrations are less about Biden winning and more about Trump losing. It must be weird to be a fanatic Trump supporter seeing all these people celebrating his loss. He still got a lot of votes - America remains a deeply divided nation, but at least under Biden there&amp;rsquo;s a chance of that being rectified at least a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have written a lot of words on this topic, considering I&amp;rsquo;m not an American. My stakes in this are a bit lower, but I still found myself glued to the ever-changing blue and red numbers. The US leadership affects the rest of the world of course, especially in terms of climate change and multilateralism moving forward, so it&amp;rsquo;s serious business. But I admit, I also enjoyed the drama and the memes. I had more than one chat groups where some of the members were living in the US, and let me tell you, they were super active during this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of all this drama has to be the whole &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/trump-four-seasons-total-landscaping_n_5fa6e08bc5b6f21920dc14f7&#34;&gt;Four Seasons Total Landscaping&lt;/a&gt; brouhaha. Basically, Trump announced his lawyers would have a press conferencce at Four Seasons in Philadelphia, then later corrected himself saying it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the Four Seasons Hotel, but rather Four Seasons Total Landscaping. Basically a parking lot in an industrial area, next to a dildo shop. It smacks of incompetence and miscoordination of the highest order. It&amp;rsquo;s the kind of comedy that TV shows just can&amp;rsquo;t make up, proving indeed that reality can be stranger (and funnier) than fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump&amp;rsquo;s loss is a repudiation of his style of populist, lying leadership. I wish I could say I was as hopeful for similar positive change in my own country in two years, but that remains to be seen&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, back to my stuff lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server migration update:&lt;/strong&gt; Today, I&amp;rsquo;ve closed my account at the old hosting provider, so there is no more turning back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I started and finished Super Mario Odyssey! Just about a week, but that was main game only, finished with a bit over 400 moons. (I believe I can get up to 999 in the game?). Immediately proceeding into the post-game, since I only borrowed this game, so I want to get as close to completion as I can before I have to give it back. That being said, there are some moons gated behind annoying minigames like jump rope, RC racing, etc, which I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d have the patience to grind through, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see. After Odyssey, I&amp;rsquo;ll take it easy on the Switch games for a little bit, though I am already considering getting either Fire Emblem or the new Paper Mario. Would be good to get back to an RPG after all these platformers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt; About halfway through The Boys season 2 now. More thoughts when I finish I guess? I thought about watching a Sean Connery James Bond flick when he died this week, but neither Netflix nor Prime had any, sadface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got a new pair of glasses last Wednesday, but up to today my eyes still feel like they are adjusting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not start Nanowrimo. I started trying something else instead, not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s gonna go anywhere though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing I was anxious about last week never pushed through. I should care less about things!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; Kaladesh Remastered comes out next week on Arena, so there&amp;rsquo;s that!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>weeknotes</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from albus_cotton https://twitter.com/albus_cotton/statuses/1325282695421730818/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1325331804165820416/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 06:58:20 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1325331804165820416/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from albus_cotton https://twitter.com/albus_cotton/statuses/1325282695421730818/:
            &lt;p&gt;Congratulations, USA, on getting a smart, hardworking woman as a VP. We’ve had one since 2016.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from KevinTemmer https://twitter.com/KevinTemmer/statuses/1325212052114219008/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1325331778253414400/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 06:58:14 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1325331778253414400/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from KevinTemmer https://twitter.com/KevinTemmer/statuses/1325212052114219008/:
            &lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to process my joy&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so I made Elmo sing A Cruel Angel&amp;rsquo;s Thesis&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&#39;320&#39; height=&#39;180&#39; controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#39;https://video.twimg.com/ext_tw_video/1325211666770919424/pu/vid/1280x720/6O-71l26yHpZwX2-.mp4?tag=10&#39; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
    &lt;/video&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from ava https://twitter.com/ava/statuses/1324899733417046016/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324998925598691339/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 08:55:35 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324998925598691339/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from ava https://twitter.com/ava/statuses/1324899733417046016/:
            &lt;p&gt;The Week in Review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&#39;320&#39; height=&#39;400&#39; controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#39;https://video.twimg.com/ext_tw_video/1324713018886938625/pu/vid/640x800/5vKi16bhq-summTE.mp4?tag=10&#39; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
    &lt;/video&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324603766390206465/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 06:45:22 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324603766390206465/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Who&amp;rsquo;d have thought it was actually a muppet that could defeat him&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/CarcinogenSDA/status/1324581045367377920&#39;&gt;CarcinogenSDA&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324603766390206465/1_1324603766390206465_EmHbavDXgAA-fUb_hu897e1389c8d1d1727c42758023a0c5bb_92553_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324571861670227968/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 04:38:35 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324571861670227968/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Pag pinadalhanka ng bill ng meralco sabihan mo sila na mukhang pera&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/PhilippineStar/status/1324374435902578689&#39;&gt;PhilippineStar&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;‘MUKHANG PERA’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was President Duterte’s comment when Health Secretary Francisco Duque III reported during a Cabinet meeting that the Philippine Red Cross has resumed conducting COVID-19 swab tests after the PhilHealth paid its close to P1-B debt. | &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/xtinamen/&#34;&gt;@xtinamen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&#39;320&#39; height=&#39;320&#39; controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#39;https://video.twimg.com/ext_tw_video/1324373973283471360/pu/vid/720x720/PlqQVfcBH2LyC-nI.mp4?tag=10&#39; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324406196514729984/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 17:40:18 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324406196514729984/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;One upside of this election is that I’ve learned a lot about where US states are on the map&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Server Setup Notes: Ubuntu, Nginx, Django, MySQL
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/server-setup-notes/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 06:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/server-setup-notes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I recently did &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/site-migration-to-django/&#34;&gt;a server migration&lt;/a&gt; since I moved to new hosting, The move was from managed/shared hosting to a VPS, these are some notes I took during the process, which I figure might be helpful if I ever tried to  do this again. (And maybe someone else finds it helpful too). Links and references to helpeful resources are included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setting-up-a-webserver-and-wsgi-container&#34;&gt;Setting up a webserver and WSGI container&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already knew I wanted to use Nginx (managed hosting on the old server always used Apache), that meant needing to choose a WSGI container for the Django apps. The choices were either gunicorn or uwsgi. Readings suggest minimal performance difference between the two. I did try setting up both, and found uwsgi&amp;rsquo;s setup much more straightforward and with more helpful step-by-step documentation: &lt;a href=&#34;https://uwsgi-docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tutorials/Django_and_nginx.html&#34;&gt;https://uwsgi-docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tutorials/Django_and_nginx.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nginx itself was pretty straightforward to set up. This &amp;ldquo;common pitfalls&amp;rdquo; article was helpful in resolving issues: &lt;a href=&#34;https://origin-www.wp.nginx.com/resources/wiki/start/topics/tutorials/config_pitfalls/&#34;&gt;https://origin-www.wp.nginx.com/resources/wiki/start/topics/tutorials/config_pitfalls/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I will note that&amp;rsquo;s not in the article above is that for static files to be served by Nginx, it was easier to just have everything be under /var/www, for permission purposes. I initially had static files in a different folder in my user root, but really there&amp;rsquo;s no reason for that since you&amp;rsquo;re going to serve them statically anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setting-up-php-on-nginx&#34;&gt;Setting up PHP on Nginx&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed PHP since I had a few minor scripts/pages and a Wordpress install that needed PHP. For the setup on Nginx, I found this guide from askubuntu super helpful: &lt;a href=&#34;https://askubuntu.com/questions/134666/what-is-the-easiest-way-to-enable-php-on-nginx&#34;&gt;https://askubuntu.com/questions/134666/what-is-the-easiest-way-to-enable-php-on-nginx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide from DigitalOcean was also helpful: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-linux-nginx-mysql-php-lemp-stack-in-ubuntu-16-04&#34;&gt;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-linux-nginx-mysql-php-lemp-stack-in-ubuntu-16-04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was encountering some issues with fastcgi not mapping requests to the correct PHP script if the Nginx location block was aliased. This was with me using the default &lt;code&gt;snippets/fastcgi-php.conf&lt;/code&gt; that was provided with the fastcgi install. I resolved the issue by adding an additional fastcgi_param to the php location block like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    location /sample-path {
        alias /var/www/sample-path;
        # autoindex on;

        location ~ \.php$ {
                include snippets/fastcgi-php.conf;
                fastcgi_param  SCRIPT_FILENAME    $request_filename;
                fastcgi_pass unix:/run/php/php7.4-fpm.sock;
        }
    }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The solution for this came from the Nginx common pitfalls article listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;choosing-a-database&#34;&gt;Choosing a database&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I initially wanted to use PostgreSQL (since that&amp;rsquo;s what I was using locally) and set that up first. Then I realized I had a Wordpress install I wanted to carry over, and apparently Wordpress needs MySQL, so oops. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have two databases running, so that was out. Plan out your database usage boys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setting-up-mysql-for-django&#34;&gt;Setting up MySQL for Django&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created the initial MySQL database with character set &lt;code&gt;utf8&lt;/code&gt;, which apparently had the dumb implementation of only supporting 3 bytes for multibyte characters. This led to errors when I tried importing records into Django that had emojis and the like in text. Apparently the &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; character set to use is &lt;code&gt;utf8mb4&lt;/code&gt; (mb4 -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;multibyte 4&amp;rdquo; I guess?). It&amp;rsquo;s kinda dumb that they had to invent a &amp;ldquo;more utf8 character set&amp;rdquo; because of their initial dumb implementation. It&amp;rsquo;s also dumb that I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize this when apparently the MySQL databases on the old server were already using &lt;code&gt;utf8mb4&lt;/code&gt;! On the Django side, you need to specify the charset in the database settings. Helpful for resolving this issue was donturner&amp;rsquo;s answer on this SO question: &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2108824/&#34;&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2108824/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some initial testing, I also encountered a &amp;ldquo;MySQL has gone away&amp;rdquo; every so often. Turns out Django was holding on to connections for too long, so a timeout had to be set in the database settings as well. SO reference: &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/26958592/&#34;&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/26958592/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: I just encountered this a few hours after I wrote this post, when I tried to make the site display all times in Manila local time. Apparently, even if I set my Django app to be timezone, aware, additional setup needs to be done on the MySQL side so it knows what the actual timezones are (feels like they should really do this as part of the install!). Basically you need to run &lt;code&gt;mysql_tzinfo_to_sql&lt;/code&gt; to load the OS timezone info into the database. This is in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://django.readthedocs.io/en/stable/ref/databases.html&#34;&gt;Django documentation&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/5.6/en/mysql-tzinfo-to-sql.html&#34;&gt;MySQL documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;misc-stuff&#34;&gt;Misc stuff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used cron to set up most of the batch jobs I usually run (like the Twitter bots, etc). Initially I had problems where it seemed like cron wasn&amp;rsquo;t running the jobs, even though syslog showed me the cron daemon was actually running. I don&amp;rsquo;t have notes on how I resolved this, but mentioning it here so that if this happens again in the future, I know to actuall take notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up log files for my cron jobs: I did it this way: &lt;code&gt;0 * * * * /path-to-batch/hourly.sh &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /var/log/cron/my-log-file.log 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1&lt;/code&gt;. The &amp;ldquo;2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1&amp;rdquo; at the end is necessary so that stderr is redirected to the same file (otherwise you&amp;rsquo;d only get stdout).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Log rotation: these is the kind of thing you don&amp;rsquo;t realize you need to do when you&amp;rsquo;re managing your own server. Anyway, I found this guide helpful: &lt;a href=&#34;https://linoxide.com/linux-how-to/setup-log-rotation-logrotate-ubuntu/&#34;&gt;https://linoxide.com/linux-how-to/setup-log-rotation-logrotate-ubuntu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed to set up AWStats on the new server (and migrate data from the old server). This guide was helpful: &lt;a href=&#34;https://larsee.com/blog/2020/06/awstats-on-ubuntu-20-04-with-nginx/&#34;&gt;https://larsee.com/blog/2020/06/awstats-on-ubuntu-20-04-with-nginx/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When migrating the old AWStats data files, the filename format from the oldserver was slightly different (new install needed to end with &lt;code&gt;*.roytang.net.txt&lt;/code&gt;), so I learned a bit of bash scripting to do the batch rename:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;for i in /path-to-tmp/awstats/*.txt ; do cp &amp;quot;$i&amp;quot; &amp;quot;/path-to-tmp/awstats/out/$(basename &amp;quot;$i&amp;quot; .txt).roytang.net.txt&amp;quot; ; done&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt SSL on Nginx: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nginx.com/blog/using-free-ssltls-certificates-from-lets-encrypt-with-nginx/&#34;&gt;https://www.nginx.com/blog/using-free-ssltls-certificates-from-lets-encrypt-with-nginx/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Lessons learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect from the migration from shared hosting to a VPS is how much memory I&amp;rsquo;d need. My old hosting plan was only on 512MB ram, and the lowest DigitalOcean droplet had 1GB RAM, so I figured that was fine! But MySQL occasionally had out of memory errors on startup even at 1GB ram, so I bumped up to the next level (2GB RAM). I guess the database RAM usage didn&amp;rsquo;t count against my limits on the shared hosting! The next tier isn&amp;rsquo;t much more expensive and is still manageable for my casual/hobby hosting purposes, but I will probably try to look into more detail into the memory situation at some point to see what I can optimize.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>tech life</category>
                        
            <category>software development</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324179840522596353/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 02:40:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324179840522596353/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;He should just migrate here to the Philippines, thats how 90% of our politicians are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/bmemike/status/1324165217643827200&#39;&gt;bmemike&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wrongwaygoback/&#34;&gt;@wrongwaygoback&lt;/a&gt; I heard something in coverage earlier today and it&amp;rsquo;s just 100% spot on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only two outcomes for Trump is that he wins or the election was stolen. He can never be a loser. It&amp;rsquo;s just not part of his brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324088239699816448/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 20:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324088239699816448/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Wow, the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PlayStation/&#34;&gt;@PlayStation&lt;/a&gt; web store is so much worse than the old one&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324009839777861632/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1324009839777861632/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been quiet on Twitter but rest assured like the rest of you I&amp;rsquo;ve been gnashing my teeth over these red and blue numbers that may very well decide the future of the planet&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to wrongwaygoback&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/wrongwaygoback/statuses/1323798271052062721/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1323801262966534145/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 01:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1323801262966534145/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to wrongwaygoback&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/wrongwaygoback/statuses/1323798271052062721/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wrongwaygoback/&#34;&gt;@wrongwaygoback&lt;/a&gt; may 2017&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1323801262966534145/1_1323801262966534145_El8WOnHVoAAtl6-_hu55d8997489e00c29861226e4a306e77b_142350_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1323789651421720576/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1323789651421720576/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Shared via pocket: &amp;amp;quot;GO GO MARIO!!&amp;amp;quot; Official Single (3/1986, English Subtitles) - NintendoComplete &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;v=hYlm_9i5Dgc&amp;amp;app=desktop&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;v=hYlm_9i5Dgc&amp;amp;app=desktop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>How To Avoid Spoilers For Everything Forever
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/how-to-avoid-spoilers-for-everything-forever/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 17:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/how-to-avoid-spoilers-for-everything-forever/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KSRWJMM98pM&amp;amp;app=desktop&#34;&gt;How To Avoid Spoilers For Everything Forever&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>13 Life-Learnings from 13 Years of Brain Pickings
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/13-life-learnings-from-13-years-of-brain-pickings/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 17:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/13-life-learnings-from-13-years-of-brain-pickings/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brainpickings.org/2019/10/23/13-learnings-13-years/&#34;&gt;13 Life-Learnings from 13 Years of Brain Pickings&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1323669425216606208/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 16:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1323669425216606208/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Okay, this feels a bit crazy. It&amp;rsquo;s a promoted tweet (basically an ad, for what idk), but then the video in the promoted tweet has an ad! Adception!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1323669425216606208/1_1323669425216606208_El6eU6YVcAAHVBq_hu79bcafc1924f23507eb9cd72621ffe36_123785_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to jaymelynilao&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/jaymelynilao/statuses/1323246720935849986/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1323293273360756736/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 15:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1323293273360756736/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to jaymelynilao&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/jaymelynilao/statuses/1323246720935849986/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jaymelynilao/&#34;&gt;@jaymelynilao&lt;/a&gt; happy birthday!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1323188153411424256/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 09:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1323188153411424256/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;All Saints Day Zendikar Rising draft (final episode) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt; #mtg #magicarena #twitch #mtgznr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think the draft itself was fine, but spoiler: the outcome was terrible! Bonus: A couple of Eternal matches!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YT: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X-b2d3VkIF0&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X-b2d3VkIF0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/1323188153411424256/El1IYRcU0AAArE__hu31c30cafbc8e202bf63dd49fdf2a4fa6_104626_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>twitch</category>
                        
            <category>mtgznr</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-01 Storm&#39;s comin&#39;
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-01/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-01/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now:&lt;/strong&gt; Stormy weekend here in Manila. Supposedly the &amp;ldquo;strongest storm of 2020&amp;rdquo; so far, typhoon Rolly made landfall earlier today and is currently battering many of the provinces south of Metro Manila. Storm signals are as high as number 5. As of this writing, weather is currently cold and nippy but not particularly rainy where I am. We expect stronger winds and rain to hit us as evening approaches as well. On top of everything, a second typhoon has entered the PH area of responsibility and is expected to affect us over the next couple of days as well. If those two typhoons get together, it may be very bad. Hoping for the best. (I thought about doing these weeknotes end of day&amp;hellip; but we might lose power, so here we go.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server migration update:&lt;/strong&gt; Migrating the final domain now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/&#34;&gt;Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening!&lt;/a&gt; Full heart and seashell completion even! It was fun and a great throwback to classic games like Link to the Past. I never played the original on Gameboy, though maybe that&amp;rsquo;s for the best, as I liked how this one looked and my memory is not tainted by nostalgia over GB graphics. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a particularly long game, especially compared to other Zeldas, but there is a custom dungeon feature (new to this remake) which probably adds some replay value, though I don&amp;rsquo;t have much interest in it at the moment. On to Super Mario Odyssey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I did terribly at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal/&#34;&gt;Eternal Card Game&lt;/a&gt; worlds LCQ, but I must admit their current celebration promo was super effective in getting me back into the game, as I&amp;rsquo;m now doing daily grinds in both Eternal and Magic Arena again. I managed to hit Mythic in Magic Arena before month end, but didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough time for Eternal, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if I can keep it up next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying games of &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/965580/Root/&#34;&gt;Root&lt;/a&gt; with the Saturday gaming group. It&amp;rsquo;s a multifaction boardgame where each faction plays differently and has different ways of scoring victory points, and the factions will naturally clash with each other. The main challenge is finding a fine balance between advancing your agenda and interfering with the others. Disrupting the other factions might lose you some momentum compared to the others, but if no one keeps the others in check, someone might run away with victory! Pretty fun. And given that the game supports asynchronous games (up to 3 days per turn), the term &amp;ldquo;Saturday gaming group&amp;rdquo; is a bit obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Done:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober2020&#34;&gt;the Inktober thing&lt;/a&gt;! I managed to get through the whole thing without missing a day! Doing daily drawings with a pen are hard for me, given my poor manual dexterity at this age (and it was never that good in the first place). My hands got tired so easily, and a lot of my lines were shaky. Still, I enjoyed doing a lot of the sketches, and while I don&amp;rsquo;t want to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/&#34;&gt;commit to daily drawings&lt;/a&gt; again (at least for now), maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll warm up the old Apple Pencil every so often and do some digital stuff? Maybe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching lately:&lt;/strong&gt; I finished Season 4 of The Expanse. I didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy it as much as the first 3 seasons, though the second half was better than the first. Things were ramping up too slowly, and a lot of things didn&amp;rsquo;t seem relevant to the what was going on with the Roci crew (and turned out to be mostly geared towards next season&amp;rsquo;s big crisis apparently?). As I said to a friend, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m here for the scifi protomolecule stuff not OPA terrorist or earth politics BS.&amp;rdquo; Still, looking forward to the next season. Also: Finished five seasons of NCIS (that&amp;rsquo;s all they had on Prime Video). In the queue: The Boys S2, Star Trek Discovery S3, Mandalorian S2. Where&amp;rsquo;s my Orville?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skipped:&lt;/strong&gt; Hacktoberfest. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Considering:&lt;/strong&gt; Nanowrimo. Haven&amp;rsquo;t done any prep, so if ever it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a late start. I do have some ideas rolling around in my head, but I also have some other stuff to do, so for now let&amp;rsquo;s say this is &amp;ldquo;low probability&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anxiety:&lt;/strong&gt; Low, most of it due to awaiting a call back about something that hasn&amp;rsquo;t pushed through yet, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really need? Why am I anxious about it then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Random:&lt;/strong&gt; This storm reminded me of my worst typhoon experience in Metro Manila, Ondoy back in 2009, so I wrote a short &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/09/ondoy/&#34;&gt;back-dated retrospective on it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad luck:&lt;/strong&gt; The hinge on one side of my glasses&amp;rsquo; frame broke while I was at the cashier at the grocery yesterday! D: I have a slightly older pair I can use in the meantime, but it&amp;rsquo;ll probably be a few days before I can even go to get a real replacement, given the storm and the long weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; the US presidential elections, with a mix of morbid dread and anticipation, like an onlooker at a car crash.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>weeknotes</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Inktober 2020 Day 31: Crawl
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-31-crawl/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 10:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-31-crawl/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Inktober 2020 day 31: CRAWL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always put far too many webs on that costume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I managed to crawl my way through all of #inktober2020 without missing a day, go me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official prompt list: &lt;a href=&#34;https://inktober.com/rules&#34;&gt;https://inktober.com/rules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-31-crawl/20201031_184204_hud6c4d51f32633f86d865a859c4828c30_766126_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>inktober</category>
                        
            <category>inktober2020</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 16:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I finished #LinksAwakening ! #NintendoSwitch&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/1_1322214646221205504_EllzNqXUYAEQpTF_hufca77d7143b0e88fd60778ab186248a8_79498_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/2_1322214646221205504_EllzNqRU0AEZguo_hu27c06787f10c878c0a516d8a14943077_104101_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/3_1322214646221205504_EllzNqcUcAExjPY_hu72bde3e146d4d6d5669e55ee0f8aeff1_105527_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/4_1322214646221205504_EllzNp0VgAAJ9cF_hue2dfce44e2adc13f7c83ee6471e19c2d_41706_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>LinksAwakening</category>
                        
            <category>NintendoSwitch</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322207028756930560/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 16:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322207028756930560/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Managed to hit mythic on #magicarena the day before rollover lol. I was using &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/karsten_frank/&#34;&gt;@karsten_frank&lt;/a&gt; &amp;rsquo;s Gruul Adventures list  #mtg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/karsten_frank/status/1320480706867449861&#39;&gt;karsten_frank&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I went 20-5 with Gruul Adventures across #RedBullUntapped2020 and the Arena Qualifier this weekend. Deck&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ArenaDecklists/&#34;&gt;@ArenaDecklists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322207028756930560/1_1322207028756930560_EllsG3FUcAEUUMH_hu0aff783c92288a7cbdff9340df010c5a_66864_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322207028756930560/2_1322207028756930560_ElMzjY0XUAAZSm1_hub2a706a7f644b48a1617edd75e484ab7_158741_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
                        
            <category>redbulluntapped2020</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Inktober 2020 Day 30: Ominous
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-30-ominous/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 06:58:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-30-ominous/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Inktober 2020 day 30: OMINOUS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels like this fancy black pen I bought 3-ish years ago is close to giving out on me. To be honest, it&amp;rsquo;s already a record for the longest time I&amp;rsquo;ve had a pen and not lost it somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official prompt list: &lt;a href=&#34;https://inktober.com/rules&#34;&gt;https://inktober.com/rules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-30-ominous/20201030_145509_huc629e801876478689f5ded7fe8a1d344_1087927_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>inktober</category>
                        
            <category>inktober2020</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from LimitedRunGames https://twitter.com/LimitedRunGames/statuses/1321841481745895425/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1321845000108306432/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 16:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1321845000108306432/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from LimitedRunGames https://twitter.com/LimitedRunGames/statuses/1321841481745895425/:
            &lt;p&gt;In honor of our fifth anniversary, we&amp;rsquo;re giving away the first SIXTY games in our Switch collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enter: simply follow us, like, and retweet this. That&amp;rsquo;s it! We&amp;rsquo;ll draw a winner tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again for supporting us. 🥰 #LimitedRun5&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1321845000108306432/1_1321845000108306432_Elgfv_DXUAEpNEV_hu7a1a990fb7aab8cd305485332316b346_114188_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>limitedrun5</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Inktober 2020 Day 29: Shoes
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-29-shoes/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 12:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-29-shoes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Inktober 2020 day 29: SHOES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official prompt list: &lt;a href=&#34;https://inktober.com/rules&#34;&gt;https://inktober.com/rules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-29-shoes/20201029_195954_hu65cb172ae570bd1bfcbb20fb1d66b4fa_869704_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>inktober</category>
                        
            <category>inktober2020</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Inktober 2020 Day 28: Float
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-28-float/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 12:01:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-28-float/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Inktober 2020 day 28: FLOAT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official prompt list: &lt;a href=&#34;https://inktober.com/rules&#34;&gt;https://inktober.com/rules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-28-float/20201028_195917_hub912350378a1a7544fb0aeed45bdf5e7_782608_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>inktober</category>
                        
            <category>inktober2020</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Inktober 2020 Day 27: Music
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-27-music/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 11:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-27-music/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Inktober 2020 day 27: MUSIC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official prompt list: &lt;a href=&#34;https://inktober.com/rules&#34;&gt;https://inktober.com/rules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-27-music/20201027_191105_hu2df26e37dc187de04d3a7e01f8ef3da7_739327_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>inktober</category>
                        
            <category>inktober2020</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to alvinjtang&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/alvinjtang/statuses/1320958858257334272/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1320978632534228994/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 06:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1320978632534228994/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to alvinjtang&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/alvinjtang/statuses/1320958858257334272/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alvinjtang/&#34;&gt;@alvinjtang&lt;/a&gt; yeap. binili ni godaddy e&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Site Migration from Hugo to Django
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/site-migration-from-hugo-to-django/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/site-migration-from-hugo-to-django/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;h3 id=&#34;leaving-hugo&#34;&gt;Leaving Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit under two years since &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-migration-to-hugo/&#34;&gt;I migrated the site from Wordpress to Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. As discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/one-year-with-hugo/&#34;&gt;this post one year ago&lt;/a&gt;, I was very happy with the general workflow of managing posts through markdown files in git, but had big problems with the Hugo build time, largely a consequence of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/archive-of-my-own/&#34;&gt;my social media archiving&lt;/a&gt;. At that time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to invest effort into migrating to a different backend, but the problem has only gotten incrementally worse since then, so I decided to take the jump and started working on it last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;migration-goals&#34;&gt;Migration goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main goal is to get rid of the unnecessary build time. I also don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to store all the pre-generated HTML files. It&amp;rsquo;s fine for a small site, but with the large number of posts here, there&amp;rsquo;s a large amount of unnecessary duplication, considering listing pages and such. That means reverting to a system where each page is generated on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to retain the current workflow of managing content via markdown files, so that rules out something like Wordpress. Still, I figured I needed some kind of database for indexing, so that things like listing and archive pages work properly. Given that we would be migrating away from a static site, I fully expect a performance hit, at least initially, but ideally it&amp;rsquo;s not too bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d also like to retain the current content written for Hugo as much as possible. This means the new system will need to be able to parse the custom Hugo shortcodes I&amp;rsquo;d set up for the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also be migrating to a new server which I would be managing myself, which means I would need to set up the deployment myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-django&#34;&gt;Why Django&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I naturally fell back on Django, it&amp;rsquo;s my ORM+backend framework of choice, and the one I&amp;rsquo;m most familiar with. Also, I already had a handful of small Django apps that I needed to migrate to the new server as well, so no matter what I needed to have a Django app on the server anyway. I also had a bunch of Python scripts that were doing already doing support functions for the site like search and ingestion of social media content, so that&amp;rsquo;s something to fold into the new backend as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-bother&#34;&gt;Why Bother?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will fully admit I spent far too much effort unnecessarily doing this, but the realization is that it&amp;rsquo;s actually work I enjoy. This site is primarily a project for myself, and I enjoy the time working on it and learning stuff and improving things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, the effort wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much. There was a lot of code to reuse and migrate, so most of the effort was testing and making sure things worked. Most of the new code was for parsing the markdown files to render the hugo shortcodes as HTML; I basically wrote Django templates for each Hugo shortcode to be supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;changes&#34;&gt;Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The migration was largely done in-place: site design remains mostly the same, post URLs should be more or less retained. I did take the opportunity to make one nontrivial change: Photos are now under &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt; category. I really only had a separate photos category before because in Hugo I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a way to query posts that have attached images. Even with everything under Notes, since I have a database now, I can do silly things like show &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/photos/random&#34;&gt;random photos&lt;/a&gt;. Also, now the notes section is closer to a microblog/tumblr-like feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source for the site content will still be &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roytang/blog&#34;&gt;available publicly via Github&lt;/a&gt;, as it was before. Unfortunately, I am not ready to make public the source for this site, because (a) a lot of it is old code that I reused so it looks terrible; and (b) some level of security by obscurity I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that the site needs to be secure; there isn&amp;rsquo;t actually any critical/important data being stored anywhere. But the fact that a database now exists means I need to follow some kind of security practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The server is now hosted on DigitalOcean. Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/6c2e6b11b260&#34;&gt;my affiliate link&lt;/a&gt;. Since I&amp;rsquo;m on a self-managed VPS now, that means Github webhooks now work, so whenever I push new posts, they take less than a minute to now appear on the site. This is a vast improvement over the old system where it would take anywhere between 30-60 minutes depending on how Travis was feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Travis, I set up a new mirror, Travis now publishes to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net&#34;&gt;https://mirror.roytang.net&lt;/a&gt; once a day, hosted on Netlify. The mirror is still generated using Hugo! I don&amp;rsquo;t know how long I can keep up having the content generate correctly for both builds, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this actually went out much smoother than I thought it would. Took less effort than expected, deployment was a breeze. The listing pages have slightly worse performance, but individual pages are hitting 100 on Pagespeed, so that&amp;rsquo;s mostly fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was just the overview of the site changes. There&amp;rsquo;s still a bunch of technical notes to be written up, so that&amp;rsquo;s stuff for a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time I used a Django backend for my website was &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/12/roytang-net-site-update/&#34;&gt;waaaay back in 2008&lt;/a&gt;, and that didn&amp;rsquo;t last more than a year before I switched to Wordpress. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how long this one holds out!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>hugo</category>
                        
            <category>django</category>
                        
            <category>Meta</category>
                        
            <category>Tech Life</category>
                        
            <category>changelog</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/current-status/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/current-status/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like every other sensible person in the pandemic, I am staying hunkered down at home all of the time. Really only going out to get groceries and meds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work/employment is not a priority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-location&#34;&gt;Current Location:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;still living in Quezon City, Philippines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still work part-time as a software developer/technical lead/system architect consultant, with the emphasis on part-time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No specific clients I care to mention, though it&amp;rsquo;s easy to find out if you dig around a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am very picky with taking on new work, and I usually have very few hours I&amp;rsquo;m willing to dedicate to any one client, and will usually prefer interesting work. I don&amp;rsquo;t consider work nor full-time employment to be an important part of my identity and it is definitely not a priority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nonetheless, if you have a work opportunity you feel I might like, feel free to contact me, maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll get lucky.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-am-i-spending-my-time&#34;&gt;How am I spending my time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working on multiple personal projects, most of which I don&amp;rsquo;t want to talk about. The only public one is this website/blog. I write as often as I can and am constantly trying to update this site to make it better or more to my liking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still do a lot of gaming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz team does online &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/03/scenes-from-a-quiz-night/&#34;&gt;quiz nights&lt;/a&gt;, a few times a month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/weeknotes&#34;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; for regular updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>current-status</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>“Fake COTS” and the one-day rule
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/fake-cots-and-the-one-day-rule/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 22:26:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/fake-cots-and-the-one-day-rule/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://sboots.ca/2020/09/16/fake-cots-and-the-one-day-rule/?s=09&#34;&gt;“Fake COTS” and the one-day rule&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Inktober 2020 Day 26: Hide
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-26-hide/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 08:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-26-hide/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Inktober 2020 day 26: HIDE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official prompt list: &lt;a href=&#34;https://inktober.com/rules&#34;&gt;https://inktober.com/rules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-26-hide/20201026_165731_hud1799c4b565d6c4fc148ecda3cf22cae_654384_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>inktober</category>
                        
            <category>inktober2020</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1320562175245598721/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 03:05:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1320562175245598721/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Local banks need to be making sure their websites work with Firefox. Not everyone uses Chrome!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1320562175245598721/1_1320562175245598721_ElOUJYUUYAAJc79_hu4946cdedf3eb043ddf3e19f5f496aa51_39971_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Inktober 2020 Day 25: Buddy
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-25-buddy/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 05:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-25-buddy/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Inktober 2020 day 25: BUDDY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was way too ambitious for my shaky hands. Proportions also a bit out of whack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official prompt list: &lt;a href=&#34;https://inktober.com/rules&#34;&gt;https://inktober.com/rules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/inktober-25-buddy/20201025_130150_hudfc3bf356de6cd4cfc1daf6943b165f5_556791_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>inktober</category>
                        
            <category>inktober2020</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>