<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Roy Tang::</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/</link>
      <description>Recent content on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
        
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Snow Crash by Neal Stephenson
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/book-review-snow-crash-by-neal-stephenson/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 02:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/book-review-snow-crash-by-neal-stephenson/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I finished reading &lt;em&gt;Snow Crash&lt;/em&gt; in around three weeks, slightly faster than the other comparable work I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year, which was &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/neuromancer/&#34;&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/a&gt;. Comparable of course only in the sense that they both have some kind of worldwide internet-like network as a central plot point. Otherwise, they are not really that similiar, though the review is made easier by having a base for comparison. Snow Crash is much less cyberpunk than Neuromancer, and maybe takes itself a little less seriously too? I mean, the main character&amp;rsquo;s name is &amp;ldquo;Hiro Protagonist&amp;rdquo;, so that ought to tell you something immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snow Crash was published in 1992, while Neuromancer came out in 1984, so definitely the latter book does take a bit of inspiration from the older one, in terms of cyberspace. The version here in Snow Crash is called &amp;ldquo;Metaverse&amp;rdquo;, and it is actually more akin to a shared virtual reality, much like you were plugged in to a MMORPG such as World of Warcraft. Users of the Metaverse even use goggles to participate, something that only became possible in reality during the last 5 years or so. Hiro in this case is one of the premiere hackers of the metaverse, having contributed a lot to the functionality of the virtual world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only the second Stephenson book I&amp;rsquo;ve read, after Cryptonomicon &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/11/cryptonomicon/&#34;&gt;waaaay back in 2004&lt;/a&gt;. I was worried that I would encounter the same issues I had with Cryptonomicon here - the general wordiness and the slow pace. Thankfully, Snow Crash turned out to be faster paced and easier to follow than the other book. The plot moves along at a reasonable clip, and revolves almost exclusively around the actions of Hiro and his partner, the Kourier who calls herself Y.T. (for &amp;ldquo;Yours Truly&amp;rdquo;) as they navigate this strange world where the United States has suffered from a severe economic collapse and had to cede parts of California to what are now a bunch of autonomous and sovereign microterritories, many of them belonging to private franchises with colorful names such as &amp;ldquo;Mr Lee&amp;rsquo;s Greater Hong Kong&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;The Mafia&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core of the plot revolves around linguistics, history, archaeology, computer science, and such (unsurprising given the subject matter of Cryptonomicon). It uses this idea that an ancient civilization was able to use language can be used to propagate a &amp;ldquo;virus&amp;rdquo; throughout society by hacking the human brain, in the same way that code can propagate a virus through a computer network. The bad guy in this story is trying to use this concept of a virus derived from an ancient language to control people and create an all-powerful religion with him at the helm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book&amp;rsquo;s title &amp;ldquo;Snow Crash&amp;rdquo; is the name of a digital &amp;ldquo;drug&amp;rdquo; that the bad guy distributes throughout the Metaverse to target hackers. The drug is actually a digital image of random black and white bits (a bit like what a TV/monitor looks like when it loses a signal in those days, literally a crash that looks like snow) that affects hackers&amp;rsquo; brains in a certain way. I guess I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t spoil any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My one complaint would be the ending felt abrupt, although everything was wrapped up neatly, it all happened mostly outside the purview of our protagonists. I do like it more than Cryptonomicon, which was a later book of his (published in 1999). This one felt easier to grok.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>books</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389349579091365888/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 22:42:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389349579091365888/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bill Gates separating from his wife right after Queen Elizabeth becomes single again. Coincidence?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from tauriqmoosa https://twitter.com/tauriqmoosa/statuses/1388925076293181441/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389238548566462466/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 15:20:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389238548566462466/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from tauriqmoosa https://twitter.com/tauriqmoosa/statuses/1388925076293181441/:
            &lt;p&gt;Dan Harmon&amp;rsquo;s amazing writers&amp;rsquo; advice&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389238548566462466/1_1389238548566462466_E0Zz66LWYAI8vIs_hub27bd65599c5ab02d557d36b989baf8c_316475_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389225567749165057/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 14:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389225567749165057/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Iguana #sketchdaily 122/365&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will fully admit to being mildly freaked out by the scales both while drawing this and while looking at reference images of igaunas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my excuse for not drawing more of the iguana.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389225567749165057/1_1389225567749165057_E0eFSmmVoAIvAwT_hu596884b3d87d4a353498ea95643c4cfb_268256_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from Marvel https://twitter.com/Marvel/statuses/1389203088498585600/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389214746822385668/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 13:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389214746822385668/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from Marvel https://twitter.com/Marvel/statuses/1389203088498585600/:
            &lt;p&gt;The world may change and evolve, but the one thing that will never change: we’re all part of one big family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&#39;320&#39; height=&#39;134&#39; controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#39;https://video.twimg.com/amplify_video/1389188293955186690/vid/1280x536/17VMLRu8tRbH6gzH.mp4?tag=14&#39; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
    &lt;/video&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from onkeikun https://twitter.com/onkeikun/statuses/1387872032025628677/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389208741283733508/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 13:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389208741283733508/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from onkeikun https://twitter.com/onkeikun/statuses/1387872032025628677/:
            &lt;p&gt;that cold open from brooklyn99 but as a japanese dub lol (b99 is on ntflxJP)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&#39;320&#39; height=&#39;180&#39; controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#39;https://video.twimg.com/ext_tw_video/1387871862647050240/pu/vid/1280x720/55lzIiRCJRIYn97R.mp4?tag=12&#39; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
    &lt;/video&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389208170111799297/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 13:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389208170111799297/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Hashtag Pinoy Pride&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/paulg/status/1389172215099412483&#39;&gt;paulg&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    Over 6% of the plastic in the ocean comes from a single river in the Philippines.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389208170111799297/1_1389208170111799297_E0dUnswX0AEQMbB_hua6e100e632d735285fd27e50920d72ae_78917_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389201688112746501/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 12:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389201688112746501/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Harpy #sketchdaily 121/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389201688112746501/1_1389201688112746501_E0dvkm0VgAY4Jxl_hu2a4a803099adec83e999eb5b9a3418c9_198060_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389145956604686336/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 09:12:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389145956604686336/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Monday Strixhaven quick drafts! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt; #mtg #magicarena #twitch #twitter #mtgstrixhaven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did two quick drafts today, both were mediocre, but one was slightly better than the other. Probably one more QD stream this week before sealed open on the weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YT episode split into two because the stream hiccuped in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 1: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zSEJrwquasA&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zSEJrwquasA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 2: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2cFee-AHMZA&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2cFee-AHMZA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389145956604686336/E0daN0BVUAstXog_hua8e8727736b4dc51f6506f3589cff98f_231110_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1389145956604686336/E0daN0TVUAMcar7_hude784917087222a3811d85c1373d0d38_200785_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>twitch</category>
                        
            <category>twitter</category>
                        
            <category>mtgstrixhaven</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Digital Boardgames Review: Root
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/digital-boardgames-review-root/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 07:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/digital-boardgames-review-root/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been regularly playing digital boardgames online on Steam with one of my friend groups, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do reviews of them. This is my fourth such review, and this time I&amp;rsquo;m gonna talk about &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/965580/Root/&#34;&gt;Root&lt;/a&gt;. This is a IRL boardgame by Leder Games with the Steam version published by Dire Wolf Digital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Root is a competitive game themed about multiple factions vying for supremacy in a forest area. Each faction vies for control of clearings, draws cards that provide special abilities or items, and generally tries to stop the others from winning the game, which is done via points. The base game has four different factions to choose from (with the Vagabond faction having three different variants) and each faction plays very differently and scores points differently. So there is a bit of a learning curve to familiarize yourself with all the different factions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cats (Marquis) faction are the like the dominant empire in the area, and they gain points primarily by establishing more buildings, but among the factions they get the fewest actions per turn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The birds (Eyrie) represent an old empire trying to make a comeback; they score points primarily by establishing roosts but they follow a strict set of decrees that govern what they must do each turn. If they fail to obey the decrees, their government goes into turmoil, loses some points and has to start over with a new leader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Woodland Alliance represent plucky rebels aiming to establish their own government. They earn points by spreading sympathizers across the map. Whenever other factions attack them or move troops through sympathizer clearings, they earn more supporters, which can be used to establish bases (which let you recruit warriors) and gain even more supporters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, the Vagabond is a freelance adventurer, wandering around the land digging up treasure for ruins and trading for items. He gets stronger the more items he has, can score points by crafting new items, completing quests, or fighting other factions. He can lend his support or even ally with one of the factions for a coalition victory. The Vagabond has several variants that start with different item sets and each have a unique special action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recently released (on Steam anyway) Riverfolk expansion adds two more factions and three more Vagabond variants to the game, adding replay value and more variation to an already very varied game. Each game lasts around an hour or so, which is totally reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Root is without question the one my regular gaming group has spent the most time playing among the digital boardgames. Not only because it&amp;rsquo;s fun (and we love interfering with whatever the others are planning), but it mostly because it has a feature none of the other games we&amp;rsquo;ve tried have: asynchronous multiplayer games. That means we can start a game and take our turns even while the others are offline, and people can just come and take their turn as they please (within the limit of minimum one turn every three days).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means at the end of our weekly gaming sessions, no matter what we&amp;rsquo;ve played, we usually end with starting a new Root game, that we play throughout the following week. Sometimes we can get two or three games done during the duration of the week, finishing the last game when we start our next weekly gaming session. We&amp;rsquo;ve been playing the game almost continuously since the Steam release in September 2020 and the physical boardgame has at least two other expansions lined up that aren&amp;rsquo;t on Steam yet, so it&amp;rsquo;s very likely that we&amp;rsquo;ll continue to play it for many more months and perhaps years to come.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/digital-boardgames-review-root/20210206231830_1_hu82b45758b8fe844de805b2bef2797491_503727_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/digital-boardgames-review-root/20210314205428_1_hu0497b5492076e39329a70644844e53f6_440608_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/digital-boardgames-review-root/20210502005350_1_hu75c9a4d0330488ba854adfb56cb0a1b9_645229_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>gaming</category>
                        
            <category>games</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by Martin187465 on &#39;2017 Macbook Air has trouble charging&#39; on /r/applehelp at https://reddit.com/r/applehelp/comments/n33ad9/2017_macbook_air_has_trouble_charging/gwnhasx/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/gwnpfu2/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 13:13:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/gwnpfu2/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by Martin187465 on &amp;#39;2017 Macbook Air has trouble charging&amp;#39; on /r/applehelp at https://reddit.com/r/applehelp/comments/n33ad9/2017_macbook_air_has_trouble_charging/gwnhasx/:

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;  Hold the power button for 10 seconds and plug in the mag safe connector  while you keep holding down the power button for another 10 seconds at  least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was I supposed to do this while the laptop was off? because of course it started turning on in the middle of the first 10 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also tried it while the laptop was on, in which case it shutdown during the first 10 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, it does not seem to have changed anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;gt;  Have you thought about switching out the battery?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you mentioned, macbook airs dont have removable batteries. Also, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t the fact that I am sometimes able to charge it, depending on how I place the magsafe connector, imply the problem is with the connector or port and not the battery itself?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>applehelp</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by Martin187465 on &#39;2017 Macbook Air has trouble charging&#39; on /r/applehelp at https://reddit.com/r/applehelp/comments/n33ad9/2017_macbook_air_has_trouble_charging/gwn5r3u/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/gwngjmo/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 11:54:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/gwngjmo/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by Martin187465 on &amp;#39;2017 Macbook Air has trouble charging&amp;#39; on /r/applehelp at https://reddit.com/r/applehelp/comments/n33ad9/2017_macbook_air_has_trouble_charging/gwn5r3u/:

            &lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ve tried this before; unsure as I&amp;rsquo;ve had this problem for a while and have been looking around for solutions for a while. Regardless, I tried it again today a couple of times, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed anything.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>applehelp</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/n33ad9/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 10:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/n33ad9/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;h4 id=&#34;posted-on-rapplehelp-2017-macbook-air-has-trouble-charginghttpsredditcomrapplehelpcommentsn33ad92017_macbook_air_has_trouble_charging&#34;&gt;Posted on r/applehelp: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/applehelp/comments/n33ad9/2017_macbook_air_has_trouble_charging/&#34;&gt;2017 Macbook Air has trouble charging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a 2017 Macbook Air. This one still has the Magsafe charger. My problem with it is that connecting the charger to the device via the Magsafe port is super finicky, most of the time if I just plug it in straight, the device won&amp;rsquo;t charge (the battery status indicator will have the lightning bolt symbol, but if you click on it, the dropdown will say &amp;ldquo;not charging&amp;rdquo;) and the magsafe connector won&amp;rsquo;t light up (if it&amp;rsquo;s charging it will light up either red or green).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually I&amp;rsquo;m usually able to get it to charge. But it takes me some number of tries disconnecting and reconnecting the charger, turning the wire or the connector every which way trying to find the proper angle where it will charge. Sometimes it takes me hours or even days to be able to get it to charge again. Obviously not very practical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a problem with the charger itself; I&amp;rsquo;ve tried borrowing another working magsafe charger from someone else and the same problems arise. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried blowing into the connector ports or using toothpicks to clean out any dust, and still the situation persists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone else encountered this kind of issue? Any advice?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>applehelp</category>
                        
            <category>reddit_submission</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1388747508688424960/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 06:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1388747508688424960/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I’m at 2. Feels like this number would be significantly lowere here in the PH&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/pamelaapostolo1/status/1388584053666889736&#39;&gt;PamelaApostolo1&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;🏠 They say an average person lives in 11 homes in their lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s your number? (I’m currently at 8🤪)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>My current HTML boilerplate
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/my-current-html-boilerplate/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 04:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/my-current-html-boilerplate/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.matuzo.at/blog/html-boilerplate/&#34;&gt;My current HTML boilerplate&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2021-05-02
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/weeknotes-2021-05-02/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 04:21:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/weeknotes-2021-05-02/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s already May? April felt like it came and went so quickly. But then again, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1242953238497751040&#34;&gt;time has little meaning in this accursed pandemic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world&#34;&gt;The world:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The brouhaha over community pantries (as &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/weeknotes-2021-04-25/&#34;&gt;described last week&lt;/a&gt;), seems to have calmed down and they are now generally coordinating with LGUs for assistance in maintaining health protocols&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, the government has embarked on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387324164910981121/&#34;&gt;propaganda campaign to assert that we aren&amp;rsquo;t the worst in terms of pandemic response in the world&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certain congress people continue to promote the usage of the drug Ivermectin, which has no known effect on Covid-19, as a Covid-19 cure or something. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1388100027684331520/&#34;&gt;DOH/FDA keep saying there&amp;rsquo;s no sufficient evidence&lt;/a&gt;, but that has no effect when the people promoting it aren&amp;rsquo;t motivated by evidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looks like the Office of the Solicitor General of the Philippines &lt;a href=&#34;https://restofworld.org/2021/philippines-data-exposure/&#34;&gt;accidentally leaked a bunch of sensitive legal documents&lt;/a&gt; due to a misconfigured public directory on their web server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently last weekend was the Oscars, which just goes to show how irrelevant they are now that I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know until I saw the tweets about it happening live. They tried to re-arrange the awards with Best Actor last, apparently with the hope of ending with a posthumous award to Chadwick Boseman, but the award went to Anthony Hopkins instead, who wasn&amp;rsquo;t even at the ceremony. Awkward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-of-interest&#34;&gt;Links of interest:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/feb/16/how-to-have-better-arguments-social-media-politics-conflict&#34;&gt;How to have better arguments online&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I have this mentor. And one of the best pieces of advice that he gave me is ‘always give someone the golden gate of retreat’, which is: give someone enough compassion, enough opportunity in a conversation for them to look good changing their mind. And it’s a really important thing to be able to do, because if you’re just like, ‘Oh you said this thing! You’re racist!’, you’re forcing that person to say, ‘No I’m not’. Et cetera. There’s no golden gate of retreat there. The only retreat there is to just barrel right through the opposing opinion.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lichess.org/blog/YF-ZORQAACAA89PI/why-lichess-will-always-be-free.&#34;&gt;Why Lichess will always be free&lt;/a&gt;. I sometimes use their site (lichess.org) to play some quick rounds of chess, so this is good to know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://caitlinjohnstone.com/2021/04/20/how-to-live-in-wonder/&#34;&gt;How to live in wonder&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make a constant practice of getting curious about all of the aspects of your experience. Not with the intention of receiving any adult-mind narrative answers, but with the curiosity of a talking monkey who has no ability to understand the universe. &amp;hellip; By continually introducing the immediate experience of not-knowing to your operating system, you will undo the stale old perceptual and cognitive habits of the adult-mind that thinks it knows, that thinks it has seen it all, that it has seen any of this before. It’s a skill like any other, and as you improve with practice you will get better at meeting everything for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2021/04/how-yahoo-became-internet-villain/618681/&#34;&gt;Yahoo the Destroyer&lt;/a&gt;, on the once-great internet company not being great at preserving the content under its purview. I&amp;rsquo;m still bitter over &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/1048949973801267200/&#34;&gt;not being able to recover my Yahoo Messenger convos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drew DeVault writes about &lt;a href=&#34;https://drewdevault.com/2021/04/26/Cryptocurrency-is-a-disaster.html&#34;&gt;how cryptocurrency is an abject disaster&lt;/a&gt;. I was tempted to write about my own experiences working with crypto, but I worry that not enough time has passed for me to talk perhaps a bit unkindly about some of the companies I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manuel Matuzovic writes about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.matuzo.at/blog/html-boilerplate/&#34;&gt;his current HTML boilerplate&lt;/a&gt;, which at the very least is a good look at how many different tags and other things one needs to put in by default to support various modern web things including social media previews and such.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone shared to me this version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uyE80ebItlA&#34;&gt;Never Gonna Give You Up with Japanese lyrics&lt;/a&gt; that I enjoyed for some reason.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extremely satisfying: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/moylato/status/1387139670962843658&#34;&gt;Belgian man parks his car in a super narrow garage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found this &lt;a href=&#34;https://acesubido.net/ph-inflation-calculator/&#34;&gt;Philippines inflation calculator online&lt;/a&gt;. Prices have almost doubled from when I started working back in 2003!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-stuff&#34;&gt;My stuff:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For some reason all the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook/&#34;&gt;sketches&lt;/a&gt; for the past week were done with pen and paper on this tiny pad I keep near my desk. Much quicker to do, but the sketches are also much simpler than anything I do in Procreate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Movies: Caught &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/3bf3bc036db88610a1c7b3474555eb69/&#34;&gt;Green Hornet (2011)&lt;/a&gt; on cable, a movie I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know existed. I should resume my James Bond run soonish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watched the &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2021/05/99d3f5dffa9b1e1f2a4029f66c2b4f2a/&#34;&gt;second season of Jack Ryan&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2021/04/183ab94b6cb10f5db0431e715cde1945/&#34;&gt;finished up season 1 of Invincible&lt;/a&gt;, both on Prime Video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Been drafting a bit more &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgstrixhaven/&#34;&gt;Strixhaven&lt;/a&gt; on Arena. I thought the Sealed Open was this weekend, but turns out it was actually next week. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably shift to Quick Drafts next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played a bunch of &lt;strong&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;/strong&gt; on PS4 already after it dropped for free last week. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t a big fan of the intro sequence, but I&amp;rsquo;ve warmed up to it as the story and the world gradually opened up. I can tell this will take a while to finish though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played a bit of Street Fighter V again this week, though I&amp;rsquo;m still languishing in the Bronze ranks again. Have tried shifting to Balrog (Boxer) as my main, though I&amp;rsquo;m not super familiar with the combos and matchups. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My regular Saturday gaming group immediately picked up the &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1586100/Root_The_Riverfolk_Expansion/&#34;&gt;new Riverfolk expansion for Root&lt;/a&gt; when it dropped last week and we had a lot of fun with some of the creepy new additions last night. And I really should get on with that Root review!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;: I am close to finishing &lt;strong&gt;Snow Crash&lt;/strong&gt; by Neal Stephenson, should be done this week, hopefully have time to write the review as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trivia: Didn&amp;rsquo;t do too well in this week&amp;rsquo;s About Quiz, so we ended up in a distant finish in the league overall. No trivia next week!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-coming-week&#34;&gt;This coming week:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No new One Piece, BNHA, etc, I assume due to Golden Week. Boo!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strixhaven Sealed Open on Arena next week, for real this time!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting my second shot of Sinovac next Sunday!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was a bit rushed, so typos etc are a feature, not a bug.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>philippines</category>
                        
            <category>covid19</category>
                        
            <category>weeknotes</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1388467632651730945/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 12:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1388467632651730945/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Green goblin #sketchdaily 120/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1388467632651730945/1_1388467632651730945_E0TT875UcAIPN9D_hu48035d196f07e5f1088a90c3140db690_144031_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/99d3f5dffa9b1e1f2a4029f66c2b4f2a/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 12:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/99d3f5dffa9b1e1f2a4029f66c2b4f2a/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I binged season 2 of Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s Jack Ryan this week (after watching season 1 back in 2018!). This season felt tighter than the first in terms of pacing and such.&lt;!--sep--&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m not happy with the way it promotes American interventionism and their easy willingness to interfere in the affairs of a sovereign nation (however justified it may be)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>tv</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1388463736625803265/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 12:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1388463736625803265/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Rich uncle pennybags #sketchdaily 119/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1388463736625803265/1_1388463736625803265_E0TQaKAUYAIbQkp_hub018d3253d4a80cfc991b348de580578_172004_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1388424945730981890/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 09:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1388424945730981890/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Saturday Strixhaven quick drafts! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt; #mtg #magicarena #twitch #mtgstrixhaven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rare-drafted a bunch (I think 6 in the deck and 4 in the board), but still got a decent enough deck. Didn&amp;rsquo;t perform well though, had some bad keeps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YT: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zj5__bJDpkY&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zj5__bJDpkY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1388424945730981890/E0S7slEVIAgGLXP_hu1bdfe13543746cf2a055725edac3d248_133915_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>twitch</category>
                        
            <category>mtgstrixhaven</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to wrongwaygoback&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/wrongwaygoback/statuses/1388357756843806721/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1388391582605316096/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 07:15:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1388391582605316096/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to wrongwaygoback&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/wrongwaygoback/statuses/1388357756843806721/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wrongwaygoback/&#34;&gt;@wrongwaygoback&lt;/a&gt; how are the bots in quick draft?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/183ab94b6cb10f5db0431e715cde1945/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 13:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/183ab94b6cb10f5db0431e715cde1945/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Invincible season 1 finale was pretty great, the fight was intense and afterwards I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe there was still half an episode to go. It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I read the books so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure, but I think they diverged a bit from the source material, but it&amp;rsquo;s fine.&lt;!--sep--&gt;The series was developed well enough, decent pacing and enough to portray the major characters well. Looking forward to season 2!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>tv</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1388100027684331520/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 11:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1388100027684331520/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Phrases like &amp;ldquo;insufficient evidence&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;no proof&amp;rdquo; does nothing to dissuade people whose arguments are along the lines of &amp;ldquo;it can&amp;rsquo;t hurt to try&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;maybe it will help&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/reportrdotworld/status/1388063075199225856&#39;&gt;reportrdotworld&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The DOH and FDA reminded the public that they do not recommend the use of Ivermectin to treat #COVID19 due to insufficient scientific evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reportr.world/news/doh-fda-do-not-recommend-ivermectin-for-covid-a4736-20210430?utm_source=Twitter-reportr&amp;amp;utm_medium=Ownshare&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20210430-twnp-news-doh-fda-do-not-recommend-ivermectin-for-covid-a4736-20210430-twfirst&#34;&gt;https://www.reportr.world/news/doh-fda-do-not-recommend-ivermectin-for-covid-a4736-20210430?utm_source=Twitter-reportr&amp;amp;utm_medium=Ownshare&amp;amp;utm_campaign=20210430-twnp-news-doh-fda-do-not-recommend-ivermectin-for-covid-a4736-20210430-twfirst&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drug actively harming people would be more effective but the disadvantage of relying on science is that we can&amp;rsquo;t just make claims like that without evidence.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>covid19</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1388058552070201344/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 09:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1388058552070201344/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Friday afternoon Strixhaven draft! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt; #mtg #magicarena #twitch #mtgstrixhaven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I drafted a couple of decent yet average decks, but didn&amp;rsquo;t perform too well, had a couple of bad draws. A poor end to my Strixhaven premiere draft run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YT: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wIHO8W9uuAY&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wIHO8W9uuAY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1388058552070201344/E0N6pf4VEAI-pFa_huf0ab941f00eed1521f09a11582b672c1_204620_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1388058552070201344/E0N6pg7VcAEPEtx_hu94c02e60b90fd513960048c295591a56_254350_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>twitch</category>
                        
            <category>mtgstrixhaven</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387897882141880321/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 22:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387897882141880321/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/talk2GLOBE/&#34;&gt;@talk2GLOBE&lt;/a&gt; i have a question about my account, can i dm you&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387740912625750017/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 12:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387740912625750017/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Chef&amp;rsquo;s kiss #sketchdaily 118/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387740912625750017/1_1387740912625750017_E0I_ARdVUAE31LM_hue448222b295f357bd9c945e784a2a1c7_200905_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>How to have better arguments online
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/how-to-have-better-arguments-online/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 08:34:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/how-to-have-better-arguments-online/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/society/2021/feb/16/how-to-have-better-arguments-social-media-politics-conflict&#34;&gt;How to have better arguments online&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Why Lichess will always be free.
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/why-lichess-will-always-be-free/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 08:34:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/why-lichess-will-always-be-free/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://lichess.org/blog/YF-ZORQAACAA89PI/why-lichess-will-always-be-free.&#34;&gt;Why Lichess will always be free.&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/3bf3bc036db88610a1c7b3474555eb69/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 07:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/3bf3bc036db88610a1c7b3474555eb69/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Last night I accidentally watched most of the latter part of Green Hornet (2011) starring Seth Rogen. I never new he portrayed this character! Movie was reasonable popcorn action-comedy.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>movies</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to joshagarrado&#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/joshagarrado/statuses/1380033043222519812/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387622193379430401/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 04:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387622193379430401/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to joshagarrado&amp;#39;s tweet at https://twitter.com/joshagarrado/statuses/1380033043222519812/:

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/joshagarrado/&#34;&gt;@joshagarrado&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/talk2GLOBE/&#34;&gt;@talk2GLOBE&lt;/a&gt; Hi Josh! It&amp;rsquo;s you! Lol sorry, for some reason Twitter never gave me a notif for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently the bundle is part of the normal package I got when I signed up for my plan, except the first 24mo were free. So when the 24mo were up, they automatically charge me for it.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>How To Live In Wonder
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/how-to-live-in-wonder/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/how-to-live-in-wonder/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://caitlinjohnstone.com/2021/04/20/how-to-live-in-wonder/&#34;&gt;How To Live In Wonder&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387385600119037953/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 12:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387385600119037953/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Robocop #sketchdaily 117/365&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is terrible lol. Also I already had to redo it once because I didnt realize at first that the visor covers his nose&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387385600119037953/1_1387385600119037953_E0D72WdVIAUK7mQ_hu2571d31db4a5b1c3168ff96ecfd3859a_133011_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from moylato https://twitter.com/moylato/statuses/1387139670962843658/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387371248435417090/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 11:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387371248435417090/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from moylato https://twitter.com/moylato/statuses/1387139670962843658/:
            &lt;p&gt;Belgian man parks in garage 6cm wider than his car&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&#39;320&#39; height=&#39;180&#39; controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#39;https://video.twimg.com/ext_tw_video/1387139144850231299/pu/vid/1280x720/drAidN3TPITBA92C.mp4?tag=12&#39; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
    &lt;/video&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387324164910981121/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 08:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387324164910981121/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;OPLAN: WE&amp;rsquo;RE NOT THE WORST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/PhilstarNews/status/1387318318252445701&#39;&gt;PhilstarNews&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    JUST IN: PCOO News and Information Bureau head Virginia Arcilla-Agtay confirms that there is a memo directing them to give updates on global data on the pandemic to show that the Philippines is doing better than other countries. | via &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/XaveGregorio/&#34;&gt;@XaveGregorio&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OPLAN LOWER STANDARDS&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387324164910981121/1_1387324164910981121_E0C-oyJVoAEHXPG_hu2ceefd0940fa9c50bece2480a0c31944_46176_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387316978612948998/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 08:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387316978612948998/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Throwing away gems on Strixhaven draft(s?)! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt; #mtg #magicarena #twitch #mtgstrixhaven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet was weird today so stream was on and off. Probably won&amp;rsquo;t have the full episode on YT (maybe just the last few matches). But spoiler alert: I was able to break my unlucky streak with some Quandrix + Prismari goodness!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I was able to record the draft itself locally, so this draft has two videos. In order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 1 (draft): &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=skUg-kWzq_g&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=skUg-kWzq_g&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part 2 (last few matches): &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7SuXcPVm0YQ&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7SuXcPVm0YQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387316978612948998/E0DXqAnVIAIiXjV_hub7577e3938627710fb206d8a6066a4c0_194075_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>twitch</category>
                        
            <category>mtgstrixhaven</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Math and Privilege
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/math-and-privilege/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 06:09:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/math-and-privilege/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://noahpinion.substack.com/p/someone-has-to-run-the-fabs&#34;&gt;a recent STEM-focused newsletter&lt;/a&gt;, Noahpinion talked a bit about the myth of math being an inborn ability:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again and again, we have seen the following pattern repeat itself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different kids with different levels of preparation come into a math class. Some of these kids have parents who have drilled them on math from a young age, while others never had that kind of parental input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the first few tests, the well-prepared kids get perfect scores, while the unprepared kids get only what they could figure out by winging it—maybe 80 or 85%, a solid B.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unprepared kids, not realizing that the top scorers were well-prepared, assume that genetic ability was what determined the performance differences. Deciding that they “just aren’t math people,” they don’t try hard in future classes, and fall further behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The well-prepared kids, not realizing that the B students were simply unprepared, assume that they are “math people,” and work hard in the future, cementing their advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, people’s belief that math ability can’t change becomes a self-fulfilling prophecy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I touched upon this in passing in a post last week about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/programming-is-hard/&#34;&gt;programming being hard&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people may make it look easy, because they may have a bit more aptitude than others (due to background or whatever), in the same way that some people find math easy and others find it nearly impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about this after a convo with some friends where they mentioned they were teaching their kids to play &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtg&#34;&gt;Magic&lt;/a&gt; at a young age, since it helps them practice simple arithmetic. It seems like a simple thing, but that kind of thing contributes towards the kids being &amp;ldquo;prepared&amp;rdquo; for a better math education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad also made a comment last week about how when we were young they (our parents) would often be bringing home activity books for us. Basically books with number puzzles, crossword puzzles, logic puzzles, that kind of thing. I loved those activity books! Among other things, I&amp;rsquo;m sure that contributed to my love of math and problem solving, which often appears as &amp;ldquo;natural aptitude&amp;rdquo; to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a form of privilege: parents having the time and energy and know-how to instill additional knowledge in their kid from a young age. I can&amp;rsquo;t expect poor to lower-class people who work hard all day and are tired at night to be able to do that. So less privileged kids tend to grow up thinking they are bad at math, and they have trouble teaching their kids, and the vicious cycle perpetuates itself and inequality grows in succeeding generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During lunchtime on weekdays, I often find myself watching reruns of a certain local quiz show shown on cable TV, and I find myself alternating between laughter and frustration whenever one of the contestants fail a simple math question. Things like &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s the decimal equivalent of 3 and a half percent&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s 75% of 200&amp;rdquo; - questions I&amp;rsquo;d expect any elementary school graduate should be able to do. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to shake your head and blame the poor education system in this country - which is certainly a factor, but I can&amp;rsquo;t help but consider how this kind of inequality, compounding across generations, also contributes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you do? Adults who grew up without this privilege often think their case is hopeless. &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mahina lang talaga ako sa math&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; (&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m just really bad at math&amp;rdquo;), people often lament, as if it were some innate ability that they were not fortunate enough to acquire at character creation. And even if they wanted to get better at math, most will not have the time or energy to do so, due to daily life struggles. I would guess at some level it&amp;rsquo;s also a bit harder for such adults to re-learn math as their brains have already been wired not to think that way. It&amp;rsquo;s probably not an insurmountable handicap like a physical injury, but it can be challenging nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just rambling. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a point, nor a solution. I don&amp;rsquo;t know where this post was going.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387152469197692932/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 21:11:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387152469197692932/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I got this PM on discord. I like how he opens with &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a fraudster&amp;rdquo;, then immediately asserts his reputation&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387152469197692932/1_1387152469197692932_E0AntCCVgAMJ_8r_hud4b451ff4ed9e5a469621a49d084c1cd_52154_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387006717796315136/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 11:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387006717796315136/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This looks like a job for&amp;hellip; #sketchdaily 116/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1387006717796315136/1_1387006717796315136_Ez-jQiXVgAUtYHl_huc29194924914f48c4ed6700d2c361b5f_159307_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Ludum Dare 48: Diver
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/ludum-dare-48-diver/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 05:49:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/ludum-dare-48-diver/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;h3 id=&#34;the-jam&#34;&gt;The jam&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A thing I did last weekend was to participate in &lt;a href=&#34;https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/48&#34;&gt;the 48th LUDUM DARE game jam&lt;/a&gt;. Doing gamedev has been a long-time elusive dream of mine, all the way back to my college years. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a number of failed attempts to get into gamedev, both solo and with other people.I&amp;rsquo;ve also played around with things like PyGame, &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2017/01/10155238560218912/&#34;&gt;Unity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2020/11/1326919888472956928/&#34;&gt;DragonRuby&lt;/a&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read about the LD48 game jam this April and signed up to participate. My expectations weren&amp;rsquo;t very high and I was anxious going on; I was pretty sure I was not going to do well and doubted I could even put things together. I had never done a Ludum Dare or a game jam before, heck I haven&amp;rsquo;t even made anything I consider a &amp;ldquo;real game&amp;rdquo; before!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game jam has two modes you can choose to submit to. The 72-hour version (called the &amp;ldquo;Jam&amp;rdquo;) was easier, as you could have a team of people working together, and you could use any assets you had legal access to. The 48-hour version, called the &amp;ldquo;Compo&amp;rdquo; (which I guess is short for competitive?), is much more challenging. You can only work solo, and all assets must be created within the 48 hour period (with a few exceptions like fonts etc).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no intention of working with a team; in fact I didn&amp;rsquo;t tell anyone I planned to participate until after the jam started last Saturday at 9AM local time. I figured I would try my best and if I finished within 48h, I would submit for the jam. If I didn&amp;rsquo;t, I had an extra 24h to try for the compo, and I could even ask for help!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That meant I would be working alone, which meant I would have to do things like art and sounds and music! I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any experience doing pixel art for games or anything like that, so I figured I could get by on &amp;ldquo;programmer art&amp;rdquo;. For sound effects, I knew there were online generators I could use, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried some before. Background music was the real challenge: I have no musical talent at all, so even if I could find tools to do it, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know how to put anything together. These were problems for me 48h into the future though. When the jam started, I just dove in to code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, not really. I woke up late and had to do some errands so I missed the start time by a couple of hours. Still, I dove right in as soon as I was free!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-tools&#34;&gt;The tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the gamedev/programming part, I decided to use the Godot Engine game development framework. I had been trying it out since earlier this year, and I was pretty happy with it compared to Unity. The IDE was a lot lighter, the APIs felt more intuitive, and basically it made it easier for me to get into the guts of a game. Unity is great, but it always seemed geared towards 3D gamedev. Godot makes 2D gamedev feel like a first class citizen. I prefer working on 2D because I feel like that&amp;rsquo;s something more achieveable for me as an indie. Doing sprites and such is more in my wheelhouse than 3D models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the art, I&amp;rsquo;ve never tried any pixel art creation tools before, so I just searched online. I settled on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.piskelapp.com&#34;&gt;Piskel&lt;/a&gt; which had the advantages of (a) being free; and (b) running entirely in-browser, without needing me to create an account. Very low friction! I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried such tools before so I was impressed with how mature they were. There were functions similar to what you&amp;rsquo;d find in paint, plus support for layers and export to various formats, including into spritesheets. It was perfect for what I needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For sound effects, I used another free online site &lt;a href=&#34;https://sfxr.me/&#34;&gt;JSFXR&lt;/a&gt;. Basically just kept rolling one of the settings until I got a sound I like. Godot&amp;rsquo;s AudioStreamPlayer didn&amp;rsquo;t seem like it accepted WAVs, so I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://convertio.co/wav-ogg/&#34;&gt;convert.io&lt;/a&gt; to convert the files to OGG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For background music, a friend suggested I tried &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinesequencer.net/&#34;&gt;Online Sequencer&lt;/a&gt;. I tried it out for a while, banging out random notes since I knew nothing about how to compose music. I looked at a few interesting ones created by other people and tried to adjust the random notes I was banging out to better follow the patterns I saw. I still don&amp;rsquo;t understand, but I was able to create a couple of tracks I was fairly happy with (they sounded like music!) which I used as BGM in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also used one of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/sketchdaily&#34;&gt;sketchdaily&lt;/a&gt; attempts to generate some &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2021/04/1385956018509664263/&#34;&gt;splash screen/cover art&lt;/a&gt; for the game. The final game used a slightly cleaned up and modified version of that one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also needed a Dynamic font, since using Godot&amp;rsquo;s built-in fonts didn&amp;rsquo;t allow me to resize text. The Compo rules allow you to use fonts you didn&amp;rsquo;t make during the jam, so I just used Xolonium-Regular from one of the Godot tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-game&#34;&gt;The game&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme of the jam was &lt;strong&gt;DEEPER and DEEPER&lt;/strong&gt;, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d go the easy route and do something with digging or undersea exploration. I felt like digging would be the more common approach, so I went the other way, since I&amp;rsquo;m a contrarian. I decided to do something inspired by things like the underwater level in TMNT (NES) or the underwater level in Earthworm Jim (SNES). These were the frustrating underwater levels I grew up with, so I wanted to replicate that experience a bit. Basically moving around underwater, with a time limit and trying to avoid obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the idea was to have a deep-sea diver exploring underwater. But for some reason the ocean is full of spikes, so he has to keep moving and swimming to avoid them. All the while trying to go deeper and deeper. I added in a few enemies like jellyfish that acted as moving obstacles, and seeker fish that actively tried to chase you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also added an oxygen tank mechanic to serve as the timer. The tank would be getting depleted constantly as you kept breathing and you had to avoid running out. There would be little things that generate air bubbles you can pick up to increase your oxygen level (this part was inspired by the 3d mario games). Initially the bubble generator was just a jar, but later I changed the sprite to a clam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also decided to add a collectible in the form of gems that you can pick up on your way down. Basically to add more things to do in each stage. And it added a bit of risk-reward mechanics: should I waste time trying to get this gem, when I might run out of air or get hit by enemies? When I added it I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how the gems would be relevant in the game. I eventually decided to have the player earn extra lives whenever he collects 5 gems. The initial gem sprite was a diamond but later changed to a pearl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the basic gameplay: Avoid obstacles, collect gems, avoid running out of air, try to get as deep as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The controls were simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;your diver is constantly sinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can move left or right using arrow keys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can swim up (or bounce, in my internal terms) by pressing space bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bounce was kind of a flappy bird bounce: you hit spacebar and you go up by a fixed amount after which you begin sinking again. I wanted the controls to be not too smooth so that you needed to know the bounce distance really well to navigate tighter corridors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I had something basic working, I showed it to some friends to get some feedback, and got some good ideas and bug reports from them. (I figured showing it to other people and getting suggestions was fine within the compo rules, as long as I did all the actual creation work myself!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of Saturday (around 16h after jam start, 32h before compo deadline), I was mostly done with all the mechanics and gameplay and such. But content was lacking: I only had five screens (&amp;ldquo;stages&amp;rdquo;) for the player to navigate through, which I felt was too short. Creating levels was fairly straightforward though once I had all the components ready. The feedback from my friends was also pretty good. By this point I was fairly confident I could finish in time, and probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t lose too much sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent Sunday working more on the game, in between a bunch of family errands. I added another five levels, and fixed a lot of bugs. By the end of day Sunday (around 9h before compo deadline), I was ready to submit. Godot lets me export both to web and to Windows binaries. I could have also exported to other OSes, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to test them. I was originally planning to host the game here on this site, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t decide how / where to put them in the site structure. Instead I went ahead and deployed the game to itch.io, as I already had an account there. This was a relatively easy and straightforward process (though I did have to answer some tax-related questions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the game is here on itch.io: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hungryroy.itch.io/diver&#34;&gt;https://hungryroy.itch.io/diver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ludum Dare requires the source code be made available, I have it up here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roytang/diver&#34;&gt;https://github.com/roytang/diver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, the page for my entry on the Ludum Dare site itself: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/48/diver&#34;&gt;https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/48/diver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aftermath&#34;&gt;Aftermath&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After submitting your game, you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to review and rate other people&amp;rsquo;s games, and you want to earn at least 20 ratings to get a &amp;ldquo;final score&amp;rdquo;. Coming in, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really aim to &amp;ldquo;win&amp;rdquo; the compo or anything like that, I just wanted to finish a game. But after submitting and checking out a few of the other submissions, I felt a bit more confident about my chances and am hoping for a decent finish. The &amp;ldquo;play, review, and rate&amp;rdquo; period lasts for 21 days after the jam ends, so it&amp;rsquo;ll be a while before I know the outcome of that! I am doing my part by playing through some of the entries and rating them and leaving helpful comments where I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, very impressed with how Ludum Dare works. The more ratings and quality feedback you give, the higher your game appears in the listings. This makes it more likely for you to receive ratings and feedback yourself, thus incentivizing the same and creating a positive feedback loop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest takeaway is that I learned how to build something with as small a scope as possible. In many of my past attempts, scope creep was always one of the bigger problems. I was used to playing big, epic games like grand strategy or long RPGs or open world games, so I often wanted to make games like those. The 48h limit helped me narrow my focus and reject stuff that would endanger that deadline. I had to discard some other ideas for enemies and stage elements because they would make things more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did enjoy the experience, no matter the outcome, I&amp;rsquo;ve already exceeded my own expectations. I expect to try my hand at game jams again moving forward. Building experience by making a series of small games might be a better way for me to find a path into &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; gamedev. That is, as opposed to &amp;ldquo;hobbyist&amp;rdquo; gamedev, which is the new level I consider myself at now that I&amp;rsquo;ve completed a Ludum Dare!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some screenshots of the game attached below!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/ludum-dare-48-diver/screen1_hu1ab9d90fcbe1b19cf3b3c266fb8605d9_88625_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/ludum-dare-48-diver/screen2_hu146bf70b25f0bdea8bc681809150f5c8_94323_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/ludum-dare-48-diver/screen3_hucc0d53084f7630bbd423b0d1b8233330_88341_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>gamedev</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Yahoo, the Destroyer
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/yahoo-the-destroyer/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 19:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/yahoo-the-destroyer/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2021/04/how-yahoo-became-internet-villain/618681/&#34;&gt;Yahoo, the Destroyer&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Cryptocurrency is an abject disaster
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/cryptocurrency-is-an-abject-disaster/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 19:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/cryptocurrency-is-an-abject-disaster/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://drewdevault.com/2021/04/26/Cryptocurrency-is-a-disaster.html&#34;&gt;Cryptocurrency is an abject disaster&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Falcon and the Winter Soldier Review
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier-review/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/the-falcon-and-the-winter-soldier-review/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Falcon and Winter Soldier review (with some spoilers):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more action-packed and straightforward compared to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/wandavision/&#34;&gt;Wandavision&lt;/a&gt;, jumping straight into the action from the get go&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some great performances here, especially from Sebastian Stan (Bucky), Wyatt Russell (John Walker), and Daniel Bruhl (Zemo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bucky and Sam have great chemistry, even though they start out annoyed at each other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pacing is a bit odd at times; feels more like an extended movie than a weekly episodic series (especially compared to Wandavision, which took advantage of the weekly format really well)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;although a complete story by itself, this one felt more of a setup for future MCU storylines (again compared to Wandavision)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;while overall the season was good, I find Wandavision was the clearly better watch for me, though I suppose your mileage may vary if your preference is for action sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ending spoilers follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I felt like so much of the finale was rushed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final confrontation and resolution with the Flag Smashers felt flat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wyatt Russell sudden redemption felt undeserved - we go from stripped of position to fighting buddies with Bucky very quickly; would have liked to see him publicly address Sam as Cap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power Broker reveal was underwhelming; would have preferred it was done via a post-credits scene, possibly via Sharon telling someone about how she had to kill Batroc because he was threatening to expose her (presumably the earlier confrontation would have been cut to omit the reveal). Overall, I would have hidden the secret more (it was really obvious), so that the reveal at the end would have had a better impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish Bucky&amp;rsquo;s redemption arc had played a stronger part in the finale, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Felt like they could have extended an episode or two to at least make some of these things more impactful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next: Loki in June!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>tv</category>
                        
            <category>comicbooks</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386714197065572353/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 16:10:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386714197065572353/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Quick #sketchdaily catchup&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shocked pikachu: 113/365&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bald eagle: 114/365&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cabbage: 115/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386714197065572353/1_1386714197065572353_Ez6ZMcYVUAI5z_Q_hu97ad4f5d5a13ad62b4f645a53e6c83ea_125895_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386714197065572353/2_1386714197065572353_Ez6ZM9tVIAEzQBC_hu43802b90c0096c3385c7e58ebcc13f8f_162420_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386714197065572353/3_1386714197065572353_Ez6ZNl8UUAAwH11_hu5c73eb6fd73d965169c0f772831d0820_200504_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386589537825136641/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 07:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386589537825136641/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Thursday afternoon Strixhaven draft(s?)! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt; #mtg #magicarena #twitch #mtgstrixhaven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two poor drafts again today. I might be hitting a ceiling now that I&amp;rsquo;ve ranked back up into Platinum D:. Have to do better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t even rare draft this time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YT: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kgwy4bEulbs&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kgwy4bEulbs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386589537825136641/Ez5Dam2VEAIofH2_hu516fa6495ddb9c6747bfabdc6ef4b577_142535_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386589537825136641/Ez5DaoaVoAc6J9m_hu345cb9d11f9369a5ec86049edb991f8b_148868_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>mtg</category>
                        
            <category>magicarena</category>
                        
            <category>twitch</category>
                        
            <category>mtgstrixhaven</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386506858328780802/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 02:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386506858328780802/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Is there an #Oscars broadcast on skycable somewhere?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
                        
            <category>Oscars</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2021-04-25: Game Jammin&#39;
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/weeknotes-2021-04-25/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 14:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/weeknotes-2021-04-25/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bit busy this weekend (see below), so this post is running a bit late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world&#34;&gt;The world:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An ongoing saga right here in the Philippines:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last weekend, community pantries for the needy started sprouting up in Metro Manila and all over the country, largely inspired by one started in Maginhawa here in Quezon City. The central idea was &amp;ldquo;give what you can, take what you need.&amp;rdquo; Stories spread of heartwarming stories like a poor old man donating some food even though he had very little and an ice cream vendor giving away the remnants of his cart for the day to those in the queue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government critics pointed out the need for these pantries was largely a result of the lack of support from the government. (They&amp;rsquo;re not wrong.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predictably, it didn&amp;rsquo;t take long for the government to butt in, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/1384280033351462912&#34;&gt;the police reportedly investigating the people behind the pantries for communist links&lt;/a&gt;. Some other national government people even said they might require permits. For what, giving food away?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The backlash was predictably quick, with netizens and even local government offcials and senators castigating the critics. Mayors started chiming in that the community pantries were welcome in their cities and that there was no permit required to help each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, notable spokespersons of the NTF-ELCAC still insisted on insinuating communist links to the pantries. There were also the usual critics who decried people getting stuff for free, speaking from the privilege of their safe houses and expensive cars. Critics also raised whether these pantries were spreading covid because of how people spend a lot of time queued up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some women in Pasig went viral for a bit after they were caught on video raiding a community pantry and getting much more than could be reasonably expected, one of them even carting off a trayful of eggs. They supposedly claimed they were going to give away to their neighbors. They later &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.msn.com/en-ph/entertainment/other/mga-babaeng-nanlimas-sa-community-pantry-sa-pasig-dumepensa-na/ar-BB1fUtan&#34;&gt;apologized&lt;/a&gt;, but supposedly they &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/news5ph/status/1384855185932042241&#34;&gt;were planning to file charges against the person who took a video of them&lt;/a&gt;. My take: the thing about decentralized movements like this is that they tend to easily self-correct through the vigilance of the participants as seen here. There have been no other reports of similar incidents after this one went viral, so at the very least they served as an example of what not to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last Friday, a community pantry started by actress Angel Locsin ended in disaster when an old man died while in the queue. Blowback from the pantry critics and the DDS was fierce. Locsin &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gmanetwork.com/entertainment/showbiznews/news/76345/angel-locsin-issues-apology-after-senior-citizen-dies-in-line-at-her-community-pantry/story&#34;&gt;quickly issued an apology&lt;/a&gt; and accepted the blame, drawing contrasts with how the national government never apologizes or admits to mistakes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recently, news broke that the National Security Adviser &lt;a href=&#34;https://onenews.ph/gag-order-imposed-on-parlade-badoy&#34;&gt;had imposed a gag order on the notorious NTF-ELCAC spokespersons re: community pantries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probably one of the reasons we can&amp;rsquo;t have nice things: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/LaTtEX/status/1384416859701792771&#34;&gt;people can&amp;rsquo;t be generous without some other people becoming suspicious and assigning nefarious motives&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;ll see what happens with these pantries moving forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of covid, India&amp;rsquo;s experiencing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-india-56798248&#34;&gt;worst surge of the pandemic so far&lt;/a&gt;. Twitter has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://mashable.com/article/twitter-hides-tweets-critical-indian-government-handling-covid/&#34;&gt;accused of censoring tweets critical of the Indian government&amp;rsquo;s covid response&lt;/a&gt;. The US is facing calls to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/apr/25/us-pressed-to-lift-export-ban-to-help-india-fight-surge-in-covid-cases?CMP=twt_gu#Echobox=1619342451&#34;&gt;loosen export bans&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/apr/24/covid-vaccines-patents-pharmaceutical-companies-secrecy&#34;&gt;lighten up on vaccine patents&lt;/a&gt; to help out India (and the rest of us in the global south, really).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some lighter news: One year ago in Apr 24 2020, an epic battle among a ton of people named Josh was scheduled a year in advance, to fight for the name. It &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/gothspiderbitch/status/1386031209457852418&#34;&gt;happened yesterday&lt;/a&gt;! They had a pool noodle battle and named a 5 year old &amp;ldquo;King Josh&amp;rdquo; or some such. Lots of fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-of-interest&#34;&gt;Links of interest:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Messaging app Signal, famous for its encryption protections, raised concerns about vulnerabilities in software often used by authoritarian regimes to bypass the security of such apps: &lt;a href=&#34;https://signal.org/blog/cellebrite-vulnerabilities/&#34;&gt;Exploiting vulnerabilities in Cellebrite UFED and Physical Analyzer from an app&amp;rsquo;s perspective&lt;/a&gt;. The great thing is how the report does a hilarious &amp;ldquo;wink wink nudge nudge&amp;rdquo; implying the users of such apps might not want to target Signal in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some stuff about blogging and personal websites:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://matthiasott.com/notes/no-wrong-notes&#34;&gt;No wrong notes.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kottke.org/21/04/the-conversation-has-never-been-wider&#34;&gt;The conversation has never been wider.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://disquiet.com/2021/04/10/q-why-blog-a-blogs-are-great/&#34;&gt;Why blog? Blogs are great.&lt;/a&gt;. (I mostly disagree with &amp;ldquo;have a topic focus&amp;rdquo; though. I&amp;rsquo;ll write what I want to write, damnit!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gq.com/story/get-fit-from-just-walking&#34;&gt;How fit can you get from just walking?&lt;/a&gt; One of the tragedies of the pandemic is that I&amp;rsquo;ve had to reduce my general walking output, since I can&amp;rsquo;t just wander around as far as I want anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kottke.org/21/04/make-everything-important&#34;&gt;Mads Mikkelsen: &amp;ldquo;Make everything important.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://blolook.osa-p.net/&#34;&gt;page / app you can check&lt;/a&gt; to see how many people have blocked you on Twitter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;did-you-know&#34;&gt;Did you know:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the Spanish dub of Terminator 2, instead of &amp;ldquo;Hasta la vista, baby&amp;rdquo;, the Terminator says &amp;ldquo;Sayonara, baby!&amp;rdquo; via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/movies/comments/mwv4nd/fun_fact_in_the_spanish_dub_of_terminator_2_he/&#34;&gt;reddit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jack Black&amp;rsquo;s parents were &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/todayilearned/comments/mxsdzu/til_judith_love_cohen_who_helped_create_the/&#34;&gt;satellite engineers&lt;/a&gt;. (This entry spoils the ending of that entry, sorry!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local liturgical song Tanging Yaman, often attributed to Carol Banawa, was actually &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.abs-cbn.com/entertainment/04/03/21/behind-the-music-tanging-yaman-by-fr-manoling-francisco&#34;&gt;first recorded by now-Senator Risa Hontiveros&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-stuff&#34;&gt;My stuff:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The big thing for me this week (that I hinted at in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/weeknotes-2021-04-18/&#34;&gt;the previous weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;) is that I decided to give &lt;a href=&#34;https://ldjam.com/events/ludum-dare/48&#34;&gt;LUDUM DARE 48&lt;/a&gt; a shot! It&amp;rsquo;s a game jam, where you make a game in 48 hours (well, that&amp;rsquo;s the mode I&amp;rsquo;m participating in). Tt&amp;rsquo;s the first time I&amp;rsquo;m doing one, despite a lifetime of flirting with the idea of gamedev. Initial build is &lt;a href=&#34;https://hungryroy.itch.io/diver&#34;&gt;already available&lt;/a&gt;, even though there&amp;rsquo;s still 9ish hours to go. (I need to sleep!) I&amp;rsquo;ll probably (should) write more about this experience in a future post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Around the middle of this week, I got the first ever email that actually complied with &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/about/contact/&#34;&gt;the contact protocol I had specified here in the site&lt;/a&gt; and on LinkedIn, namely putting a certain keyword in the subject line. I&amp;rsquo;ve had that condition for years, so I was really amazed someone actually read it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook/&#34;&gt;still sketching&lt;/a&gt;, though I&amp;rsquo;ve fallen a couple of days behind due to the game jam. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1385224243848179719/&#34;&gt;tried to do one on paper like a comic&lt;/a&gt; but my handwriting was so terrible I had to edit it digitally!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Movies: Watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/b178a1efcfc005930f062c7be447d7c1/&#34;&gt;Rocky (1976)&lt;/a&gt;, and I meant to watch the next Bond flick too, but ran out of time. New Mortal Kombat movie also came out this past week, I might watch that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Falcon and Winter Soldier&lt;/strong&gt; season finale ran last Friday. A lot of people are happy with it (and the season overall), but I felt like some parts were too rushed and the finale suffered as a result. Will probably post more thoughts on it this week. After this, we won&amp;rsquo;t have MCU content until Loki kicks off next month I think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Invincible&lt;/strong&gt; is getting to the good part!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still drafting a bunch of Strixhaven on Arena (though I had to stop for the weekend due to the game jam). Most of my drafts went well, though the last 2 I did this week were terrible. I ended up listening to &lt;a href=&#34;http://lrcast.com/limited-resources-593-strixhaven-first-impressions/&#34;&gt;the Limited Resources podcast&lt;/a&gt; for the first time and got some good tips, hopefully that improves my drafts moving forward. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably play in the Sealed Open next weekend! Follow along via &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgstrixhaven/&#34;&gt;the MTGStrixhaven tag&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fire Emblem: Three Houses&lt;/strong&gt; actually had some progress this week. I really should finish this run soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloaded &lt;strong&gt;Horizon Zero Dawn&lt;/strong&gt; on PS4 because it&amp;rsquo;s temporarily free! I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to play this for a while, hopefully I have time for it this coming week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played some Street Fighter V again this week; I figured since a new character dropped, it might be easy to find matches again. I did manage to fight quite a few, but I also did quite poorly, dropping back to Ultra Bronze. Thinking about switching to a different character since everyone seems to know how to fight Ryu, so I unlocked Honda! We&amp;rsquo;ll see who I actually end up using.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;: Currently about halfway through &lt;strong&gt;Snow Crash&lt;/strong&gt; by Neal Stephenson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trivia: Pop Quiz is back (albeit monthly now, not weekly), so the trivia team was able to join two quizzes this past week. We didn&amp;rsquo;t win either though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had a couple of birthdays in the family this weekend, so my game jamming was interspersed with zoom / messenger calls and food deliveries and such.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-coming-week&#34;&gt;This coming week:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new Invincible, One Piece, BNHA, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new expansion dropping for Root, one of the digital boardgames we&amp;rsquo;ve been playing (and the one I have yet to write a review for&amp;hellip; sounds like a perfect opportunity!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strixhaven Sealed Open on Arena next week!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was a bit rushed, so typos etc are a feature, not a bug.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
            <category>post</category>
            
                        
            <category>philippines</category>
                        
            <category>covid19</category>
                        
            <category>weeknotes</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386215271027732481/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 07:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386215271027732481/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;This is great&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/gothspiderbitch/status/1386031209457852418&#39;&gt;gothspiderbitch&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    so did anyone else know that there was a massive pool noodle battle planned between all the people named Josh today that was ultimately won by a 5-year old named Josh who was crowned The Supreme Josh or was I just supposed to find this out on my own
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386215271027732481/1_1386215271027732481_EzwsCBcXEAo1WsT_huba72fcbe95634bf67e78b1938f4af5b7_59288_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386215271027732481/2_1386215271027732481_EzwsCBaXsAEkLfe_hud38ecb74038eaadb17b40d954dfc01c0_195686_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386215271027732481/3_1386215271027732481_EzwsCBbWUAEIIqw_hu0b263b96d0abbfe2d22fb7c8975f4999_118518_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386215271027732481/4_1386215271027732481_EzwsCCdWQAME4hA_hu66e56a6d9fddc1c0586cedc7b9828cc8_137553_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386011173275922433/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 17:36:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1386011173275922433/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s actually amazing how computers have become exponentially more powerful in my lifetime (yet somehow our web browsers manage to eat up most of the memory)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/ChefJags/status/1385743779408355330&#39;&gt;ChefJags&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You can only retweet this if you know exactly how it feels to have this rig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&#39;320&#39; height=&#39;568&#39; controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#39;https://video.twimg.com/ext_tw_video/1385743522628784131/pu/vid/576x1024/tw7ab46dfrNnO-xK.mp4?tag=12&#39; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
            <category>notes</category>
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1385956018509664263/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 13:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1385956018509664263/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Diver #sketchdaily 112/365&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1385956018509664263/1_1385956018509664263_EzvnozBVkAYbyq__huda93d6739919b05f63de40167753bd68_186429_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
            <category>photos</category>
            
                        
            <category>sketchdaily</category>
            
            
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Exploiting vulnerabilities in Cellebrite UFED and Physical Analyzer from an app&#39;s perspective
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/exploiting-vulnerabilities-in-cellebrite-ufed-and-physical-analyzer-from-an-apps-perspective/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 14:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/exploiting-vulnerabilities-in-cellebrite-ufed-and-physical-analyzer-from-an-apps-perspective/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via pocket:
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://signal.org/blog/cellebrite-vulnerabilities/&#34;&gt;Exploiting vulnerabilities in Cellebrite UFED and Physical Analyzer from an app&amp;#39;s perspective&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
            <category>links</category>
            
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>