<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>ustrip2019 on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/tags/ustrip2019/</link>
      <description>Recent content in ustrip2019 on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 05:56:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/tags/ustrip2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Travel Anxiety, Part 2
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/07/travel-anxiety-part-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/07/travel-anxiety-part-2/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I had written about &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2015/11/travel-anxiety/&#34;&gt;travel anxiety&lt;/a&gt; before, but I&amp;rsquo;m revisiting the topic because the recent US trip reminded me how much of a problem it is for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US trip was a new experience because I would be abroad for 40 days with multiple travel legs, it involved 4 international flights (back and forth) plus three domestic flights within the US, and on one leg and several flights I would be travelling alone. I had travelled abroad before for a longer period (3 months for London in 2015), but for those 3 months I was based in the same place and didn&amp;rsquo;t need anybody&amp;rsquo;s help to move around the city, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can get a bit crazy in planning for possible problems. Loss of passport is probably the worst-case scenario, followed by getting sick/injured while abroad (especially since I&amp;rsquo;m wary of the expensiveness of US health care), and of course there&amp;rsquo;s the possibility all your other stuff getting lost or stolen. In case of catastophe, I set up an online URL (known only to me) where I can access emergency info such as my passport details, contact number for relatives, and so on. Of course I also have paper printouts of needed info.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By my own count, I had ridden on an airplane 23 times now in my lifetime (19 international, 1 domestic PH, 3 domestic US), but I still worry a lot about any given flight. There are multiple possible points of failure for any one flight, some of them unique to the US, specifically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;need to arrive at the airport on time, without forgetting your travel documents&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;need to pass security/immigration/customs. Added feature this time was the stricter TSA screening. And the customs form I needed to fill up as I entered the US gave me some worry as well, because I was carrying some foodstuffs meant to be given to relatives and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if I had to declare them or not (apparently the default answer is just don&amp;rsquo;t declare them? IDK). I had a similar issue on the way back into the PH, but even though I was given a customs form to fill up, no one actually asked for it?!? ¯\_(ツ)_/¯&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;need to pray that your checked luggage doesn&amp;rsquo;t get lost or stolen from. Additionally, in the US, the TSA may open your checked luggage outside of your presence, and if you&amp;rsquo;re using a non-TSA approved luggage lock, they will break your lock to do so. I had the misfortune of getting &lt;a href=&#34;https://photos.app.goo.gl/BMYFgcLnrtpwiEd66&#34;&gt;this souvenir from the TSA&lt;/a&gt; because of this (I have since purchased TSA-approved locks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;need to make sure no one else claims your checked baggage at the carousel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;will I even be able to sleep during the long haul flight? Undoubtably yes, but only in very short bursts that I presume are not healthy. Airplane economy seats are often very uncomfortable for me and and have very little leg room, and the seat backs are not conducive to me sleeping. I am so uncomfortable on airplanes that I&amp;rsquo;ve come to realize that me preparing movies/books/comics/games to entertain me during the flight is a waste of time, as I typically won&amp;rsquo;t indulge in those activities when I&amp;rsquo;m not very comfortable. Typically, a long haul flight goes like this for me:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to sleep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wake up after 2-8 minutes due to some noise or due to my neck hurting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the flight status/time to see how much longer I have to tolerate this nonsense&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stare for a while into the void, doing nothing, hoping I can somehow make this flight go by faster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Optional) Get up and go to the 0.5 square meter lavatory so I can stretch my legs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make tiny adjustment in neck or butt or leg position(s) and hope that helps me sleep better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The start of my trip gave me some anxiety as well, when I went to the check-in counter at NAIA, the Asiana lady could not scan my machine-readable passport, presumably due to a fold on the relevant page. She said she would process me manually but warned me that there was a possibility that they would reject my passport at my US entry point since a machine-readable passport was a requirement. I even had to sign a waiver absolving Asiana of any liability in case I was not allowed to enter the US! Basically they gave me reason to be worried during the entire length of the 18-hour trip to SFO. Spoilers: there was no issue at the US border, and there was never any further issue scanning my passport at any point including at the e-Gate as I was re-entering the PH. (Props to NAIA for having e-Gates now.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another issue I encountered was because this was my first time actually visiting relatives during a trip, so I was not prepared for the Filipino culture thing of having your relatives give you stuff to bring back home. I always pack as lightly as possible and have a small luggage unit specifically because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to worry about lugging around a lot of weight. Because of this, on my way back to Seattle from Houston, and from Seattle to Sacramento, I had to handcarry a large paper back with stuff for my folks and siblings. I did not have a spare bag to carry the items, and on the trip to Sacramento, the bag was even slightly ripped, I did not have a contingency plan for if it fell apart. Luckily, things worked out lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned in the previous post that I don&amp;rsquo;t really do much shopping, but my parents did, and we ended up having 3 additional checked luggage pieces ((all of them near the 50lbs limit), which meant I had to carry one myself during my flight. (We were flying back on the same day, but had separate flights). This added to bit about my anxiety, as what if some customs official asked me what I had in the large luggage and I had no idea? Luckily again, things worked out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the flights, I also had to arrange for lodging, as not all the places we were going to had friends or relatives we could crash at. I ended up using 3 different AirBNBs, one each in Anaheim, Los Angeles and Seattle. AirBNBs come with their own set of anxieties:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;will I be able to find the place?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;will there be an issue with the check in process?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can I trust the host not to steal my stuff or spy on my with a hidden camera or something? The thing about AirBNBs is you basically have to trust strangers; one of my issues this time is I was travelling with a laptop, so I was worried that it might not be secure to leave the laptop at the AirBNB when I went out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is the AirBNB area secure? Can I walk around the area at night?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happily, I encountered no issues with the AirBNBs I rented and had pleasant stays all around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Luckily, things worked out&amp;rdquo; is generally the outcome to be expected for most of these overthinking-type anxieties I guess. I know it&amp;rsquo;s not rational to worry about all of these things a lot, and I understand the odds are low for any particular risk, but sometimes I can&amp;rsquo;t help myself. Often I can manage the happy-go-lucky &amp;ldquo;eh, I&amp;rsquo;m sure it&amp;rsquo;ll be fine&amp;rdquo; attitude for any single problem, but in this instance the fact that I had to worry about so many different flights (not to mention iteneraries like theme parks, meetups, etc) made it extra challenging. I guess I just need to remind myself not to worry too much. While there are certainly a lot of possible &amp;ldquo;things that can go wrong&amp;rdquo;, most of them are easily recoverable from, and the odds are very low anyway. I&amp;rsquo;ve survived this long in a harsh environment like Metro Manila, so I can probably survive something going wrong in more &amp;ldquo;civilized&amp;rdquo; (?) countries like the US anyway!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>US 2019 - San Francisco area and Trip Summary
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/07/us-2019-san-francisco-area-and-trip-summary/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/07/us-2019-san-francisco-area-and-trip-summary/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After the &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/07/us-2019-seattle/&#34;&gt;Seattle part of the trip&lt;/a&gt;, I reunited with family for the final leg of the trip where we all be hanging around the San Francisco bay area. We were based in my uncle&amp;rsquo;s place in Vacaville, which one of my friends kindly described as &amp;ldquo;in the sticks&amp;rdquo;, i.e. basically far away from everything. Like Houston, we had to rely on the kindness of relatives who were willing and available to drive us around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the laziest part of the trip by far: not much walking, most of it either just driving to places and taking pictures; or going to outlets for shopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent a few days near Monterey, staying at a cousin&amp;rsquo;s house. This let us visit some nearby stuff like cannery row, the 17-mile drive and pebble beach. Climbed some rocks, saw some squirrels, walked by the wharf, that kind of stuff. After that, we also visited San Jose for a day to meet some other relatives, then the next day we drove over to San Francisco and visited the Golden Gate Bridge area, the Palace of Fine Arts (sadly closed on that day, but the exteriors were nice), and drove around the SF roads for a bit too. I was a bit underwhelmed by the Golden Gate bridge, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as long nor as wide as I imagined it would be, but from the exhibits there I can imagine what a big deal of an engineering feat it was at that time. The streets of SF were even steeper than Seattle&amp;rsquo;s were! I&amp;rsquo;m glad I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to walk them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day was just hanging out the Vacaville area and visiting (and revisiting) the outlets for shopping. Apparently Vacaville is known for the outlets. I&amp;rsquo;m not much of a shopper myself - I don&amp;rsquo;t have the patience to sift through rows of clothes or shoes looking for bargains - it&amp;rsquo;s mostly my parents who bought a bunch of stuff. I just walked around mostly looking at things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did make a couple of electronics purchases, one was a cheap gaming mouse (not as cheap as the ones in the PH, but not like a $60 razer either), and the bigger purchase was a 2018 iPad from Best Buy. I wanted to get a new tablet because my current iPad Pro was falling apart (I literally had some tape at the seams to hold it together), and the battery was in horrible shape. I was hesitating because the iPad Pro was actually still perfectly usable - as long as it was plugged in and the tape held. At first I wanted to get a new iPad Pro, since I wanted the pencil support, but those were wildly expensive, and even the refurbished 9.7-inch ones would have cost as much as a new 2018 iPad. Luckily, I found out that the 2018 iPad did in fact support the Apple Pencil, so I ended up getting a new one of those instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a fourth of July barbecue at my uncle&amp;rsquo;s house, and I stayed the night at a friend&amp;rsquo;s house in Hercules, then more lazy days of shopping to wind down our US trip. Some overall impressions of the US and random stories follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;everything is so far apart. During our Houston and Vacaville legs we basically had to be driven everywhere. Probably basically impossible to live without a car (as I prefer) unless you&amp;rsquo;re willing to pay the higher rents in the downtown areas. There&amp;rsquo;s also so much idle land everywhere. Basically the opposite of congested Metro Manila. I have a better understanding now of why Americans are so obsessed with cars (and pickup trucks apparently) (Slight tangent: interesting article I read on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2019/07/car-crashes-arent-always-unavoidable/592447/&#34;&gt;why Americans are basically forced into car dependency by laws, infrastructure and big oil&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no bidets! This is why Japan is superior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s only logical given how far apart things are, but this is the first country I&amp;rsquo;ve visited with wildly different climates in different zones. SF and LA were manageable hot - cool in the shade, but close to PH temps if you&amp;rsquo;re in the sun in the afternoons. Vegas and Houston were very, very hot. Seattle was cold in the mornings and never got too hot during the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Americans are very chatty, even with strangers. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect them to be as chatty as Filipinos since we allegedly have a reputation for being &amp;ldquo;warm and hospitable&amp;rdquo;, but Filipinos don&amp;rsquo;t randomly ask how my day is going the way random people on the street do in the US. In Las Vegas, a large black woman was trying to chat up me and my brother while we were on a food run and we were ignoring her and she asked us why we were being so antisocial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently Filipino expats in the US watch a lot of TFC and Telenovelas and Pinoy movies. Reminds them of home I guess. I actually sat through a couple of Pinoy movies myself, I&amp;rsquo;ll write about them in the next &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/tags/watching-lately/&#34;&gt;watching lately&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are so many, um, shall we say, &amp;ldquo;large&amp;rdquo; Americans. Not in terms of height, but in terms of width! Not that I&amp;rsquo;m fat shaming or anything like that - I mean, I&amp;rsquo;m a huge guy myself, but seeing so many larger folk around made me feel a bit more comfortable with myself. Some of the stores we went to had shirt sizes that went as high as 6x! I think the larger Americans I saw were mostly in the theme parks and the city areas, not so much in the suburbs, not sure if that&amp;rsquo;s indicative of anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I used Southwest for all the domestic flights. SW is interesting because they don&amp;rsquo;t have reserved seatings for their flights - you&amp;rsquo;re assigned a boarding priority and when you board you just pick from whatever seat is available. Also apparently they let me bring free checked baggage whereas other airlines don&amp;rsquo;t so I guess I randomly made a good decision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US airports don&amp;rsquo;t seem very interesting, or maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just spoiled by airports like Singapore&amp;rsquo;s Changi or HKIA where I don&amp;rsquo;t mind spending a lot of time there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t spend as much as I thought I would (mostly due to the hospitality of our hosts), but still the fact that food is so expensive here really tells me a lot about how Americans view things financially. A decent meal is typically $10-$15, maybe more. Compare that to the cost of things that would be considered luxuries in the Philippines: a new video game is $60, basically 4 or 5 meals worth; a month&amp;rsquo;s Netflix sub or a comic book are less than the cost of a meal; and so on. It basically makes it so easy to impulse buy say, a $1 chocolate bar or a $4 bag of chips since these are so inexpensive compared to normal meals, but over here I&amp;rsquo;d balk at P35 chocolate bars or P150 bag of chips. I guess I&amp;rsquo;m worried that having spent time in the US, I&amp;rsquo;d be more spendy when I get back lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in summary, I was able to visit 4 states: California, Nevada, Texas, and Washington. (Arizona for a layover). Not bad! I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to visit the East Coast during this trip, so maybe that&amp;rsquo;s something to look forward to in the future. I am not yet sure if I even want to go back; maybe one trip is already plently, just enough to experience what life is like over there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>US 2019 - Seattle
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/07/us-2019-seattle/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/07/us-2019-seattle/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Seattle was the riskiest part of my trip, relatively speaking, because it was my solo leg - I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any friends or relatives in the city I could turn to in case of an emergency. I had also read online that while Seattle was very much a walkable city, there was a nontrivial homeless population, and some areas may be a bit sketchy after dark. As a friend of mine said though, &amp;ldquo;sketchy&amp;rdquo; in the US is probably a lot safer than &amp;ldquo;sketchy&amp;rdquo; in Metro Manila. I still worried a little bit, but given where I from, it didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to worry about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My primary purpose for this leg of the trip was of course &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/07/grand-prix-seattle-2019/&#34;&gt;GP Seattle&lt;/a&gt;, but I also looked forward to being able to walk and explore the city by myself. Not that I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy hanging out and travelling with my family, but I enjoy being able to wander around freely by myself with no real agenda, &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2009/03/sometimes-you-just-go-where-your-feet-take-you/&#34;&gt;letting my feet take me wherever&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That meant instead of theme parks and tourist attractions and shopping outlets, I found myself walking around looking into small bookstores, vintage shops, collectibles stores, hobby shops, gaming arcades, and so on. My poor performance at the GP main event gave me some extra time to wander the streets as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did hit a few tourist spots:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I took some pictures at the Space Needle. Didn&amp;rsquo;t bother going up, I felt like I&amp;rsquo;ve already climbed enough tall structures in my lifetime and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really worth the cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did take half a day to go through the Museum of Pop Culture near the Space Needle, which I enjoyed. They had exhibits on Washington state bands like Pearl Jam and Nirvana, fantasy and sci-fi exhibits, and even an independent gaming exhibit sponsored by Nintendo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supposedly, Seattle&amp;rsquo;s number one tourist attraction is Pike Place Market, which I found weird, because well, it&amp;rsquo;s a market. I did visit the market and wander the shop and had some of Beecher&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;World&amp;rsquo;s Best Mac and Cheese&amp;rdquo; (tastes great, but the cheese is very sharp, some people might not like it). There were some nice market shops - I enjoyed browsing a couple of the used bookstores there and there was a comic book store as well (was able to resist adding more to my reading backlog though). I think there was supposed to be some performance by the fishmongers in the market proper, and I did see some crowd gathered around one of the stalls and clapping, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t push through quick enough to see what was going on, and didn&amp;rsquo;t bother waiting for something to happen again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I did not enjoy was how steeply inclined Seattle&amp;rsquo;s streets were. Going from my Airbnb near Capitol Hill to the downtown area was easy enough as it was mostly downhill, but going back home at the end of the day was always a bit of a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like Seattle as a city, especially the Capitol Hill district - it feels like it has a lot of character, compared to say, Los Angeles (although that might be an unfair comparison as I didn&amp;rsquo;t really get to wander LA much). The city has more of a west coast-artistic vibe going on, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of posters for events everywhere, art murals on a lot of walls, there&amp;rsquo;s more music shops and book shops, a lot of random small parks, and a lot of place are very LGBTQ-friendly, even some of the crosswalks are rainbow-colored. The bookstores I browsed were great, a couple had the staff leaving small notes on the shelves about various titles they recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my last day in Seattle, due to some combination of poor planning and cheapness, I had to spend an inordinate amount of time at SEATAC airport, pre-security. I was basically at the airport 8 hours before my flight, a personal record. I thought Southwest would at least let me check my bags and go through security maybe 3-4 hours before the 5am flight, but their counter only opened an hour and a half before the flight. So I have no real opinions on whether SEATAC is a good airport or not lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ll leave you with some pictures!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seattle photo dump:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;a/Q6yBFyk&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//imgur.com/a/Q6yBFyk&#34;&gt;Seattle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MoPOP photo dump (part 1):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;a/45uzuCk&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//imgur.com/a/45uzuCk&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MoPOP photo dump (part 2) - scfi and fantasy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;a/KgOUcEX&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//imgur.com/a/KgOUcEX&#34;&gt;MoPOP part 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>US 2019 - Anaheim, Los Angeles, Las Vegas and Houston
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/06/us-2019-anaheim-los-angeles-las-vegas-and-houston/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/06/us-2019-anaheim-los-angeles-las-vegas-and-houston/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Not much to say about Anaheim, it felt like the town was all about Disneyland and not much else. But then again we did spend our three days there just going to Disneyland, so what can you do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In LA we stayed in the Koreatown district, so everything felt weirdly Asian. Not Asian like living in Asia, but like Chinatown in any other city I guess? The city felt a bit dirty, I&amp;rsquo;m told the metro elevators smelled bad, and there was grafitti everywhere and a high incidence of homeless people. One time we took an elevator to get to the Metro and there was a homeless person smoking in the elevator. When he saw the kids, he promptly killed the cigarette and muttered apologetically &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t smoke near kids.&amp;rdquo; Hollywood was all ritz and glitter and tourist traps though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We only spent a couple of nights and one full day in Las Vegas, but the heat was insufferable. And considering I&amp;rsquo;m from Manila, that&amp;rsquo;s saying something. It was hot too in LA and Anaheim, but LV had a weird sort of desert heat that seemed to linger on your skin. On our full day, we opted to spend most of daylight just hanging out in the hotel room, with the occasional outside forays for food. We spent the night on a short walking tour among the nearby hotels and the free shows like the Atlantis show at the forum or the fountain at Bellagio. Our LV-native cousin was our guide, and we (or they at least) took a lot of pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spent a few days in Houston, enough to bring the kids to attractions like the Space Center, Kemah Boardwalk, the Aquarium, and the Natural Science Museum. The kids enjoyed some of the rides; I tried one of the tamer ones at the Boardwalk, but still came away dizzy. I&amp;rsquo;m too old for these things. Science geek that I am, I most enjoyed the Space Center and the Natural Science Museum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Houston felt like a large expanse where everything was so far away from each other. We were lucky to be visiting a cousin who could drive us around; it would have been impossible to live here without a car. There&amp;rsquo;s always so much room everywhere, even downtown Houston never felt congested or anything remotely like Metro Manila.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip is only halfway done, but I think the most exhausting days should be behind me. Famous last words?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>US 2019 - Theme parks
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/06/us-2019-theme-parks/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/06/us-2019-theme-parks/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of theme parks. I think for the most part they are overpriced and not worth the time, effort or money. And I&amp;rsquo;d probably never go to one by myself or without one of my nieces/nephews. I understand the impetus of bringing kids to a theme park of course, they really enjoy it. Prior to this trip, I&amp;rsquo;ve only ever been to a theme park once, and that was in Unversal Studios Singapore with my brothers back in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time we went to Disneyland in Anaheim and Universal Studios Hollywood. The kids with us were the nieces, 9yo and 3yo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, the kids loved Disneyland. We got a 3 day pass and spent the first day in Disneyland Park and the next 2 days in California Adventure. The kids had been to the Asian Disneylands before, so there was more new stuff for them in the California Adventure side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visiting Disneyland reminded me of what a cultural tour de force Disney is in general. Kids from all the over the world come visit Disneyland and they instantly recognize and respond to all of these characters. When the nieces spot one of the mascots walking around they just shout out in glee and run up and wave to them. Yes, even the older niece. It&amp;rsquo;s not just the major Disney characters like Mickey and Minnie and Donald either. Kids respond well even to the minor characters or the obscure ones from random Disney channel shows. Disneyland really is for kids. (On a less Disney-branded note, I was also amused by how kids everywhere react the same way to bubbles being blown their way.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some highlights of the 3 days at Disneyland:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a short play re-telling &lt;em&gt;Tangled&lt;/em&gt;. Well, I only note this because I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched Tangled before and only now found out its story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Disneyland parade that happen at the main central area. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty long, and the music can get repetitive and earwormy, but I liked how they highlighted a bunch of their properties like Aladdin, Little Mermaid, etc., though there were some weird choices there too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the California Adventure side, the best thing was the live action &lt;em&gt;Frozen&lt;/em&gt; play at the Hyperion theatre. It&amp;rsquo;s a one hour re-telling of the movie (with a few liberties taken), with all the songs and everything. The performances were great, and the entire show in general was a masterful use of the stage, props, lighting, projectors, holograms, etc. It&amp;rsquo;s not the sort of show they could stage at just any theatre either. Having two nieces I have of course seen the movie a few dozen times so one would think I&amp;rsquo;d be tired of it by now, but I was very entertained.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there was also this nice Toy Story-themed game/ride where you used a virtual gun to shoot at targets like in a carnival, it was fun. If you only had time for one ride in California Adventure, this is the one I&amp;rsquo;d recommend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did quite a number of other simpler rides (just the ones where you&amp;rsquo;re sitting and there&amp;rsquo;s a show going on around you), and picture taking with various characters. I don&amp;rsquo;t have many pictures handy to show here, but here&amp;rsquo;s me with Captain America:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/uploads/2019/disney-cap.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything like roller coasters or that new Guardians of the Galaxy which goes up and down and stuff. The kids don&amp;rsquo;t like it, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I could either, tbh. There was also a lot of wandering around the mechandise shops of course, I&amp;rsquo;m sure they make a lot of money off all the toys. I ended up buying something my brother requested for my nephew, only to find it available again at another place for a cheaper price. Lol, I should learn never to buy stuff at theme parks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Anaheim, we took a short train over to LA, and we went to Universal Studios Hollywood. This theme park is not as kid-focused as Disneyland was, so the 3yo didn&amp;rsquo;t have as much of a good time, though she did enjoy seeing characters like the Simpsons, Harry Potter, and so on. The rides are also for bigger kids mostly - they&amp;rsquo;re the sort of rides that are full of high-speed movement, jumping and jerking around, some falling and so on. I only did the Transformers ride (which was the same as the one in Singapore) and the Minions ride, I already got a bit dizzy just from those two. I suspect the Harry Potter one was more intense (just based on the warnings), but there was like an 80 minute wait for that so we didn&amp;rsquo;t bother. I did enjoy walking around the Simpsons area and seeing all the references and the characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also did the Studio Tour, which is really for movie geeks than anyone else, so again the kids didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy it as much. The first part was a bit boring, just showing us the exteriors of the sound stages (basically just looking at warehouses). Things got a bit more interesting when they showed us some exterior locations, and there were a few parts where we got to experience a bit of a show . The &amp;ldquo;shows&amp;rdquo; were basically projected into a tunnel while our trams moved around. One was a Skull Island themed scene where King Kong was fighting a t-rex or such, and another was Fast and Furious themed which involved a high speed chase and jumping off bridges and such. There was also a special effects part where we were in a subway tunnel when an earthquake strikes, and there&amp;rsquo;s fire and suddenly the tunnel is flooded. I think the studio tour was the highlight for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also attended the special effects show, a 30-minute show demoing various special effects. Again, the 3yo didn&amp;rsquo;t like it so much, especially in the parts where they pretended to saw off a volunteer&amp;rsquo;s hand or send the volunteer flying through space. It was fun for me though, and a bit informative as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had also been planning to go to Legoland near San Diego, but it turns out the trip would&amp;rsquo;ve cost a bit more than we&amp;rsquo;d like, and online reviews said we might be disappointed especially coming from Disneyland, so we ended up not going. Instead we wandered around Hollywood boulevard and went to a few exhibits there - namely Ripley&amp;rsquo;s Believe it or Not, Guinness Book of World Records, and the Hollywood Wax Museum. The Guinness one was the best of the three, as there were a bunch of interactive games and exhibits that we enjoyed. The 3yo didn&amp;rsquo;t like being in the Ripley&amp;rsquo;s or the Wax Museum as she was a bit scared of some of the exhibits. Ripley&amp;rsquo;s had some creepy and weird stuff, including a couple that made the 9yo scream and run in surprise. I did like some of the displays, like the model of Minas Tirith made entirely of matchsticks, or the Darth Vader made out of car parts. The Wax Museum was nice, but didn&amp;rsquo;t have much and was over too quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the theme park experience was fun. Still not changing my view that they are overpriced, and since I don&amp;rsquo;t have kids, I may never go to a Disneyland ever again, but it&amp;rsquo;s probably good that I got to experience it at least once so I know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>US 2019 - Tourist mode exercise
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/06/us-2019-tourist-mode-exercise/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/06/us-2019-tourist-mode-exercise/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/04/i-got-a-us-visa/&#34;&gt;US trip&lt;/a&gt; started on the first of the month. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write more regularly about it, but one thing I had forgotten was how exhausting it would be to be a tourist, walking everywhere all of the time. Here&amp;rsquo;s how many steps my Fitbit recorded during that first week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#140de2aae4f2bd4af2c3b96f67e4e8e3-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/06/us-2019-tourist-mode-exercise/tourist-walk_hubb6c862ea0b30f21225525a73c2d37c5_46266_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;140de2aae4f2bd4af2c3b96f67e4e8e3-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/06/us-2019-tourist-mode-exercise/tourist-walk.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;8 Jun 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;8 Jun 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished this week with a bit more than 105k steps, which I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure is a lifetime record (though I dont have the data anymore from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2015/03/europe-trip-2015/&#34;&gt;Europe trip in 2015&lt;/a&gt; - I suspect that it&amp;rsquo;s comparable in scale.) Compunding the tiredness was that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting much sleep, especially during that first day when we spent more than 13 hours on a plane:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#071561184d14b0f0885313488fa27619-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/06/us-2019-tourist-mode-exercise/tourist-sleep_huec9f4a7d48df0d9a1cf1534e36be2e84_62542_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;071561184d14b0f0885313488fa27619-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/06/us-2019-tourist-mode-exercise/tourist-sleep.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;8 Jun 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;8 Jun 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 0 hours there is probably a bit inaccurate. I always find it difficult to sleep on planes, so long hauls are difficult, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I managed to get a few short bursts of sleep here and there. I suspect the Fitbit is not very well suited to measuring that sort of sleep especially when seated upright in an airplane seat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, that is my excuse for not being able to write much. It&amp;rsquo;s likely that this first week will have been the most exhausting part of the trip, this is where we scheduled the California theme parks after all (more on that in the next post). It is of course a net positive that I am walking so much, since this is pretty much the only exercise I get these days. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about whether I would be able to maintain this level of walking (or even half as much!) when I get back home after the trip, as I have been slacking off on the walking the past few months. Hopefully I can find a way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/06/us-2019-tourist-mode-exercise/tourist-sleep_huec9f4a7d48df0d9a1cf1534e36be2e84_62542_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/06/us-2019-tourist-mode-exercise/tourist-walk_hubb6c862ea0b30f21225525a73c2d37c5_46266_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>