<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Review on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/review/</link>
      <description>Recent content in Review on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 01:02:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Atomic Habits by James Clear
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/atomic-habits/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 01:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/atomic-habits/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Hopefully managing to read at least one book at month this year, kicking it off with &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com/atomic-habits&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits by James Clear&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I forget where I heard of this book, but it&amp;rsquo;s highly recommended and an Amazon best-seller. I followed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jamesclear&#34;&gt;author on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for a while before deciding to buy the book. I read it sporadically through the month. It&amp;rsquo;s not very long - less than 300 pages on the Kindle app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is fairly good and insightful, although I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if there are any ideas I haven&amp;rsquo;t encountered elsewhere (especially if you read a lot of self-improvement stuff). Most of the concepts are easy to arrive at if you sat down to spend like thirty minutes thinking about (&amp;ldquo;Oh, I should make my good habits easier to do!&amp;rdquo; seems kind of obvious in hindsight).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the book shines in tying these ideas together thematically into what the author describes as &amp;ldquo;four laws of behavior change.&amp;rdquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m taking anything away from the book by listing the four laws here as: make it obvious/make it attractive/make it easy/make it satisfying. As is typical with this kind of book, the theme is further supported by citing research, anecdotes, success stories, quotes, tips, and such. While the material in question doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel entirely revolutionary, the presentation is very good and makes it a worthwhile read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had my own share of trouble building new habits in the past of course. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a specific set of good habits to learn/bad habits to unlearn when I started reading, but the book&amp;rsquo;s insights did give me some ideas of how I could restructure some of my daily habits to make things easier for me. And I thought of some new habits during the course of reading and have been keeping them up for a week or so. So, the book has already provided some value for me personally. I hope I can keep it up.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: December 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/watching-lately-december-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/watching-lately-december-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Been watching a lot of things this December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally got back on &lt;strong&gt;The Expanse&lt;/strong&gt; after finishing S1 more than a year ago. I only finished S2, but it was already a vast improvement over S1. S1 felt like a lot of meandering around until the characters actually ran into the plot. S2 was stronger, faster-paced, and there&amp;rsquo;s always a lot of things going on in each episode. I really like this series now, looking forward to S3 and S4 when I have the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix-wise, I enjoyed their recently-added &lt;strong&gt;Jeopardy&lt;/strong&gt; series (always a great show to have playing in the background), the new documentary &lt;strong&gt;The Movies That Made Us&lt;/strong&gt; (loved their selection of movies to feature), and the second season of &lt;strong&gt;Final Space&lt;/strong&gt; (a fun sci-fi space romp if ever there was one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of crazy sci-fi, &lt;strong&gt;Rick and Morty&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve caught up with the recently released S4 as well. This series seems a lot more self-aware now, and a lot more unafraid to make fun of tropes and genre conventions. I liked the heist episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broadcast-wise, I enjoyed the front half of the Arrowverse&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Crisis of Infinite Earths&lt;/strong&gt; crossover. It had that same feeling as Avengers Endgame where I knew what was likely to happen based on comic book knowledge, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t think they could do it, but they did it! Whenever discussion of this crossover leaked over to the mainstream TV subreddits/forums, there was a lot of criticism of how it looked so low-budget, but I think any expecations of them being able to provide Avengers-quality costumes and effects on a broadcast TV show budget are unrealistic. The Arrowverse shows certainly have a lot of flaws, but this type of multiversal crossover isn&amp;rsquo;t something that could have been achieved without all the setup of the past eight years (and even beyond, considering older shows like Smallville and 90&amp;rsquo;s Flash), and that&amp;rsquo;s something comparable to what the MCU has built, even at a fraction of the budget. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll have more words for this series and the Arrowverse in general when the back half airs in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend also somehow tricked me into watching &lt;strong&gt;Sky High&lt;/strong&gt;, a rather old and campy and totally predictable superhero-type movie. I did finish it so I guess I enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nieces were over this weekend so I finally got to watch &lt;strong&gt;Toy Story 4&lt;/strong&gt;. I was a bit skeptical that they decided to add another installment when I felt the trilogy was already pretty tight. I have to admit I was surprised with the direction this movie took and the ending it gave, which leaves an opening for future movies in the franchise, though they might already be quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;Star Wars: Rise of Skywalker&lt;/strong&gt; before Christmas, here are &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/star-wars-rise-of-skywalker-spoilers/&#34;&gt;my thoughts on the film and the trilogy&lt;/a&gt;. WHile I wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely happy with it, I did enjoy watching the film and I recognize that it was a good retelling of Star Wars for new/modern fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also rewatched &lt;strong&gt;The Last Jedi&lt;/strong&gt; for the first time about a week later, it was still pretty good, especially that third act. (Casino subquest still felt superfluous). I did come out a bit more disappointed that ROS didn&amp;rsquo;t follow through with some of the themes of TLJ. I can only assume there are a couple of alternate universes out there where both Rian Johnson&amp;rsquo;s direction and JJ Abrams direction came true for the Skywalker saga ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Star Wars, I enjoyed the ending of &lt;strong&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/strong&gt;, although it did have a couple of weaker episodes in the middle that felt like filler (or maybe just there to seed characters for the eventual second season). The final two episodes are pretty good, and we get the payoffs of actualy learning the Mandalorian&amp;rsquo;s history and all. I do find it ridiculous that the Jedi and the Force are still unknown enough that the Mandalorian has never heard of them considering it probably hasn&amp;rsquo;t even been more than 30 years since Palpatine took down the Republic, which had literally an entire council of Jedi as an advisory body to the Senate and featuring prominently in the Clone Wars. Do they not have recorded history? Lol. In any case, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to season 2 whenever it lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THat&amp;rsquo;s it for the decade!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: So Good They Cant Ignore You by Cal Newport
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Aha! I finally managed to finish a book again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of Cal Newport since years ago tangentially due to his Study Hacks blog, which was pretty good at the time. I haven&amp;rsquo;t followed his career too closely, but he&amp;rsquo;s an academic at Georgetown apparently. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t looking for any career advice in particular, but I did have a recommendation for this book from somewhere so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is &lt;em&gt;So Good They Can&amp;rsquo;t Ignore You&lt;/em&gt;, and focuses on what it takes to have a &amp;ldquo;successful career&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite thing about this book is that from the get-go, the author discards something most self-improvement books focus on: passion. The author discards passion as non-essential. A lot of self-improvement books also lay out a bunch of principles and rules and wink at the reader and say something to the effect of &amp;ldquo;You just have to do all of this stuff, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be super successful!&amp;rdquo;, as if all of those rules + a bit of passion are some sort of secret ingredient that allow you to skip past all the hard work necessary to find success. This book doesn&amp;rsquo;t shy away from the concept of hard work. Instead, it embraces it, in the form of what the author calls &amp;ldquo;career capital&amp;rdquo;. Basically, you need to earn enough &amp;ldquo;career capital&amp;rdquo; in order to then exchange that capital for the trappings of a successful career, such as more control over your time. &amp;ldquo;Career capital&amp;rdquo; is what makes you &amp;ldquo;so good they can&amp;rsquo;t ignore you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many books of this type, the ideas are presented as if the author came by them scientific analysis, but really the basis seems to be a series of anecdotal success stories of people whose career paths coincide with the author&amp;rsquo;s central thesis. This is not inherently a bad thing, though it does weaken the foundation of the books claims that it&amp;rsquo;s not backed by a detailed scientific study. But for purposes of laying out his ideas in an entertaining manner, the format is certainly sufficient. The success stories are really the meat of the book, designed to lay out the author&amp;rsquo;s rules and show how they are applicable to real, actual careers. And in most of the success stories, he traces their story for more than a decade of building up &amp;ldquo;career capital&amp;rdquo;, again emphasizing hard work over dreaming of overnight success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally relate to the concept of not being defined by passion and instead working hard to earn &amp;ldquo;career capital&amp;rdquo; and the idea that you can cash that capital in for more control. This mirrors my own career path where I spent more than a decade working for some multinational company, not really specializing in anything in particular and developing a variety of interests before deciding to use that career capital to go freelance and establish more control over my life. What I don&amp;rsquo;t have yet, is the overarching &amp;ldquo;mission&amp;rdquo; described by the author&amp;rsquo;s Rule #4. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a unifying vision driving my life forward, probably a result of my being very &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/unfocused/&#34;&gt;unfocused&lt;/a&gt;. Or perhaps I already have one and it is yet to be clearly articulated? Hmm, we&amp;rsquo;ll see. In any case, I find the book&amp;rsquo;s contents quite relevant to my own career and the ideas presented here will probably be relevant to me personally as I try to crystallize my own plans for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is a relatively short (Kindle version says 276 pages, and a lot of that is notes and links) and a quick read (I finished it piecemeal over 3 days, but could have easily finished in 1). I think I got it on sale a few months ago for around $4, not bad for that price, and a decent pickup for anyone looking to chart a clearer career path.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: March 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/watching-lately-march-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/watching-lately-march-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The big one this month was &lt;strong&gt;Captain Marvel&lt;/strong&gt;. I posted &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/183266384975/captain-marvel-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;the usual spoiler-free review over on Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, but I have some more spoiler-y thoughts over here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I thought the movie was ok, I was underwhelmed by the third act and specifically the lack of any serious threat for Carol to defeat towards the end of the movie. As this &lt;a href=&#34;https://mabeloni-sandwich.tumblr.com/post/183645870983/the-biggest-problem-with-every-single-bad-review&#34;&gt;tumblr post explains&lt;/a&gt; more clearly than I ever could, perhaps the issue is that the narrative is not something targetted towards me as a man, who has not experienced the emotional gaslighting IRL that many women are exposed to. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting way to frame the narrative, and probably explains why some movies (i.e. chick flicks) really don&amp;rsquo;t appeal to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did enjoy most everything else about the movie, especially most of the comic book tie-ins and links to other MCU movies. I appreciated how they re-told the &amp;ldquo;Carol getting her powers from an explosion&amp;rdquo; and Mar-vell still being there. I appreciate the surprise that Annette Benning was Mar-Vell all along. I appreciate their reimagination of the Kree Supreme Intelligence. I appreciate that by the time Avengers Endgame or any potential Captain Marvel 2 rolls around, Monica Rambeau will be old enough to be her own superhero as well. I appreciate all the little things connecting this movie to the first Iron Man, the first Avengers, and even to Infinity War itself. I also appreciated that their depiction of the Kree did not rule out the Agents of SHIELD versions existing! (That being said, I would have appreciated an explanation for why some Kree are blue and some are not!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much else to report. The Arrowverse is limping along. Recent episodes of &lt;strong&gt;Supergirl&lt;/strong&gt; have been great, I loved Jon Cryer as Lex Luthor, and I love how they&amp;rsquo;ve been able to adapt multiple comic book storylines this season such as &lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s So Funny About Truth, Justice, &amp;amp; the American Way?&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;American Alien&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Red Son&lt;/em&gt;. (Excuse me, red daughter.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In more sci-fi land, &lt;strong&gt;The Orville&lt;/strong&gt; has been fantastic, with their surprise twist to the Isaac storyline culminating in one of the best space battles portrayed on TV. &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; is not as good, but I still like it, as it feels a lot more classic Trek than S1 and the overarching S2 plot is more interesting to me too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next month is looking packed. The big headliners to look forward to are of course &lt;strong&gt;Avengers Endgame&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Shazam&lt;/strong&gt;, and the final season of &lt;strong&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: February 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/watching-lately-february-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/watching-lately-february-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;Alita: Battle Angel&lt;/strong&gt;, with the friend who introduced me to the series in the first place. The movie looked fantastic and the fight scenes were great. Plot was supercondensed, several books&amp;rsquo; worth of story combined into one. Ended in a weird place, kinda? Easily the best western live action anime adaptation by far.&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2019-02-07 14:06:10&#34;&gt;7 Feb 2019 2:06pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&lt;/p&gt;

        









  



&lt;a href=&#34;#18a9e28c111c6e73a78bad7b0dd717a5-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/1093511652643762176-DyzvBZ9W0AAC1JS_hu8c01b3250c12dfdca724a95257de8ea7_116708_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up
After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&#34; title=&#34;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up
After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;18a9e28c111c6e73a78bad7b0dd717a5-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/1093511652643762176-DyzvBZ9W0AAC1JS.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up
After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;7 Feb 2019 2:06pm&#34;&gt;7 Feb 2019 2:06pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;







    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another volume of &amp;ldquo;catching up with older films to improve my geek cred&amp;rdquo;, I watched &lt;strong&gt;The Usual Suspects&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. The movie was still really good, despite the internet having spoiled the Keyser Soze twist for me (and countless others) many years ago. I can see why Spacey won an Oscar for his performance here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;strong&gt;Ralph Breaks The Internet&lt;/strong&gt; with the nieces last weekend. The younger one really enjoyed the scenes with the Disney princesses. Movie was pretty good, despite losing the novelty of the first film. Many tropes were visited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over on the Netflix side, I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying &lt;strong&gt;The Patriot Act with Hasan Minaj&lt;/strong&gt;. Highly informative about a wide range of topics, I thought it would be solely about politics, but there were some surprising discussions on things like, uh, shoes? Conservatives may be annoyed by the liberal bias, but otherwise the show does a good job of breaking down complicated topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also had a few seasons of &lt;strong&gt;Family Guy&lt;/strong&gt; up recently, and it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good series to have running in the background while I&amp;rsquo;m working on other stuff so I managed to watch all of it fairly easily. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s good for my mental health though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Seth MacFarlane shows, I&amp;rsquo;ve caught up with &lt;strong&gt;The Orville&lt;/strong&gt; recently, and this show has been great. It&amp;rsquo;s basically &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; for a newer generation, but with a different (and sometimes more interesting) mythos and history and so on. The show is much more willing to tackle complex ideas relevant to the modern world as well. I hope it does well and goes on for many seasons to come.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: January 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/watching-lately-january-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/watching-lately-january-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bumblebee&lt;/strong&gt; only came out over here in January (thanks to the usual MMFF shenanigans), and I decided to watch it on a whim. Pretty decent soft reboot, read my &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/181926569205/bumblebee-spoiler-free-review-attached-image&#34;&gt;spoiler-free review over on the Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first half of &lt;strong&gt;Young Justice Outsiders&lt;/strong&gt; is out, and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. Focus is back on a smaller group after the larger team in YJ season 2. A few new characters are introduced and I learned about a couple of DC heroes I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with before. Probably still the best animated superhero show to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Netflix side, season 2 of &lt;strong&gt;Punisher&lt;/strong&gt; is out as well. I finished watching it but didn&amp;rsquo;t bother posting a spoiler-free review this time. It was okay, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have much commentary. Not as strikingly good as the first one was, but pretty decent. It feels weird now watching these shows knowing they are likely to end soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 2 of &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; has also started! Only two episodes in so far, but still very good. Feels a lot more classic Trek than the previous season, and a much lighter tone, not just because their captain isn&amp;rsquo;t afraid of the light anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Netflix history also says I watched Bird Box, which became a bit viral early this month for some reason, but that was just my niece making my mom watch it with her, even after I warned her she would get scared (she did).&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: December 2018
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/watching-lately-december-2018/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/watching-lately-december-2018/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I very much enjoyed &lt;strong&gt;Elseworlds&lt;/strong&gt;, the Arrowverse crossover this year. I mean sure, a lot of it didn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense, but it was like a love letter to DC fans. I actually consider myself more of a Marvel fan than DC, but I still loved it! I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/181046297550/aquaman-spoiler-free-review-i-came-in-with-low&#34;&gt;a spoiler-free review over on the Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;strong&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/strong&gt; on a couple of &amp;ldquo;Best TV of 2018&amp;rdquo; lists so I decided to catch up with it since it was on Netflix. I was actually two seasons behind. This series is great, and I really enjoy Bob Odenkirk&amp;rsquo;s portrayal, but it might be just a bit overhyped for me. We already know where Jimmy/Saul, Mike, the Salamancas, and Gus Fring end up given &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;, so that kind of takes away a bit of tension. Still, it&amp;rsquo;s a fine TV show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got caught up with &lt;strong&gt;The Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a weird show for me to watch given how hillbilly it is, but I find the perspective strangely refreshing. Also, Elisha Cuthbert really helps. I was surprised that they had killed off Danny Masterson&amp;rsquo;s character (oops spoilers), apparently it was a #MeToo thing or such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Into the Spider-Verse&lt;/strong&gt; was great, especially for a fan of the comics. You can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/181171084805/into-the-spider-verse-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;my spoiler-free review on tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;Aquaman&lt;/strong&gt; with a friend at UPTC, my first time watching at the theaters there. I had low expectations, but the movie was a surprisingly fun spectacle. You can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/181046297550/aquaman-spoiler-free-review-i-came-in-with-low&#34;&gt;my spoiler-free review on tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At home, I watched &lt;strong&gt;Incredibles 2&lt;/strong&gt; with the niece, who has a bad habit of spoiling things for movies she&amp;rsquo;s already seen. To the tune of &amp;ldquo;Oh, did you know &lt;code&gt;Character&lt;/code&gt; is actually &lt;code&gt;Villain&lt;/code&gt;?!?&amp;rdquo;. Still, the movie was nice, exceeded my expectations. It expanded the Incredibles&amp;rsquo; superhero universe and there was even some surprise Bob Odenkirk!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also watched &lt;strong&gt;Solo: A Star Wars Story&lt;/strong&gt; on Christmas eve (since we didn&amp;rsquo;t get a Christmas Star Wars film this year). We didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to finish it before we went to mass though, so I finished the movie myself a couple of days later. I had skipped watching this in the theater given the mediocre ratings, but now that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it, that&amp;rsquo;s a decision I&amp;rsquo;ve come to regret. It&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable movie with a servicable plot, especially given it&amp;rsquo;s basically meant to expound upon a couple of throwaway lines from the original trilogy. The plot even leaves some dangling threads that could have picked up in succeeding movies, had Disney not decided to scrap (at least for now) the Star Wars spinoff movies. The movie compares unfavorably to &lt;em&gt;Rogue One&lt;/em&gt;, which had the far superior heist scheme. In both movies we expected many of the introduced characters to be killed off, but the Rogue One deaths were much better than the Solo ones. Still, it&amp;rsquo;s an okay addition to the Star Wars universe. I read that it also has some tie-ins to the various animated series, which I&amp;rsquo;m not too familiar with. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get into those someday.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: November 2018
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/watching-lately-november-2018/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/watching-lately-november-2018/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, I watched two biopics this month. The first one is &lt;strong&gt;Hidden Figures&lt;/strong&gt;, about three black women who were instrumental during the early days of NASA leading up to the Friendship 7 mission piloted by John Glenn. The movie is fairly interesting if you are even remotely interested in either the challenges faced in black history or math and science or the early days of the space program competition between the USA and Russia. It feels even more appropriate to have watched this since it helps me appreciate the recent Insight mission. (The Oatmeal has &lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/insight&#34;&gt;a fun preview of this event&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second biopic was &lt;strong&gt;Bohemian Rhapsody&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a magnificent film, both for the music and the Freddie Mercury story. I guess it appeals more to those who are familiar with Queen music though. I&amp;rsquo;ve read that the movie isn&amp;rsquo;t super accurate especially with regards to the timeline, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s fine. Both the liberties they take and the music serve to construct a compelling narrative. The movie ends with a ten-minute recreation of the 1985 Live Aid concert and they do a good job of communicating the insane energy at Wembley Stadium back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In less-biographical movies, I also watched &lt;strong&gt;Teen Titans Go To The Movies&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of Teen Titans Go, it&amp;rsquo;s way too silly and it&amp;rsquo;s obviously for kids, I much preferred the previous Teen Titans series. I only got a copy of this movie because my niece said they watched this all the time back home, so now they can watch it when they&amp;rsquo;re over here either. I did enjoy the ridiculous plot and the Stan Lee cameo, but this isn&amp;rsquo;t something I would have watched in the theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In rewatch land, since I finished the Spider-Man PS4 game lately, I also watched &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man 2&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man 3&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Amazing Spider-Man&lt;/strong&gt;, they&amp;rsquo;re nice movies to have playing in the background while you&amp;rsquo;re working on other stuff. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/07/movies-spiderman-2/&#34;&gt;Tobey 2&lt;/a&gt; was pretty good and I think it aged well, I&amp;rsquo;d say comparable with Tobey 1 even. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/05/spider-man-3/&#34;&gt;Tobey 3&lt;/a&gt; was trying to do way too much what with Venom and Sandman and Harry-Goblin. Andrew 1 had a lot of potential, but I think this series leaned too much into the dark and mysterious and sinister plot route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, nothing much other than the usual superhero series, though I&amp;rsquo;m still behind on Gifted and Doctor Who. I caught Trevor Noah&amp;rsquo;s new Netflix special, it was okay, but too exceptionally. Netflix also added a couple of &amp;ldquo;best of&amp;rdquo; seasons of Jeopardy which I thoroughly enjoyed. Watching these makes me think I&amp;rsquo;d never be able to win an episode of Jeopardy, but of course I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s fair to compare myself to some of Jeopardy&amp;rsquo;s all-time champions.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Eternal or &#34;Eternal primer for MTG players&#34;
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal-or-eternal-primer-for-mtg-players/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2018 02:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal-or-eternal-primer-for-mtg-players/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I said in my previous &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/&#34;&gt;Duelyst review&lt;/a&gt; that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.direwolfdigital.com/eternal/&#34;&gt;Eternal&lt;/a&gt; didn&amp;rsquo;t really hook me. That was in Feb 2017. I stopped playing Duelyst after around six months. I started playing Eternal regularly July of that year, and have been playing regularly ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What changed my mind? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure, but once I got around to playing Eternal regularly, I found myself enjoying it. I think one of the main factors is that out of all &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/ccgs/&#34;&gt;the online ccgs&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve tried, Eternal is the one that&amp;rsquo;s closest to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/categories/magic-the-gathering/&#34;&gt;Magic the Gathering&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s not really surprising, since a number of Eternal&amp;rsquo;s lead designers are MTG Pros and Hall of Famers. As such, my review will tend to compare Eternal to MTG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eternal games play out almost exactly like MTG games. Each player plays mana sources (called Power in eternal), then uses his pool to play creatures and spells to interact with the enemy. You send in creatures to attack and deal damage to the enemy until the enemy&amp;rsquo;s life total is at 0 (Eternal starts at 25 life vs MTG&amp;rsquo;s 20.), the enemy can send his units to block your attackers, and so on. Eternal feels like a smoother, more streamlined MTG. I&amp;rsquo;m also playing MTG Arena regularly these days, so I know that by comparison Eternal&amp;rsquo;s games feel like they flow quicker and finish faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the relevant changes that I believe make it feel like a faster MTG:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;limited fast effect windows. This is the main one. MTG Arena has to stop and ask you what you want to do every time there&amp;rsquo;s an opportunity to play fast effects, and there&amp;rsquo;s tons. In Eternal, there are only three windows: during combat, at the end of the enemy&amp;rsquo;s turn, and whenever the enemy plays a spell. And you can only play fast spells (basically MTG instants), there are no creature abilities to activate at instant speed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the game will automatically pass priority whenever you don&amp;rsquo;t have any relevant plays. MTG Arena does this automatically as well. You can turn it off, since it has a bit of disadvantage (it conveys information to the opponent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;similar to HS, Eternal limits the number of creatures you can have on the board. Eternal allows twelve on each side vs Heathstone&amp;rsquo;s seven. This is more due to technical constraints than anything else. MTG Arena has to play the same on paper, so you can crash the game by generating some large number of creatures somehow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#f653e5535156b73f5d214483a5874674-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal-or-eternal-primer-for-mtg-players/eternal_board_limit_hub36af13f9519955d1931871364475345_567453_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;f653e5535156b73f5d214483a5874674-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal-or-eternal-primer-for-mtg-players/eternal_board_limit.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;25 Nov 2018 2:00am&#34;&gt;25 Nov 2018 2:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eternal&amp;rsquo;s power system is similar to MTG&amp;rsquo;s mana system - you have to draw cards that provide power the same way that you have to draw lands in MTG. This means one of MTG&amp;rsquo;s inherent &amp;ldquo;problems&amp;rdquo; - mana screw - still happens in Eternal. In fact, on the forums mana screw is one of the complaints that often comes out (I suspect from former HearthStone players). Coming from MTG, I understand that building your deck to avoid mana screw is one of the skills needed in games like Magic and Eternal. Eternal eases the problem a little bit with its mulligan mechanic: Eternal gives you one free mulligan, and the 2nd hand is guaranteed to have 2-4 power. As I write this, they are also experimenting with allowing a 2nd mulligan that drops your starting hand size by one, still with the guarantee of 2-4 power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color screw can still be a problem in Eternal, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough of the correct influence (Eternal&amp;rsquo;s analogue to color), you can&amp;rsquo;t play cards that require that influence. They improved on this a bit because in Eternal, power and influence aren&amp;rsquo;t tied together the way mana and color are, they are independent. The influence requirements are &lt;em&gt;minimums&lt;/em&gt; that aren&amp;rsquo;t used up like mana of a given color. That is, if you have one Fire influence, you can play any number of cards that require one Fire influence. In MTG, if you only have one source of red mana, that red mana can only be spent for one card at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of color/influence, Eternal has five factions like MTG&amp;rsquo;s color pie:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Faction&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Symbol color&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Closest analogous MTG color&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fire&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Red&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Red&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shadow&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Purple&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Black&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Primal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Blue&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Blue&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Justice&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Green&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;White&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Time&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yellow&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Green&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, they don&amp;rsquo;t map cleanly. Often in my own head I still refer to the factions by their MTG analogue (and I call Justice Green and Time White), but I&amp;rsquo;ve been improving on this lately. The play styles largely map correctly though. Fire decks are often aggressive with small quick creatures and burn for reach. Primal decks have card draw and counter magic. Shadow decks have a lot of removal and life draining. Time decks have mana acceleration and big creatures. Justice decks have Wrath of God lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, many of Eternal keywords are similar or analogous to MTG keywords. And they added some fun, unique keywords of their own. Eternal already has a number of expansions out, so there are quite a number of keywords already. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Keyword&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;MTG Analogue&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aegis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hexproof&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unlike hexproof, Aegis only works once (it resets if the unit enters play again). Also, Aegis will protect against Wrath-style effects whereas Hexproof does not. I think this is a neat hexproof variant that could also work in MTG, maybe.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Berserk&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;None&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This is a fun, unique risk-reward mechanic that has no equivalent in MTG. Basically you can choose to attack twice if a unit has Berserk, one time only. After activating berserk, the unit becomes Reckless.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Haste&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deadly&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deathtouch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deadly + Overwhelm/Quick Draw work exactly the same as MTG&amp;rsquo;s Deathtouch + Trample/First Strike&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Double Damage&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Double Strike&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Well, the damage is just doubled, there&amp;rsquo;s no second damage step.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Endurance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vigilance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;In addition to not tapping to attack, units with Endurance can&amp;rsquo;t be tapped (exhausted) or stunned by enemy effects&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Flying&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Flying&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Big surprise!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Killer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fight&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fight is a close analogue, but there are major differences. A unit with Killer can attack one enemy unit at any time (even with summoning sickness), and the fight is treated as a combat (effects that trigger on attack or block will take place)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lifesteal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lifelink&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Overwhelm&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Trample&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Quickdraw&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;First strike&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;But only when attacking. No defensive first strike!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Reckless&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Attacks each turn if able&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Revenge&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The first time this unit dies, it gains Destiny (automatically played when drawn) and is shuffled back the top ten cards of your deck&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unblockable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unblockable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Warcry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Warcry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This was my favorite when first starting out. Whenever a unit with Warcry attacks, the next unit or weapon in your deck gains an attack/defense buff. Value! This is one of those abilities that can&amp;rsquo;t happen in a paper game like MTG.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scout&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scry&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just the battle skills! Eternal also has a set of trigger keywords that define when an effect will happen. There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Summon&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Entomb&lt;/strong&gt;, analogous to HS&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Battlecry&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Deathrattle&lt;/strong&gt;; &lt;strong&gt;Empower&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spark&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Tribute&lt;/strong&gt;, are analogous to MTG&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Landfall&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Bloodthirst&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Morbid&lt;/strong&gt;; and so on. There&amp;rsquo;s far too many to cover here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re: other mechanics, the main one to note is that Eternal takes full advantage of the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s a computer game and doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to deal with player memory issues. This means that buffs and debuffs stay on cards, even when they leave zones. Unlike Hearthstone, the graveyard/void zone exists and thus reanimator strategies are viable. There is some amount of RNG, such as &amp;ldquo;units gain a random battle skill&amp;rdquo;, but not as much as HS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A nice mechanic they have is the &amp;ldquo;Market&amp;rdquo;. Basically each deck can have a set of five cards set aside as a &amp;ldquo;Market&amp;rdquo;/sideboard, and there are a set of cards (one for each faction) that allow you to fetch a card of that faction from the market. Basically similar to the way the Wishes worked in Magic. It&amp;rsquo;s a clever approach that allows for some form of &amp;ldquo;sideboarding&amp;rdquo; even for best of one matches&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skill Level, Competitive Play and F2P&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Eternal is inherently more skill-based than HS because of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manabase decisions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;much less RNG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;attacking and blocking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meta for competitive play is rather healthy, there are a number of viable decks in different archetypes that can you to Master ranking on the ladder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eternal provides several modes for Limited play as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s Forge, which is similar to Hearthstone&amp;rsquo;s Arena&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s monthly sealed leagues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s 4-pack draft available at any time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of F2P, Eternal is the most generous among CCGs I&amp;rsquo;ve tried in terms of how much it gives players for free, as far as I can tell. Aside from the standard three daily quests, your first ranked win of each day gets you a free pack. There&amp;rsquo;s a free Gauntlet mode where you fight against AIs, and just grinding Gauntlet can get you enough gold to purchase the campaigns, which give you more cards to work with. When you start out, you quickly earn starter decks for five factions and five color pairs. These decks are decent enough for ranked play; I remember I took the Rakano and Stonescar starter decks up to Gold rank during my first month. They recently nerfed gold rewards from chests (that you earn from quests) by 10% for balance reasons, but I think the rewards are still pretty generous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hit Master rank in constructed on my third month of play (same rate as with Duelyst I believe) and have regularly hit it ever since. By comparison, I&amp;rsquo;ve never hit legend rank in HS. It really helps that Eternal games are quick and a lot more fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a while longer to hit Master rank in draft - more than one year in fact, I only hit it last week. This was the last achievement I needed for Steam completion too.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#16ef1703755644be4695f85a61fdc85d-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal-or-eternal-primer-for-mtg-players/eternal_draft_master_hu00fcd3b62d84728fe9d738e25b00aec7_359716_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;16ef1703755644be4695f85a61fdc85d-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal-or-eternal-primer-for-mtg-players/eternal_draft_master.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;25 Nov 2018 2:00am&#34;&gt;25 Nov 2018 2:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lore and Aesthetics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eternal&amp;rsquo;s world is described as &amp;ldquo;Six Guns and Sorcery Combined&amp;rdquo;, which means there&amp;rsquo;s Gunslingers alongside magic users and shamans and such. There&amp;rsquo;s a little bit of steampunk in there too, along with valkyries, yetis, centaurs, wisps, dinosaurs, radiants (basically magical aliens), grenadin (basically goblins), sentinels (basically giant robots), and a bunch of other stuff too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty fun, and the story is continuously being updated. Each monthly league and the occasional campaign or new card set represents a change in the story. Major characters are represented by powerful cards and often have multiple versions representing their stages of growth. A prime example is Icaria, the young Valkyrie captain who later becomes a rebellious keyword-souped Akroma-like avenger after witnessing her superior&amp;rsquo;s misdeeds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://vignette.wikia.nocookie.net/eternalcardgame/images/6/6d/Icaria%2C_Valkyrie_Captain.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/318?cb=20180307222958&#34; alt=&#34;Icaria, Valkyrie Captain&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://vignette.wikia.nocookie.net/eternalcardgame/images/e/eb/Icaria%2C_the_Liberator.png/revision/latest/scale-to-width-down/318?cb=20181012184436&#34; alt=&#34;Icaria, the Liberator&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from the lore, I like the game&amp;rsquo;s overall aesthetic. Many game actions have smooth and quick animations that keep the game alive. Units with Aegis are wrapped with an animated bluish glow. Legendary units crash onto the field with force, attacking units dive towards their blockers, and so on. I think the animations and aesthetic are comparable with HS in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is now: will I keep playing Eternal now that I&amp;rsquo;ve hit my usual target of all the Steam achievements? Or should I focus on MTG Arena for the foreseeable future? (MTG Arena blog post sometime in the next month maybe)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is still pretty fun to play Eternal, and they just came out of Early Access and launched on XBoxOne, so there might be an upsurge in community activity. I think I will play it for a while, the designers seem to know what they&amp;rsquo;re doing, and a new set comes out next month too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few other online CCGs I have accounts for that I haven&amp;rsquo;t really gotten into for some reason or another, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll try giving them another chance next year. There&amp;rsquo;s Spellweaver (very slow games and kinda boring), Shadowverse (not a fan of the aesthetic and ugh the UI is so messy/cluttered), and Gwent (uh, it&amp;rsquo;s weird). There&amp;rsquo;s Valve&amp;rsquo;s Artifact coming out too, I might try that if reviews are good. So many card games to play!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal-or-eternal-primer-for-mtg-players/eternal_board_limit_hub36af13f9519955d1931871364475345_567453_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal-or-eternal-primer-for-mtg-players/eternal_draft_master_hu00fcd3b62d84728fe9d738e25b00aec7_359716_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game Review: Marvel&#39;s Spider-Man for PS4
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/game-review-marvels-spider-man-for-ps4/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 02:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/game-review-marvels-spider-man-for-ps4/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Finally had the time to play &lt;em&gt;Marvel&amp;rsquo;s Spider-Man for PS4&lt;/em&gt;. Took just a little under two weeks from start to Platinum. Maybe mild, unmarked spoilers somewhere in this review, be warned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall: the game was amazing and spectacular and fun, especially for a big comic book fan like me, well worth the buy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mechanics: Combat felt a bit weird to me at first, mainly because I was expecting it to be closer to Arkham-style combat, and I kept trying to use Spider-Man&amp;rsquo;s Circle Dodge the same way I use Batman&amp;rsquo;s Triangle counter, and that got me clocked by the first boss of the game (Kingpin) a few times. Spider-man&amp;rsquo;s Dodge doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow you to cancel out of existing animations like Batman&amp;rsquo;s counter, so I really needed to unlearn that instinct. Once you get a hang of it, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good, but feels a lot more chaotic than Arkham style combat. Arkham combat felt a lot more rhythmic where you just tap commands out and point at the baddie you want to hit. Here it feels like you have to be jumping all the time and swinging across the air and moving the camera around to look for objects to throw at enemies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mechanics: Web-swinging around Manhattan also felt weird at first. Sometimes the command to web swing would be unresponsive, which I would later realize would be because I was at a height that was too high to find surfaces to swing from. Once you get the hang of it, it feels very smooth and fun and you&amp;rsquo;re zipping around Manhattan like a boss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story: Peter Parker in this universe is reminiscent of old-school Peter Parker who&amp;rsquo;s always late to things and always behind on his rent. The early parts have him getting evicted from his apartment (classic Parker!) and looking for a place to crash. (Although after that point, it&amp;rsquo;s never mentioned where he&amp;rsquo;s sleeping, if he is at all.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story: Spider-man here is however, a well-known public figure, a veteran of super-heroing who even gets some assistance from law enforcement primarily in the form of Captain Yuri Watanabe. He&amp;rsquo;s been webslinging around long enough to build a stable of villains who are constantly referenced about being held in the Raft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mechanics: There&amp;rsquo;s actually a lot to do around the city. Not really collectibles, but more like different kinds of challenges and missions. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of crimes to stop that you&amp;rsquo;ll hear on police bands as you&amp;rsquo;re web-swinging around. More difficult crimes and missions unlock as the story progresses, and they all come with optional objectives (such as perform X type of special move, etc) that give you bonus rewards. There&amp;rsquo;s also stealth missions reminiscent of Arkham&amp;rsquo;s predator modes, pigeon chasing, research missions that have you doing all sorts of weird tasks, and so on. Missions typically reward you with some form of tokens, which are used to unlock suits, gadgets and upgrades. This Spider-Man has a lot of gadgets, making him closer to a Batman figure in this universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story: In this universe, J. Jonah Jameson is retired from his days at the Daily Bugle and instead hosts an internet radio show where as can be expected, he&amp;rsquo;s always castigating Spider-Man. His broadcasts come in as you&amp;rsquo;re swinging around the city, and Jonah will often comment on things you&amp;rsquo;ve recently done or missions recently accomplished. I especially like it when one of the missions had you doing something ridiculous like intentionally swinging through smog and Jonah makes wild speculations about what the hell you were smoking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mechanics: The suit selection in the game is fairly good, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of suits available and you unlock more as you level up (you need to purchase them with tokens). You can change costumes at any time, and most cutscenes will show Spider-Man wearing whatever suit you have on at the time, which can be sometimes hilarious. I&amp;rsquo;m severaly disappointed at the lack of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vignette.wikia.nocookie.net/spiderman/images/6/69/F0ab528486904cef1297397514b73ef9.jpg/revision/latest?cb=20120721011355&#34;&gt;Fantastic Four Amazing Bag-Man costume&lt;/a&gt; though. My favorite costume from this game is the classic comic book costume (screenshots below), I really like how well it&amp;rsquo;s animated so smoothly and gives such a cartoony vibe. I would totally play an entire game rendered in this fashion. It&amp;rsquo;s also hilarious when this costume is used in cutscenes!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/KcHOHTc.png&#34; alt=&#34;My favorite costume!&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/4KOBWj0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Why won&amp;rsquo;t you take me seriously MJ?!?&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imgur.com/XyiqRIW.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Those guns won&amp;rsquo;t work on me, I&amp;rsquo;m a cartoon!&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mystery: I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why, but the distance scaling in this game is super-off. In-game measurements tell me Manhattan island is about 4 km from top to bottom, which feels really small. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manhattan&#34;&gt;Wikipedia entry&lt;/a&gt; says Manhattan is almost 60 sq km, but in-game it can&amp;rsquo;t be more than 10 sq km. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why it would be like this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story/Mechanics: You don&amp;rsquo;t get to play as Peter Parker/Spider-Man all the time, there&amp;rsquo;s also a few missions you have to play out as one of two side characters. One of them is the lovable spunky red-headed Mary Jane Watson, who in this universe is not a supermodel actress, but rather has a more Lois-Lane like role as an investigative reported for the Daily Bugle. That means she gets herself into all sorts of troublesome situations where she has to sneak around enemies in order to escape. She&amp;rsquo;s no damsel in distress here, I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure if Peter ever rescues her directly. I like this MJ iteration, she has a lot more spunk. The other side character you get to play at is young Miles Morales, who enter&amp;rsquo;s Peter&amp;rsquo;s life somewhere in the 2nd act of the story. Miles parts consist of sneaking around as well, although he has a different toolset than MJ, mainly consisting of a hacking app that lets him create distractions to bypass guards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story: One of the best things in this game&amp;rsquo;s story is the mentorship relationship between Peter Parker and Otto Octavius, although if you know comics, you have a pretty good idea of where this is headed. Unlike the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/07/movies-spiderman-2/&#34;&gt;2nd Tobey movie&lt;/a&gt;, the game gives their relationship sufficient time to develop before you start to see signs of trouble. The fall itself is well-executed and heavily foreshadowed and Peter has only himself to blame when he finds out he helped turn his mentor into an insane mechanical octopus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story: The overall story had some twists and some surprises in the ending itself. At the heart of all the problems facing Spider-Man this time around is the incumbent Mayor Norman Osborn, but who never actually turns into a green villain himself. The game&amp;rsquo;s ending heavily hints at a 2nd outing, so they&amp;rsquo;re probably saving Norman for later. Wise decision as well, Spider-Man has a deep bench of villains to pull from, and many of the classic ones haven&amp;rsquo;t been hinted at yet in this game. Aside from the Goblin, the 2nd game could very well introduce us to the Lizard, Sandman, Mysterio, and maybe even Venom among others!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After getting the platinum, I was tempted to purchase the &amp;ldquo;City That Never Sleeps&amp;rdquo; DLCs as well for additional content, but I decided to hold off for now. My experience already feels &amp;ldquo;complete&amp;rdquo; and just right anyway, and adding more missions might be too repetitive. Maybe if it goes on sale sometime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stan Lee (RIP) also had a small cameo in this game. For me it&amp;rsquo;s bittersweet that I got the platinum a couple of days after his death; I consider the game to be a fitting tribute to his life&amp;rsquo;s work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is tradition, here&amp;rsquo;s a screendump, awash with in-game spoilers! (Mainly because I chose to include the automatic screenshots that came with each Trophy unlock). You can see during the later parts I was using the comic costume almost exclusively!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;a/GXG9Qb5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//imgur.com/GXG9Qb5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Late Game Review: The Elder Scrolls V - Skyrim
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 05:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(“Late Game Review&amp;rdquo; because I’m trying to play through games on my ridiculously old backlog, so these games are pretty old)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#1ccd2f8fa01458a68ea2f507764820b1-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/skyrim_hu5ea856a5f4ee556128f7f54c61c7f970_58367_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;1ccd2f8fa01458a68ea2f507764820b1-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/skyrim.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;11 Nov 2018 5:07am&#34;&gt;11 Nov 2018 5:07am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Elder Scrolls V Skyrim came out on 11/11/2011. I remember I bought the game for Steam on launch day. I finally &amp;ldquo;finished&amp;rdquo; it after 350 hours of gameplay and seven years real-time. &amp;ldquo;Finished&amp;rdquo; in this case means &amp;ldquo;achievement complete&amp;rdquo;, not just &amp;ldquo;main quest complete&amp;rdquo;, because as any Bethesda gamer knows, that’s not how their RPGs roll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been looking forward to this game because I had previously enjoyed both ES4: Oblivion and Fallout 3 on PS3 and had also just finished Fallout: New Vegas on Steam and was open to more open-world exploration. I remember being tempted by the badass collector’s edition Alduin statue too but opted out due to price and the fact that it was huge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first character was a male Nord named Hunter. I actually managed to finish the main quest a bit more than a month after getting the game (fairly fast!). I used that first character to complete all the guild quests &amp;ndash; Companions, Mage’s Guild, Thieves Guild, Dark Brotherhood. Afterwards I immersed myself with the open world and toyed around with mods for a bit. I played it on and off again for a few years, and buying the DLC expansions (Hearthfire, Dawnguard and Dragonborn) eventually when they were on sale. I started a few other runs but never got far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2016, I started my final run &amp;ndash; the character that I would be able to bring to &amp;ldquo;achievement completion&amp;rdquo; including all DLCs. This final character was Arche, an Imperial (named after the Tales of Phantasia character).&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#1b033aa856422de0367794d936365c4d-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/2%20-%200mR5pvs_hu199fdb365079d28ca2b0d5d133f8063f_273613_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;My final armor set was the Deathbrand from the Dragonborn expansion since I was trying to level up Light Armor.&#34; title=&#34;My final armor set was the Deathbrand from the Dragonborn expansion since I was trying to level up Light Armor.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;My final armor set was the Deathbrand from the Dragonborn expansion since I was trying to level up Light Armor. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;1b033aa856422de0367794d936365c4d-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/2%20-%200mR5pvs.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My final armor set was the Deathbrand from the Dragonborn expansion since I was trying to level up Light Armor.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;11 Nov 2018 5:07am&#34;&gt;11 Nov 2018 5:07am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I greatly enjoyed this game obviously. It’s been available for a while and been ported to every platform imaginable (it even got a new console release this year!), so there’s not much point talking about the features and whatnot. There are some other things I’d like to cover though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Levelling Up and Legendary Dragons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last achievement I got was the one for killing a legendary dragon, which took me forever. The first issue was that legendary dragon’s don’t spawn unless you’re already level 78. In my 2nd run, I finished the Dawnguard and Dragonborn content and all other achievements by around level 50, and it was a grind to get to level 78 througn conventional means. I didn’t want to do any console cheats to get to 78, so I tried to look for faster ways to level up. There’s a bunch of suggestions on the internet, but here are the best ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Telekinesis &amp;ndash; with enchantments to reduce MP cost, you can use Telekinesis to quickly level up Alteration, simply by levitating an object in front of you until you run out of magic, then you just rest and repeat. This method was still fairly slow for me though and more importantly it was really boring. I read some posts saying you could speed up this process by levitating an object then doing fast travel to a far location so that the game thinks you were using Telekinesis during the entire trip, but I could never get this to work and that feels a bit too exploit-y for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giant blocking &amp;ndash; basically go find a camp with high level giants, then keep blocking their attacks with your shield, healing when necessary. The advantage of this is that it increases multiple skills &amp;ndash; Block, Restoration and Light/Heavy Armor (depending on what you’re wearing). However, it wasn’t much faster than the Telekinesis method and it was also quite tedious and if you weren’t careful, you could die.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, I came upon, in my opinion, the single fastest way to level up in Skyrim: the Illusion mastery spell Harmony. You can use Muffle to level up your Illusion until you learn Harmony, but once you have Harmony, things go into overdrive. You simply go into the middle of Whiterun (near the plaza is fine, or that big tree in the middle section) and cast Harmony. The spell has a very, very wide AOE so it affects almost all citizens, gaining you ridiculous amounts of Illusions skill levels. A single casting can earn you as much as 50+ Illusion levels. This method is quick, safe, easy, and I wish I had discovered it earlier. As it is, it took me from 68 to 81 in around an hour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting to Level 81, the next problem was actually finding a Legendary Dragon to fight. Supposedly there was one that always spawns at Arcwind Point, but I never got one to spawn there, even after clearing my mods. I tried fast-travelling across dragon burial grounds for a while with no luck. Eventually I managed to randomly find a Legendary Dragon while wandering near Dragon Bridge (that’s where my last save is!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a *lot* of mods installed, mostly additional gameplay/quests, additional items added to the game world, convenience mods (adding map markers etc), or stuff to improve the ambience. I’m not much for stuff like graphics improvements or silly mods that add Thomas the Tank Engine or Macho Man dragons. I did have this mod that added Star Wars lightsabers to the game that I wanted to get rid of but I had so many mods installed I always gave up trying to find it on the list. The best mods I used throughout my 350 hours were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nexusmods.com/skyrim/mods/70219/&#34;&gt;Forgotten City&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; this mods add a self-contained quest that involves time travel, groundhog day-style time loops, multiple paths to resolution and investigating a mystery. It was so good it got turned into its own &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/874260/The_Forgotten_City/&#34;&gt;standalone game&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=720815421&#34;&gt;Stan Bush combat music&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; basically replaces Skyrim’s combat music Stan Bush’s songs &amp;ldquo;The Touch&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dare&amp;rdquo; from &lt;em&gt;Transformers The Movie,&lt;/em&gt; giving you a quick adrenaline boost when combat starts. I didn’t actually notice that Skyrim had separate combat music before I installed this mod!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That’s it, out of literally two hundred mods only two stood out for me lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wishlist for Elder Scrolls 6 (or things I wish they had done in Skyrim)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the shovel useful &amp;ndash; it’s weird that there’s a shovel object in the game but it’s not really used for anything, not even as a weapon (I’m sure there’s mods that do that), but I was thinking stuff like buried treasure quests could require you to have a shovel to dig up chests or maybe you can randomly dig in the dirt and hope for goodies (one of the Zelda games did this AFAICR)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mountain climbing &amp;ndash; okay, this wish is straight from Breath of the Wild. One of the best things about BOTW was the ability to climb anywhere, a refreshing addition to an open world overworld after Skyrim’s &amp;ldquo;How the heck do I get to the top of this mountain&amp;rdquo; challenge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More immersion in the Hearthfire DLC &amp;ndash; don’t get me wrong, I liked the Hearthfire DLC, it added a nice opportunity for role-playing with the chance to get married and adopt kids, makes for some nice stories and &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/174535189435/playing-skyrim-i-have-my-wife-aela-and-adopted&#34;&gt;fun moments like this&lt;/a&gt;. After a while everything falls into a rut though, it would have been nice if they had expanded the Hearthfire content with some additional radiant quests. Some random ideas: Your wife or one of your kids goes missing, you have to find her; bandits threaten your house and you and your family have to defend it; you gave one of your kids two many daggers and now he accidentally stabbed one of his friends; your entire house has vanished along with your family! It has been teleported somewhere!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actually just more radiant quests in general would have been nice for a bit more variance (I’m not sure if I will ever be satisfied). I think there’s already mods that do this, but I never tried them out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to take over a fort after you clear it. Skyrim has a lot of small forts or buildings held by bandits or whatever, it would have been a nice alternative to buying a house, after you clear a bandit the Jarl of the containing hold offers you a chance to buy/earn the title for the hold. Once you own a hold, whenever you recruit new followers you can choose to send them to the hold instead of following you around, and same as the house you could build improvements like a smith, stables, etc, and earn money from shops maybe?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have the Legendary Edition on Steam (free upgrade since I had the DLCs), but I don’t think I have the patience to go through the entire game again. The size of the game and the excellent mod community mean one could very well play Skyrim forever, especially since Bethesda tells us &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcgamesn.com/the-elder-scrolls-6/elder-scrolls-6-next-console-generation&#34;&gt;The Elder Scrolls 6 is still a ways away&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, there are still a lot of other games to play, and now I’m finally able to uninstall Skyrim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attached to this post are a dump of my Steam screenshots folder. (These used to be embedded via an &lt;a href=&#34;//imgur.com/a/ZWNxtnz&#34;&gt;Imgur album&lt;/a&gt;, but I edited the post on 2020-Sep to embed them here instead, for reasons.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/1%20-%20AkYnYIn_hu41fdc29aae2780b6be7991aa0a3bf185_310877_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/10%20-%208V0lNyp_hu8d3f036e2555f0927f4f53d2a533fbc2_230249_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/11%20-%201E1Wjhr_hu81cc34b18e3188720809ef6e52910c69_334783_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/12%20-%206s3WfUE_hub5173a4e06373e12fb6b46f44294afa3_217785_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/13%20-%20Iqgq7wB_hub112fda75441dd6662660c55ba2e590e_256787_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/2%20-%200mR5pvs_hu199fdb365079d28ca2b0d5d133f8063f_273613_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;My final armor set was the Deathbrand from the Dragonborn expansion since I was trying to level up Light Armor.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/3%20-%20hnY3iRT_huf4b550b89ece9b543be8ecddcedd4da8_256208_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/4%20-%20QYJOo7q_hu4978170b1732288f06c4db9f6657c375_233812_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/5%20-%20kViXkDw_hu5ea35231c61a28fdd3119d3fcbc8c03c_263182_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/6%20-%20VdTgdpU_hu99fb7cbce8c875aba4799f616b753283_133092_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/7%20-%20ooJRL5p_hu6406719ef51b59371af4224d866e4e77_248943_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/8%20-%20pxB7uUo_hubdde76013a8355c9e4da538726f4198d_145567_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/9%20-%20woxxmcl_hu2a3451c1ceffa0f01dd9a8bf71b31b72_288294_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/skyrim_hu5ea856a5f4ee556128f7f54c61c7f970_58367_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: October 2018
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/october-2018-watching-lately/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 05:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/october-2018-watching-lately/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s Jack Ryan (on Amazon Prime)&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; surprisingly good, even if I&amp;rsquo;m not too familiar with the Jack Ryan stuff. I only know John Krasinski from &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoilers for Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s Jack Ryan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The story starts with Ryan tracking down Suleiman&amp;rsquo;s network via financials, but they never follow-up on who was financing his group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what was the point of the whole drone pilot side story (including the weird trip to the casino and the night with the couple), although it was admittedly kind of entertaining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daredevil season 3 (on Netflix)&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I enjoyed the season a lot. I posted a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/179331448050/daredevil-season-3-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;spoiler-free review over on the ireadcomicbooks tumblr&lt;/a&gt;. Over here I can post spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Murdock&amp;rsquo;s parentage from the comics, so the Maggie reveal came as a surprise to me. A+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sad that there was no Bullseye namedrop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ending kind of flubbed it a bit, could have used an explanation of at what point Matt decided not to kill Fisk. It&amp;rsquo;s not clear if it was something he decided on the spot or if the compromise was part of a plan he devised after interrogating Manning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venom&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I initially wasn&amp;rsquo;t planning on watching this given the terrible early reviews, but eventually I was like, hey I watched &lt;em&gt;X-Men Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt; so might as well watch this too. It turned out not so bad (low expectations helped), although I find the movie&amp;rsquo;s enhancements to the symbiote abilities a bit disconcerting. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/179008685600/venom-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;Read my spoiler-free review here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Batman Ninja &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/179485492410/i-found-out-batman-ninja-is-on-netflix-so-i&#34;&gt;I found out this was on Netflix and went ahead and watched it&lt;/a&gt;. The animations and character designs are nice, but the plot is just ridiculous lol. Feels like someone wrote a Batman fanfic.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Masters of Doom by David Kushner
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-masters-of-doom-by-david-kushner/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 01:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-masters-of-doom-by-david-kushner/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a copy of this book for quite a while now, but for some reason only got around to starting on it three days ago. It&amp;rsquo;s not a particularly long book, but I pretty much devoured it in twenty four hours.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#31c9d6ecd9e95ab6056f95bf11438150-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-masters-of-doom-by-david-kushner/doom_screenshot_huaea7d8611a246efb988e49157007cb6b_97425_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mandatory screenshot of old-school Doom&#34; title=&#34;Mandatory screenshot of old-school Doom&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Mandatory screenshot of old-school Doom (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;31c9d6ecd9e95ab6056f95bf11438150-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-masters-of-doom-by-david-kushner/doom_screenshot.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mandatory screenshot of old-school Doom&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;14 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;14 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book traces the paths of the lives of John Romero and John Carmack &amp;ndash; two legends of the software development world that changed PC gaming forever. It&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic read for anyone who grew up playing PC games during the 80s and 90s. It gives us a birds-eye view of what the burgeoning gaming industry was like back then, not just with the technical and business aspects, but a lot of the human aspects as well: there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of drama, conflict, and betrayal to go around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book&amp;rsquo;s narrative does a good job of contrasting the Two Johns: Carmack was a programmer, a technical wizard who pushed the boundaries of game programming where no one else dared go. He was interested purely in the programming and in the creation of virtual worlds and preferred a smaller, leaner, ruthlessly efficient company focused on making the most of his technology. Romero was a gamer first, and an ambitious and competitive one. He was the number one competitor on their own deathmatch games and dreamt of building a gaming empire, living the life of a rock start among the gaming community as the front man of id software. Together their complimentary skill set would take them through a dizzying rise to fame and fortune in the game development world as they blazed new trails, defined new genres, and inspired a new generation of competitors. At the same time, their differences would ultimately cause them to go down different paths &amp;ndash; knowing full well in advance how the story ended for their partnership made me turn the pages quicker as I dreaded the inevitable split.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a gamer since the late eighties, and though I never considered myself particularly good at first-person shooters, I did play most of the games that comprised id software&amp;rsquo;s wonder years &amp;ndash; Wolfenstein 3D, Doom, Doom II, Quake and Quake II. I will freely confess I mostly used the build-in cheat codes to just fool around in most of these games, although I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I finished Quake II&amp;rsquo;s single-player campaign legitimately. We didn&amp;rsquo;t have good internet back then, so the only opportunity I ever had to play Deathmatch back then was split-screen on a console at a friend&amp;rsquo;s house, even then it was helluva fun. Post-Quake II, I never played FPSes much again, though I did enjoy reading about John Romero and Ion Storm and was looking forward to their promised RPG Anachronox and only later heard about what a failure Daikatana turned out to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have this lingering dream of breaking into game development somehow. Though I&amp;rsquo;m not envious of the death march crunch mode periods typically described in the book, I am a bit envious of what a huge advantage it was for geniuses like Carnack and Romero to have been at the right place and time for the nascent games industry to turn them into legends. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;d have had the technical chops to compete with them if I had the same opportunities, but I surely would have given it a go. I consider myself closer in temperament to Carnack than Romero &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m more interested in the technical side and could probably use some help in the promotion and game design and level design stuff. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ll ever actually get there, but I take solace in this quote from the penultimate chapter of the book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Carmack disdained talk of highfalutin things like legacies but when pressed would allow at least one thought on his own. &#34;In the information age, the barriers just aren’t there,&#34; he said. &#34;The barriers are self-imposed. If you want to set off and go develop some grand new thing, you don’t need millions of dollars of capitalization. You need enough pizza and Diet Coke to stick in your refrigerator, a cheap PC to work on, and the dedication to go through with it. We slept on floors. We waded across rivers.&#34; &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-masters-of-doom-by-david-kushner/doom_screenshot_huaea7d8611a246efb988e49157007cb6b_97425_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Mandatory screenshot of old-school Doom&lt;/p&gt;
    



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Late Game Review -- Ni No Kuni: Wrath of the White Witch (2013)
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/late-game-review-ni-no-kuni-wrath-of-the-white-witch-2013/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 01:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/late-game-review-ni-no-kuni-wrath-of-the-white-witch-2013/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&amp;ldquo;Late Game Review&amp;rdquo; because I&amp;rsquo;m trying to play through games on my ridiculously old backlog, so these games are pretty old)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got my digital PS3 copy of &lt;em&gt;Ni No Kuni&lt;/em&gt; during some kind of PSN sale a while back for like $10 and seeing as how the sequel came out recently, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d better finish the first game before my rarely-used PS3 decides to die on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the game was great and I enjoyed it enough to go for the platinum (post-game was a bit grindy though):&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#ed40962d3c92d7f644de56616ab1d035-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/late-game-review-ni-no-kuni-wrath-of-the-white-witch-2013/DopmwwhUcAMCTak.jpg-large_hu00624a9d56d0f06fdbe8477345c3c7f9_109019_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;ed40962d3c92d7f644de56616ab1d035-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/late-game-review-ni-no-kuni-wrath-of-the-white-witch-2013/DopmwwhUcAMCTak.jpg-large.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;13 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;13 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visually, it&amp;rsquo;s a very pretty game, animated Ghibli-style. The combat system is basically Pokemon. So yes, it&amp;rsquo;s Ghibli+Pokemon. Pokemon in this game are called &amp;ldquo;familiars&amp;rdquo; and each party member can have up to 3 familiars ready to fight in battle. The party members can fight directly as well, but most of the time it&amp;rsquo;s a better idea to let your familiars go at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, the grindiest part of the post-game was collecting all the familiars. Ok, not all of them, the achievement only required 250 different species captured, but that&amp;rsquo;s a helluva lot. During the normal main game run, I only captured a bit less than 100 different species. It was made more grindy by the fact that there&amp;rsquo;s no mechanism for trying to capture the familiars (i.e. pokeballs), you basically just have to beat them in battle and whenever you beat one, there&amp;rsquo;s like a 2-8% chance that you will get an opportunity to recruit it. Thankfully, you can shortcut the grind a bit by collecting the lower level ones and using metamorphoses (basically pokemon evolutions) to get the higher level ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story feels like it&amp;rsquo;s targeted towards children, so it has a kind of fairy tale feel, and the world is very bright and cheerful (mostly) and there&amp;rsquo;s things like a kingdom where the king is a giant cat, and so on. Not that the plot is simple mind you &amp;ndash; there&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit or parallel worlds, a tiny bit of time travel, and a few plot twists thrown in (although you might have seen them coming).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of the game has to be all the puns. Many of the familiars have some sort of pun involved in their name, like there&amp;rsquo;s a dog familiar called &amp;ldquo;Ruffian&amp;rdquo;; there&amp;rsquo;s an egg-shaped familiar with a pharoah mask called &amp;ldquo;Eggyptian&amp;rdquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s a cat thief familiar called &amp;ldquo;Purrloiner&amp;rdquo;, who evolves into a &amp;ldquo;Cutpurrse&amp;rdquo;, and can then evolve into another form which you can fight on the seas called a &amp;ldquo;Puss in Boats&amp;rdquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s a sheep familiar called &amp;ldquo;Baatender&amp;rdquo; who can evolve into a &amp;ldquo;Baabarian&amp;rdquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s a familiar that wears a turban and he&amp;rsquo;s called a &amp;ldquo;Turbandit&amp;rdquo;, and he has higher forms called &amp;ldquo;Turban Myth&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Turban Legend&amp;rdquo;. Okay, I&amp;rsquo;ll stop before I enumerate them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a few other systems familiar to JRPG players &amp;ndash; crafting, a casino, farming enemies for drops, bounty hunts, errand boards and so on on. Oh and some nonsense about fixing people&amp;rsquo;s hearts by finding people willing to contribute attributes like confidence and kindness and whatnot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all a very fun game and something I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have gotten off my backlog! Not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll have time to play the second game though, maybe in another five years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;__&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/late-game-review-ni-no-kuni-wrath-of-the-white-witch-2013/DopmwwhUcAMCTak.jpg-large_hu00624a9d56d0f06fdbe8477345c3c7f9_109019_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>My Top 10 Favorite Movies of All Time
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 01:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This started as one of those silly Facebook memes where you post one thing every day and didn&amp;rsquo;t have to explain and you tagged other people and they continued with the meme. I was very bad at following the meme instructions, but I did find the exercise interesting. I found it difficult to identify 10 specific movies, and since I didn&amp;rsquo;t explain during the FB posts, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d make a blog post about them instead. So here we go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back to the Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#211954650e5fab190b25a1faa13dc56b-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/35972673_10156725021203912_4346463077705711616_n1_hu9dfa9b6a66ad488017a14ca3b0a59a39_92346_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The meme was supposedly to post movie posters, but for the first few ones I was feeling inspired enough to try to draw the movie posters instead.&#34; title=&#34;The meme was supposedly to post movie posters, but for the first few ones I was feeling inspired enough to try to draw the movie posters instead.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The meme was supposedly to post movie posters, but for the first few ones I was feeling inspired enough to try to draw the movie posters instead. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;211954650e5fab190b25a1faa13dc56b-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/35972673_10156725021203912_4346463077705711616_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The meme was supposedly to post movie posters, but for the first few ones I was feeling inspired enough to try to draw the movie posters instead.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started the meme, this was the only movie I was sure would be on my list, the only real easy pick. The rest of the list took a lot more thinking. Back to the Future (and the rest of the trilogy, really it&amp;rsquo;s hard to take them separately) is undoubtedly my favorite movie of all time. (And unquestionably the best time travel of all time, fight me!) There is not much to say: it came out when I was growing up and instilled with me a great love for time travel stories of all kinds. I was especially fond of how cleverly all three movies tied together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Star Wars&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#875308872ffa50d886359ed09811a51c-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/13124658_10154577028233912_132731298121342553_n1_hu5cad911239373995ab8d84b28b83ed34_103940_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Han looks terrible in this drawing. I have yet to master capturing RL human faces properly.&#34; title=&#34;Han looks terrible in this drawing. I have yet to master capturing RL human faces properly.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Han looks terrible in this drawing. I have yet to master capturing RL human faces properly. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;875308872ffa50d886359ed09811a51c-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/13124658_10154577028233912_132731298121342553_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Han looks terrible in this drawing. I have yet to master capturing RL human faces properly.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of both Star Wars and Star Trek, but was a fan of light sabers before phasers. The original Star Wars actually came out the year before I was born, and I never saw any of the original trilogy in the theaters (or at least I don&amp;rsquo;t remember doing so). My earliest memory of these movies was watching A New Hope via betamax at my &lt;em&gt;ninong&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; house during one of our visits there when I was a child.  ANH is my choice here, but Empire and Jedi hold up really well for me as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Dark Knight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#e616091f8ede1ba0372b1fa03c796486-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36314767_10156731563033912_3316285489241128960_n1_hu1b8f59cb036cf5e37dc07c18e0d2bb4f_78432_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;e616091f8ede1ba0372b1fa03c796486-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36314767_10156731563033912_3316285489241128960_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dark Knight is still easily the best superhero film of all time. Marvel&amp;rsquo;s MCU films have been good and entertaining, but nothing still comes close to Nolan&amp;rsquo;s second outing with the Batman. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of movie where I wish I could watch it again for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Few Good Men&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#aa957a74f77ff856ef90a720b1afb93a-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36233305_10156735952983912_6853244375221141504_n1_hudb065ff79c960b1fd51551660b2710fd_78682_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;aa957a74f77ff856ef90a720b1afb93a-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36233305_10156735952983912_6853244375221141504_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may or may not have reenacted that final showdown between Caffy and Jessop more than once. This movie is my favourite lawyer movie and/or show of all time, and was a big reason why I enjoyed lawyer shows like &lt;em&gt;The Practice&lt;/em&gt; moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zoolander&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#50b899abdfa867731026ecdc511b3cb3-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36616232_10156747344928912_7709216556856639488_n1_hu9e56f213d8103841d7ca4e585642761b_77187_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;50b899abdfa867731026ecdc511b3cb3-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36616232_10156747344928912_7709216556856639488_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certain elements of pop culture that have a shared special meaning for certain groups of people. Zoolander is one of them. For some reason, me and a group of work friends latched onto the movie and kept quoting it in our internal chats for ridiculous reasons. The movie isn&amp;rsquo;t of the best quality, but it&amp;rsquo;s hilarious and we still randomly say &lt;em&gt;Merman!!&lt;/em&gt; when we see each other. (The sequel did not make any particular impression on our group.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toy Soldiers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#73af35b4e06b140252ea792c276c576e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36606393_10156750051318912_2937498257388994560_n1_huf8c3987b7acfaf1c139350f312ef52f4_94344_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;73af35b4e06b140252ea792c276c576e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36606393_10156750051318912_2937498257388994560_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those weird instances where I can&amp;rsquo;t tell why I like this movie so much. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen it in the theatres or TV nor do I have any digital copy, but I do believe we had a betamax copy of it back in the day and that me and my brother watched it several times. I have fond memories of this movie and being especially excited at the sequence where they use the flying drone thing to create a distraction while one of the kids sneaks out avoiding the hostage takers in order to communicate information to law enforcement, and he has to sneak back in in time for roll call, which he misses and he has to pretend he was in the shower all along. Actually, that&amp;rsquo;s mainly the only part of the movie that I can clearly remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#17915e2f8b54952267619aeb9d3f2f58-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36849180_10156758886428912_8944807849674932224_n1_huebca6b4e75d9adaa678438e6973b744f_111072_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;17915e2f8b54952267619aeb9d3f2f58-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36849180_10156758886428912_8944807849674932224_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit strange for me to have a kind of a sappy romance movie on this list, but it&amp;rsquo;s also an awesome time loop movie that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many, many times. I thought about putting &lt;em&gt;Ghostbusters&lt;/em&gt; on this list as the representative Bill Murray movie, and it was close but &lt;em&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/em&gt; won out, probably because I really really like stories that mess with the flow of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain America: Winter Soldier&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#35cceb2d82c2bc44c509e0b7744cd9e1-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36825371_10156761814598912_5429857823523602432_n1_hu784036112c08a86a93886e8addaada1c_91677_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;35cceb2d82c2bc44c509e0b7744cd9e1-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36825371_10156761814598912_5429857823523602432_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve greatly enjoyed the MCU over the past ten years, so I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure it deserved at least one slot on this list. I waffled between choosing &lt;em&gt;Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt; for this, but while the space adventure was fun, I chose the Captain America one because of the timely themes of government surveillance and the government being controlled by evil Nazis and well-meaning civil servants having to defy orders to save the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Street Fighter the Movie&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#0148429c1b9b3104fba412708b5c4543-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36866236_10156763524533912_7213879159724965888_n1_hu78273c5fd6613c6ece6abcc2614de68e_107837_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;0148429c1b9b3104fba412708b5c4543-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36866236_10156763524533912_7213879159724965888_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like &lt;em&gt;Zoolander&lt;/em&gt; was the cult classic for my work friends, &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter The Movie&lt;/em&gt; is the so-bad-its-good cult classic for me and my high school friends. The person who tagged me to make this list had to comment that he wishes he had added this one to his list since we basically quote it all the time whenever we get together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transformers the Movie&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#dd543702ac753002ea253fdb22727625-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36915645_10156766339513912_8749918855305887744_n1_hu93c80739fed7dc6b145b65068e735fa2_166614_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;dd543702ac753002ea253fdb22727625-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36915645_10156766339513912_8749918855305887744_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transformers the Movie&lt;/em&gt; is basically a summary of everything that was awesome about childhood pop culture in the 1980s. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad no one ever thought about making a series of live-action movies in this franchise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started this list I had trouble getting beyond the first item, but after having thought about it a while, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of other movies I&amp;rsquo;d have liked to be able to fit in this list. _Ghostbusters, Die Hard, the Indiana Jones trilogy, Con Air, Shawshank Redemption, Inception, Infinity War, The Lord of the Rings trilogy, _and that&amp;rsquo;s just off the top of my head. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! What are your top ten favourite movies of all time?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/13124658_10154577028233912_132731298121342553_n1_hu5cad911239373995ab8d84b28b83ed34_103940_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Han looks terrible in this drawing. I have yet to master capturing RL human faces properly.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/35972673_10156725021203912_4346463077705711616_n1_hu9dfa9b6a66ad488017a14ca3b0a59a39_92346_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;The meme was supposedly to post movie posters, but for the first few ones I was feeling inspired enough to try to draw the movie posters instead.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36233305_10156735952983912_6853244375221141504_n1_hudb065ff79c960b1fd51551660b2710fd_78682_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36314767_10156731563033912_3316285489241128960_n1_hu1b8f59cb036cf5e37dc07c18e0d2bb4f_78432_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36606393_10156750051318912_2937498257388994560_n1_huf8c3987b7acfaf1c139350f312ef52f4_94344_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36616232_10156747344928912_7709216556856639488_n1_hu9e56f213d8103841d7ca4e585642761b_77187_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36825371_10156761814598912_5429857823523602432_n1_hu784036112c08a86a93886e8addaada1c_91677_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36849180_10156758886428912_8944807849674932224_n1_huebca6b4e75d9adaa678438e6973b744f_111072_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36866236_10156763524533912_7213879159724965888_n1_hu78273c5fd6613c6ece6abcc2614de68e_107837_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36915645_10156766339513912_8749918855305887744_n1_hu93c80739fed7dc6b145b65068e735fa2_166614_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The 1-Page Marketing Plan by Allan Dib
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-the-1-page-marketing-plan-by-allan-dib/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 01:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-the-1-page-marketing-plan-by-allan-dib/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I realise it&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird for me to be reviewing a marketing book, given my self-proclaimed aversion to marketing and sales. A while back I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2018/06/book-review-tribe-of-mentors-by-tim-ferris/&#34;&gt;review for Tim Ferris&amp;rsquo; book Tribe of Mentors&lt;/a&gt; on this blog, and for some reason someone decided to contact me citing this review and asked if I would review this other book and they would give me a complimentary copy. This was something new to me, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try it out! (I guess this a thing I do know. Feel free to send me books on random topics to review!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/1-Page-Marketing-Plan-Customers-Money/dp/1989025013/ref=la_B01B715MGW_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1529560817&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Link to the book on Amazon.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, on to the book: It&amp;rsquo;s relatively short, it only took me a while to get through it because of general busy-ness. Coming from someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much experience in marketing and sales, I think the book gives a decent overview of this space. I have some prior informal knowledge of many of these concepts, but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have a more structured idea of how the general flow of marketing works. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find a lot of modern marketing techniques distasteful. I&amp;rsquo;m not especially fond of people aggressively push-marketing to me via cold calls or pushing flyers in my face. To the book&amp;rsquo;s credit, it points out that such blind-shotgun techniques are wildly ineffective. And while it doesn&amp;rsquo;t go into too much detail about each particular area, I think having a more solid understanding of modern marketing techniques and mentalities will help me &amp;ldquo;understand the enemy&amp;rdquo; better, so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to the 1-page marketing plan itself: I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough marketing knowledge to say whether it&amp;rsquo;s really an innovation in implementation as the author claims, but it seems like a reasonable checklist for a business to consider when planning out their marketing activities. If I ever manage to talk myself into starting a business, the overview given by this book would certainly be useful. The book itself isn&amp;rsquo;t very expensive, so I think it&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable buy for someone new to the marketing space.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Persona 5 (You Never Saw It Coming)
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 01:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My first Persona game was Persona 4 Golden on the Vita &amp;ndash; a fantastic game. After that I dived into Persona 3 Portable and eventually the spin-off games Persona 4 Arena (and Ultimax) and Persona Q on 3DS. So it was no surprise that one of the game releases I was most looking forward to this year would be the next numbered game in the series: Persona 5 on the Playstation 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like P4G before it, the focus is on the school life of a young man forced into a new environment, interspersed with some good old JRPG dungeon crawling. You meet a ragtag group of misfits and somehow band together to save all of Japanese society from itself. Or something to that extent. This is just an excuse to dump some screens of P5, so let&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;#resources&#34;&gt;get that out of the way&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JRPG side streamlines a lot of the problems from P4G: the main story dungeons are hand-built JRPG style dungeons and there are save points in between to make dying not so much of a pain. Even on normal difficulty, I still managed to die a few times &amp;ndash; notably to those Angel enemies that tend to suicide when low on life. And they brought back Persona negotiation! I didn&amp;rsquo;t appreciate this too much in &lt;em&gt;Shin Megami Tensei IV&lt;/em&gt; as it felt a bit obtuse there, but here the Persona&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;personality&amp;rdquo; is shown which makes it easier to figure out the &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be leading a team of thieves there&amp;rsquo;s also a bit of a &amp;ldquo;stealth system&amp;rdquo; while dungeon crawling. It&amp;rsquo;s not a very deep stealth system, basically just hide behind corners and ambush enemies to gain battle advantage. The only problem is that the camera and the controls don&amp;rsquo;t always agree with your stealth plans, and sometimes the wrong button press can lead you to disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Phantom Thieves story is okay, although most of the plot is telegraphed ahead of time. I kind of liked P4G&amp;rsquo;s big murder mystery where you had to figure out who among your confidants was a big ‘ol bad guy. Here in P5, it&amp;rsquo;s painfully obvious who sold you out, even if you hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed his &amp;ldquo;mistake&amp;rdquo; early on. That being said, there is a surprise twist near the end that caught me by surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to P4G, Persona 5 comes out at the height of social media, so while I like the P4G&amp;rsquo;s battle theme a bit better, P5&amp;rsquo;s battle music has managed to become a meme of its own:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WUWQFnC2zqU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must&amp;rsquo;ve seen this video at least 50 times now due to some of my friends (you know who you are).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I dislike about the Persona series is that because of the time management aspect of the game, a lot of things are missable. Since I tend to play RPGs without any guides or walkthroughs the first time around, it&amp;rsquo;s problematic for me. This means that on my first run through I missed completing the Confidants/Social Links, even though when I started the run I told myself I&amp;rsquo;d prioritize them over other activities. Definitely need a second run for the platinum. (Of course, I have yet to platinum P4G either due to a mistake I made during the second run~)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion: Despite (or maybe because of?) it&amp;rsquo;s ridiculousness, Persona 5 is a great game. Story is tight, and the dungeon crawling has been streamlined a lot. That being said, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not a game for everyone, mostly because of the style. If you dislike Japanese stuff or anime or anything turn-based, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not for you. Go play Call of Duty or something. For everyone else, enjoy one of the year&amp;rsquo;s best JRPGs (sorry FF15!)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5-2_hu921f21792efe6df58cfdd76cc74be3f8_1295752_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;This game is educational, I didn&amp;amp;rsquo;t actually know this before.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5-3_huc3882e386c7a8a1fe1199c9823a3a394_1622367_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;That&amp;amp;rsquo;s totally his canon name in the lore.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5-4_hu36baa77a2b24d7d4993bb9d0138d9738_2108521_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Some of them are&amp;amp;hellip;  stranger than the others&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5-5_hud41f742dfb241d068ac375adca4bcf5e_270706_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Your teammates have the utmost respect for you as team leader.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5-6_huce6524213e574f1aa1ba9f56e1737e15_2730189_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5-7_huef1bbf1d2db0431d96dfa605ad8d6cf4_2009996_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;When dungeon crawling, you can summon mighty persona in battle! They&amp;amp;rsquo;re like Pokemon, only way more phallic.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5_huab9f56f516e8a2df605d7d86f58b39c8_656798_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Guardians of the Galaxy Vol 2
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/05/review-guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 01:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/05/review-guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-2/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;First, the spoiler-free summary (spoilers after this part):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;overall a very entertaining movie to sit down and watch popcorn and to enjoy the jokes and the space battles and the different colored lights and the tiny adorable tree creature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GOTG&amp;rsquo;s humor was one of its strong points and for the 2nd movie, they push the comedy up a notch, perhaps a little too much in some places. Lots of funny gags and one-liners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt like some of the character/background development stuff was pushed a bit too hard as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie&amp;rsquo;s plot also felt a bit thin and straightforward. I mean, you could see some of the major plot points coming a mile away. Maybe from the trailers even&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Lord was ok. Gamora/Nebula felt poorly written. Rocket was a bit annoying. Drax and Mantis were ok, although the space they have for Mantis&amp;rsquo; character overlaps with Drax a bit. I&amp;rsquo;m still not super happy with how Drax and Gamora are characterized in the MCU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m less happy with this movie&amp;rsquo;s soundtrack compared to the first one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Certainly not. In fact, she chose to derp around the mall instead of coming with me and my cousin to watch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMAX or not: Some visuals used the 3d effect, but nothing too exaggerated or critical. I&amp;rsquo;d say IMAX optional, but it definitely adds something to some scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are five extra scenes near the credits (one of them is right before the credits roll, so I can&amp;rsquo;t really say &amp;ldquo;post-credit&amp;rdquo; screens). Most of them are just setting the tone for the inevitable GOTG3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, just pay attention to the background of the credits roll as well, it&amp;rsquo;s great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I felt the movie was ok, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of just more of the same of what we got with the first movie, which felt a lot stronger overall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoilers follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would have been silly to expect Ego the Living Planet to have his Marvel comics appearance of a planet with a face, but guess what, we actually got it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stallone as Starhawk and Yondu being officially a member of the &amp;ldquo;original Guardians&amp;rdquo; team was great. Oh and apparently Michael Rosenbaum was Martinex!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Stan Lee cameo here was really meant to push the &amp;ldquo;Stan Lee has been playing the same character in all his cameos&amp;rdquo; narrative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Giving Peter a Zune was a cruel joke on Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s expense, but sets us up for more music (maybe from later decades even!) for the 3rd movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of random other Marvel fan-service cameo appearances too: Watchers, Cosmo, Howard the Duck, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I missed/forgot quite a lot more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Final Fantasy XV
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 01:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;With The FFXIII trilogy not being particularly well-received and FFXIV being an MMO, Final Fantasy XV has been a long awaited as the next mainline single-player game in the much-acclaimed series. This review will have minor spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/mxS7hvb.png&#34; width=&#34;1920&#34; height=&#34;1080&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FFXV follows the story of Noctis, prince of Lucis and his band of brothers (okay they&amp;rsquo;re not really brothers, but they might as well be). They&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be on a road trip to get Noctis married, but things happen along the way and eventually they have to figure out how to liberate their homeland from The Evil Empire. That&amp;rsquo;s the backstory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story as presented in the game has a few problems. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of significant back story and goings-on that happen off-camera:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s both a feature-length movie (Kingsglaive) and a six-episode anime (Brotherhood) that expounds on the four main characters&amp;rsquo; backgrounds and how the current political situation got to where it is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s supposedly a whole effort by minor characters like Cor to organize a resistance against the Empire, but we&amp;rsquo;re never really exposed to it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s Lunafreya, Noctis&amp;rsquo; betrothed, who goes off and does her own stuff to try to undermine the Empire and supposedly help Noctis, but for most of the game it&amp;rsquo;s never really explained what exactly she&amp;rsquo;s doing or how it&amp;rsquo;s relevant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of your friends, Gladio, goes off on a short sidequest of his own and vanishes for a while, and it&amp;rsquo;s never explained WTH that was about. Presumably it will be covered in a future DLC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another problem is that Noctis and the gang spend most of the game sort of lollygagging around enjoying their road trip without much sense of urgency. Understandably they wanted to present an open world this time (since much of the criticism of FFXIII was for its linearity), but the problem is that the open world is filled with a lot of frivolous things that don&amp;rsquo;t seem particularly urgent given the fate of the world being at stake. I mean, the party spends a lot of time camping out, cooking food, fishing, taking pictures, driving around looking for auto parts, and so on. The sense of urgency is not apparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose the lack of urgency is an acceptable trade-off for the open world, but even for the supposed main story quests in the earlier chapters, it&amp;rsquo;s not immediately clear how they serve to help you overcome the Empire. I feel like there should have been more story quests related to helping establish a resistance and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The later chapters narrow down the open world significantly, and the second half of the game takes place outside the main continent where there is significantly less freedom to explore. It feels a bit like they spent a lot of their design budget on the open world half and so just restricted the second half to the meaty story parts. Reminds me a bit of Xenogears disc 2!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the chapters near the end was also executed very poorly. To establish a sense of tension, most of the systems you had been relying on throughout the game are taken away from you. While this would have been okay for a short segment, the chapter goes on a bit too long and ends up being far too tedious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did find myself surprised by events leading up to the final chapter, although I felt like it was another wasted opportunity. The final chapter gives us a glimpse at a different version of the open world but never really let us see most of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ending itself was bittersweet (and easily trolled haha), but I found it an acceptable ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/RTcRL3u.png&#34; width=&#34;1920&#34; height=&#34;1080&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I found the main cast of Noctis, Ignis, Gladio and Prompto to have engaging personalities, they don&amp;rsquo;t really have much backstory in-game (most of the character backstories are in Brotherhood). In fact, later on, a startling revelation is made about one of them and none of them really bat an eye at all. It was in the sense of &amp;ldquo;hey, we don&amp;rsquo;t care about that, we&amp;rsquo;re your friends,&amp;rdquo; but it still felt like something that should have been explored further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interaction among the group is great though. They regularly banter and tease each other even during combat. It really felt like they were a group of long-time friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Combat **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an old-school FF fan, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit I miss ye olde active time battle. FFXV&amp;rsquo;s battles take place entirely in real-time, with the player controlling Noctis and the other characters controlled by AI. The AI control goes about as well as you could expect, they do fine against weak enemies but against tougher battles you find yourself constantly having to help them with potions or other items. You can command them to do special attacks when available, and they will participate in combo attacks when possible, but for the most part it&amp;rsquo;s just Noctis warping and striking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://imgur.com/iEmsTOE.png&#34; width=&#34;1920&#34; height=&#34;1080&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combat is fluid and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of movement and jumping around and looking for opportunities to strike from behind. Early on you are discouraged from wandering around at night as the enemies might be too high level, but the combat system is set up such that most tough battles can be overcome simply by having enough recovery items around. I only got a game over once, early in the game when didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I was doing and I tried wandering at night and promptly got squashed by an iron giant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Open World&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open world gives the party a lot to do. There&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;hunts&amp;rdquo; dished out by people in diners (basically quests to go kill a specific bunch of monsters) and other side quests given out by various characters. There&amp;rsquo;s a fishing minigame, because apparently it&amp;rsquo;s a hobby of Noctis. The fishing minigame is okay, except I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the patience to try to get the most difficult fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s the photos and the food porn. A lot of pandering to the modern-day youths here, I&amp;rsquo;m surprised instagram hasn&amp;rsquo;t been invented in their world. Cooking is Ignis&amp;rsquo; specialty, and the game renders each dish really well, sometimes enough to make you hungry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the photos are the specialty of Prompto. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those things that feels really frivolous in the game. Every time you camp you can browse pictures that Prompto has taken so you can save them for later viewing. A later patch provided a photo mode that you can control directly. There&amp;rsquo;s an entire reddit thread about how players have snapped more pics for this game than for their own vacations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m no exception. Exporting a lot of photos is a pain though, as there is no batch export option in-game. Here are a sampling of the photos I got (a bunch of them are from achievements):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;a/ECX4J&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/a/ECX4J&#34;&gt;View post on imgur.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of achievements, I was a touch disappointed with FFXV&amp;rsquo;s achievement set. I got the Platinum trophy, but I felt like it was a bit too easy, as there was still a lot of things to do in the game outside of the achievements. I don&amp;rsquo;t want annoying grindy achievements, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want them to be too easy and &amp;ldquo;no challenge&amp;rdquo; either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other stuff&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had this weird Chocobo carnival DLC that somehow takes place in another timeline or something LOL. IDK how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://imgur.com/2Uj1VM3.png&#34; width=&#34;1920&#34; height=&#34;1080&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that the more action-oriented combat system is indicative of where SE plans to take the series moving forward, there&amp;rsquo;s still a significant amount of nostalgia in the game for old-schoolers to appreciate. Callouts range from Prompto humming the classic victory fanfare after the battle to 2d sprites in the store menus jumping up in down to indicate which characters can equip each item. Classic FF beasties like the Malboro still make an appearance (and are still a pain to fight!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weirdest thing overall has to be the Cup Noodles thing! They had some sort of tie-up with Nissin and Cup Noodles is one of the meals your party can have in the game and Gladio is obsessed with them. Later on you even get a quest to try to find a way to improve on Cup Noodles and it ends with the characters saying there&amp;rsquo;s really no beating the original since it has a perfect mix of ingredients already. I feel like the VA&amp;rsquo;s really enjoyed doing those lines haha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://imgur.com/MDiYsIS.png&#34; width=&#34;1920&#34; height=&#34;1080&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I had a bunch of complaints and nitpicks but to be honest, I enjoyed the game. There was a lot of gameplay, some seriously though battles and some annoying dungeons that took forever, but I finished most of it and got the platinum in under a month. Nowadays for an RPG that&amp;rsquo;s very quick for me, an indication of how much I liked the game. There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch more content planned for it, including DLC story packs for each of the other main characters, and high-end boss fights and what not. Not sure if I&amp;rsquo;d still play those since there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more RPGs on the horizon (2017 is a good year for RPG gamers.) But if Final Fantasy XV is the next step for the series moving forward, I find it acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Sony 4K HDR Bravia X8000D
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/sony-4k-hdr-bravia-x8000d/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 15:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/sony-4k-hdr-bravia-x8000d/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;4k XLocal tech blog YugaTech is doing a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yugatech.com/tv/giveaway-win-this-4k-hdr-sony-bravia-x8000d-with-android-tv/&#34;&gt;giveaway of a Sony X8000D Bravia 4K TV&lt;/a&gt;. To be honest I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure about using this blog to participate in a promo, but I was already in the market for a new TV since our living room TV is already starting to have some problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I checked out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sony.com.ph/electronics/televisions/x8000d-series/specifications#features&#34;&gt;product features of the Sony X8000D Bravia on their website&lt;/a&gt;. Some of the features stood out for me specifically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4K HDR &amp;ndash; this means you get to watch high definition 4k videos. Perfect for those who really enjoy high quality displays. The TV also comes with some technologies to enhance your viewing experience such as 4k X-Reality and Triluminos display. And if you have a gamer in the family, this means you can now maximize the Playstation 4 Pro since it supports gaming in 4K resolution!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connectivity &amp;ndash; Wifi is a big deal for me because our current TV is a bit old and only supports wired connection. Wifi makes it a lot easier! The TV also has 4 HDMI slots &amp;ndash; let me see&amp;hellip;  that&amp;rsquo;s one each for the PS4 Pro, Nintendo Switch, and XBox One, plus one more to spare for those times when you want to connect your laptop to a big display (one can dream right?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Android TV &amp;ndash; this means all the apps on the Google Play store can be downloaded and run on the TV. That means built-in Youtube, Netflix, etc, without need for a separate device to stream from!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Cast &amp;ndash; oh, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know this even existed until now! Apparently TV&amp;rsquo;s can now have Chromecast functionality built-in, without the need for the separate Chromecast device. Awesome! We can just send content from our mobile devices directly to the TV!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Netflix recommended &amp;ndash; one of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for in a new TV is that I want my folks to be able to easily use my Netflix account. Currently the only way they can use it on the TV is through the PS4, which is a bit difficult if you don&amp;rsquo;t know your way around a controller. Having the TV itself support Netflix will make it a lot easier for my parents to take advantage of Netflix&amp;rsquo;s library of movies and TV shows!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X-Protection PRO &amp;ndash; to protect against power surges, this seems like it would be really good especially here in Metro Manila where power supply is not always the most stable. Added protection for your investment!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model has a lot of other features designed to enhance your enjoyment of audio and video content. With all of these features, the Sony Bravia X8000D could definitely be the perfect home entertainment companion for the modern family!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Duelyst
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 01:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/hearthstone-vs-mtg/&#34;&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/a&gt;, I tried out a couple of other digital CCGs: &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/429680/&#34;&gt;Spellweaver&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/531640/&#34;&gt;Eternal&lt;/a&gt;, but neither one hooked me. The one I enjoyed the most and did pick up to play regularly was &lt;a href=&#34;https://duelyst.com/&#34;&gt;Duelyst&lt;/a&gt;. So this review is written from the perspective of someone who has played both Magic the Gathering (MTG) and Hearthstone (HS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hearthstone, Spellweaver and Eternal played like digital MTG with some advantages, as I outlined in the HS post linked above. Duelyst keeps many of the same elements and advantages, but adds an extra dimension. Besides being a card game, Duelyst is also a board game.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#45dce95b50f9d04ecee469edc104a35d-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20161015104936_1_hu28345954637ff43c1f8b238adc065a50_415978_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;45dce95b50f9d04ecee469edc104a35d-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20161015104936_1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Feb 2017 1:30am&#34;&gt;18 Feb 2017 1:30am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Board game&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a game of Duelyst your General (the analogue to Hearthstone&amp;rsquo;s hero) and his minions are played into a 9×5 board. Minions can only be summoned on empty spaces adjacent to one of your units. During your turn, each unit can either: attack an adjacent enemy; or move up to two spaces, then attack an adjacent enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a board and unit movement greatly enhances the &amp;ldquo;positioning matters&amp;rdquo; mechanic as compared to Hearthstone. In HS, it only mattered whether minions were adjacent, to the left or to the right. In Duelyst, you can position minions to prevent enemies from reaching your General, or to restrict enemies from moving completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means a number of spells and abilities care about positioning too. Each of the available Generals has a Bloodborn spell (BBS), the equivalent of Hearthstone&amp;rsquo;s Hero Power. One of the Generals has a BBS which allows her to deal damage to all enemy units in the same column as the opposing General. This means you have to be careful where you place your minions whenever her BBS is active! There are spells that affect a small area (2×2 or 3×3 and so on). There are spells that care about adjacency (&amp;ldquo;Destroy target minion that is not nearby any general&amp;rdquo;). And so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factions and Generals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hearthstone has different heroes, and each hero has a different card pool available. By contrast, Duelyst has factions and Generals. Each faction has its own card pool, and of course there is a global or &amp;ldquo;neutral&amp;rdquo; card pool as well. Each faction also has two Generals, each of which has a different BBS. The factions and Generals encourage a lot of different playstyles.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#7893d4dff4403b69eaab48e91d493637-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20170216154217_1_hu2712e8d2214bb80d8b8cbb3f52aa2fad_388288_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;7893d4dff4403b69eaab48e91d493637-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20170216154217_1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Feb 2017 1:30am&#34;&gt;18 Feb 2017 1:30am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some factions like the Songhai are more focused on spell-based damage and backstabs. The Lyonar focus on cheap, efficient creatures. Vetruvian has obelisks that can generate temporary minions. Abyssian focuses on swarm tactics and shadow creep. The Vanar rely on placement and trickery. My favorite General, the Magmar Vaath, likes to go toe-to-toe with the enemy General and &lt;strong&gt;punch him in the face!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, many of Duelyst keywords care about positioning, and thus have no meaningful equivalent in either MTG or HS. Namely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airdrop&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; minions with Airdrop can be summoned anywhere on the board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backstab&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; this unit deals extra damage when attacking from behind (yes, even facing matters!) and doesn&amp;rsquo;t receive a counterattack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blast&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; attack hits all enemies in the same row or column&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flying&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; may move anywhere on the battlefield&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frenzy&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; normal attacks hit ALL adjacent enemies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infiltrate&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; gains bonus effect if its on the enemy&amp;rsquo;s starting side of the board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Provoke **&amp;ndash; somewhat like HS&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Taunt. A&lt;/strong&gt;djacent enemies cannot move and &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; attack a Provoke unit if there is one nearby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ranged&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; can attack from anywhere on the board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shadow Creep&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; this is a modifier that can be added to board tiles. An enemy standing on Shadow Creep takes 1 damage at the end of the Shadow Creep owner&amp;rsquo;s turn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Zeal **&amp;ndash; gains bonus effect as long as it&amp;rsquo;s next to the General&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duelyst also has a number of keywords that are analogous to abilities in MTG and HS. &lt;strong&gt;Rush&lt;/strong&gt; is the same as MTG&amp;rsquo;s **Haste **and HS&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Charge&lt;/strong&gt;. **Opening Gambit **and &lt;strong&gt;Dying Wish&lt;/strong&gt; are the same as HS&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Battlecry&lt;/strong&gt; and **Deathrattle. **(I worry that at some point new cardgames will run out of names for &amp;ldquo;enters the field&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;leaves the field&amp;rdquo;.) And so on &amp;ndash; no need to cover everything here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skill Level, Competitive Play and F2P&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The added dimension of positioning means that Duelyst is strictly more skill-based than HS. This is obvious if you note that there are a lot more choices for where to place minions. Hearthstone is also more reliant on RNG than Duelyst is, although I can&amp;rsquo;t say that will hold for the future. I enjoy some level of RNG as it creates variance, but the randomness means a higher chance of losing due to bad luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find competitive play on the ranked ladders for both Duelyst and Hearthstone to be about the same. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying either meta is healthy, but as I see it there are more viable decks in Duelyst ladder as compared to HS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;ve already spent a bunch of money in MTG, I don&amp;rsquo;t like spending money on digital card games. So for both HS and Duelyst, I am strictly free-to-play (F2P). Both games offer similar monetization models (pay money for booster packs/cosmetics) but I was able to get further up the ladder in competitive Duelyst.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#b2f9e96959d46d69b74fdfb70152125d-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20170131192316_1_hub7a52f37225406efe877da2275b8d6f8_162003_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;b2f9e96959d46d69b74fdfb70152125d-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20170131192316_1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Feb 2017 1:30am&#34;&gt;18 Feb 2017 1:30am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my first full month (December), I was already able to get to Duelyst&amp;rsquo;s Gold Division. This should be similar to around rank 10 in HS. After a lot (and I mean &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt;) of grinding from Diamond rank, I managed to hit the S-Rank Division last month. This is the equivalent of HS&amp;rsquo;s Legend rank. The highest rank I ever got in HS was around rank 6 or 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I think Duelyst is more skill-based than HS, why did I find it easier to get to S-Rank than HS&amp;rsquo;s Legend rank? Two reasons come to mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I found Duelyst games more fun&lt;/strong&gt;. This means I was playing Duelyst on a daily basis since it started. At the start, I played regularly because I wanted to get Steam Achievement completion. But I found myself enjoying the game and continuing to play even after that. There are also a lot more variance in decks being played on the Duelyst ladder. By comparison, HS ladder seemed to be almost 50% the one best deck (used to be Midrange Shaman, nowadays Pirate Aggro&amp;hellip; ) while the other 50% are trying to beat it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It was easier to get the powerful cards and build the tier one decks in Duelyst&lt;/strong&gt;. The pricing of packs is about the same (100 gold), but on average I could earn around 100-150 gold per day from Duelyst&amp;rsquo;s quests, compared to 40-60 for HS. The drop rates for Legendaries (highest rarity in both games) is higher in Duelyst as well. Unlike HS, Legendaries in Duelyst are not restricted to one per deck, you can play as many as three. This meant you need more of them, which annoyed me at first. But I think that&amp;rsquo;s counterbalanced by the higher drop rate. For comparison, I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing HS for more than a year and have only gotten two premium (golden) Legendaries. Three months into Duelyst and I&amp;rsquo;ve opened the same amount of premium (prismatic) Legendaries. (Well, this comparison may be skewed since I open more Duelyst packs due to the increased gold rate.) Another factor was the Bloodborn expansion, which you could complete by playing enough to grind 3900 gold. That expansion came out in December, and I completed the set early in January. This set gave me access to many useful cards that were important in the meta. This allowed me to build a tier one deck and reach S-Rank in January. Even after that deck was nerfed, I was also easily able to shift to another tier one deck from another faction. In HS, I still haven&amp;rsquo;t found a new competitive deck after Midrange Shaman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I told myself I would stop playing Duelyst after I completed the Steam Achievements. Then I said I would stop playing after I got to S-Rank. But I&amp;rsquo;m still playing it now. By comparison, I now launch HS once or twice a week, and I don&amp;rsquo;t clear the quests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duelyst is still a young game &amp;ndash; the second expansion just came out last December. So in the future it may yet be plagued with the problems Hearthstone currently has. The developers have shown themselves to be responsive in nerfing problematic cards and shaking up the meta though. Whether they are able to keep this up remains to be seen. In the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;m willing to keep playing as long as the game is still enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20161015104936_1_hu28345954637ff43c1f8b238adc065a50_415978_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20170131192316_1_hub7a52f37225406efe877da2275b8d6f8_162003_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20170216154217_1_hu2712e8d2214bb80d8b8cbb3f52aa2fad_388288_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Xenoblade Chronicles X
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:44:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Just in time for the end of the year, I finally finished Xenoblade Chronicles X, which I started playing around the first week of August (5 months!), with 120+ hours of game time. The game doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the best graphics (WiiU, etc), but I really like how it looks and how the world is built and all the different environments and the weird and sometimes absurdly large beasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/KnpoEd3.png&#34; width=&#34;1280&#34; height=&#34;720&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a whole lot of stuff to do in-game. It plays mostly like a single-player MMO, with party members that act on their own and most skills on a cooldown. There&amp;rsquo;s a ridiculous number of quests and items to grind for, I&amp;rsquo;m even tempted to still continue with the post-game content (if only I didn&amp;rsquo;t have FFXV waiting for me!), as I&amp;rsquo;m only at around 70% completion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story was okay, at many points well-told and hitting a lot of emotional highs (although some of the characters felt a bit over-acted). The ending was&amp;hellip;  well, kind of sequel-baiting. A mixture of disappointment and confusion and hope haha. I don&amp;rsquo;t imagine that they&amp;rsquo;ll have a sequel set in the same universe/timeline, so it felt a bit like they made up a ridiculous explanation that would attempt to explain some of the nonsense that happens in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an imgur album with some stuff I screen-grabbed along the way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;a/CEbsI&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;//imgur.com/CEbsI&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Stranger Things
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/review-stranger-things/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 01:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/review-stranger-things/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/38/Stranger_Things_logo.png&#34; width=&#34;728&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Stranger Things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s true, it&amp;rsquo;s great. I thought it might be overhyped, but it&amp;rsquo;s not. And I can see why people find it hard to explain without spoiling things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about strange things happening in a small town. Creepy things. It&amp;rsquo;s a mystery. It&amp;rsquo;s suspense. It&amp;rsquo;s not a jump-scare sort of thing if you&amp;rsquo;re not into that. Well, there&amp;rsquo;s maybe a little bit of jump scares. The best description I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s about as scary as an X-Files or Doctor Who episode. So if that&amp;rsquo;s not too scary for you, you&amp;rsquo;ll be fine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about a child who goes missing in a small town (not a spoiler) and the succeeding events. It&amp;rsquo;s about the mother searching for her son. It&amp;rsquo;s about a group of kids trying to solve a mystery. It&amp;rsquo;s about a small-town police chief in over his head. It&amp;rsquo;s about the 80s. It&amp;rsquo;s about kids in the 80s, music in the 80s, school in the 80s, small American towns in the 80s. It&amp;rsquo;s about outcasts and bullies and first times and trying to fit in and how they all deal with these stranger things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like Stephen King wrote an episode of X-Files and it was directed by Stephen Spielberg starring the cast of Stand By Me. The acting is great too, especially the kids&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe minor spoilers follow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of told in that weird True Detective way, with perspectives jumping around a lot among the ensemble cast. Past and present scenes are interspersed with only context to rely on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It keeps you hooked. I wanted to watch only a couple of episodes at first but ended up awake past three AM at episode six. I finished it the net morning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love how the mystery unfolds to different parties and separately they uncover parts of it and they all come together in the end to force a resolution. I love how the characters overcome their horror-movie tropes. I love all the 80s references and the geeky references&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was satisfied with how it ended and all came together. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what to expect for a second season though&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>X-Men, Green Lantern and a little bit of Batman
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2011/06/x-men-green-lantern-and-a-little-bit-of-batman/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 14:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2011/06/x-men-green-lantern-and-a-little-bit-of-batman/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So Metro Manila is at the peril of heavy rains, flooding and traffic again (as often happens this time of the year) and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do some actual blogging for a change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to brave the rush hour traffic last night so I finally got around to watching X-Men First Class (luckily it was still showing at Mega). I had actually seen Green Lantern first despite X1C showing two weeks before the DC movie. It&amp;rsquo;s a good time to be a comic book fan with all these comic book movies coming out; I saw Thor a couple of months ago and of course we still have Captain America to look forward to next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some level though I&amp;rsquo;ve started thinking that being a big comic book fan is actually a bit of a handicap when watching these big Hollywood adaptations of our favorite spandex-clad heroes, if only because we cringe twice at much at every small fault or piece of bad writing that we find in these movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may have subconsciously delayed watching X1C because one of my brothers had watched it while I was in Singapore and didn&amp;rsquo;t really give the gushing review &amp;ldquo;regular&amp;rdquo; people had given. And GL wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting such rave reviews on opening weekend either and there were rumors that even the studio was not confident in the movie. So I came into both movies with a bit of lowered expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My quick reviews of the two movies first then: X1C was fun and it was nice seeing an entirely new crew of mutants (more or less). I can forgive the ridiculous recruitment and training montages (and lol&amp;rsquo;ed at the cameo). It looks they didn&amp;rsquo;t bother keeping in continuity with the first trilogy and Wolverine: Origins, which is fine since Wolverine: Origins was ridiculous anyway. The ending felt a bit contrived in the same way that the ending of Smallville and Wolverine: Origins did &amp;ndash; mainly because they need to wrap up things to sync with whatever &amp;ldquo;continuity&amp;rdquo; they&amp;rsquo;re supposed to have. The movie feels a bit campy at times and it&amp;rsquo;s far from the &amp;ldquo;Dark Knight of X-Men&amp;rdquo; that some reviews made it out to be, but still a good watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green Lantern was fun as well, though the writing left a bit to be desired for me. At some points the abrupt transitions and especially the poor portrayal of Carol Ferris reminded me of Smallville-quality writing at some point. It&amp;rsquo;s still a good movie to watch and the scale is definitely more epic than X1C, but it kind of left me hanging the same way Thor did: it&amp;rsquo;s like there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much that happened in the movie aside from the telling of the origin story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I was just spoiled by Nolan, but Batman Begins set a new height for me in terms of superhero origin movies, and the latest set have yet to reach that bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Batman I&amp;rsquo;ve also just finished watching the DC straight to video animated feature &amp;ldquo;Under the Red Hood&amp;rdquo; which covers the death and resurrection of Jason Todd (duh, spoilers) and to be honest I found the climactic scene more well-written than the above two movies. But then again Under the Red Hood follows the comic book story arc more closely so I guess it&amp;rsquo;s closer to the type of stories I enjoy on a regular basis. In fact I find that the DC animated film line to be pretty good; not something I&amp;rsquo;d watch in a cinema or anything but enjoyable enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just really more or less random ramblings about comic books and comic book movies so here&amp;rsquo;s something else I thought of while watching X1C: the problem with the character of Magneto or in general any character whose origin story or background is tied to a real-life historical event the same way Magneto&amp;rsquo;s is tied to the holocaust. See the problem is that comic book characters live in some sort of time-distorting reality bubble where they don&amp;rsquo;t grow old as fast as the readers do. Characters like Magneto however, have no choice but to grow old at the regular rate, since we cannot move the historical dates upon which their characters are based. In twenty to thirty years, Magneto will be a hundred years old regardless of what happens in X-Men continuity. How will they make X-Men movies then, will they have a hundred year-old Ian McKellen take the role? With the character of Magneto anchored in time, the fictional world of the X-Men remains tied to a particular era. They&amp;rsquo;ll probably come up with some handwaved solution about how his powers include not aging; or maybe they&amp;rsquo;ll take a bold leap and actually kill him off permanently (hey, they haven&amp;rsquo;t brought back Jean Grey for a while right?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a side note, the first character that I ever noticed had this problem was Bab from Pugad Baboy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway maybe that&amp;rsquo;s enough rambling for now. Looking forward to Captain America, Transformers 3, etc, etc. Despite my not being 100% satisfied with the current wave of superhero movies, it&amp;rsquo;s still a good time to be a comic book fan. 😀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watchmen
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/03/watchmen/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2009 08:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/03/watchmen/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I had actually read the much-acclaimed graphic novel only last year. And while I found the story decent enough, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure whether to like it or hate it. Undoubtedly it was an important point in the history of &amp;ldquo;superhero&amp;rdquo; comics, but I was never entirely sure about it&amp;rsquo;s point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So of course I saw the movie, and it had remained roughly 85-90% loyal to the source material, which made it a bit boring for me since I generally knew what was going to happen most of the time (except for you know, that thing about the bad guy&amp;rsquo;s master plan&amp;hellip; ). Not only does the story remain true to the comic-book style, but the backgrounds and choice of music seemed oddly appropriate for all the flashbacks going on to explain the Watchmen and Minutemen backstories. And the movie leaves me feeling the same way the comic did&amp;hellip; ambivalent as it were, and unsure of what deep, thought-provoking message about human existence the Watchmen story was really trying to convey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, if you&amp;rsquo;re any sort of comic book fan, you should watch it even if you hadn&amp;rsquo;t read the source material. The only real problem with the movie is that Dr. Manhattan seriously needs to wear more pants.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Street Fighter: The Legend of Chun Li
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/02/street-fighter-the-legend-of-chun-li/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2009 22:54:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/02/street-fighter-the-legend-of-chun-li/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I had time to kill before going to see my brother&amp;rsquo;s art exhibit at megamall, so I went and watched Street Fighter: The Legend of Chun-Li.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was so bad. I could&amp;rsquo;ve been able to forgive the fact that they roughly 80% of the story shied away from Street Fighter canon, had the movie&amp;rsquo;s storyline actually been good. As it is, you can expect short, unsatisfying fight scenes, ridiculous background stories, disjointed plot/scenes (reminds me of Smallville and/or Heroes writing =/), terrible wigs and the ridiculous sight of Michael Clark Duncan getting beaned by a pineapple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it was a problem with the theater&amp;rsquo;s copy, but there were no subtitles for the Chinese/Thai dialogues, which made up a nontrivial portion of the movie. Also, did they really, absolutely need to have the Kikoushou? The internal world of the movie would have been so much more consistent if Chun-Li did not magically learn the ability to create a fireball from nothing. And it&amp;rsquo;s totally unexplained as well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nash and Maya were pretty much useless. Gen, supposedly a really old guy who&amp;rsquo;s a rival for Akuma, was played by the same guy who played Liu Kang in Mortal Kombat, except he was wearing a really bad wig and apparently could not die. Michael Clark Duncan is wasted in his role as Balrog, who is not even hinted to be a boxer at all&amp;hellip; in fact he went so far as to use a bow and arrow in this movie. (Oh, and getting beaned by a pineapple)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/altealice&#34; title=&#34;altealice on twitter&#34;&gt;@altealice&lt;/a&gt; asks: are there enough lolz to make watching it worthwhile?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It depends on how &lt;em&gt;mababaw&lt;/em&gt; you are at the time I guess. The plain ridiculousness of the storyline makes you want to facepalm. Things seem to happen at random and with no explanation (It&amp;rsquo;s never explained why the hell Bison took Chun-li&amp;rsquo;s father.) I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend watching it in the moviehouse, but maybe pickup a pirated DVD :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least, it&amp;rsquo;s still better than the Van Damme movie.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Eagle Eye
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/10/eagle-eye/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 22:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/10/eagle-eye/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;On a whim, my brother and I went to Trinoma to see Eagle Eye, barely catching the last full show (including the trailers of course, we love watching trailers). Our mom had said we&amp;rsquo;d like the movie and she still owed us one since it was her fault we watched Big Stan. So we&amp;rsquo;re giving her a chance to redeem herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spoilerless review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Eagle Eye trailers seem to be everywhere, you probably have some idea of at least the start of the story. Jerry Shaw is an ordinary loser working at Copy Cabana when he comes into seven hundred fifty thousand dollars and a whole lot of terrorist hardware in his apartment, facilitated by a mysterious woman who contacts him via his cellphone. The FBI bust his apartment and suddenly he&amp;rsquo;s a fugitive on the run for reasons unknown to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the gauge of how good an action movie is how difficult it is for me to see how it ends. For Eagle Eye, it started out a bit slow, then became action-packed without explanation then got to the middle where the plot was developed, and by that point I thought I had a pretty good handle of where it was going. Except I was wrong. And towards the end of the movie there were a few moments of &amp;ldquo;Oh, so that&amp;rsquo;s what it was for!&amp;rdquo; which was a pretty good indication. There was a bit of a cop out at the ending, but I guess that they want this to be a &amp;ldquo;feel-good&amp;rdquo; action movie so whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not yet tired of Shia Lebouf and his half-dorky antics, the movie&amp;rsquo;s not a bad way to waste a couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;flockcredit&#34; style=&#34;text-align: right; color: #ccc; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;
  Blogged with the&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a style=&#34;color: #999; font-weight: bold;&#34; title=&#34;Flock Browser&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flock.com/blogged-with-flock&#34; target=&#34;_new&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Flock Browser&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Indiana Jones: Raiders vs Crystal Skull
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/06/indiana-jones-quotraidersquot-vs-quotcrystal-skullquot/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 12:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/06/indiana-jones-quotraidersquot-vs-quotcrystal-skullquot/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So I saw _Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull _last Friday. Two days later I also watched for the first time &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones and the Raiders of the Lost Ark.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of doing a lame movie review, here&amp;rsquo;s a double header feature!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Warning: Spoilers for both movies follow)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border=&#34;1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Criteria
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Raiders of the Lost Ark
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Kingdom of the Crystal Skull
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Winner
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Opening Sequence
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Indy explores an abandoned ruin, is betrayed by his companion, recovers a lost artifact only to get it snatched by the bad guy. Later, his boring lecture at the university is interrupted by some university official telling him the government was looking for him
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Indy explores an abandoned warehouse, is betrayed by his companion, recovers a lost artifact only to get it snatched by the bad guy. Later, his boring lecture at the university is interrupted by some university official telling him the government was looking for him
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Tie
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Death Traps
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Walls that shoot arrows, spike-filled pits, spears thrusting out of the walls, huge rocks rolling down the corridor, weight-sensitive platform.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Refrigerator and a nuclear bomb
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Crystal Skull
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Indy&#39;s Love Interest
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Young Marion Ravenwood, played by Karen Allen
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Old Marion Williams, played by Karen Allen
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Raiders
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Indy&#39;s Sidekick
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      John Rhys-Davies, famous for appearing in Sliders and as Gimli in&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Lord of the Rings&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt; . Makes me think of Pavarotti.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Shia Lebouf, famous for appearing in Transformers. Homer Simpson describes him as &#34;not quite a nerd, not quite a hunk.&#34; Makes me think of Bumblebee.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Raiders. I liked Sliders.
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      The bad guy
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      A snooty French Archeologist, played by Paul Freeman.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      A snooty Soviet agent, played by Cate Blanchett. Thinks she is psychic.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Crystal Skull
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Other adversaries
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Nazis; Hitler; Egyptian street punks who are really bad at fighting.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Russians; Mayans with poison darts
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Crystal Skull
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Artifact
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      The Ark of the Covenant, said to contain the original Ten Commandments. Inexplicably cursed.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      A crystal alien skull, said to be able to speak directly to the mind. Inexplicably magnetic.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Crystal Skull
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Best fight scene
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Indy versus large Russian brawler while Marion attempts to get a small plane under control.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Shia Lebouf fencing with Cate Blanchett, while straddling two running vehicles.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Crystal Skull
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Number of times Indy gets caught
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      3
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      5
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Raiders
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      What happened to the bad guys?
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Had the flesh peeled off their bones via dated 80&#39;s-style special effects
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Disintegrated and transported through the space bridge, but not before achieving omniscience.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Raiders
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      What happened to the artifact?
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Hidden away in Area 51 warehouse
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Re-attached to it&#39;s body and flew off to Dimension X
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Crystal Skull
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Ending sequence
    &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      The government denies everything. Indy and the museum get a lot of cash.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Indy and Marion get married, and we&#39;re tempted with Shia Lebouf attempting to don the fedora.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;
      Crystal Skull
    &lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winner: &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones and Kingdom of the Crystal Skull!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>300
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/03/300/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2007 01:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/03/300/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Mostly due to my antisocial nature and my laziness, I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually seen a movie in a theater since&amp;hellip; forever. I broke that fast mostly because of the hype surround 300, the movie based on Frank Miller&amp;rsquo;s comic book retelling of the Battle at Thermopylae.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone who&amp;rsquo;s seen the movie has the same thing to say: it&amp;rsquo;s really good. So I went to see it with a brother of mine. And it was good. Really good. The highlights of the movie are the very impressive battle scenes (which is like 90% of the movie), with awesome usage of slow-motion to enhance the battle drama. It feels like a video game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I think the movie was hyped a bit too much for me. It&amp;rsquo;s good, but not OMGWTFThat&amp;rsquo;sAwesome!!!111 good for me. History lessons told me how that battle ended, and some of the lines in the movie sound like trash-talk from WWE shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still enjoyable though, despite the high theater prices nowadays. It&amp;rsquo;s just that I went in expecting my socks to get knocked off; they rolled up a bit, but they stayed on my feet.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>God&#39;s Debris by Scott Adams
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/02/gods-debris-by-scott-adams/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2006 06:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/02/gods-debris-by-scott-adams/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.andrewsmcmeel.com/godsdebris/&#34;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; was Scott Adams&amp;rsquo; first non-Dilbert book. If you&amp;rsquo;re used to reading Adams go on about Induhviduals and stupid managers, or if you&amp;rsquo;ve never read Adams trying / pretending to sound philosophical in one of his books, then this isn&amp;rsquo;t what you&amp;rsquo;d expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adams describes it as a &amp;ldquo;thought experiment&amp;rdquo; of sorts, one where he tries to provide some sort of explanation for basically life, the universe and everything. Although it&amp;rsquo;s a work of fiction, it sounds like Adams is trying to see how people will react to his form of philosophy — it seems to be one of his favorite things to do something just to provoke reactions. (Yeah, he and I are alike that way.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adams starts from simple assumptions about the nature of God, and the nature of probability, and proceeds to try to explain everything from gravity to string theory to psychics to women. Yeah, women. You&amp;rsquo;d think a guy would know better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a thought-provoking read, as long you keep some of the skepticism down. Adams himself acknowledges that some parts of his book are just plain-old creative BS trying to pass itself off as something deeper. Smart people would appreciate it as quick and light-philosophical reading, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think it would survive serious logical scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely worth the read, if only to get inside the head of a popular cartoonist. I think this part of Scott Adams is the part that writes all those garbageman strips. =p&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Music - Ultraelectromagnetic Jam
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/12/music-ultraelectromagnetic-jam/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2005 09:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/12/music-ultraelectromagnetic-jam/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no music critic; often I can&amp;rsquo;t even carry my own tune. But I do know what I like, and I know I like the Eraserheads&amp;rsquo; music. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know who the ‘heads are, they&amp;rsquo;re basically the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eraserheads&#34;&gt;Beatles of the Philippines&lt;/a&gt;, galvanizing the local music industry and serving as an example and inspiration to numerous other bands that followed after them. It&amp;rsquo;s only fitting then that many of the current crop of Filipino performers pay tribute to them in the form of Ultraelectromagnetic Jam. This fantastic album features several artists performing their own versions of some of the Eraserheads best hits, namely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alapaap by 6-Cycle Mind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alcohol by Radioactive Sago Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ang Huling El Bimbo by Rico J Puno&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard to Believe by Cueshé&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huwag Kang Matakot by Orange and Lemons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huwag Mo Nang Itanong by MYMP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ligaya by Kitchie Nadal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magasin by Paolo Santos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maling Akala by Brownman Revival&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overdrive by Barbie Almabis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pare Ko by Sponge Cola&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoliarium by Imago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Superproxy by Francis M.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tikman by Sugarfree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Torpedo by Isha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Para sa Masa by all of them!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to comment on each track separately, but I&amp;rsquo;m too lazy :p They&amp;rsquo;re all pretty good, mostly because the originals were great in the first place. Paolo Santos carried Magasin surprisingly well, and Superproxy was just the right track for Francis M. Radioactive Sago&amp;rsquo;s Alcohol is hilarious, and I like the way Orange and Lemons mixed a little bit of Julie Tearjerky and Tikman in Huwag Kang Matakot. I also think I actually like Cueshé&amp;rsquo;s version of Hard To Believe better than the original. My least favorite track on the album is Kitchie Nadal&amp;rsquo;s Ligaya, (cute laugh on the &amp;ldquo;inaahit&amp;rdquo; bit notwithstanding) as I really prefer the more upbeat original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish more bands had contributed to the effort though, as the ‘heads probably deserve it. According to my brother, the participating artists were all from the same recording studio (I don&amp;rsquo;t really pay attention to studios, so yeah I&amp;rsquo;ll just agree here.) Still, it would&amp;rsquo;ve been nice to hear some renditions from ‘heads contemporaries like Rivermaya and Parokya ni Edgar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, awesome album. If you have listened to the Eraserheads music at one time or another, go find a way to get it.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Movies: Transformers the Movie
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/05/movies-transformers-the-movie/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2005 08:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/05/movies-transformers-the-movie/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I should&amp;rsquo;ve thought of this as soon as I got DSL: I went ahead and downloaded Transformers the Movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transformers was of course, the epitome of my youth. Unlike most other guy kids, I preferred the Transformers to G.I. Joe. I guess I preferred high-tech fantasy over soliders back then, with the war of the heroic Autobots and the Evil Decepticons appealing more to my young mind than soldiers trying to fight terrorists. I watched the show, I read the comics (the first comic series I really collected), I had a lunch box, and I even bought and ate the unhealthy cheap knock-off Transformers-branded chips they sold near the St. Joseph parish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transformers: the Movie was the pinnacle of my childhood experience with the Transformers cartoon, since the seasons following the movie were never broadcast on Philippine TV. I watched it yesterday, hoping I would still find the old charm which enthralled me as a child.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not disappointed. Well, not much anyway. As an adult I&amp;rsquo;ve grown more critical of things in general, quick to spot and point out minute flaws. Some notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year is 2005 in Transformers the Movie, some 19 years after the movie&amp;rsquo;s actual release. At least they didn&amp;rsquo;t predict flying cars like Back to the Future, but how come we don&amp;rsquo;t yet have cars that look like Hot Rod? The &amp;ldquo;futuristic&amp;rdquo; look of the six new Autobots introduced in the movie (Ultra Magnus, Hot Rod, Kup, Blurr, Springer and Arcee) give you an indication of how the people of 80s perceived future transportation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, Transformers can use lightsabers, er&amp;hellip; Laser Swords! Megatron pulls one out during his fatal battle with Optimus Prime, and later in the movie one of the Autobots does too. (I think it was Hot Rod, I forget.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazingly, while the Autobots and Decepticons never actually hit each other with their weapons in the TV series, their appearance in a movie suddenly made Starscream&amp;rsquo;s use of the Megatron-gun a lot more efficient, accurate and lethal. Ironhide, Prowl, Brawn and Ratchet go down with a single shot each in the first few minutes of the movie. More Autobots died in the first twenty minutes than in the entire run of the series prior to the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be much of a problem if the Autobots actually had the same numbers they had in the series. It&amp;rsquo;s a well-known fact that the Autobots greatly outnumbered the Decepticons almost all the time, since there are far more types of cars than there are jets and guns and other stuff. But in the movie, there are apprently less than twenty Autobots still in active service. What happened to the rest? We&amp;rsquo;re limited to Optimus Prime, the more popular first-batch Autobots, the Dinobots and the new guys. The Decepticons get a slightly better deal. They get both the first and second batch of jets, the Constructicons, Insecticons, and even the triple-changers Blitzwing and Astrotrain. Also, I think Blaster&amp;rsquo;s cassette-bots make their first cartoon appearance here. Conspiciously absent are the second set of ‘combiner&amp;rsquo; teams&amp;hellip; the Protectobots, Aerialbots, Combaticons and Stunticons. Some of the fights might have gone better had the Autobots thought to bring around Omega Supreme or Skyfire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dinobots are apparently stupider than I remember. I guess my memories preferred the comic-book Dinobots, where Grimlock actually managed to become Autobot leader. Here Blurr has trouble convincing them to board a ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s too bad the Autobots didn&amp;rsquo;t think of bringing Optimus Prime to the planet of junk, where apprently an Autobot can still live after being blown into some twenty-thousand pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ultra Magnus character was created solely to have someone fail to be a leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strangely enough, when the Autobots crash through Unicron&amp;rsquo;s eye, we don&amp;rsquo;t see any sort of optic sensors on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the movie went pretty much as I remembered it. With a lot of forgettable 80s-style music running in the background. Amazingly, at the end, Rodimus Prime declares an end to the Cybertronian wars, and a new era of peace. I don&amp;rsquo;t recall any peace being negotiated with the Decepticons, who looked like they outnumbered the Autobots fifteen-million to one during Unicron&amp;rsquo;s attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m quite relieved, as watching the movie failed to change my nostalgic childhood memories of the Transformers, although I still vastly prefer the comic book series. Not at all bad for a series made to sell toys.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Wheel of Time 10 -- Crossroads of Twilight
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/05/wheel-of-time-10-crossroads-of-twilight/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2005 11:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/05/wheel-of-time-10-crossroads-of-twilight/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Haven&amp;rsquo;t read Robert Jordan in a while. Someone gave me Crossroads of Twilight as a gift, so I read it and hope that his pacing has improved. It has not. He writes well enough, dialogue is nice, descriptions are more than adequate, but I expect some things to happen in his books! He has so many plots running at once, he should at least resolve two or three per book. Perrin, Mat and Elayne get a lot of chapters, but they barely get anything done. Rand al&amp;rsquo;Thor himself barely gets one chapter, and I&amp;rsquo;m thinking it was just put in &amp;lsquo;cause people would be pissed if he didn&amp;rsquo;t actually appear in the book. Egwene at least had the good sense to go out and try to do something. Not that she got anywhere sensible of course&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swear, with so many things going on, it will take him forever to wrap up this series. And while that may be good for him, I wonder how many people will bother following the books for so long? Especially when they&amp;rsquo;re more of the same&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Books: Dark Tower series
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/03/books-dark-tower-series/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2005 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/03/books-dark-tower-series/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I do not aim with my hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who aims with his hand has forgotten the face of his father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I aim with my Eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not shoot with my hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who aims with his hand has forgotten the face of his father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shoot with my Mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not kill with my gun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who kills with his gun has forgotten the face of his father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kill with my Heart.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;The Gunslinger&amp;rsquo;s Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve finished books 3 (Wastelands) and 4 (Wizard and Glass) of Stephen King&amp;rsquo;s amazing Dark Tower series. The sprawling worlds travelled by Roland of Gilead and his band of gunslingers continues to draw me in; I guess the romantic western atmosphere really appeals to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During these two books, we follow Roland Deschain, the last gunslinger, Eddie and Susannah, gunslingers-in-training as they forge ahead on the road to the Dark Tower, where the fate of all worlds may be decided. Along the way, they gain new allies, one thought previously dead. They storm across the fallen city of Lud, blaze across the wastelands on an insane sentient train, and finally land in Kansas. It is in Kansas that Roland narrates a tale of his youth, and of his days and Gilead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Roland&amp;rsquo;s tales of Gilead that I most enjoy in the series. Roland&amp;rsquo;s world, the world that has moved on, is a medieval-western hybrid of sorts. A world where people look to gunslingers with fear and respect, a world where a misspoken word in a tavern can get you killed, a world fraught with danger and adventure. In this tale we learn of what happened to Roland after he passed his rite of passage, his first love, and his decision to pursue the Dark Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to the last three books&amp;hellip; all of which are out in hard cover versions. Wizard and Glass ends on much less of a cliffhanger than Wastelands, so I&amp;rsquo;m willing to wait a bit for the paperback copies to come out, though I hope it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take too long.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Books: More Bob Ong
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/03/books-more-bob-ong/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2005 09:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/03/books-more-bob-ong/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A while back I blogged about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/02/books-abnkkbsknplako-by-bob-ong/&#34;&gt;Bob Ong&amp;rsquo;s first book&lt;/a&gt;. A short while after, I also picked up his next two books, &lt;em&gt;Bakit Baliktad Magbasa ng Libro Ang Mga Pilipino?&lt;/em&gt; (Why Do Filipinos Read Backwards?) and &lt;em&gt;Ang Paboritong Libro ni Hudas&lt;/em&gt; (Judas&amp;rsquo; Favorite Book).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bakit Baligtad&amp;rdquo; focuses on the Philippines, its people, its quirks and its problems. &amp;ldquo;Paboritong Libro&amp;rdquo; is a lot harder to classify, as it jumps across several topics, with the unifying theme being the chapters named after anagrams of the seven deadly sins. At least I think that&amp;rsquo;s the unifying theme&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Paboritong Libro&amp;rdquo; is also the better of the two books. Or at least the easier read, as &amp;ldquo;Bakit Baligtad&amp;rdquo; had a tendency to be a lot more serious and preachy, which might turn off people looking for a light read. Also, &amp;ldquo;Bakit Baligtad&amp;rdquo; contains a significant amount of non-original material, from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=bobong+pinoy&amp;amp;sourceid=mozilla-search&amp;amp;start=0&amp;amp;start=0&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;client=firefox-a&amp;amp;rls=org.mozilla:en-US:official&#34;&gt;apparently-now-defunct Bobong Pinoy website&lt;/a&gt; and from several online forums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, after reading &amp;ldquo;Bakit Baligtad&amp;rdquo;, I realized the particular appeal of Bob Ong&amp;rsquo;s books&amp;hellip; all of them, including the first one, read like they were written on the internet. Maybe in a blog or something. Each book is like some sort of running commentary on some part of life in general; (the first book was about education, the second about the Philippines; I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure what the third book was about) That&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s so hard to pin down, it leaves you with that internet feeling of &amp;ldquo;hey-when&amp;rsquo;s-the-next-update?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both books are generally hit-or-miss though, with a bit more hit than miss, same as the first one. Some good parts, some you&amp;rsquo;d want to sleep through. They&amp;rsquo;re good for the price they&amp;rsquo;re at. In any case, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably pick up his next book as an impulse buy if I see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of these two books (I&amp;rsquo;m not sure which book it was in anymore) was a list of amusing signs found all over the Philippines. One of them is described as such: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;lr=&amp;amp;c2coff=1&amp;amp;client=firefox-a&amp;amp;rls=org.mozilla%3Aen-US%3Aofficial&amp;amp;q=%22danger+wall+is+falling%22&amp;amp;btnG=Search&#34;&gt;on a cracked lopsided wall along Libis, QC: Danger Wall is Falling!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hehe, that cracks me up, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why. I&amp;rsquo;d like to see that wall.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Manna
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/12/manna/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2003 10:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/12/manna/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; is a very nicely written, and highly plausible &lt;a href=&#34;http://marshallbrain.com/manna1.htm&#34;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>