<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>mtgpreviews on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgpreviews/</link>
      <description>Recent content in mtgpreviews on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 12:45:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgpreviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/07/219773806825320448/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 12:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/07/219773806825320448/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;No Llanowar, no BoP, no Noble Hierarch in #M13, all we get is&amp;hellip; Arbor Elf? =/&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2011/09/112154578966949890/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 13:25:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2011/09/112154578966949890/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Why are we getting four preview weeks of #MTGINN? I hope it&amp;rsquo;s because they&amp;rsquo;re holding back on all the awesome, exciting cards.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2011/08/108009915523674112/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 02:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2011/08/108009915523674112/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;#mtginn transform cards as flip cards: &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/a/VFAcp&#34;&gt;https://imgur.com/a/VFAcp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/07/17822789658/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 22:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/07/17822789658/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;White Leyline: Really? RDW died again. Reprint Anarchy! #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[12:27] Slightly disappointed with the remainder of #m11. No Ranger of Eos, no Jace2, no Imperious Perfect, etc. Oh, and no &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Grizzly_Bears/&#34;&gt;@Grizzly_Bears&lt;/a&gt;  #mtg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:48] Devastating Force: I love it, but makes me wish we had better signets. #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:52] Dark Tutelage: I would miss Phyrexian Arena a bit less if this guy could swing for two. Or at least cost a mana less. #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:56] #m11 reminds me of rav block standard. There&amp;rsquo;s hierarch, wildfire, a dark confidant effect, leylines. But yeah, better signets, stat! #mtg&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/07/17766472931/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 04:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/07/17766472931/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Destructive Force: This card is literally &amp;ldquo;Wildfire+1&amp;rdquo;. Is it because six is the new seven? Will Wildfire decks return? #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[12:31] Autumn&amp;rsquo;s Veil: This is pratically a green Flashfreeze. Will it be enough to fight the wave of new blue permission decks? #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/06/17387862994/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 04:10:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/06/17387862994/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Pyretic Ritual - first Timetwister, now Dark Ritual? #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[13:57] I hope &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/fivewithflores/&#34;&gt;@fivewithflores&lt;/a&gt; has something good for us tomorrow. Other than the Lich, the previews this week have been a bit meh. #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[16:28] I hope a pull a Juggernaut at the prerelease and fight today&amp;rsquo;s preview card. I get to say &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m the Juggernaut, Lich!&amp;rdquo; #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/06/17225053999/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 04:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/06/17225053999/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Boo SGC is out. #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[12:11] #mtg #m11 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mtgaaron/&#34;&gt;@mtgaaron&lt;/a&gt; just confirmed Elvish Archdruid reprinted, that should debunk the silly Imperious Perfect rumor?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[12:11] I think Grave Titan is easily the strongest of this cycle. #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[12:15] Interestingly, Green Titan gets any lands, not just basics. #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[13:37] Today&amp;rsquo;s previews weren&amp;rsquo;t as exciting as I had hoped. Though Grave Titan is solid, we already knew about this cycle. #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[13:42] Gaea&amp;rsquo;s Revenge needed trample. Or &amp;ldquo;Protection from nongreen&amp;rdquo; #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[13:45] Hm&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/maro254/&#34;&gt;@maro254&lt;/a&gt; &amp;rsquo;s article mentioned &amp;ldquo;rare and mythic rare cycle that you&amp;rsquo;ll be learning about pretty soon&amp;rdquo;, what are they? #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[23:54] Aw man, the number crunch already rules out Char in #m11. I need a replacement for Staggershock, it&amp;rsquo;s kinda bad unless opp&amp;rsquo;s at 4. #mtg #rdw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[12:19] Turn 5/6 Primeval Titan fetching 2 Eldrazi temple. Untap, swing, 2 more Temples, land drop, Emrakul. #mtg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[23:56] I wonder if Wizards will someday have a set with randomly assigned card numbers. Just to screw with number crunchers. #mtg&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/06/17081832742/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 09:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/06/17081832742/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Seriously? Imperious Perfect?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[20:30] I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I get it. Isn&amp;rsquo;t Overwhelming Stampede just a crappier Overrun at rare? Sure, the CC is slightly easier, but still&amp;hellip; #mtg&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[20:38] Combust needed &amp;ldquo;can target creatures with protection or shroud as if they did not have protection or shroud&amp;rdquo; #mtg #m11&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/06/17007965092/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 11:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/06/17007965092/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Still missing from today&amp;rsquo;s M11 spoilers: Steel Overlord, Roc Egg, Frost Titan. #mtg I&amp;rsquo;ll go to sleep, maybe they&amp;rsquo;ll be there when I wake up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:54] Ah, Steel Overseer just got spoiled! &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/aeH6RW&#34;&gt;http://bit.ly/aeH6RW&lt;/a&gt; #mtg&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Lorwyn -- Some Other Cards of Note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/09/lorwyn-some-other-cards-of-note/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 04:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/09/lorwyn-some-other-cards-of-note/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Lorwyn prerelease in two days, and of course MTG Salvation is &lt;a href=&#34;http://mtgsalvation.com/lorwyn-spoiler.html&#34;&gt;spoiler-complete&lt;/a&gt;.  Some thoughts on cards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thoughtseize&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorcery (Rare)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target player reveals his or her hand. Choose a nonland card from it. That player discards that card. You lose 2 life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undercosted cards that demand a 2 life payment are usually pretty good. (See: Shocklands, Char, Psionic Blast, Vampiric Tutor). Thoughtseize is widely anticipated to be the chase rare of the set, with starcitygames.com pre-order prices starting at a staggering 17.50 USD. That seems bit too high for a utility spell though, so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go out of my way to get them yet. Although I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind opening one or two this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incandescent Soulstoke&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2R&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creature &amp;ndash; Elemental Shaman (Rare)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other Elemental creatures you control get +1/+1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{1}{R}, {T}: You may put an Elemental creature card from your hand into play. That creature gains haste until end of turn. Sacrifice it at end of turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nova Chaser&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3R&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creature &amp;ndash; Elemental Warrior (Rare)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trample&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Champion an Elemental &lt;em&gt;(When this comes into play, sacrifice it unless you remove another Elemental you control from the game. When this leaves play, return that card to play.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10/2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The elemental deck almost builds itself. (Most of the tribe decks do, actually) I hope one or both of the above rares are in the precon, that makes &amp;lsquo;em easier to get. With the elemental harbinger, I can see a toolbox-type elemental deck that can use various evoke elementals and giants like Nova Chaser to finish &amp;lsquo;em off.  Lots of possibilities here actually. Force of Savagery pops in for 9? Pandemonium? Fatal Frenzy? Elementals are hot, and I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about just the Flamekin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;eyes-of-the-wisent&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eyes of the Wisent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1G&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tribal Enchantment &amp;ndash; Elemental (Rare)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever an opponent plays a spell during your turn, you may put a 4/4 green Elemental creature token into play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this the end of Draw-Go style decks?!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;doran-the-siege-tower&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doran, the Siege Tower&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BGW&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legendary Creature &amp;ndash; Treefolk Shaman (Rare)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each creature assigns combat damage equal to its toughness rather than its power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Each year that passes rings you inwardly with memory and might. Wield your heart, and the world will tremble.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0/5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think my jaw literally dropped when this was previewed. Midrange decks will love this guy. Thoughtseize provides disruption, and Doran gives the cheap beats. A &amp;ldquo;Rock&amp;rdquo; style deck may be in the offing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vivid Creek&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Land (Uncommon)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vivid Creek comes into play tapped with two charge counters on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{T}: Add {U} to your mana pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{T}, Remove a charge counter from Vivid Creek: Add one mana of any color to your mana pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a good chance I&amp;rsquo;d like this land cycle better than the rare ones. I think Gemstone Mine just became stupid. The red one may be the best, as it facilitates a mostly-red elemental deck splashing for various evokers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hoofprint of the Stag&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1W&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tribal Enchantment &amp;ndash; Elemental (Rare)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you draw a card, you may put a hoofprint counter on Hoofprint of the Stag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{2}{W}, Remove four hoofprint counters from Hoofprint of the Stag: Put a 4/4 white Elemental creature token with flying into play. Play this ability only during your turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a tier-one card, but one can&amp;rsquo;t help imagine the mischief created by turn 2 Hoofprint, turn 3 Hoofprint, turn 4 Careful Consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goldmeadow Stalwart&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;W&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creature &amp;ndash; Kithkin Soldier (Uncommon)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an additional cost to play Goldmeadow Stalwart, reveal a Kithkin card from your hand or pay {3}.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comparison to Isamaru is obvious of course, as is the reason the Lions were pulled out of the Core Set. That said, I like the next guy better&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrens-run-vanquisher&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wren&amp;rsquo;s Run Vanquisher&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1G&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creature &amp;ndash; Elf Warrior (Uncommon)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an additional cost to play Wren&amp;rsquo;s Run Vanquisher, reveal an Elf card from your hand or pay {3}.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deathtouch &lt;em&gt;(Whenever this creature deals damage to a creature, destroy that creature.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3/3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this better than the red or white equivalents. Face it, if Isamaru were in the same standard as 3/3 for 1G with deathtouch, he might not have been able to swing on turn 2 that often. That being said, I could see a deck with 4 Goldmeadow Stalwart and 4 Wren&amp;rsquo;s Run Vanquishe&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of speed. And it also puts you in the correct colors for the next card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gaddock-teeg&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaddock Teeg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GW&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legendary Creature &amp;ndash; Kithkin Advisor (Rare)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noncreature spells with converted mana cost 4 or greater can&amp;rsquo;t be played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noncreature spells with {X} in their mana costs can&amp;rsquo;t be played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So great is his wisdom and spirit that many who have met him say that they stood before a giant of a man and talked to the wisest of the four winds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2/2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guy stops Force of Will. Oh and Wrath of God and Damnation. That W/G aggro deck is looking pretty good. Throw in some Changeling effects (to facilitate the Vanquisher and the Stalwart) and you&amp;rsquo;re good to go. Not sure how well such a deck would fare in standard, but Block Constructed seems to be a given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for today!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Lorwyn -- Planeswalkers
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/09/lorwyn-planeswalkers/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2007 05:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/09/lorwyn-planeswalkers/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The full spoiler is of course now available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.mtgsalvation.com/showthread.php?t=85382&#34;&gt;MtgSalvation&lt;/a&gt;; I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about planeswalkers first. Each planeswalker is rare and has 3 abilities: a normal attack, a special move, and a finishing move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ajani Goldmane&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2ww&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planeswalker &amp;ndash; Ajani&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;+1: You gain 2 life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-1: Put a +1/+1 counter on each creature you control. Those creatures gain vigilance until end of turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-6: Put a white Avatar creature token into play with &amp;ldquo;This creature&amp;rsquo;s power and toughness are each equal to your life total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loyalty: 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike every other planeswalker, resolving Ajani&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;finishing move&amp;rdquo; does not guarantee a win in a Limited game. More likely, it&amp;rsquo;s going to die to a common like Oblivion Ring. However, Ajani is still pretty good in limited, due to that very nice special move: you play her on turn 4 with 2-3 creatures on the board, pump them once, then swing. Next turn, play another creature or so, pump, swing. Sooner or later, all your guys are bigger than his guys. Also, if you&amp;rsquo;re dying to some stupid 1/1 evasion guy, just gain 2 life a turn. Constructed application: A finisher and support life gain in Martyr-based decks. If you use Sacred Mesa, her special ability even becomes useful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jace Beleren&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1UU&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planeswalker &amp;ndash; Jace&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;+2: Each player draws a card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-1: Target player draws a card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-10: Target player puts the top twenty cards of his or her library into his or her graveyard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loyalty: 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Costing 1UU is useless for Jace, as you will almost never play him on the third turn. More likely you would play him on a later turn, with counter back-up. A simple Constructed application would be to use his special move 3 times, but that&amp;rsquo;s just a bad Harmonize. The other two abilities require you to build your deck around them &amp;ndash; you&amp;rsquo;re not going to use that finisher unless you&amp;rsquo;re actually a mill deck, and the normal ability smells of Owling Mine to me. In limited, just build a defensive deck around him and keep pumping up loyalty. Resolving the finishing move will surely win you the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liliana Vess&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3BB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planeswalker &amp;ndash; Liliana&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;+1: Target player discards a card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-2: Search your library for a card, then shuffle your library and put that card on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-8: Put all creature cards in all graveyards into play under your control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loyalty: 5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, Liliana, first among equals. Well, first to be previewed anyway. The finisher will win you games in Limited &amp;ndash; but only after much blood has already been spilled. The special move on the other hand, pulls out all your other bombs from your deck (hope you had a few!) The normal move is meh in both Limited and Constructed &amp;ndash; paying 5 for a repeating single discard effect isn&amp;rsquo;t really that good. For Constructed, her finisher has a strange synergy with Jace Beleren&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; populate the graveyards, then animate &amp;lsquo;em all under my control. Well, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good with Damnation as well. A bit of a &amp;ldquo;win more&amp;rdquo; card, if you live long enough to get Liliana online, you&amp;rsquo;re probably a control deck and you&amp;rsquo;re already winning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chandra Nalaar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3RR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planeswalker &amp;ndash; Chandra&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;+1: Chandra Nalaar deals 1 damage to target player.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-X: Chandra Nalaar deals X damage to target creature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-8: Chandra Nalaar deals 10 damage to target player and each creature he or she controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loyalty: 6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chandra&amp;rsquo;s card looks awesome, let me get that out of the way. People will collect her just for that. That 6 loyalty there is really good as well. Slam this down in limited and make sure you can defend her for two turns = you win the game. Or, in more dire times, just take down a 6/6 guy for five mana. In Constructed, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what deck would take her, as burn doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be very strong in Lorwyn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Garruk Wildspeaker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2GG&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planeswalker &amp;ndash; Garruk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;+1: Untap two target lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-1: Put a 3/3 green Beast creature token into play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-4: Creatures you control get +3/+3 and trample until end of turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loyalty: 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My take:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite is the green one of course. Garruk compares favorably with Call of the Herd. Play him, and immediately make a 3/3 to defend him. If he takes an Incinerate, that&amp;rsquo;s fine, you still have the token you made. If not&amp;hellip; wow, more free Beasts! I&amp;rsquo;d use him this way in either Limited or Constructed. In fact, I can build a green deck just starting with 4 Call of the Herd 4 Garruk Wildspeaker&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s at least 20 creatures right there. Another application would be to use the normal move to accelerate into early 6-7 casting cost threats, butI like 3/3s better. The finisher is decent, and pretty good in Limited. It has a disadvantage over an actual Overrun in that your opponent can see it coming, but if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to use it then you&amp;rsquo;re probably winning anyway; in a defensive board the 3/3 beast is a better idea.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>