<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>router on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/tags/router/</link>
      <description>Recent content in router on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 17:28:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/tags/router/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2017/08/1242765/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 17:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2017/08/1242765/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;For the past 2 weeks or so now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been having issues with my ISP (I&amp;rsquo;m not in the US, so it&amp;rsquo;s not Comcast or whatever).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, I often lose access to Google-related sites/services: the search engine itself, Gmail, Google Docs/Drive, Youtube, Google Keep are the ones I use most often. I&amp;rsquo;ve restarted my router multiple times already over the past couple of weeks. Same issue is encountered on my desktop (wired), laptop, iPad, phone (when connected over wifi) etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;rsquo;s related to my ISP because (a) I&amp;rsquo;ve read some other users experiencing similar issues on social media; (b) if I tether to my phone&amp;rsquo;s data connection, the problem isn&amp;rsquo;t encountered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a proxy server configured. I used to be using Google DNS but I&amp;rsquo;ve also tried switching back to my ISP&amp;rsquo;s default DNS with no luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the best way for me to figure out what the issue is? (Preferably in a way that I can bring it up to my ISP so that they know specifically what they need to fix - talking to their customer service is a tedious experience so I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to figure out as much as possible before going back to them)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screenshot of the error from the browser:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://i.stack.imgur.com/cin58.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.stack.imgur.com/cin58.png&#34; alt=&#34;enter image description here&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample tracert:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://i.stack.imgur.com/PB5zP.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.stack.imgur.com/PB5zP.png&#34; alt=&#34;enter image description here&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pings seem ok right now (although if I leave ping -t running for a while, there&amp;rsquo;s an occasional &amp;ldquo;Request timed out&amp;rdquo;):
&lt;a href=&#34;https://i.stack.imgur.com/VxB92.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.stack.imgur.com/VxB92.png&#34; alt=&#34;enter image description here&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2012/11/503769/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 11:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2012/11/503769/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s happened a few times, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to diagnose/debug, so any advise would be appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symptons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sometimes the router will randomly disconnect; the connection icon on my desktop (wired to the router) gets that yellow &amp;ldquo;!&amp;rdquo; symbol that tells me my connection just went down. At this point I&amp;rsquo;m unable to ping the router.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;afterwards I try to reset the router by removing then reconnecting the power jack on the router side (this is the fastest way as I can&amp;rsquo;t reset the power strip it&amp;rsquo;s connected to without rebooting my desktop. the router has a reset thingy, but it&amp;rsquo;s one of those things where i have to find a pin to stick into the hole, and when I get disconnected I usually need to get reconnected immediately so I just pull and put back the power jack), but even after that the connection has the same state.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;after the router reboots, if I try to connect to it using a wifi device like my ipad, the ipad prompts me for the wifi password even though it had already &amp;ldquo;remembered&amp;rdquo; all the settings for this router forever&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;after i finally decide to reboot the power strip, and my desktop and the router boot up again, the connection returns to its normal state somewhat and i&amp;rsquo;m able to connect to it as normal using the desktop and wifi devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I need to check the next time this happens so I can figure out the problem? Is it possibly because we&amp;rsquo;ve been using the power jack on the router as an easier way to reboot it? Should I be shopping around for a new router?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it helps, the router is a DLink DIR-300&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>