<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>fanfiction on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/fanfiction/</link>
      <description>Recent content in fanfiction on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/fanfiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Final Fantasy VIII: Seifer Almasy Full Circle
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/07/final-fantasy-viii-seifer-almasy-full-circle/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/07/final-fantasy-viii-seifer-almasy-full-circle/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/874948/1/Seifer-Almasy-Full-Circle&#34;&gt;Fanfiction.net mirror&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fanfiction.net/r/874948/&#34;&gt;Fanfiction.net reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seifer Almasy : Full Circle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Final Fantasy VIII mini-fanfic by Roy Tang (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:zroytang@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;zroytang@yahoo.com&lt;/a&gt;) Final Fantasy
and all related characters (C) Squaresoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Seifer Almasy, please come forward.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever defiant, the tall, blond cadet stood and took his place in front of
the three-man committee. &amp;ldquo;Get on with it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ignoring him, the committee head went on, &amp;ldquo;Seifer Almasy, it is the finding
of this committee that the acts you performed opposing Garden were a direct
result of your being under the influence of Sorceress Ultimecia. However,
this does not forgive the fact that your actions before, during and after
the Ultimecia incident not to mention your allowing yourself to fall under
her influence speak towards your lack of discipline and lack of respect
towards the institutions of Garden. Such characteristics do not befit one
who would aspire to become SeeD. This committee hereby recommends your
immediate expulsion from Balamb Garden.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Seifer, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry.&amp;rdquo; Quistis said, &amp;ldquo;I tried to convince them to let you
stay, but&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Save it instructor,&amp;rdquo; Seifer said, looking around at the gathered SeeDs and
cadets. Quistis, Zell, Selphie, Rinoa and Irvine had come to see him off.
&amp;ldquo;We all know the decision was already made even before I came back.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Seifer&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Rinoa said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where&amp;rsquo;s Squall? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t he want to gloat at me a bit before I get going?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Seifer,&amp;rdquo; Quistis said, &amp;ldquo;I think you grossly underestimate how everyone
feels about you.&amp;rdquo; Zell started to make a comment but Selphie quickly
elbowed him in the gut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah whatever,&amp;rdquo; Seifer said, picking up his duffel bag. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m off.&amp;rdquo; He
stepped out of the dormitory hallway and made his way to the exit. Not one
of the others could follow after him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Seifer turned the corner towards the exit, he heard a voice behind him.
&amp;ldquo;Hey.&amp;rdquo; Seifer turned around to see Squall leaning against the Garden
directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What, you come to laugh at me or something?&amp;rdquo; Seifer said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squall traced a line across his forehead scar with his forefinger.
&amp;ldquo;I still owe you. Don&amp;rsquo;t die.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hmph,&amp;rdquo; Seifer said and he walked off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Seifer wait up!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seifer looked at the two figures running towards him. &amp;ldquo;Raijin, Fujin,&amp;rdquo;
Seifer said, &amp;ldquo;What do you guys want?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What, you were just gonna leave without us?&amp;rdquo; Raijin said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;EXPLAIN.&amp;rdquo; Fujin said. It was a command, not a request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I convinced them I forced you both to do what I said.&amp;rdquo; Seifer replied.
&amp;ldquo;You guys get to stay. I&amp;rsquo;m the only one who has to go.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What are you talkin&amp;rsquo; about Seifer?&amp;rdquo; Raijin said, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re a posse, we can&amp;rsquo;t
be split now, y&amp;rsquo;know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You two still have a chance to take the SeeD test next year,&amp;rdquo; Seifer said,
&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t screw up your lives on my account.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;IDIOT.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wha&amp;ndash;?&amp;rdquo; Raijin was caught unawares. As far as he knew, Fujin had never
insulted Seifer before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What did you say Fujin?&amp;rdquo; Seifer said, surprised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Idiot. You think we didn&amp;rsquo;t know what we were doing?&amp;rdquo; Fujin said, her tone
of voice different. &amp;ldquo;We knew we&amp;rsquo;d get in trouble, yet we stuck by you. Now
you just want to leave us behind.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Heh.&amp;rdquo; Seifer&amp;rsquo;s face formed into his usual sneer. &amp;ldquo;I should&amp;rsquo;ve known.
Alright, gather your stuff, and meet me at Balamb.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alright,&amp;rdquo; Raijin said, &amp;ldquo;Where we goin, Seifer? Galbadia? Esthar?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seifer looked up for a bit before responding. &amp;ldquo;I think we&amp;rsquo;ll go fishing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zell rushed into the room. &amp;ldquo;Hey guys, turn it to channel 31.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Channel 31? Galbadia News?&amp;rdquo; Irvine picked up the remote and changed the
channel. A scene near a train station was being shown, and the field
reporter&amp;rsquo;s voice came through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;the situation was resolved when three unidentified mercenaries came in
and brought the Galbadian president to safety.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mercenaries?&amp;rdquo; A different voice spoke, probably the news anchor at the
station. &amp;ldquo;You mean SeeD?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, the authorities say they were definitely not SeeD. We cannot ascertain
their identities as they were taken by the Galbadia military for
questioning, but on of the witness reports their leader was a tall, blond
man wearing a white trench coat.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Blond wearing a white trenchcoat&amp;hellip; could it be?&amp;rdquo; Irvine said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squall put his palm over his forehead. &amp;ldquo;Can&amp;rsquo;t stay out of trouble can he?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ALMASY TO BE MILITARY CHIEF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Galbadian military announced today the ascension to the top post of
controversial General Seifer Almasy after the previous commander General
Hein died under mysterious circumstances. General Almasy will be the
youngest general ever to head the Galbadian military, having rapidly risen
up the ranks since he joined eight years ago. Civil groups have questioned
Almasy&amp;rsquo;s appointment, citing his spotty human-rights record. More on Page 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Galbadia Chronicle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;The crowds have really turned out tonight.&amp;rdquo; The reporter spoke above
the din of thousands of people in the streets of Galbadia watching the
parade. &amp;ldquo;Many Galbadian citizens have come to celebrate Vice President
Almasy&amp;rsquo;s assumption of the presidency, following President Orinas&amp;rsquo;s
scandalous impeachment. Seifer Almasy represents a new ho&amp;ndash;wait, it looks
like the new president is about to give his speech, I&amp;rsquo;m going in.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elsewhere, atop the Galbadia clock tower&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Who would&amp;rsquo;ve thought we&amp;rsquo;d be here again, fifteen years later?&amp;rdquo; Irvine
Kinneas waxed nostalgic as he readied his gun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be here at all Squall,&amp;rdquo; Quistis said, addressing their
commander.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Squall turned to Irvine, &amp;ldquo;Are you ready?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irvine nodded. &amp;ldquo;As ready as I&amp;rsquo;ll ever be.&amp;rdquo; He took his position and loaded
the gun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Squall&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Quistis said, &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;why?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You know the answer Quistis,&amp;rdquo; Squall said, giving Irvine the signal to
fire, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re the only ones who can.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-fin-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author&amp;rsquo;s Notes: This mostly pointless fic was written in just under twelve
minutes and was brought to you by the letters &amp;ldquo;K&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;W&amp;rdquo; and the number 7.
Written as a post on the Final Fantasy Forum
&lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/Final-Fantasy-Forum/&#34;&gt;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/Final-Fantasy-Forum/&lt;/a&gt; in response to the question
&amp;ldquo;What do you think happened to Seifer after the game?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Final Fantasy VIII: The Ultimate Junkie
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/07/final-fantasy-viii-the-ultimate-junkie/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/07/final-fantasy-viii-the-ultimate-junkie/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/447639/1/The-Ultimate-Junkie&#34;&gt;Fanfiction.net mirror&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fanfiction.net/r/447639/&#34;&gt;Fanfiction.net reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ultimate Junkie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Roy Tang (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:zroytang@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;zroytang@yahoo.com&lt;/a&gt; / roytang.cjb.net)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final Fantasy VIII is a copyright of Squaresoft, Inc. Standard disclaimers
apply. Spoilers? Not really&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m almost there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must&amp;rsquo;ve been walking for a day and a half now. A day and a half through
snow-filled forests and mountains, barely eating. I haven&amp;rsquo;t slept since that
ship dropped me off on this island. I&amp;rsquo;m tired and exhausted. But I need to get
there. I have to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The others&amp;ndash;they don&amp;rsquo;t understand. None of them understand. They tried to stop
me, to hold me back. You don&amp;rsquo;t need it, they said. How could they know? They
know what it&amp;rsquo;s like. The feeling of strength, the feeling of power, the rush of
adrenaline that I get. I need that rush. I want it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There it is! I&amp;rsquo;m finally here, after all that walking. The dome-like structure
stands out among the surrounding snow, like an out-of-place metal igloo. My goal
is here, I&amp;rsquo;m mere steps away. I quicken my pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In front of the dome, three figures stand. Barely four feet tall, they are
obviously not human. Yellow-skinned humanoids, Shumi. These three are the ones I
seek. They&amp;rsquo;re the only ones now between my goal and me. As I approach, they
glance at me before once again assuming their ready stances. They know what they
guard is valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bring out my purse, hoping I have enough money. It&amp;rsquo;s the last of my cash, the
last of my supplies. It&amp;rsquo;s not even my money, I had to swipe it from Rinoa. It&amp;rsquo;s
not like she needs it, her dad&amp;rsquo;s well off anyway. What I need is more important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shumi nod at me, and I toss the purse at them. They look over the purse,
then turn to look to each other. What? Not enough? No, please. I need to have
it. Come on&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll pay you back the rest later, I tell them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They shake their heads. Sorry. Sorry? Sorry won&amp;rsquo;t do. I need to have that power,
that rush. My own supply ran out days ago. I need a fix, and I need it bad. They
shake their heads once more, and ask me to leave. But I can&amp;rsquo;t leave. I need that
rush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I know it, the gunblade is in my hand. The Shumi, they&amp;rsquo;re sturdy people,
and some are known to be fierce warriors. But they haven&amp;rsquo;t faced the battles
I&amp;rsquo;ve faced. And of course they weren&amp;rsquo;t expecting it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first guard explodes into white blood before the other two can react. They
draw their weapons, I stare them down. They know they&amp;rsquo;re going to die. Fools.
They should&amp;rsquo;ve just given me what I wanted. One of them charges, the other runs
for the nearby dome entrance, hoping to sound an alarm. The second one dies
quickly, the gunblade going through his throat. Before his body even falls to
the ground, a low ringing sound begins to echo around the structure. The other
guard was quicker than I thought. As I turned, he was already on top of me,
blade ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that he would have gotten me. Not in a hundred years. He barely has time to
shout a death cry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guards are down. The alarm is sounding. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. My goal is
here, mere steps away. It&amp;rsquo;ll take them several minutes to get up here, and by
then it&amp;rsquo;ll be mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walk to the bright patch of snow the Shumi were guarding and lean down,
looking for that sensitive spot. There! There it is! Finally! It&amp;rsquo;s been so long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweating slightly, I close my eyes and focus on the goal. I can feel it there.
That power. That rush. I reach out with my mind, and take it for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes! An incredible rush comes over me, too much for me to handle. I fall over
from the shock. I can feel it come over me, overwhelming me with unbelievable
force. It fills my body and soul, flowing through my veins, invigorating every
cell of my body. God, yes! This is what I live for, this power, this
overwhelming power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rush passes, all too quickly. More, I need more. As I reach down to draw
more of that power, the gate of the dome opens, and five Shumi warriors come
out, determined looks on their faces. I smile and reach out my hand to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their eyes widen in fear as they realize what is about to happen. But it&amp;rsquo;s too
late. I feel the power flow through me again. Outwards this time, another
incredible rush, though not as good as the first one. I feel the energy course
through my veins, flowing out my outstretched arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shumi don&amp;rsquo;t have time to think. They move to scatter, but they are slow, too
slow. Before they can take a single step, a scintillating white light, with the
faintest hint of green appears around them, surrounding them, bathing them in a
pure white glow that makes the surrounding snow look like an oil slick. Their
faces recoil in fear, and the white glow seems to pulse for an infinite time,
before finally exploding into a thousand brilliant shards of pearl and emerald.
The glow settles, and there is nothing left. Not even a trace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now free of distractions, I reach down and continue to extract more of that
power. That sweet, flowing power. I look around, seeing the carnage I had
caused, and I realize that they were all right after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Squall Leonhart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I am an Ultima junkie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-fin-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author&amp;rsquo;s rants: &amp;ldquo;What? Squall would never do anything like that! That&amp;rsquo;s totally
OOC!&amp;rdquo; Maybe, maybe not, I don&amp;rsquo;t know. What I do know is that obsession and
addiction can bring out the worst in the best of us. And the worst about Squall
is that he would willfully place the lives of millions in danger to get what he
wants. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I have no such additions. Well, maybe to video games, maybe. Not
that I&amp;rsquo;d kill anyone over a video game, of course. This one was a quickie, done
in no more than thirty minutes, twenty even. I just thought about it while
watching someone play FF8. He kept going back to that draw point every so often
I said &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like you&amp;rsquo;re addicted to it.&amp;rdquo; Totally spur-of-the-moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah, I was just watching THE WEAKEST LINK (yeah all caps), so here&amp;rsquo;s a
little something extra:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nida: &amp;ldquo;Quistis, why Zell?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quistis: (shakes head) &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m ashamed to say I was his teacher. He flubbed so many
easy questions. Like the one about Hyne&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nida: &amp;ldquo;What about you, you&amp;rsquo;ve been to FH, haven&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quistis: &amp;ldquo;Well&amp;hellip; yes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nida: &amp;ldquo;How come you didn&amp;rsquo;t know the name of the mayor there?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quistis: &amp;ldquo;Well, that&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip; not exactly Garden curriculum&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nida: &amp;ldquo;Rinoa, why Zell?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rinoa: &amp;ldquo;Well, he seems to take so long to answer, and he got a lot of wrong
answers, so&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (shrugs)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nida: &amp;ldquo;You have a boyfriend, don&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rinoa: (embarassed) &amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nida: &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t you go out on dates?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rinoa: &amp;ldquo;We do&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nida: &amp;ldquo;Then how come you don&amp;rsquo;t know the meaning of &amp;lsquo;foot the bill&amp;rsquo;? Doesn&amp;rsquo;t he
pay for your meals?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rinoa: &amp;ldquo;Well&amp;hellip; he&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squall: (puts his palm to his forehead)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rinoa: (embarrassed) &amp;ldquo;He doesn&amp;rsquo;t earn much, so we always go Dutch.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nida: &amp;ldquo;How cheap!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squall: &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;Whatever.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nida: (turns to Zell) &amp;ldquo;Zell, according to our statistics you are not the weakest
link. However, with four votes, you are THE WEAKEST LINK. Goodbye.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Final Fantasy VIII: Days of Future Past (Part 1)
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/final-fantasy-viii-days-of-future-past-part-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/final-fantasy-viii-days-of-future-past-part-1/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/566295/1/Days-of-Future-Past&#34;&gt;Fanfiction.net mirror&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;part 1
by Roy Tang (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:zroytang@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;zroytang@yahoo.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://roytang.cjb.net&#34;&gt;http://roytang.cjb.net&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: Final Fantasy VIII and all related characters copyright of
Squaresoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Woah!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecis looked on in awe as she saw her fellow SeeD catapult out of the Lunar Base
at incredible speed. She looked up to her companions. &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s amazing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kai simply nodded at her. He had seen all this before, and every time a new SeeD
came to watch the launch process the reaction was always the same. He looked at
the other SeeD beside him, Mecis&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;special friend&amp;rdquo;, as she put it. Laguna
Hilmark looked on at the launch process in a bored sort of way, as if it was
nothing out of the ordinary, even though this was his first time at Lunar Gate
as well. &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s up, Laguna?&amp;rdquo; Kai said, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s something, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, well,&amp;rdquo; the 21-year old SeeD drawled, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it before in the training
simulations.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kai smiled. &amp;ldquo;Training isn&amp;rsquo;t much compared to the real thing, kid.&amp;rdquo; Laguna and
Mecis had been SeeDs for little more than three years now, but they had spent
most of their time in administrative functions rather than actual combat duty.
This was only Mecis&amp;rsquo; second assignment outside of Garden, but Laguna had far
more actual combat experience, and he tended to act like nothing surprised him
anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Next please.&amp;rdquo; The technician handling the launch pods gestured towards them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mecis, you&amp;rsquo;re up.&amp;rdquo; Kai gave her a friendly pat on the back. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;ll be fine.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Er, yeah&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Mecis said not a bit nervously, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s safe right?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laguna put an arm around her to reassure her. &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry. You&amp;rsquo;ve seen the sims
right? It&amp;rsquo;ll be over before you know it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecis nodded, and Kai couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but chuckle to himself. He had known these
two since they were cadets at Trabia, being one of their instructors, and he
knew that Mecis always had a tendency for travel sickness. &amp;lsquo;She should be fine
if Laguna&amp;rsquo;s with her&amp;rsquo;, he figured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laguna helped Mecis into the launch capsule. &amp;ldquo;It would help if we could all go
at once you know,&amp;rdquo; he muttered a bit loudly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes, it would, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo; Kai replied before the technicians could respond.
&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s just your luck that the other launch units are being serviced today. Don&amp;rsquo;t
worry, you&amp;rsquo;ll be launched right after her.&amp;rdquo; Laguna, Mecis and another SeeD were
being assigned to guard duty at the orbiting Lunar Base, and Kai was there to
see them off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laguna ignored him and turned to Mecis. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ll be fine, okay, I&amp;rsquo;ll be there
right after you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecis smiled back at him, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laguna smiled as well. Stepping down, he closed the hatch and moved away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Launch error correction, plus 2. Orbital correction, minus 1. Corrections
complete. Commencing launch&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; the technicians powered up the launch unit,
&amp;ldquo;3&amp;hellip;2&amp;hellip;1&amp;hellip;go!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the second time in his life, Laguna witnessed the powerful force of the
lunar launch unit. Acting as a magic-enhanced catapult, the device propelled
Mecis&amp;rsquo; Launch capsule upwards at a precalclated angle, going at more than twice
the escape velocity. The launch generated a powerful wake, and it was several
seconds before Laguna noticed Kai had said something to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; Laguna said to the senior SeeD even as his hearing recovered from the
momentary shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I said,&amp;rdquo; Kai repeated, &amp;ldquo;This is gonna be the last mission for the two of you,
isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laguna said nothing and looked up at Mecis&amp;rsquo; capsule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything flashed by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She felt a bump. Then another. And another. She started to regain her senses,
and Mecis felt slightly queasy. &amp;ldquo;Why did I agree to this?&amp;rdquo; she thought ruefully
to herself. The hibernation process initiated at the Lunar Gate prevented her
from moving around, but she was still flly conscious. Finally gathering enough
strength to look around, she glanced out the transparent glass hull of her Lunar
Capsule. Everything was still moving too fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another bump rocked the capsule, and she realized that the bumps were being
caused by large energy nets that served to slow the capsule&amp;rsquo;s momentum as it
hurtled towards the Lunar Base. Another bump, then another. After one more bump,
she realzed the capsule&amp;rsquo;s speed was relatively slower now, and that it was in
fact about to come to a halt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking outside, she saw the Lunar Base, a massive space station set into orbit
by the Esthar government more than a hundred years ago. &amp;ldquo;Amazing,&amp;rdquo; she said to
herself, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s larger than I thought.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four figures dressed in white appeared around her capsule. &amp;ldquo;Astronauts,&amp;rdquo; Mecis
realized, as the four figures started to bring her capsule towards the space
station. They loaded her capsule into a large machine, some sort of relay device
apparently. The device carted her capsule into the Lunar Base&amp;rsquo;s Dock Area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She felt a few more bumps, and the next thing she knew, she was inside a large
hangar-like structure. She heard a faint voice over the transceiver on the
capsule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Initiating quick thaw.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With relief, Mecis felt the temperature around her start to increase. Slowly,
the numbess vanished from her body, and she was able to move. The capsule hatch
opened, and she started to step out. As she looked around, she was surprised to
see her capsule was suspended off a wall roughly ten meters off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry,&amp;rdquo; she heard a voice, &amp;ldquo;Gravity&amp;rsquo;s off.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecis recognized the voice as belonging to Rez, the other SeeD she had met at
the mission briefing. Turnin towards him, she saw him floating around,
surrounded by several more astronauts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You okay?&amp;rdquo; Rez asked her. He was a tall, blond-haired guy, probably no more
than 20 years old. Mecis didn&amp;rsquo;t know much about him, except that he was from
Galbadia and that they would be working together at the Lunar Base for the next
three months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecis nodded. &amp;ldquo;Just a bit woozy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t go seasick now.&amp;rdquo; Rez said cautiously. Mecis smarted at the comment. Kai
knew she was conscious about her travel sickness, but went ahead and mentioned
it on the way to Lunar Gate anyway. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m so gonna smack him when we get back,&amp;rdquo;
she thought to herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She stepped out of the capsule, and felt herself floating in mid-air. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like
a Float spell,&amp;rdquo; she thought to herself. She recovered her duffel bag from the
capsule and floated towards Rez and the astronauts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s with the luggage?&amp;rdquo; Mecis asked Rez. Rez was carrying not only the
standard SeeD duffel bag, but also an additional backpack he wore over his
shoulder. It was unusual for SeeDs to carry more than the duffel bag during
missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rez shrugged. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a heavy packer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecis was about to reply when one of the astronauts spoke. &amp;ldquo;Third capsule
incoming.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Looks like your boyfriend&amp;rsquo;s coming in.&amp;rdquo; Rez commented. Mecis didn&amp;rsquo;t answer and
just looked out the transparent glass walls of the hangar. She saw another Lunar
Capsule come in from the distance, and row upon row of vibrant energy nets
appeared in front of it. As the Capsule hit each net, it lost a bit of speed,
until if finally slowed to a crawl. The four astronauts loaded the capsule into
the waiting relay machine, and she saw how the machine manuevered the capsule
into a nearby tube. The capsule shot out and reappeared near where her own
capsule was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Initiating quick thaw.&amp;rdquo; Mecis realized the voice was coming over a loudspeaker.
She saw Laguna&amp;rsquo;s capsule glow momentarily before the hatch opened. Laguna
stepped out, dragging his bag behind him. Unlike Mecis, he quickly adapted to
the zero-gravity condition and immediately went over to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You okay?&amp;rdquo; Laguna said to her. Mecis detected a bit of fatigue in his voice and
replied. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m fine. You look like that trip shook you a bit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, I just need a bit of sleep that&amp;rsquo;s all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecis smiled at his reply. Laguna would never admit to being shaken by anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They heard Rez call out to them. &amp;ldquo;If you lovebirds are ready, we gotta go see
the director.&amp;rdquo; He was already being escorted by a couple of astronauts towards a
nearby doorway. A couple more astronauts moved towards the pair, motioning them
to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s go,&amp;rdquo; Laguna said to Mecis. The astronauts guided them to the doorway and
into another room. The door shut behind them, and the astronauts slowly moved
them towards the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Locking gravity.&amp;rdquo; The same voice spoke over the loudspeaker. Mecis felt a
feeling of weightedness start to appear around her, similar to how a Float spell
wore off. She and the others gently landed on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gravity lock complete. Welcome to Esthar Lunar Base.&amp;rdquo; The door on the other
side of the hallway opened and the astronauts motioned them towards it. The
voice spoke again, &amp;ldquo;Please follow the right-hand corridor to report to the
Director. Thank you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three SeeDs stepped out into the corridor. It opened into three paths, one
heading left, one heading right, and a stairway goind up. &amp;ldquo;Well, time waits for
no one,&amp;rdquo; Rez said as he went down the right-hand hallway. Laguna and Mecis
followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Check it out!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecis was looking out the large glass window in the hallway. The window provided
a clear view of the surrounding space. At a slight distance from the space
station, there was a huge circular structure that seemed to be filled with some
sort of translucent crystal. A humanoid figrue dressed in blue could be seen
inside the structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Man, you get amazed easily, don&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rdquo; Rez needled her, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s Rinoa&amp;rsquo;s Tomb.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know what it is!&amp;rdquo; Mecis shot back, slightly annoyed. Rinoa&amp;rsquo;s Tomb was the
reason the Esthar Lunar Base was built. Rinoa Heartily, the last sorceress in
historical record, was being kept in suspended animation within the crystal
prison. Shortly after participating alongside SeeD in the last Sorceress War,
she was struck with a fatal disease that was impossible to recover from. Fearing
that her death would cause her powers to be passed on to a new, more powerful
sorceress, she had willfully succumbed to the suspension process. And she had
remained in this same place for the last hundred years, a grim reminder of the
danger posed to the world by the sorceress powers. And a grim reminder of why
SeeD&amp;rsquo;s vigilance was needed at all times. She had seen pictures of it before of
course, but the view from this close was completely different. One could see
completely into the crystal prison, and Mecis could almost see the expression on
her face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;She seems so&amp;hellip;sad.&amp;rdquo;, Mecis said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sad? What are you talking about? She&amp;rsquo;s a sorceress!&amp;rdquo; Rez retorted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s not what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about!&amp;rdquo; Mecis replied. &amp;ldquo;Rumor has it that her lover
was a SeeD!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, please, that&amp;rsquo;s just an urban legend.&amp;rdquo; Rez said. &amp;ldquo;Why would a SeeD become
involved with a sorceress?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laguna, having had enough of their witty reparte, nudged Mecis. &amp;ldquo;Come on, the
director&amp;rsquo;s waiting.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just three of you this time? Garden&amp;rsquo;s getting overconfident aren&amp;rsquo;t they?&amp;rdquo; Dr.
Kasim was the head of the Lunar Base staff and director of the Sorceress
Research project. &amp;ldquo;Or are they too busy fighting other people&amp;rsquo;s wars?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecis seethed at the insult. Ever since the last Sorceress had been defeated,
SeeD had made a name for itself as a powerful mercenary force. The current head
of Garden, Cid IV had justified it by saying Garden needed the money to maintain
it&amp;rsquo;s vigilance against the Sorceresses. This, along with SeeD&amp;rsquo;s tendency to
unfairly prosecute suspected potential Sorceresses had considerably dimmed
SeeD&amp;rsquo;s reputation worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That was an unnecessary comme-&amp;rdquo; Mecis was cut off as Laguna nudged her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laguna saluted the director and spoke. &amp;ldquo;Sir, with all due respect, three SeeDs
are more than enough to handle any threat that may appear, and Garden&amp;rsquo;s
peacekeeping operations are all geared towards protecting the peace of the
world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, whatever.&amp;rdquo; The director looked over the assignment sheet Laguna had
handed him. &amp;ldquo;Laguna Hilmark. Named after the former president eh?&amp;rdquo; Laguna simply
nodded. The director picked up a metallic card from his desk and tossed it to
Laguna.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s the pass for your quarters, take the elevator further down the hall to
sub-level III. Dismissed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laguna saluted again, and all three SeeDs filed out of the director&amp;rsquo;s room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nice guy,&amp;rdquo; Rez muttered, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m so gonna enjoy working for him&amp;hellip;NOT!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The door to the SeeD quarters slid open, and the three of them stepped inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Two rooms huh,&amp;rdquo; Rez said, looking around, &amp;ldquo;Will it be guys and girl, or will
you two be sharing a room?&amp;rdquo; He grinned at the two mischievously. Laguna shot him
a hard look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Heh, you said the wrong thing.&amp;rdquo; Mecis said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Garden Code Article 45 Paragraph 12.&amp;rdquo; Laguna recited in a monotone. &amp;ldquo;SeeD
members are forbidden from having relations while on duty.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sheesh, you&amp;rsquo;re really anal about the rules, aren&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rdquo; Rez said, &amp;ldquo;Lighten
up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Whatever.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I call this room!&amp;rdquo; Mecis said, entering the bigger bedroom. She put down her
duffel bag and started to unpack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laguna shrugged. He went into the other room. It had two bunker-style beds,
similar to those in Garde dormitories. Rez followed, tossed his bags unto the
top bed and walked out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where are you going?&amp;rdquo; Laguna asked him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m gonna go take a look around.&amp;rdquo; Rez said casually as he walked out of the
quarters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t get into any trouble,&amp;rdquo; Laguna called after him as he went on unpacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecis stepped into their room after Rez walked out. &amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t he tired? He&amp;rsquo;s okay
though, isn&amp;rsquo;t he?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laguna looked up at her. &amp;ldquo;Yeah, I guess. He&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird though.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do you mean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with him before, during the Timber mission. &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Against the Forest Owls?&amp;rdquo; Mecis had heard the story from Laguna before. The
Forest Owls were a revolutionary group led by pro-Sorceress fanatics. Laguna had
been assigned there a year ago to defend Timber after a potential Sorceress was
rumored to have been found in that area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah,&amp;rdquo; Laguna nodded, &amp;ldquo;He was kind of a loner and was really quiet, like he
didn&amp;rsquo;t like what was going on.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecis shrugged. &amp;ldquo;He seems fine to me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, you should get used to him, we&amp;rsquo;ll all be working together for the next
three months.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Laguna&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laguna hesitated before asking. &amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;After this mission, are we&amp;ndash;?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laguna sighed. Mecis had wanted to retire from SeeD after this mission. While
she was a tough girl, she was physically weak compared to other SeeDs, which was
why she had preferred to take administrative functions during her tour of duty.
She was tired of her and Laguna constantly being in danger because they were
SeeDs, and had wanted to start a peaceful life in her hometown of Winhill.
&amp;ldquo;Didn&amp;rsquo;t the Headmaster at Trabia invite you to be an instructor?&amp;rdquo; Laguna said to
her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, but&amp;hellip;I dunno. I&amp;rsquo;d still be a SeeD.&amp;rdquo; Even as an instructor, SeeDs could
be called to combat duty at any time if needed. Mecis sighed, &amp;ldquo;Do you still want
to&amp;ndash;?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s just that if we quit,&amp;rdquo; Laguna replied, &amp;ldquo;then what would I do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecis smiled. &amp;ldquo;You could be something ordinary. Like a barber!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Laguna shook his head. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re being silly. Tell you what. Let&amp;rsquo;s wait &amp;lsquo;til this
mission is over. After this one, we&amp;rsquo;ll go on vacation, and we&amp;rsquo;ll decide then,
okay?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mecis smiled at him again. A vacation was better than nothing. &amp;ldquo;Okay.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kai was walking down a hallway in the Tears Point research facility, several
kilometers from the Lunar Gate. He stopped at a door marked &amp;ldquo;Lunar Observation
Control&amp;rdquo; and made his way in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room was a large array of computers and monitors. Several heads craned to
look at him when he entered, and all but one went back to their work after they
did not recognize him. Sienna Balmont, commander of SeeD&amp;rsquo;s Dincht division
responsible for Esthar, nodded to him. &amp;ldquo;Did the launch go well?&amp;rdquo; she asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kai nodded back. &amp;ldquo;They&amp;rsquo;re fine. They should be resting up at the Lunar Base by
now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, they&amp;rsquo;re going to need that rest,&amp;rdquo; Sienna muttered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do you mean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Readings here indicate unusual activity on the surface of the moon over the
past few weeks. The &amp;lsquo;residents&amp;rsquo; of the moon seem to be converging on a
particular spot.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You mean&amp;ndash;?&amp;rdquo; Kai was surprised at what she was implying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes. Apparently, the time has come for another Lunar Cry.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TBC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author&amp;rsquo;s Rants:
Well, this is the first time I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing a multi-part &amp;lsquo;fic, so wish me luck!
Anyway, I know nothing much happened in this part, but I just wanted to lay the
groundwork for some future events. I wanted to include the first major plot
event in this one, but after writing the above, I felt it would be a bit too
long, so I&amp;rsquo;ll just cut it here. Between the cheesy title and the happenings
here, can you guess what this &amp;lsquo;fic will be about? Stay tuned.
On a side note, if FF8 is my least favorite FF game, why am I writing about it?
It&amp;rsquo;s because the story was so weak I have to supplement it myself, lol. No
offense to FF8-lovers. =)
As always, any comments, corrections, suggestions, e-mail me. Flames, send &amp;lsquo;em
to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:bill@microsoft.com&#34;&gt;bill@microsoft.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Final Fantasy IX: Nobody Wants To Live Forever
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2001/11/final-fantasy-ix-nobody-wants-to-live-forever/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2001/11/final-fantasy-ix-nobody-wants-to-live-forever/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/447644/1/Nobody-Wants-to-Live-Forever&#34;&gt;Fanfiction.net mirror&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fanfiction.net/r/447644/&#34;&gt;Fanfiction.net reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody Wants to Live Forever&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;by Roy Tang (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:zroytang@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;zroytang@yahoo.com&lt;/a&gt; / royness.vze.com)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final Fantasy IX is a copyright of Squaresoft, Inc. Standard disclaimers apply.
Final Fantasy IX spoilers, all the way baby!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Vivi Ornitier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a black mage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is to say, I can call upon elemental forces to weave powerful magical
spells of destruction. Which is often quite handy, especially when facing a
large group of plant-like creatures that can tear me apart with their limbs or
petrify me with a single drop of their saliva.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple flick of my wrist and a small burst of concentration is all it takes,
and three of the plant-creatures explode into ice shards. Six more appear to
replace the fallen ones. I had hoped I would never have to use these powers
again. Fate seemed to have a different opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freya walked silently along the street of Treno. She wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to come
back here for a while, with all the events over in Burmecia. So she wanted to
take one last stroll before she took the ride to Lindblum. The moon cast a pale
glow over Treno at this time of day. Strange that for a city that never
sleeps, it looks its brightest when the moon is full.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freya stopped at the stairway leading to the street near Dr. Tot&amp;rsquo;s house. A lone
figure was sitting at the landing on top of walkway. Recognizing the hat, Freya
walked up and sat down beside him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, what&amp;rsquo;s wrong?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure gave a start, apparently noticing Freya for the first time.
&amp;ldquo;Oh&amp;hellip; I&amp;hellip; well&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s nothing, I guess&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Did you visit Dr. Tot?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Y-yeah. He wanted to see me that&amp;rsquo;s all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You sure there&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong?&amp;rdquo; Freya made a worried face at her friend. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve
been hearing some rumors from the village.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, I&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s nothing.&amp;rdquo; He got up. &amp;ldquo;Sorry, I promised Eiko I&amp;rsquo;d teach her how to
bid at the auction today.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freya nodded, and the little guy ran off with his unusual stride. A faint
screeching sound echoed in the distance and Freya recognized it as the familiar
hum of the railway cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Guess that&amp;rsquo;s my ride,&amp;rdquo; she said to no one in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Vivi, behind you!&amp;rdquo; The voice belonged to Blank, one of the Tantalus Crew. He&amp;rsquo;s
a nice guy, always looking out for other people. It&amp;rsquo;s a good thing he&amp;rsquo;s looking
out for me right now, as I spin around to see a giant green tentacle about to
slam down on me. As he jumped up to take on the offending vegetable, I threw a
quick bolt of lightning at his sword, and his enchanted blade took the target
down in one blow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate fighting, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad I decided to come along with the Tantalus. Back
here, to where it all began. For me and my brothers at least, although we can&amp;rsquo;t
say we were born here, this is where our souls came from. The excuses we have
for souls at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come on, we&amp;rsquo;re almost there!&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s Marcus, another one of the Tantalus Crew.
I pointed a finger, and a large ball of flame exploded against the plant walls
before us, opening the way deeper into the maze of plant-life that was the Iifa
Tree. Or what remained of it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bargaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looked up at the avian doctor. He knew it would come eventually, but to hear
someone say it was an entirely different matter all together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Doctor Tot&amp;hellip;are you sure&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; His high-pitched voice trailed off. &amp;ldquo;There must
be something you can do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doctor Tot sighed. He always hated to be the bearer of bad news. He adjusted his
spectacles and looked at the young man with sadness in his eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;ll conduct some more tests with the samples I took but&amp;hellip; I can&amp;rsquo;t
promise anything.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What about the other tests? Didn&amp;rsquo;t you find anything?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I haven&amp;rsquo;t had enough time to complete the other tests, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Doctor&amp;hellip; please&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Tot could here the desperation in his voice. &amp;ldquo;There has to
be something&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry. We all knew this would happen, sooner or later.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No&amp;hellip; This can&amp;rsquo;t be&amp;hellip; not now&amp;hellip; I&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; He couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the strength to gather
his thoughts. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry Doctor.&amp;rdquo; He ran off without another word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doctor Tot closed his eyes, adjusted his spectacles and grimaced. He hated being
the bearer of bad news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another wall breaks down, and we rush forward, stopping suddenly at the edge of
what seemed to be a deep semicircular crevice with walls made of green foliage.
As if on cue, twigs, branches and leaves gave way inside the crevice, revealing
numerous spider-like plant-creatures, the same ones we&amp;rsquo;d encountered before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tantalus Crew almost cringed at the sight of these hordes, but their
attention was drawn by Marcus&amp;rsquo; outstretched hand. &amp;ldquo;Over there!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Near the center of the crevice, two human like figures lay on the ground,
unmoving, and right at the base of the Iifa Tree. Without hesitation, we make
our way across the valley of beasts. I provide covering fire as Blank and Cinna
make their way toward the two figures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just as I thought,&amp;rdquo; Blank says, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the same thing as the petrified forest.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cinna inspects the first body. &amp;ldquo;This one&amp;rsquo;s dead. Looks like he&amp;rsquo;s been this way
for weeks.&amp;rdquo; Marcus and I turn to look at the body, and heave a sigh of relief
when it&amp;rsquo;s not the one we&amp;rsquo;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Must&amp;rsquo;ve been Kuja. Poor sap,&amp;rdquo; Blank said. But our attention was already held by
the other figure, a somewhat short humanoid form, encased in stone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Zidane.&amp;rdquo; I manage to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ouch!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eiko had been one her way to Doctor Tot&amp;rsquo;s residence when she collided with a
small figure apparently in a hurry. Apparently, the other one was as surprised
as she was, as both of them were knocked back a bit by the collision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Watch where you&amp;rsquo;re&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo; Eiko looked at the one she had bumped into. &amp;ldquo;Vivi?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vivi dusted himself off and looked at the young summoner. &amp;ldquo;Oh, hi Eiko. Excuse
me, I&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey!&amp;rdquo; Eiko said, grabbing Vivi&amp;rsquo;s arm before he could dash off, &amp;ldquo;Where do you
think you&amp;rsquo;re going? I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking all over for you! You made me wait up at
the auc&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eiko was surprised to be cut off as Vivi shook off her hand. &amp;ldquo;Sorry, Eiko, but I
don&amp;rsquo;t have time for this right now, okay?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What? Is there a problem? Some sort of emergency?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Problem? Of course not!&amp;rdquo; Eiko was astonished to hear a hint of sarcasm in
Vivi&amp;rsquo;s voice, a tone she&amp;rsquo;d never heard from the black mage before. &amp;ldquo;The world is
safe remember? We went out and saved the world! Why should there be a problem?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Vivi, what are you&amp;ndash;?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We went all the way to a different world, faced the spirit of destruction, and
that&amp;hellip; that monkey Kuja is dead!&amp;rdquo; Vivi&amp;rsquo;s voice was completely different from his
usual shy tone, even though his featureless face revealed nothing. &amp;ldquo;Everything
should be great! Everyone should be happy!&amp;rdquo; Vivi shook his hands around him in
frustration. Eiko noticed sparks starting to form around her erstwhile friend.
People had started to stop and stare at the ranting little boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Vivi, I think you should calm down.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Calm down? Look at what&amp;rsquo;s happened to us! The princess hasn&amp;rsquo;t spoken to anyone
since Zidane&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Vivi&amp;rsquo;s voice trailed off, &amp;ldquo;And now I&amp;hellip;I&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Tendrils of energy
started to twirl around his cone-shaped hat, totally unnoticed by the now
ranting mage. &amp;ldquo;We went out and gave everything for everyone! It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be
like this!&amp;rdquo; The ground around Vivi suddenly burst into an explosion of flames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aaah!!!&amp;rdquo; Eiko was knocked off her feet and was thrown to the nearby wall.
&amp;ldquo;Ou&amp;ndash;ch!!!&amp;rdquo; The nearby townspeople were forced back by the sudden blaze. Despite
all the events that had happened lately, exploding flames were never a good
thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vivi stopped and noticed the flames swirling around him. &amp;ldquo;Wha&amp;ndash;? Oh no!&amp;rdquo; He
turned to see a slightly scorched Eiko trying to stand up. He looked down at his
own hands to see traces of the flames still lingering on his gloves. &amp;ldquo;Eiko, I&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;
Not knowing what to say, Vivi ran off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eiko heard footsteps behind her and turned to see Doctor Tot approaching from
his residence. The doctor adjusted his spectacles, and turned to help Eiko get
up. &amp;ldquo;What happened here?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re running now, as hard and as fast as we can. As soon as the Supersoft had
taken effect, a large bulbous head had appeared from the Iifa Tree, as if
defending it&amp;rsquo;s home from a robbery. Marcus had taken the unconscious Zidane over
his shoulders, and we made our way back to daylight. By the time we reached the
Tantalus, I was exhausted, and nearly drained of my power. The Benero brothers
waved us on board, and the engines roared to life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right behind us however, the mass of tentacles at the base of the Iifa Tree
started to move. They shot out, with the bulbous head just behind them, as if
ordering them to prevent our escape. I drew upon my last remaining reserves and
tried to hold them off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baku ordered the liftoff, and the Tantalus took to the air. Three tentacles shot
out, two of them latching onto the Tantalus&amp;rsquo; bow, the other onto the tail. More
tentacles came out as the ship was swung around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baku came out armed now, &amp;ldquo;The ship&amp;rsquo;ll break apart if this goes on!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amarant nodded grimly to the guard as the gate closed behind him. He hefted his
pack over his left shoulder, and looked towards the station. The night was
young, and he had a long way to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mr. Amarant?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amarant turned around at the high-pitched voice. It&amp;rsquo;s the kid, he thought to
himself. The &amp;ldquo;kid&amp;rdquo; was seated on a small knoll just outside of the Treno city
gate. Judging from the dew gathering around his hat, he&amp;rsquo;d been there for a
while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Are you leaving too?&amp;rdquo; He heard the kid say the words, but he couldn&amp;rsquo;t see how
he spoke. Not that it mattered. Amarant was never one to try to figure
everything out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah. I still got some &amp;lsquo;unfinished business&amp;rsquo; elsewhere.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh. I see. Everyone&amp;rsquo;s leaving then&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; The kid&amp;rsquo;s voice trailed off with a
familiar tone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah. You&amp;rsquo;re the last one left. Still got business with the doc?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well&amp;hellip; I&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; His bright eyes seemed to affix themselves to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amarant grunted. &amp;ldquo;Guess what the brat told me was true, huh?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;B-brat?&amp;rdquo; The kid looked up, &amp;ldquo;You mean Eiko?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah. She kept pestering me about cheerin&amp;rsquo; you up.&amp;rdquo; Amarant turned to go. &amp;ldquo;Not
that I care, mind you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amarant took a couple of steps, then, as if changing his mind, stopped in
mid-stride. &amp;ldquo;You wanna live forever, kid?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;W-what?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amarant went on without turning around. &amp;ldquo;Everybody goes sometime you know.
You&amp;rsquo;re luckier than most, &amp;lsquo;coz you know when to expect it. But people like me,
that brat, even that goof-off knight or that guard by the gate, we have no idea.
We could be dead tomorrow for all we know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;M-Mr. Amarant&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But you don&amp;rsquo;t see us sittin&amp;rsquo; on a hill wonderin&amp;rsquo; why we gotta die, do you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you think sitting there feeling sorry for yourself is the best you can do,
go ahead. But the rest of us, we go ahead, and do whatever it is we do, even if
we die the next day. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what you believe in, but that&amp;rsquo;s gotta be
better than moping around.&amp;rdquo; Amarant started to walk off again. &amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Sides kid,
nobody wants to live forever.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vivi looked at Amarant&amp;rsquo;s departing figure and considered the mercenary&amp;rsquo;s words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blank shouted something to his companions as he tried to keep the ship steady. I
couldn&amp;rsquo;t hear above the noise of the battle. Baku, Marcus and Cinna came
forward. Cinna took the helm, and the others tried to hack off the offending
plants. It was no use however, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t break free. It seemed like the more
we fought, the more tentacles appeared. And we were too tired to go on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zidane, awakened by the violent assault, got to his feet groggily. &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s going
on?&amp;rdquo; he asked as he held on to Cinna for balance. Cinna told him to stay down,
but Zidane, quickly taking stock of the situation, drew a dagger from Cinna&amp;rsquo;s
belt. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not gonna go without a fight,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;If Tantalus goes down, we
all go down!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Down below, the giant bulbous head looked up at us, as if taunting us. &amp;ldquo;There is
no escape.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think you should come with us, little guy.&amp;rdquo; Baku looked down at the
small figure beside him as the crew loaded their gear unto his ship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;B-but, Mr. Baku&amp;hellip;I really want to help.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know that, kid, but&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s a Tantalus thing, you know?&amp;rdquo; Baku smiled grimly.
&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re the ones who gotta go after that idiot.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s up Boss?&amp;rdquo; Blank walked up to the pair, slightly sweaty from the day&amp;rsquo;s
work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t what&amp;rsquo;s up me, how&amp;rsquo;s the loading?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s fine. Everything oughta be finished by dusk. Heya Vivi.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The diminutive black mage nodded, adjusted his hat, and decided to convince
Blank instead. &amp;ldquo;Please let me come with you Blank!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What? It&amp;rsquo;s gonna be pretty dangerous, y&amp;rsquo;know.&amp;rdquo; Blank said, as if uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s what I keep tellin&amp;rsquo; the kid,&amp;rdquo; Baku agreed, before going to look over the
loading process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blank turned to Vivi. &amp;ldquo;You really want to find him don&amp;rsquo;t you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Please Blank, it&amp;rsquo;s the least I can do for him,&amp;rdquo; Vivi pleaded. &amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s done so
much for me, for all of us! I, I&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blank smiled and crouched down beside the black mage. &amp;ldquo;To be honest, I don&amp;rsquo;t
think we can do it by ourselves.&amp;rdquo; He looked over at Baku&amp;rsquo;s hulking form. &amp;ldquo;Didn&amp;rsquo;t
want to mention it in front of the boss, though.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Then will you&amp;ndash;?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blank shook his head, and Vivi&amp;rsquo;s eyes showed signs of disappointment. &amp;ldquo;The
Boss&amp;rsquo;d never agree. Sorry Vivi, gotta keep packin&amp;rsquo;. See those crates over
there.&amp;rdquo; Vivi looked over to where he pointed and saw several large wooden
crates. &amp;ldquo;I still gotta load those, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know why we&amp;rsquo;re usin&amp;rsquo; such large
crates.&amp;rdquo; He smiled at Vivi again. &amp;ldquo;Probably enough space in those crates to fit
a small person, you know what I mean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vivi looked up, a surprised look in his eyes, and nodded gratefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blank stood up. &amp;ldquo;I think I&amp;rsquo;ll talk to the boss for a bit before packing those
crates.&amp;rdquo; He winked at Vivi and turned to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baku looked over his shoulder as Blank came to stand beside him. &amp;ldquo;Did you
convince him?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, I told him you&amp;rsquo;d never agree.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Poor kid. You hear about the thing from Doctor Tot?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blank nodded at his boss. &amp;ldquo;Perfectly understandable why he wants to come
though.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, I guess.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you do the same thing in his position?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baku grunted and shouted to his men. &amp;ldquo;Hurry it up, we gotta schedule to keep! We
gotta play in Alexandria in a week, Iifa Tree or no Iifa Tree!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these thoughts flashed back through my head as Zidane spoke his words. We
were almost gonna now, the Tantalus was about to be broken in half. Only a
miracle could get us out. In desperation Blank went to the side of the airship
and looked down at the ominous plant core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Blank!&amp;rdquo; Marcus said, &amp;ldquo;What are you thinking?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s just like the Evil Forest Marcus!&amp;rdquo; Blank shouted as he fended off the
attacking tentacles. &amp;ldquo;These plants&amp;rsquo;ll die down once the core is dead!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t be an idiot!&amp;rdquo; Baku shouted, grabbing Blank back from the ship&amp;rsquo;s railings.
&amp;ldquo;You won&amp;rsquo;t last two seconds out there!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All of us are gonna die at this rate!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Baku and Blank&amp;rsquo;s voices faded out of my head as they kept arguing. I knew Blank
was right. The ship wouldn&amp;rsquo;t hold much longer, and all of our lives were now
threatened. Zidane. Baku. Blank. Marcus. Cinna. Benero. Zenero. Genero. And me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, there was no choice, really. One dying soul in exchange for eight
others to live. After all, nobody wants to live forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Zidane!&amp;rdquo; I turned to him as I started to gather the last of my energies. This
man had taught me to appreciate who I was, to enjoy life, and to give all of
myself for what I believe in, and today, I was proud to give myself for him.
&amp;ldquo;Please make the princess happy!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What? Vivi!&amp;rdquo; I could hear Zidane&amp;rsquo;s shout as I ran to the edge of the ship and
dived towards the core, that green bulbous plant that had threatened our lives.
I felt the power coalesce around me as I hurtled downward, dark energies from
beyond this world gathering around my fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came to this world spawned from this tree, and today I return to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Doomsday!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-fin-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author&amp;rsquo;s rants: Ye gods, the last semester of college really took a lot of wind
out of me, I think. I&amp;rsquo;m exhausted now, maybe because I decided to do half of
this all in one sitting. Which would explain why some parts might look like they
were written hastily. =) Anyway, if you find any such parts, please email me so
I can get around to fixing &amp;lsquo;em. Also, I know there&amp;rsquo;s bound to be a lot of
spelling errors here seeing as how my keyboard is behaving abnormally and I
don&amp;rsquo;t use a spell checker. (I hate Word!) Ah, I&amp;rsquo;m rambling now. Must be a result
of several months of not writing anything but technical papers. Gotta get some
sleep. (Goes to sleep.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Final Fantasy VI: Something to Live For
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2001/11/final-fantasy-vi-something-to-live-for/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2001/11/final-fantasy-vi-something-to-live-for/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fanfiction.net/s/393006/1/Something-to-Live-For&#34;&gt;Fanfiction.net mirror&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fanfiction.net/r/393006/&#34;&gt;Fanfiction.net reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An FF6 fan fiction work by: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:zroytang@yahoo.com&#34;&gt;zroytang@yahoo.com&lt;/a&gt;. Final Fantasy VI and all
characters involved are copyright of Squaresoft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Author&amp;rsquo;s note: This story takes place before the start of FF6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stop, thief!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He heard the shopkeeper shouting after him, and grimaced. A couple of
years or so ago if someone told him he&amp;rsquo;d be stealing food off merchants in South
Figaro, he&amp;rsquo;d laugh in their faces. He was a different man then, with different
worries. The man he was today couldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to think about such things as
honor or ethics. He was too busy thinking about food, and money. And his
research of course. He had to do his research. What did it all mean otherwise?
The months of living off stolen food and money, moving from place to place,
robbing scholars and merchants alike, living as a thief. Damn, he said to
himself. These aren&amp;rsquo;t the thoughts to be having while being pursued by Imperial
Troopers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hurry up, Biggs, he&amp;rsquo;s getting away!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His somewhat stout companion was lagging a step or so behind him,
adjusting his brown helmet. But he couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to slow down and wait for
him, he thought as he saw his quarry turn right into the next alley. This had
been the chance they were waiting for, a chance to prove themselves to their
superiors. He sped up the chase as his prey knocked down a couple of merchant
stalls in his haste to get away. He looked around and tried to figure out where
his target was heading. Biggs was still right behind him, panting, but still
running. They had known each other since they were kids back in their hometown,
dreaming of becoming Imperial Generals. He looked back to his friend and shouted
an unnecessarily rough command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Biggs, he&amp;rsquo;s headed for the west side exit! Get the Guards to cover that
side!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biggs nodded at Wedge words, and turned down the next corner to alert
the Figaro Guards on the west side. He was a bit miffed at Wedge&amp;rsquo; tone. They
were, after all, of equal rank, having been Sergeants in the Imperial Army for,
what, two years now? His mind flashed back to the time he and Biggs were
promoted, how happy they were that they were one step closer to their dream. He
remembered that dream and forgave his friend&amp;rsquo;s words. He was merely excited
after all, since this capture would undoubtedly lead to a promotion. He caught
sight of the Figaro Guardsmen at their post, and stepped up his running a notch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damn, he&amp;rsquo;s still right behind me, the object of the soldiers&amp;rsquo; attention
said to himself. He was a pretty fast runner, but this guy was hot on his tail.
He glanced back at his pursuer as he jumped down the steps from the rampart to
ground level. He looks young, he thought to himself, probably hasn&amp;rsquo;t even been
in the service five years, a private or a sergeant at most. He considered
stopping and pulling out the dirk in his belt, as the guy probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t
stand a chance. But he hated killing, and avoided it whenever he could. Besides
the guy just needed to hold him off for a few minutes before the Guard could
surround him. No, I&amp;rsquo;ll just stick to the plan &amp;ndash; out the west side wall and off
to Narshe. He turned the corner, stopped and fell back as he caught sight of the
seven or eight Guards at the gate, with an Imperial Soldier commanding them. Oh
well, it was a bad plan anyway. He looked back to see the other soldier about to
pounce on him. He drew his blade and parried just before the sword cut off his
left arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, take it easy! I&amp;rsquo;m a thief, not a murderer!&amp;rdquo; Not yet, at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hmph. I know who you are.&amp;rdquo; Wedge made a feint, hoping to fake out a
counterattack. &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve had reports of your activities in this area for some time
now. And your time is up.&amp;rdquo; When his opponent failed to counter, he followed
through, hoping to catch him in the right shoulder with a quick thrust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry, kid,&amp;rdquo; the thief said as he knocked the incoming blade to the
side.
&amp;ldquo;But there&amp;rsquo;s no way I&amp;rsquo;m letting myself get caught here.&amp;rdquo; He turned around
quickly, letting the man&amp;rsquo;s thrust slide harmlessly behind him, and proceeded to
knock him down with the hilt of his blade. He heard the soldiers coming before
he saw them, so he started running again as his opponent fell to his knees,
hands massaging the back of his neck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wedge, what happened?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about me, just go get that guy!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Biggs attended to his defeated partner, the thief looked back to see
seven Figaro Guards in hot pursuit. Damn, I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll have to go out the other
side. I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll be hiding in a cave again for a couple of days. He changed
his mind when he saw the guards gathered at the east side entrance. He sighed to
himself as he turned and ran up the stairs to the ramparts. Why did I always
come back to South Figaro anyway? South Figaro was well-manned, both by Figaro
Guards and Imperial Soldiers, mainly because most of the trade between the
Empire and Figaro passed through here. That meant a lot of merchants to steal
from, but it also meant you had a hell of a time escaping. Uh oh, he muttered as
he saw the two Imperial Soldiers who had chased him earlier right in front of
him. He looked around, jumping off the rampart was out of the question, there
were three guards on the ground level just waiting for him. And the other four
were right behind him. He stopped, shrugged, and turned to the two Troopers, a
despondent look on his face. It&amp;rsquo;s not like he was worried about getting
captured. After all, he&amp;rsquo;d been captured before, and he would probably be out
again in a couple of days. What bothered him was that the chase was over. That
was all he really lived for these days, the thrill of the chase. That and
his&amp;hellip;research of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I guess you got me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Like I said, your time&amp;rsquo;s up. By order of the Imperial Magistrate, you
are
under arrest, Locke Cole.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biggs produced a pair of shackles and Wedge grabbed Locke, pinning his
arms
behind him. He was about to snap on the shackles when the Figaro Guards came up
to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Release this man to our custody,&amp;rdquo; the Guard Commander said to the two
Troopers. &amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s wanted by the King of Figaro for crimes against the nation of
Figaro.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What? This man is wanted under Imperial Law, and we came here
specifically
to bring him to the Emperor&amp;rsquo;s justice.&amp;rdquo; Wedge said. Although officially, they
were just stationed here as part of the &amp;ldquo;diplomatic envoy&amp;rdquo; to Figaro, they had
taken it upon themselves to prove their abilities to their superiors by catching
a notorious thief. &amp;ldquo;It is our duty to bring him back to the Imperial Capital for
summary execution.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Execution? Yeah, right. Locke wasn&amp;rsquo;t worried about that. He felt a bit
miffed though, being fought over by two sets of soldiers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, Sergeant,&amp;rdquo; the Guard Commander said, emphasizing Wedge&amp;rsquo;s
rank.
&amp;ldquo;But this man was captured on Figaro territory, and the King&amp;rsquo;s Guards get first
crack at him. We&amp;rsquo;re allies, yes. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t give your Imperial Army
authority in these lands.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was here again. It seems he was here every night. Wherever he was,
his
dreams almost always brought him back to this place. A place he hadn&amp;rsquo;t visited
for little more than a year now. Kohlingen.
It seemed only yesterday he was living in this quiet little town, an
aspiring treasure hunter. He used to love this place. He wasn&amp;rsquo;t very well off,
but he had a house here, a cozy little place he had inherited a long time ago.
He loved the people here, the atmosphere, and the scenery. And Rachel. Of
course, there was always Rachel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t be silly Locke,&amp;rdquo; Rachel had said to him as they sat at their
usual
table at the town&amp;rsquo;s only restaurant. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve been in those caves a million
times. What makes you think you&amp;rsquo;ll find anything new today?&amp;rdquo; She always needled
him about his &amp;lsquo;job&amp;rsquo;, or lack of it as the case may be. But she loved him. Of
this he was sure. He would never be able to provide for her in the way her
parents wanted, but he knew he loved her as well, and that he would always take
care of her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just a feeling I got,&amp;rdquo; he had said with his usual air of confidence.
&amp;ldquo;There was an unusual cleft I saw the last time I was in there. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure
that there are other artifacts in there like the last one.&amp;rdquo; He had found an
ancient spear in the cave before, and a scholar had verified for him that it was
indeed an artifact, from the War of the Magi perhaps. Which was why he wanted to
explore the caves more. Rachel always worried about him, and he hated worrying
her. But a few more artifacts like that, and the two of them could probably be
set for life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No good will come of these &amp;lsquo;artifacts&amp;rsquo; you know,&amp;rdquo; had Rachel said in
her
most lecturing tone, &amp;ldquo;the War of the Magi ended a thousand years ago, and
digging up long-forgotten weapons won&amp;rsquo;t help the peace any. Who knows, one of
these weapons you excavate could catch the interest of the Empire. What would
happen to Kohlingen then?&amp;rdquo; Rachel&amp;rsquo;s father was a scholar, a historian who
studied the War of the Magi. So her father always told her of the horrible
struggle that ended a thousand years ago, and how they should all learn from
history&amp;rsquo;s mistakes. She smiled at him, &amp;ldquo;After all, if something were to happen
to our little town, where would we live when we got married?&amp;rdquo; Locke&amp;rsquo;s face went
red at the memory of her smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locke woke up to the sound of a voice from the other side of his cell
wall.
Oh well, he said to himself. I&amp;rsquo;ve dreamed the same dream a thousand times
anyway. The voice behind the wall repeated itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; Locke said to the wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, you&amp;rsquo;re awake. I heard the guards talking about you. Is it true
you&amp;rsquo;re
Locke Cole?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, what of it?&amp;rdquo; he responded cautiously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wow! I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to meet you! You&amp;rsquo;re my hero! I&amp;rsquo;ve heard all
about
your &amp;lsquo;jobs&amp;rsquo; back in the Empire!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locke sighed. It&amp;rsquo;s bad enough he was a thief. Now he was a famous thief.
With an enthusiastic fan. He curled up and tried to get back to sleep. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re
thinking of someone else, just let me sleep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently his excited prison mate hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard him. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m Lone Wolf, the
pickpocket. I mean, I&amp;rsquo;m just a pickpocket now, but someday I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be a famous
thief like you! So, when are you planning to escape? You are planning to escape,
right?&amp;rdquo; Another two-bit crook, Locke figured. They were being held in the prison
in the basement of Figaro Castle. The Guards had taken him here after a rather
heated argument with the two Troopers. He figured he&amp;rsquo;d stay for a couple of
days, if only to take advantage of the free food. But his &amp;lsquo;friend&amp;rsquo; behind the
wall didn&amp;rsquo;t need to know that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not gonna escape. Just go to sleep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What? You can&amp;rsquo;t be serious! I mean, they probably won&amp;rsquo;t execute us like
the Empire would, but&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voice trailed off at the sound of the far doors of the prison
creaking
open, something eerily noticeable in the darkness. A couple of guards walked up
to his cell, one of them carrying a candle. Behind them, Locke could see the
silhouette of a tall, robed man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Locke Cole?&amp;rdquo; The robed man turned to the guard for confirmation. &amp;ldquo;The
King
wishes to see you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locke wondered what the King of Figaro would want with him as the Guards
opened his cell and brought him to his feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Be strong, man!&amp;rdquo; His unseen friend spoke out to him again, albeit in a
more subdued voice. &amp;ldquo;You can get out of this!&amp;rdquo; He never heard from that guy
again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edgar Roni Figaro, king of the small nation of Figaro, was in his throne
room. You&amp;rsquo;d think someone who was royalty would be surrounded by servants
willing to do his every bidding. But Edgar didn&amp;rsquo;t really like servants hovering
around him, except for the occasional pretty servant girl perhaps, but not
today. Today, there were greater concerns to be met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The king of Figaro was conversing with a bearded old man standing in
front
of his throne. If not for the throne, one might think Edgar actually deferred to
the old man, instead of being the king that he was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Are you sure about this, old friend?&amp;rdquo; Edgar asked the old man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He would be a great help to us, I&amp;rsquo;m sure,&amp;rdquo; came the reply, &amp;ldquo;and you
know
we need all the help we can get.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How can you be sure he&amp;rsquo;d agree?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just leave it to me.&amp;rdquo; The old man smiled knowingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chancellor of Figaro, wrapped in his flowing red robe with golden
trimmings, strode into the throne room. &amp;ldquo;Beg your pardon, your majesty, but the
prisoner is here.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All right, bring him in.&amp;rdquo; Edgar nodded briefly to the old man, who then
moved conveniently to the shadows in the far wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two guards nudged Locke into the throne room. He complied and walked
into the room with no hint of awe or majesty at Figaro&amp;rsquo;s throne room. It was
majestic, yes, worthy of a king, but nothing he had not seen before. The guards
brought him before the throne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kneel.&amp;rdquo; The guard gruffly ordered, and Locke felt his head pushed to
the
ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Get up, you know I hate that.&amp;rdquo; Edgar said. The guards complied, lifting
Locke back to his feet. Locke looked up at the king of Figaro. He&amp;rsquo;s younger than
I thought, Locke said to himself, what does he want with me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locke looked around the room and took note of any means of escape. There
were six other guards, aside from the ones holding him, and two more outside the
door; the fat old chancellor who had taken him out of his cell; and an old man
standing to the side, trying to remain unnoticed. Who is he? Some sort of
servant?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He heard the king speak again and focused his attention to the throne.
&amp;ldquo;Thank you for bringing him here, Chancellor. Please leave us, I wish to speak
to him in private.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But your highness,&amp;rdquo; the Chancellor started, a bit ruffled, &amp;ldquo;We can&amp;rsquo;t
leave
you alone with this&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s alright.&amp;rdquo; Edgar looked at the guards. &amp;ldquo;And please remove his
shackles.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guards looked at one another before complying. Locke felt the
shackles
come off, and rubbed his wrists to warm them. He saw the king nod to the other
guards, and they accompanied the chancellor out the throne room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;With all due respect your highness,&amp;rdquo; Locke finally said, &amp;ldquo;You sure you
wanna be alone with me? I&amp;rsquo;m a dangerous thief you know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edgar smiled. No respect for authority in this one, he thought to
himself.
He looked to the shadows on the wall, and the old man stepped forward. Locke
finally got a good look at him, although he still couldn&amp;rsquo;t recognize the man.
The old man spoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes, we know all about you Locke Cole. A very daring thief, who has
conducted various operations throughout the imperial domains and beyond over the
past few months.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve got quite a reputation you know,&amp;rdquo; Edgar said, looking directly
at
him, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re wanted for about twenty-seven charges of theft, breaking and
entering and evading arrest in Figaro alone. You&amp;rsquo;re lucky we don&amp;rsquo;t execute
thieves like the Empire does.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Empire&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Locke thought a bit before speaking again. &amp;ldquo;Listen, I
don&amp;rsquo;t
know what dirty work you and your allies want me to do, but I don&amp;rsquo;t care. I may
be a thief but there&amp;rsquo;s no way I&amp;rsquo;m doing Gestahl any favors!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well said.&amp;rdquo; The old man spoke again. &amp;ldquo;Just what we would have expected
from you. And just what we wanted.&amp;rdquo; He paused before going on. &amp;ldquo;We are not the
Empire.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What are you talking about old man? Figaro&amp;rsquo;s practically Imperial
territory with all those soldiers running around and your king bowing and
scraping to that old dog of an Emperor&amp;ndash;!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, hey,&amp;rdquo; Edgar interrupted. &amp;ldquo;The king of Figaro doesn&amp;rsquo;t bow or scrape
to
anyone. The Empire and Figaro are allies, yes. Equally? No. They forced this
alliance down our throats, knowing we had no choice, but Figaro will never bow
down to the Empire.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So what are you doing here, then?&amp;rdquo; Locke sneered, &amp;ldquo;Hiding in your
desert
castle while Imperial Troops harass your people and tax your merchants.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Allow me to explain,&amp;rdquo; the old man said. &amp;ldquo;Edgar here, king of Figaro,
and
myself, are members of a small underground group working to destabilize the
Empire.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Rebels?&amp;rdquo; Locke said incredulously. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve got to be kidding. There&amp;rsquo;s
no
way Figaro&amp;rsquo;s army could stand up to the Empire. They&amp;rsquo;ve only used a fraction
their power to dominate the Southern Continent, and even the King of Doma is
having a hard time against them!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s exactly why Figaro is still openly an ally of the Empire.&amp;rdquo; Edgar
explained. &amp;ldquo;We have no intention of meeting them in war, as that would only
result in a bloody loss. But once Doma falls, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty certain that Figaro
will be their next target.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We have no means of fighting them, really,&amp;rdquo; the old man continued,
&amp;ldquo;Except
with our hearts and with our minds. We have supporters scattered throughout the
Empire, waiting for our word. We have people disrupting Imperial supply lines,
sabotaging their machinery. We may not be able to topple them today, or anytime
soon, but we will eventually. But we need help. We need more people.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;People like you,&amp;rdquo; Edgar said, looking directly at Locke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do you think I can do?&amp;rdquo; Locke said, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m just a thief. I can&amp;rsquo;t do
anything against an Empire!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;A small stone may make a ripple at first, but someday it will be a
wave.&#39;&amp;rdquo; Edgar said, &amp;ldquo;An ancient quote.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You are no ordinary thief, Locke Cole.&amp;rdquo; The old man said, &amp;ldquo;You were
once
the best treasure hunter in Kohlingen. We need someone like you, someone who can
work their way through Empire lands, disrupting their communications and supply
lines, providing and gathering information. And most importantly, to contact our
allies. It has become increasingly dangerous for me to meet with our allies like
the king here.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If the Empire finds out we&amp;rsquo;ve been meeting with our allies in secret,
it&amp;rsquo;s
hard to tell what they&amp;rsquo;d do.&amp;rdquo; Edgar said, &amp;ldquo;Especially since some of our contacts
are deep inside the Imperial hierarchy. What do you say? Not much pay, but you
don&amp;rsquo;t really do these things for the money do you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locke paused for a while. These guys knew him inside out, and his
conscience begged him to help them out. But there were other things he had to
do, something else he was fighting for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His memory flashed back to that fateful day. He had wanted to show
Rachel
the buried ruins he had found in one of his explorations up on Mt. Kolts. With
all the artifacts there, he was pretty sure they would be pretty much set for
life. It had taken him a while to convince her to come with him, but he
eventually got her to agree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;ll watch over you every step of the way.&amp;rdquo; He grinned at
her
as they strode up the mountain path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sure you will,&amp;rdquo; Rachel replied, &amp;ldquo;the same way you were watching
over
that bar girl the other night, eh?&amp;rdquo; She smiled at him teasingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hey, I told you, she looked just like my cousin!&amp;rdquo; Locke smiled right
back
at her. &amp;ldquo;The cave&amp;rsquo;s just beyond the next bridge.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;d better hurry,&amp;rdquo; Rachel said, pulling close to him. &amp;ldquo;If my parents
find
out I&amp;rsquo;ve been gallivanting with you&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;ndash;they&amp;rsquo;d chase me out of Kohlingen, right. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;ll just show
you
what I&amp;rsquo;ve found, and have you back in Kohlingen before your father can give you
one his trademark lectures.&amp;rdquo; Locke stopped and faced her, made a stern face and
started to mimic her father. &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what you see in that Locke fellow!
He&amp;rsquo;s a regular rapscallion, that he is! He&amp;rsquo;ll do you no good, you hear!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel laughed at him and slapped him lightly on the chest. &amp;ldquo;Knock it
off,
okay? I can see the bridge already.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachel had stopped at the summit just before the bridge. She looked off
into the southward horizon, at the small town seemingly a lifetime away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;South Figaro looks so&amp;hellip; small from up here.&amp;rdquo; This was the first time
she
had ever climbed a mountain, and the natural beauty she could see amazed her. &amp;ldquo;I
could see for miles&amp;hellip; everything is so&amp;hellip; pristine&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;C&amp;rsquo;mon Rachel, you&amp;rsquo;re the one who told me to hurry!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh&amp;hellip; yes.&amp;rdquo; She said, hurrying over to him. &amp;ldquo;I would be a little more
excited if you maybe told me what it is we&amp;rsquo;re going to see.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re not gonna believe what awaits us up here!&amp;rdquo; Locke said as he
crossed
the bridge. &amp;ldquo;Come on, it&amp;rsquo;s worth a fortune!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything else had seemed to happen in slow motion. It was a moment he
had
relived time and again. His footing had been wrong, and he had felt the bridge
begin to give way. He heard her shouted warning, but had been caught unawares
when she threw herself at him. He had been so surprised that he wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to
put up any resistance. He had felt himself pushed back to the far end of the
bridge. He had stumbled clumsily, and his instinct took over as he jumped clear
of the collapsing bridge. He had looked back, and she was not there. He ran to
the edge of the ravine, shouting her name without hearing anything. He had
climbed down after her, and everything else was a blur. Rushing her back to her
father&amp;rsquo;s house, the worried looks on her parent&amp;rsquo;s faces, the relief when the
doctors said she&amp;rsquo;d be fine, and finally, that blank look on her face when she
woke up to him. No gleaming eyes or bright smile. Simply an emotionless stare,
as if she had never seen him before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her parents had been outraged, but he had just sat there, not knowing
what
to do or say. He tried to speak, but Rachel&amp;rsquo;s father wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even hear of it.
He was chased out of Kohlingen by nightfall, nowhere to look or turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember how he had wound up in South Figaro, or how long he
had been there. He didn&amp;rsquo;t know how he was able to survive, living off food he
found or stole off the streets. Somehow, he found himself under the care of an
old scholar who had retired to South Figaro. The weeks of desperation had taken
their toll on him and he was bedridden for several days. But he had found
comfort with the old man who listened to his story, the only one he ever told it
to. He had poured his heart out, sometimes with tears running down his face, as
he recounted Rachel&amp;rsquo;s tragedy. Luckily, his newfound friend had with him a
glimmer of hope that brought him out of his stupor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t be sure about this, you know,&amp;rdquo; The old scholar had droned in
his
monotone voice, &amp;ldquo;But I seem to recall an old chap a while back who had done
research on this sort of thing&amp;hellip; memory loss and recovery, I believe.&amp;rdquo; Locke
remembered how his face had lit up when he realized what the old man was saying.
A cure? Rachel&amp;rsquo;s condition can be cured?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, as I said, it&amp;rsquo;s somewhat of a long shot,&amp;rdquo; the old man said, &amp;ldquo;but
I
think the old chap was one of the Empire scientists.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so his hunt had began. After thanking his benefactor, he had set off
for Imperial territory, determined to find a cure for her recovery. He lived by
stealing off merchants and Imperial officers, traveling throughout the Southern
continent, asking scientists and researchers about this so-called cure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And all for what? Locke asked himself as he considered the offer being
made
to him. He had been searching for almost a year now, with not even a single
clue. He was wanted for numerous crimes throughout the empire, but he couldn&amp;rsquo;t
even sneak into the fortress at Vector to question their scientists. Maybe, this
job was the right thing for him to do? No, he decided. He had already devoted
too much time and effort to what he was doing, it all had to mean something, he
had to do it, for Rachel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry,&amp;rdquo; He replied to Edgar and the old man, &amp;ldquo;I understand your
needs,
but there are some things I just have to do, some things that are more important
to me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edgar frowned a him. &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have to remind you that you&amp;rsquo;re a
criminal under my jurisdiction.&amp;rdquo; He looked straight at him, &amp;ldquo;I hold your life
in my hands.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is that supposed to be a threat?&amp;rdquo; Locke said mockingly, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve escaped
worse fates than this before.&amp;rdquo; He stood there defiantly, as if daring Edgar to
strike him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Now, now, no need to be hostile to each other&amp;rdquo;, the old man said
soothingly. The two backed down a bit. He looked at the young king. &amp;ldquo;Edgar, no
need to be rough with him, is there? I&amp;rsquo;m sure you can arrange a &amp;lsquo;pardon&amp;rsquo; for
this young man, can&amp;rsquo;t you? So that he can consider our offer.&amp;rdquo; He turned back to
Locke. &amp;ldquo;Please take the time to consider it, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to decide now.&amp;rdquo; The
old man looked at Edgar, &amp;ldquo;Well?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All right, tell you what,&amp;rdquo; Edgar sighed resignedly, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll tell some of
the
guards at the night shift to take an early break around midnight, okay? Just
don&amp;rsquo;t hurt any of my guards.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old man nodded and turned back to Locke. &amp;ldquo;We can&amp;rsquo;t force you to help
us, that isn&amp;rsquo;t our way. But please think about it. If you wish to contact me,
talk to Arvis of Narshe, I&amp;rsquo;m sure you know him.&amp;rdquo; He smiled at Locke. &amp;ldquo;My name is
Banon.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Or, you could just get yourself caught again,&amp;rdquo; Edgar grinned as he went
to
call the guards back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locke nudged his chocobo to go just a bit faster. He was anxious, and at
the same time worried. He hadn&amp;rsquo;t been back to Kohlingen for the past year, but
he needed to go back now. He needed to reassure himself that he was doing the
right thing, to remind himself what he was fighting for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His conscience had been bothering him since the guard brought him back
to
his cell. He had wanted to catch a couple of hours sleep before midnight, but he
kept thinking about what it is that he was he was doing. He was on a wild-goose
chase, he could recognize that, for some cure that may or may not exist. But he
had to do it, because he owed it to her, to fight for her. To protect her. But
now, he had turned his back on people who needed him, people he could help, to
pursue this unknown cure. Had he met the right choice? He would know when he saw
Rachel again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure enough, the guards left around midnight, and Locke had been the
only
prisoner awake. He had looked around warily, still not sure what to make of the
situation, but then started to work on the cell&amp;rsquo;s lock. Nothing too difficult,
he was out of the dungeon in three minutes. He had promised not to hurt any of
the guards, but he had to knock a couple of them unconscious and steal a
chocobo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now here he was, just a couple of miles to Kohlingen now, and he
would
see her again. He didn&amp;rsquo;t need to talk to her, just to see her. To remind himself
of what he was doing, and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off the horizon, in the direction of Kohlingen, he sighted a thick
pillar
of black smoke rising from the ground. Worried, he kicked his chocobo into high
gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sight was disturbing. The slightest traces of dawn had begun to
appear,
and the rays of light seemed to grotesquely outline the destruction that had
happened here. Several houses were burned to the ground, some had collapsed on
themselves, now simply a heap of wood and rubble. As Locke rode into the city
and through the empty streets, he could feel several eyes looking out of the
houses that were still standing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What the hell happened here?&amp;rdquo; Locke pondered for a moment before his
heart
took over again. &amp;ldquo;Rachel!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He got off his Chocobo, and took a shortcut down a narrow alley. Looking
around, he saw that most of the brick-and-mortar houses here had survived
whatever it was that caused this carnage, so he figured Rachel and her family
would be alright. His stomach turned as he saw the remnants of their house
collapsed on the ground like a random pile of rocks. He stood there gaping for
several moments before he heard someone call out to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Master Locke!&amp;rdquo; Seymour, Rachel&amp;rsquo;s family&amp;rsquo;s manservant, came running up
to
him. He was a skinny man in his late forties, and he was often sympathetic to
Locke and Rachel&amp;rsquo;s relationship even when his master didn&amp;rsquo;t approve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Seymour!&amp;rdquo; Locke said in relief, &amp;ldquo;What happened here? Where&amp;rsquo;s Rachel?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It was the Empire, sir!&amp;rdquo; Seymour spilled, as he stopped in front of
Locke,
gasping for breath. Even though he was almost fifty, he had always insisted he
was healthy enough to run a marathon. &amp;ldquo;They came through here last night, saying
&amp;lsquo;Imperial enemies&amp;rsquo; had been hiding here.&amp;rdquo; He looked around. &amp;ldquo;They burned down
and destroyed houses and buildings with some new weapon they had. MagiDuck, or
something such, sir! A ghastly meld of monster and machine, a weapon of
destruction&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; He looked at Locke, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s good to see you again, sir, despite
the circumstances&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Rachel!&amp;rdquo; Locke almost shouted, &amp;ldquo;Where is she? Is she alright?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seymour hesitated before replying. &amp;ldquo;Best you go see for yourself sire,
she&amp;rsquo;s at Largo&amp;rsquo;s right now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locke nodded, and hurried off. &amp;ldquo;Thanks, Seymour. Get some rest, you
hear?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting aside his concerns for Seymour&amp;rsquo;s health, Locke made his way to
the
herbalist&amp;rsquo;s shop. Old Largo, the medicine man of Kohlingen, had done many good
things for him back when he was still climbing mountains and all. Hopefully,
Rachel would be alright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He had been sitting on this bench for half a day now. He felt so
useless.
All his efforts, all his sacrifices to find a cure for Rachel, and what happens?
He&amp;rsquo;s not there for her at the time she needed him most. Largo had told her what
happened, how their house had collapsed on top of them. Seymour and the others
had dug through the rubble, expecting to find only their dead bodies. Rachel&amp;rsquo;s
parents didn&amp;rsquo;t make it. But surprisingly, Rachel did. She had been holding
something in her hand when they found her, gasping for breath, bruised and
battered all over. She had been delirious and weak as they carried her to
Largo&amp;rsquo;s for treatment, mumbling all the way. Once they laid her down on a bed,
she had promptly collapsed and had not awakened since. She had dropped whatever
it was she was holding, a small pendant which had given her something to live
for, which Largo had seen fit to give to Locke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He fingered the small pendant Largo had given him, and opened the
locket,
the same way he had been doing for the past few hours. The picture inside was a
bit burned at the edges, but he could nonetheless see their faces so clearly.
Locke and Rachel. They had taken this picture several months before the
accident, and she had promised to treasure it forever. He closed the locket and
slammed his fist into the ground as he recalled Seymour&amp;rsquo;s words. &amp;ldquo;She was
mumbling your name all the way, sir, even before we found her in the rubble, and
up to the time she fainted.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So bloody useless,&amp;rdquo; he muttered to himself, &amp;ldquo;What the hell have I been
doing this past year, what the bloody hell has it all been for?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He remembered Largo telling him about her condition. He said she was in
bad
shape, and that it was a miracle she survived. He had given her some medicine to
keep her from the brink of death. But that was the best he could do. He didn&amp;rsquo;t
know whether she could be revived in any way. The herbs would keep her like
this, in a form of suspended animation, for a long while, but that was the best
he could do. For all intents and purposes, it was as if she were already dead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bloody useless, Locke repeated to himself. What could he do now? Raise
the
dead? A slight rain began to fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Master Locke,&amp;rdquo; he heard Seymour&amp;rsquo;s voice behind him, &amp;ldquo;You should get
some
rest. And get out of the rain, sir.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He ignored him for a while, and eventually Seymour&amp;rsquo;s voice vanished from
his hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next dawn found him still in the spot, staring lazily at the
herbalist
shop across the street. The rain had stopped a few hours before, but he was
still quite drenched. He felt his eyelids starting to fall, for the umpteenth
time now, and snapped himself awake. He heard footsteps behind him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry.&amp;rdquo; The voice was the old man&amp;rsquo;s. The one he had met in Figaro
Castle. What did he say his name was? Oh yeah, Banon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I came up here as soon as I&amp;rsquo;d heard.&amp;rdquo; The old man sat down beside him.
&amp;ldquo;We
knew of your history with the girl here in Kohlingen, and we knew that was why
you didn&amp;rsquo;t want to join us. Too bad things had to be like this.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locke&amp;rsquo;s silence disturbed him but he went on, &amp;ldquo;Listen, about the
offer&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
Banon wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what to say, but he decided to press on, &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;we understand if
you choose to decline. After all it must be a difficult time for you ri&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll do it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;ndash;ght now. Eh?&amp;rdquo; Banon turned to him in surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Rachel would&amp;rsquo;ve wanted me to help you guys, I guess,&amp;rdquo; Locke said
resignedly, &amp;ldquo;She always said the Empire would someday threaten Kohlingen. I
never really listened to her.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Locke&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about me. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a long time to think about things. I
sacrificed a lot of things trying to bring back the Rachel I knew, only to have
the Empire take her away again. I owe it to her to fight for the ideals she
believed in. I have to do this now, or else, it all has no meaning.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old man nodded. &amp;ldquo;Very well. I&amp;rsquo;ll be staying at the inn. When you&amp;rsquo;re
ready, just look for me there alright?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locke nodded. He stood up and looked down at himself. &amp;ldquo;I guess I should
clean up a bit, huh? Maybe Largo&amp;rsquo;s awake already.&amp;rdquo; He started towards the
herbalist&amp;rsquo;s shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh and Locke,&amp;rdquo; Banon started to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locke looked at him questioningly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Welcome to the Returners.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;finis&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Ramna 1/2: Time and Time Again
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/1997/01/ramna-1/2-time-and-time-again/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/1997/01/ramna-1/2-time-and-time-again/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma 1/2 and all associated characters, places and events are
undoubtedly property of the esteemed Rumiko Takahashi, and any attempts
to claim otherwise shall be attended with accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nikholas F. Toledo Fanfic Group
presents&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time and Time Again
by VECTOR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part One&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the usual lunchtime scenario at the Furinkan High cafeteria.
Various students were in various states of gobbling. One particular
student, however, was trying to avoid his lunch. This student, Ranma
Saotome, had concealed himself behind the cafeteria doors in hopes of
avoiding the &amp;ldquo;lunch&amp;rdquo; his &amp;ldquo;fiancee&amp;rdquo; had prepared for him. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t
exactly normal behavior for such a boy to avoid free food, but the
fiancee in question was one Akane Tendo, and her cooking could be used as
nuclear weaponry if only the government realized it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fiancee, however, managed to spot him. This time it was
okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranchan! I brought you some okonomiyaki!&amp;rdquo; Ukyo Kuonji&amp;rsquo;s voice came
to Ranma&amp;rsquo;s ears, and Ranma thankfully accepted the okonomiyaki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thanks Ucchan&amp;rdquo;, he said between gobbles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly the nearby wall started to break down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh no&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, Ranma said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And suddenly there was a flash of light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the light dissipated, the wall was broken down and a purple-
haired young girl carrying a delivery tray was looking around a bit
confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ai ya! Where Ranma go?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma and Ukyo had vanished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part Two&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the usual lunchtime scenario at the Furinkan High cafeteria.
Various students were in various states of gobbling. One particular
student, however, was trying to avoid his lunch. This student, Ranma
Saotome, had concealed himself behind the cafeteria doors in hopes of
avoiding the &amp;ldquo;lunch&amp;rdquo; his &amp;ldquo;fiancee&amp;rdquo; had prepared for him. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t
exactly normal behavior for such a boy to avoid free food, but the
fiancee in question was one Akane Tendo, and her cooking could be used as
nuclear weaponry if only the government realized it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fiancee, however, managed to spot him. This time it was
okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranchan! I brought you some okonomiyaki!&amp;rdquo; Ukyo Kuonji&amp;rsquo;s voice came
to Ranma&amp;rsquo;s ears, and Ranma thankfully accepted the okonomiyaki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thanks Ucchan&amp;rdquo;, he said between gobbles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly the nearby wall started to break down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh no&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, Ranma said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A purple-haired young girl carrying a delivery tray smashed through
the wall and deftly pushed Ukyo away from Ranma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranma, I cook special deluxe ramen for ai len!&amp;rdquo; Shampoo said,
glomping onto Ranma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this had not gone unnoticed to Akane Tendo, and right now she
was emanating an incredibly red battle aura.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranma&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; she began, rather furiously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And suddenly there was a flash of light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the light dissipated, Ukyo and Akane looked around in shock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma and Shampoo had vanished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part Three&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma Saotome felt the sensation and recognized it. It was a
feeling he regularly had, that of submitting his will to gravity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was falling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, Ranma managed to fall into a convenient clump of bushes on
the outskirts of Nerima, staving off any real damage (which Ranma
would&amp;rsquo;ve been impervious to, anyway). He jumped up to his feet and
brushed the dust off his red Chinese clothes. At least this time, he
hadn&amp;rsquo;t landed in water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What in the world just happened?&amp;rdquo; he said to himself out loud. The
shrubbery he had fallen into was just outside the Nerima cemetery,
meaning he must&amp;rsquo;ve flown quite a long way from the Tendo Dojo. The
problem was, this time he didn&amp;rsquo;t recall anyone in particular smashing him
into the sky. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t even recall being at the Dojo for the last
thirty minutes. To the best of his knowledge, it was presently lunchtime
at Furinkan High.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma&amp;rsquo;s musings were interrupted by two familiar voices coming from
within the cemetery. For some strange reason, Ranma&amp;rsquo;s brain decided to
kick in and realized something strange was going on. The female voice he
heard was definitely Ukyo&amp;rsquo;s. The weird part was the male voice. He could
swear it was&amp;hellip;himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confused, Ranma leaps over the wall and crosses to a nearby tree.
Several yards away, he sees Ukyo, and surprisingly, himself! They are in
front of a grave, and Ukyo seems to be comforting Ranma for some reason.
Deciding that discretion was the better part of valor, Ranma decided to
spy on this impostor. Concealing himself in the nearby shrubbery, he
listened in to their conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re doing it again, Ranchan. You keep blaming yourself for what
happened. Year after year for five years now we&amp;rsquo;ve been coming here, and
you still haven&amp;rsquo;t forgiven yourself.&amp;rdquo; Ukyo&amp;rsquo;s voice came to the (hidden)
Ranma&amp;rsquo;s ears. &amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; Ranma said to himself, &amp;ldquo;Ukyo&amp;rsquo;s known this impostor
for years? Whose grave is this anyway?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then he heard the impostor&amp;rsquo;s voice, as clear as his own. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re
right Ucchan&amp;hellip;I just can&amp;rsquo;t help but remember what she meant to me&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
She? Ranma wondered to himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come on, Ranchan. It&amp;rsquo;s time to go. Time to move on.&amp;rdquo; Ukyo said,
moving away with the impostor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Puzzled, Ranma steps out of the shadows after they leave, then
walks over and inspects the grave they were visiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I..it can&amp;rsquo;t be&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, he said, shocked, &amp;ldquo;A&amp;ndash;Akane Tendo&amp;hellip;died age
seventeen&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;. Ranma&amp;rsquo;s brain, which normally could not handle anything
more complicated than one of Ryoga&amp;rsquo;s schemes, was working overtime. He
had just been with Akane about an hour ago, insulting her cooking. How
could she be dead, with her grave here for the past five years? And who
was that impostor?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Only one person can explain what&amp;rsquo;s going on here,&amp;rdquo; Ranma muttered
to himself, &amp;ldquo;Either that or she&amp;rsquo;s behind it all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, Ranma ran off in the direction of the
Nekohanten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find it no longer there. This was even more of a visual shock
for Ranma, as it meant he couldn&amp;rsquo;t get free food there anymore. Besides
that, he had just eaten at the Nekohanten this morning! Something strange
was definitely going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Looking for someone, son-in-law?&amp;rdquo; a familiar old voice came from a
nearby rooftop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma leapt up to the rooftop and found Cologne there. At least she
still looked the same, if everything else in Nerima had gone crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s going on, old ghoul?&amp;rdquo; Ranma spat out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ah, son-in-law, you are as impolite as ever, in any time.&amp;rdquo; Cologne
remarked, &amp;ldquo;And to think I came all the way from China to visit you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;China? What were you doing in China? Where&amp;rsquo;s the Nekohanten? What
do you mean in any time? And what the hell happened to Akane?&amp;rdquo; Ranma
indignantly shot back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;One question at a time, Ranma.&amp;rdquo; Cologne pulls out a folded
newspaper from within here robes. &amp;ldquo;Here&amp;rdquo;, she said, passing the paper to
Ranma, &amp;ldquo;read it, and tell me what date it is.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;November 16&amp;hellip;1999?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That is correct, son-in-law. You have traveled in time, and you
are now five years into the future.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Time travel? But how? Why?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stop blabbering for a while and listen to me, boy.&amp;rdquo; Cologne said,
&amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t have much time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Okay.&amp;rdquo; Enough time for what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Five years ago, you and Shampoo were sucked into a temporal rift
near Furinkan High. You ended up five years in the future, as you are
now. However, in that future, Shampoo was dead, her body found after she
had mysteriously vanished for months. When you and Shampoo talked to the
Ukyo Kuonji from that time, she said she had also traveled to the future
with Ranma five years before, and she had seen a timeline where she had
died. Apparently, in that other time, the same thing that happened to
Shampoo happened to Ukyo instead. With their knowledge of their future,
Ranma and Shampoo came back, and Shampoo&amp;rsquo;s death was averted. Instead of
Shampoo, however, it was Akane Tendo who met their fate.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What? How could all this be happening?&amp;rdquo; Ranma said, confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I believe it has something to do with the temporal rift five years
ago, son-in-law. After that experience and with the death of Akane Tendo,
Shampoo withdrew her claim to you out of respect for her, and we moved
back to China. The present-day Shampoo told me to meet you here so that I
could tell you all this. I believe that some force at this time, but not
necessarily in this timeline, is trying to get you, but someone else
always gets in the way.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma tried to follow all this, failed, tried again, and finally
got it right. &amp;ldquo;How can I stop this? If this is the third time it&amp;rsquo;s
happened, even if I save Akane in the past, it&amp;rsquo;ll happen to someone else,
right?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is a chance, son-in-law. You yourself must face whatever
fate it was that would have fallen upon Ukyo, Shampoo, and now, Akane.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Can you help me?&amp;rdquo; Ranma said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m afraid not, for in this timeline, you are a temporal anomaly,
so you can &amp;ldquo;Shift&amp;rdquo; back to your time easily, while I cannot. You are
alone this time, son-in-law.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma just nodded gravely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;One more thing&amp;rdquo;, Cologne added, &amp;ldquo;when Shampoo came back from her
temporal journey, she was very disoriented and could barely remember what
had happened in the past, and she was beaten and bruised. This could help
you find out who&amp;rsquo;s responsible.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Waitaminute!&amp;rdquo; Ranma said, &amp;ldquo;If Ukyo and Shampoo were with me when
they time-traveled, then this time&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;Akane Tendo would have made the journey with you.&amp;rdquo; Cologne
ended. &amp;ldquo;That is correct, son-in-law. You must find her, before any danger
comes to her. You might even figure out what&amp;rsquo;s going on.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;One last thing, &amp;quot; Ranma said, as the ghoul prepared to hop away,
&amp;ldquo;If I do manage to prevent Akane&amp;rsquo;s death, then this timeline is
destroyed? Do you all die?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know son-in-law.&amp;rdquo; Cologne replied, &amp;ldquo;We might cease to
exist, or just go on as if nothing happened. We don&amp;rsquo;t truly understand
the intricacies of time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thanks, ghoul. Gotta go!&amp;rdquo; Ranma said, heading for the Dojo. If
Akane was in this timeline, she would head straight for the Dojo. And who
knows how her old man would react!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, Akane was having troubles of her own. She had
suddenly found herself wandering on some street after eating her lunch.
Maybe Ranma was right&amp;hellip;maybe her cooking did have hallucinogenic
effects, she thought. That thought had quickly fled her mind and she
rushed to the Dojo to find out what&amp;rsquo;s going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When she got there, everyone seemed shocked to see her, as if she
had come back from the dead or something. Even more shocking was when
they told her she did come back from the dead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do you mean I died five years ago?!&amp;rdquo;, she asked, incredulous,
while trying to shake a crying Soun off her leg, &amp;ldquo;Is this some sort of
sick joke ?&amp;rdquo;, she said, pointedly looking at Nabiki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nabiki looked hurt, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not like we would fake your death
Akane&amp;hellip;the body was there, we all saw it&amp;hellip;Ranma couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop crying
for weeks&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranma&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; she said, turning to him, &amp;ldquo;were you really worried about
me?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Akane&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; the purple-shirted Ranma said, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;hellip;I always regret not
having told you before&amp;hellip;but I want you to know that I&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The red-shirted Ranma Saotome had watched Akane enter the Dojo, but
had carefully concealed himself on a nearby rooftop. As he watched the
purple-shirted Ranma hug Akane closely, he shifted a bit and considered
revealing himself and explaining everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he knew no one would listen to him anyway, particularly
himself. He just had to wait until he could talk to Akane alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranma&amp;rdquo;, Akane said, breaking the hug, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m confused&amp;hellip;just this
morning I was at school&amp;hellip;at Furinkan&amp;hellip;how could I have died five years
ago?&amp;rdquo; She looked at everyone for an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, Akane&amp;rdquo;, Nabiki said, &amp;ldquo;It seems that five years ago, you and
Ranma vanished in flash of light near Furinkan&amp;hellip;when Ranma came back, he
had no memory of what happened&amp;hellip;and when you came back a week later, you
were near death&amp;hellip;we couldn&amp;rsquo;t save you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry Akane&amp;rdquo;, Ranma said, &amp;ldquo;If only I had done something back
then&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh! My Daughter!!! My Long-Lost Daughter!!!&amp;rdquo;, Soun wailed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma had caught enough of the conversation to understand what had
happened. He and Akane had leapt forward five years into the future, and
Akane did not come back alive from the encounter&amp;hellip;which meant that
sometime between now and their going back to the past, something bad
would happen to Akane. He would have to stop whatever it was that was
going to happen&amp;hellip;but what was it? And why did it also happen to Shampoo
and Ukyo?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that night, when Akane was about to go to sleep in her newly-
refurbished room, she heard a knock on her door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come in&amp;rdquo;, she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma, still wearing the same purple shirt, came in, and sat down
next to Akane on her bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do you want?&amp;rdquo; she said, a bit annoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma held her hand. &amp;ldquo;I just wanted to see if you were okay&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; he
trailed off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akane was a bit surprised that he held her hand, &amp;ldquo;Sorry&amp;rdquo;, she said,
&amp;ldquo;didn&amp;rsquo;t mean to snap at you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma squeezed her hand gently, and she squeezed it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside Akane&amp;rsquo;s bedroom window, Ranma-chan, wearing a wet red
shirt, was watching them. He waited until the purple-shirted Ranma had
left the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akane sighed as Ranma left the room. Then she heard a slight
tapping on her window. When she turned to look, she was surprised to see
a very wet Ranma-chan, in a red shirt, hanging outside her windowsill,
asking to come in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranma!&amp;rdquo; she said, opening the window and letting him in,
&amp;ldquo;wha&amp;hellip;how did you get there? I&amp;hellip;we were just&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Shh&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, Ranma said, putting a finger to his lips, &amp;ldquo;Keep quiet and
I&amp;rsquo;ll explain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Okay&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You notice how we were in school today, and suddenly you found
yourself somewhere else?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, I was wondering what happened&amp;hellip;but nobody here could
explain it&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, I can. Listen&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Ranma proceeded to tell her Cologne&amp;rsquo;s
story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You really expect me to believe something like that?&amp;rdquo; Akane said,
&amp;ldquo;Cologne must have been joking or something.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s no other explanation Akane. The Nekohanten wasn&amp;rsquo;t there
this afternoon, but it was definitely there when I had breakfast this
morning.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You mean you had breakfast with Shampoo?!&amp;rdquo; Akane shouted, &amp;ldquo;What
did you think you were doing?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The red-shirted Ranma heard footsteps coming and threw himself
outside the window and flipped up to the roof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purple-shirted Ranma and Kasumi opened Akane&amp;rsquo;s door and rushed
into the room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is it, Akane?&amp;rdquo; Kasumi said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is there anything wrong?&amp;rdquo; Ranma said, his concern showing, &amp;ldquo;We
heard you shout and&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;N&amp;hellip;no, it&amp;rsquo;s okay. I, um, just saw a mouse, that&amp;rsquo;s all&amp;hellip;yeah
that&amp;rsquo;s it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh my, a rodent!&amp;rdquo; Kasumi said, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll have to call some
exterminators!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Uh, that&amp;rsquo;s okay Kasumi&amp;rdquo;, Akane stammered, &amp;ldquo;I threw it out of the
house.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Okay&amp;rdquo;, Ranma said, stepping out of the room, &amp;ldquo;You sure you&amp;rsquo;ll be
all right?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sure&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma and Kasumi left and locked the door behind them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akane went to the window and looked up. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s okay&amp;rdquo;, she whispered
to the moon, &amp;ldquo;You can come out now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The red-shirted Ranma flipped back into Akane&amp;rsquo;s room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That was close&amp;rdquo;, Ranma said, &amp;ldquo;we can&amp;rsquo;t let them know who we really
are. They&amp;rsquo;d never believe it. I know I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranma&amp;rdquo;, Akane said, &amp;ldquo;If that other person is really you, in the
future, do you and him have the same, um, feelings? About us, I mean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s no time for this Akane&amp;rdquo;, Ranma said, a bit embarrassed, &amp;ldquo;I
have to go and figure out who or what is up to this&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; Akane said, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ll leave me here?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You should be safe here, Akane. They can protect you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I can take care of myself.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know, Akane, you&amp;rsquo;re a martial artist too, and all that.&amp;rdquo; Ranma
responded, &amp;ldquo;but whatever it is that hits us here, is going to kill you.
And I can&amp;rsquo;t risk that happening.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranma&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I gotta go. I&amp;rsquo;ll come back when I&amp;rsquo;ve figured out what to do.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma stepped out of the window and was about to leap into the yard
when he heard Akane scream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma turned around and saw a weird sight. A blue-violet haze was
forming in Akane&amp;rsquo;s room and there were blue tendrils of energy grabbing
onto her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Akane!&amp;rdquo; Ranma shouted, echoed by another voice from the hallway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma tried to stop the pulsating blue trails of energy but he was
grabbed in mid-air and both the red-shirted Ranma Saotome and Akane Tendo
vanished into the vortex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purple-shirted Ranma Saotome crashed through Akane&amp;rsquo;s room to
find a small energy vortex shrinking out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part Four&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akane found herself conscious and tried to move. Unfortunately, her
hands wouldn&amp;rsquo;t agree with her. They were tied up for the moment,
literally. She was in a small room and tied to a pole. The building
looked old, as if it would fall down any second. Numerous crates were
located in the room. She heard a familiar voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He got you too, huh?&amp;rdquo; Ukyo&amp;rsquo;s voice came from behind her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ukyo!&amp;rdquo; Akane turned to see Ukyo and Shampoo also tied up, all
three of them around the pole. &amp;ldquo;Who did this to us?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ai ya!&amp;rdquo; Shampoo remarked, &amp;ldquo;Violent girl not know? It was&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shampoo&amp;rsquo;s sentence was cut short by a small maroon projectile sent
hurtling through the far wall. Instead of crashing into the crates,
however, the maroon blur stopped itself in mid-air and settled down on
its feet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Still can&amp;rsquo;t beat me Ranma m&amp;rsquo;boy!&amp;rdquo; Akane recognized the voice; it
was&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Happosai!&amp;rdquo; Akane said, surprised, &amp;ldquo;So you were behind all this!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ai len!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranchan&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma had emerged from the hole Happosai had made through the far
wall. He was burning red with battle aura. His clothes were torn in
several places and he had a bruise on his right arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This ain&amp;rsquo;t over yet, you old freak!&amp;rdquo; Ranma spat out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re right, Ranma!&amp;rdquo; Happosai gloated, &amp;ldquo;You still have to bring
me more girlies!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bring&amp;hellip;?&amp;rdquo;, Akane said, &amp;ldquo;Ranma, you&amp;hellip;!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, Akane&amp;rdquo;, Ukyo said, &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s not his fault&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do you mean, oh!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma and Happosai had decided to resume their hostilities, and
they were moving at incredible speeds. Ranma was dishing out low-level ki
bursts to Happosai at maximum speed. Happosai, however, managed to dodge
each and every one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enough playing around, Ranma&amp;rdquo;, Happosai said, landing on a crate,
&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve got work to do!&amp;rdquo; Suddenly, Ranma noticed a blue sapphire Happosai
wore on his neck. The gem glinted a bit and then blue energy formed in
front of Happosai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Time Flare!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranchan look out!&amp;rdquo;, Ukyo shouted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too late. A pulsating blue energy burst flew towards Ranma. Ranma
leapt out of the way, but the blast followed him and enveloped him. A
bright light formed around him and he vanished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranma!&amp;rdquo; Akane shouted, &amp;ldquo;What did you do to him?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why, sent him back in time, of course!&amp;rdquo; Happosai said gleefully,
&amp;ldquo;So he can bring back more girls!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What? Where&amp;hellip;when are we anyway?&amp;rdquo; Akane said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In your future, of course&amp;rdquo;, Happosai said, as if Akane would
understand immediately. When he saw she didn&amp;rsquo;t he elaborated, &amp;ldquo;Five years
to be exact.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why are you doing this to us?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, dear Akane, you don&amp;rsquo;t know how terrible it&amp;rsquo;s been!&amp;rdquo; Happosai
whimpered, latching himself unto Akane&amp;rsquo;s chest, &amp;ldquo;Allow me a moment in
your bosom to tell my tale.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akane fumed a bit, but realizing there was nothing she could do,
nodded. &amp;ldquo;Go on.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You see, in this future, my future, I had accidentally killed you
all when I discovered the powers of this&amp;rdquo;, Happosai pointed to the gem
laced around his neck. &amp;ldquo;This&amp;rdquo;, he continued, &amp;ldquo;is the TimeStone. It allows
someone to displace another person through time! So, using the powers of
the Stone, I sent Ranma to the past, knowing that there&amp;rsquo;d be girls around
him for sure, and then I moved him five years into the future, and then
shifted him to this future!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What! You pervert!&amp;rdquo; Akane shouted, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re doing all this just so
you can harass some girls?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You don&amp;rsquo;t understand, Akane&amp;rdquo;, Happosai continued, &amp;ldquo;In this future,
the Time Stone gives me incredible powers, and I&amp;rsquo;m close to becoming all-
powerful. However, I need to be in the presence of pretty ladies to be
effective! I drain their youthful energy to become stronger. So I used
Ranma as a temporal female magnet!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wait&amp;rdquo;, Ukyo said, whereupon Happosai immediately leapt off Akane
and glomped onto Ukyo&amp;rsquo;s chest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes?&amp;rdquo; Happosai said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thanks, Ukyo&amp;rdquo;, Akane smiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Grr&amp;hellip;anyway, if all this is true, how come Ranma didn&amp;rsquo;t tell us
when we time-traveled?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, you see, when I shoot him back in time, his mind also goes
back in time. He only remembers what&amp;rsquo;s going on when he gets back here.&amp;rdquo;
Happosai explained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s it, Akane thought. &amp;ldquo;But wait&amp;rdquo;, she interrupted, &amp;ldquo;In the
other timelines, Shampoo and Ukyo managed to survive. That means Ranma&amp;rsquo;s
going to beat you!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No way, girl!&amp;rdquo; Happosai laughed, &amp;ldquo;Those weren&amp;rsquo;t my timelines. They
were just branch-offs that resulted from Ranma&amp;rsquo;s perpetual time-jumping.
Why, you&amp;rsquo;re already the third batch of girls here!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What! Where are the others then.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I sent them back, of course. I can&amp;rsquo;t use them anymore after I&amp;rsquo;ve
run them out of energy. In that state, they&amp;rsquo;re already near-death.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You monster!&amp;rdquo; Akane said, realizing why the other Ukyo, Shampoo
and Akane had died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nothing can stop me, Akane-chan!&amp;rdquo; Happosai said, glomping on Akane
again, &amp;ldquo;Nothing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Perhaps you are right. Perhaps not.&amp;rdquo; The voice came from somewhere
outside the building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What the&amp;ndash;?!&amp;rdquo;, Happosai said, &amp;ldquo;That voice&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You are indeed a menace, in any time, Happy.&amp;rdquo; The small figure
said as it came into the building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ai ya! Great-grandmother!&amp;rdquo; Shampoo said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure was indeed, Cologne, carrying her staff around her. &amp;ldquo;You
didn&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;d come along with Ranma, did you?&amp;rdquo; Cologne said, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s
over Happosai. Surrender the TimeStone!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To you? Ha!&amp;rdquo;, Happosai snickered, &amp;ldquo;I killed you months ago, and
I&amp;rsquo;ll kill you again !&amp;rdquo; Happosai leapt towards her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ll see&amp;rdquo;, Cologne said, also leaping towards Happosai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The battle began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranchan!&amp;rdquo; Ukyo said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Huh?&amp;rdquo; Akane said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ai len!&amp;rdquo; Shampoo said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Shh&amp;rdquo;, Ranma said, &amp;ldquo;Cologne and I heard everything. Relax, I&amp;rsquo;ll get
you all free.&amp;rdquo; He started to work on the ropes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Elemental Storm!&amp;rdquo; Happosai shrieked, creating a powerful hurricane
within the building. The roof was blown off and lightning and thunder
crashed across the sky. He extended his battle aura into the hurricane,
lighting the night with energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hiryu Shoten Ha!&amp;rdquo; Cologne countered with the Dragon Cyclone, and
soon the area was filled with a storm of lightning and flame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma, Akane, Shampoo and Ukyo were struggling to stay standing in
the midst of the powerful display of energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry, Cologne&amp;rdquo;, Happosai said, momentarily halting the Elemental
Storm, &amp;ldquo;I have to send you back now. You just weren&amp;rsquo;t good enough.&amp;rdquo; The
gem around Happosai&amp;rsquo;s neck glowed with power and pulsating blue energy
gathered around his body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No!&amp;rdquo; Ranma said, gathering his ki, &amp;ldquo;Mokou Takabishya!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ki bolt hit Happosai from behind and disrupted his Time Flare.
Cologne, however, was exhausted and landed on the ground, breathing hard.
Happosai turned his attention on Ranma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All right, then&amp;rdquo;, Happosai said, gathering his energy again, &amp;ldquo;You
first. Time Flare!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pulsating blue energy bolt leapt towards Ranma. Ranma was
expecting it and leapt high into the air. Th bolt turned before hitting
the girls and was close behind him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma twisted in mid-air and made a dive for Happosai. The energy
bolt turned and followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kachu Tenshin Amaguriken Maximum!&amp;rdquo; Ranma said, bringing his fists
into Happosai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t beat me, boy!&amp;rdquo; Happosai said, blocking all 23,000
attacks. Suddenly Ranma turned sharply and leapt away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Scared you, didn&amp;rsquo;t I&amp;ndash;Ahh!! No!!!&amp;rdquo;, Happosai&amp;rsquo;s words were cut off
by the blue energy bolt that slammed into him. The energy bolt had failed
to turn and had collided with Happosai, enveloping him with pulsating
blue energy. Happosai faded out of sight. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be back &amp;hellip; &amp;quot; his voice
trailed off. The TimeStone glistened then fell off his disappearing neck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not bad, son-in-law.&amp;rdquo; Cologne said. They had recovered from the
battle and were studying the TimeStone left behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So, how do we get back?&amp;rdquo; Ranma said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This TimeStone is said to be unique throughout all of time. If we
destroy it here and now, all other traces of it across time and space
shall be destroyed as well.&amp;rdquo; Cologne said, &amp;ldquo;In which case Happosai would
never have found it in the first place.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wait&amp;rdquo;, Akane cut in, &amp;ldquo;What about us? And all those alternate
timelines? If Happosai never found it, we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be here, right?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s a temporal paradox&amp;rdquo;, Cologne explained, &amp;ldquo;Once we destroy this
Stone, we, and all the alternate timelines, will cease to exist. The day
will go on as if something never happened. And we will have no memory of
what happened.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Akane said, sounding disappointed. She turned to her
fiancee. &amp;ldquo;Ranma, what I asked you back in my bedroom&amp;hellip;?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Um, well&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enough fooling around&amp;rdquo;, Cologne said, smashing the TimeStone to
bits, &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s go.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there was a flash of light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part Five&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the usual lunchtime scenario at the Furinkan High cafeteria.
Various students were in various states of gobbling. One particular
student, however, was trying to avoid his lunch. This student, Ranma
Saotome, had concealed himself behind the cafeteria doors in hopes of
avoiding the &amp;ldquo;lunch&amp;rdquo; his &amp;ldquo;fiancee&amp;rdquo; had prepared for him. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t
exactly normal behavior for such a boy to avoid free food, but the
fiancee in question was one Akane Tendo, and her cooking could be used as
nuclear weaponry if only the government realized it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another fiancee, however, managed to spot him. This time it was
okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranchan! I brought you some okonomiyaki!&amp;rdquo;, Ukyo Kuonji&amp;rsquo;s voice
came to Ranma&amp;rsquo;s ears, and Ranma thankfully accepted the okonomiyaki.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Thanks Ucchan&amp;rdquo;, he said between gobbles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly the nearby wall started to break down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh no&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;, Ranma said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A purple-haired young girl carrying a delivery tray smashed through
the wall and deftly pushed Ukyo away from Ranma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranma, I cook special deluxe ramen for ai len!&amp;rdquo; Shampoo said,
glomping onto Ranma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this had not gone unnoticed to Akane Tendo, and right now she
was emanating an incredibly red battle aura.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranma&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; she began, rather furiously, &amp;ldquo;How dare you eat their
cooking, and refuse mine!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Look, Akane&amp;rdquo;, Ranma said, pushing off Shampoo, &amp;ldquo;In case you
haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed, a garbage can would be a better alternative than your
cooking!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ranma you jerk!&amp;rdquo; Akane screamed, sending Ranma into LEO at the
same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ranma landed in the Nekohanten&amp;rsquo;s trash can. Cologne fished him out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Having trouble with your girlfriends, son-in-law?&amp;rdquo; Cologne said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am not your son-in-law!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in China&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jusenkyo guide looked out of his window to see a bright blue
light form over Jusenkyo. The light quickly vanished and a small figure
of a man hurtled towards the cursed springs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guide rushed to the pools and saw a small frog hop out of a
nearby pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aw, too bad.&amp;rdquo;, the Guide said in his weird voice and accent, &amp;ldquo;You
fall into Spring of Drowned Frog. Very tragic story of frog that drown
there seven hundred year ago.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ribbit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;End&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-----------------------------------------------authors-witty-repartee---&#34;&gt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;Author&amp;rsquo;s Witty Repartee&amp;mdash;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fic is weird. I wrote this after watching some weird time loop
TV show I couldn&amp;rsquo;t place. Anyway, it&amp;rsquo;s really my first fic, so if you
wanna say anything &amp;lsquo;bout it, send stuff to the Nikholas F. Toledo
address. If is suck, say so, if I don&amp;rsquo;t you can say that too. Oh yeah,
please check for misspellings or grammar errors or whatever. I am not
&amp;ldquo;SWITCH&amp;rdquo; OK? I&amp;rsquo;m just using his address. Oh yeah, could people please
write more weird time travel thingies. I&amp;rsquo;m kinda sick and tired of all
the herbs and spices plots, and I kinda like pointing out continuity
faults. BTW, does anybody think Ukyou can beat Kunou in combat?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-fic-was-written-in-1994&#34;&gt;Notes (07/04/2003)
This fic was written in 1994!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VECTOR (aka roytang)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>