<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>IReadComicBooks on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/source/ireadcomicbooks/</link>
      <description>Recent content in IReadComicBooks on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/source/ireadcomicbooks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>X-Men First Class
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2013/04/xmen-first-class/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 13:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2013/04/xmen-first-class/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Just rewatched the ending of &lt;em&gt;X-Men First Class&lt;/em&gt;. As far as origin stories go, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty decent (although a number of continuity issues with the other X-Men movies exist). Charles getting crippled during the time that he and Erik part ways is certainly better than the canon comics story of him getting crippled by a random alien. The use of the Cuban Missile Crisis was also a good idea considering how the timeline matched up with Erik&amp;rsquo;s time in the Nazi camps. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad Magneto&amp;rsquo;s character is tied to that particular time period - as time passes it will get harder to write Magneto stories as we&amp;rsquo;re currently approaching the time when he should be around a hundred years old already. Future reboots might need a new villain altogether or maybe a rewrite of Erik&amp;rsquo;s origin to replace the concentration camp traumas with something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the mediocrity of the X-Men movies so far (they&amp;rsquo;re ok, but they&amp;rsquo;re no T&lt;em&gt;he Dark Knight) &lt;/em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m actually fairly excited to see where Bryan Singer is going to take the series with &lt;em&gt;Days of Future Past&lt;/em&gt; as all indications point to the present day timeline of the 3 X-Men movies being the dystopian future to the timeline of &lt;em&gt;First Class.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind Marvel coming up with a new series with a similar set of origin stories for Charles and Erik (and maybe some of the kids from &lt;em&gt;First Class&lt;/em&gt;, but too bad for Darwin lol). Maybe when they have the next &amp;ldquo;Ultimate&amp;rdquo; universe eh?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Marvel NOW So far part 1 (Remender and Hickman)
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2013/03/marvel-now-so-far-part-1-remender-and-hickman/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 11:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2013/03/marvel-now-so-far-part-1-remender-and-hickman/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Due to general business and/or laziness I&amp;rsquo;ve missed a few weeks of posting so to get back into pace I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through the current Marvel NOW titles and see how they&amp;rsquo;re going so far. (We&amp;rsquo;ll see if I have time for DCnU later)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain America &lt;/strong&gt;(4 issues in) - I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of Romita&amp;rsquo;s art but at least it&amp;rsquo;s better in this book than his AvX work. Despite my issues with the artwork I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself surprisingly entertained by Remender&amp;rsquo;s current story arc. It&amp;rsquo;s far out, it&amp;rsquo;s insane and it&amp;rsquo;s easily accessible, with no need to follow any other Marvel books to understand the things going on. There&amp;rsquo;s Captain America trapped on some strange alien world facing an enemy with vast resources interspersed with short vignettes about Steve Rogers&amp;rsquo; childhood. I&amp;rsquo;ve never really followed a Captain America book before, so the childhood stuff is pretty new to me and it&amp;rsquo;s refreshing to have a new take aside from the boy scout soldier stuff. If Remender&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Uncanny X-Force&lt;/em&gt; run is any indication, Cap is in for quite a ride and it might be worth tuning in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncanny Avengers&lt;/strong&gt; (4 issues in) - from one Remender book to another, this one is the direct fallout of AvX. From the ending of the first story arc, it looks like Remender is playing the long game with this one. It&amp;rsquo;s obviously not as accessible as &lt;em&gt;Captain America&lt;/em&gt; given the AvX background and I don&amp;rsquo;t even know whether this is the original Red Skull or a clone or whatever. The &amp;ldquo;team&amp;rdquo; still has a long way to go given the mistrust between Rogue and Scarlet Witch, and their first &amp;ldquo;mission&amp;rdquo; could hardly be called a success. Red Skull&amp;rsquo;s plan itself seemed a bit too ridiculous and some of his ranting was pandering to modern concerns about American society. But then again, he&amp;rsquo;s a crazy man who desecrated a dead psychic in order to take his powers, so he might not be all up there anyway. Cassaday&amp;rsquo;s art isn&amp;rsquo;t bad but I&amp;rsquo;m still glad that we&amp;rsquo;re getting Copiel in the next issue and Daniel Acuna after that. I&amp;rsquo;m also looking forward to Sunfire. Sunfire! And I think this book is getting Wonder Man too. So, lots to look forward to here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers&lt;/strong&gt; (6 issues in) and &lt;strong&gt;New Avengers&lt;/strong&gt; (3 issues in) - it&amp;rsquo;s hard to discuss these books separately because Jonathan Hickman obviously has some vision for the larger Marvel Universe that involves both of these books, in the same way his &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Four &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;FF&lt;/em&gt; runs worked together. &lt;em&gt;New Avengers &lt;/em&gt;appears to be the more complicated of the two books so far, as it involves the new Illuminati facing a universe-level crisis beyond the power of even the fabled Infinity Gauntlet. &lt;em&gt;Avengers&lt;/em&gt; on the other hand seems to be focusing more on team-building, with each issue after the initial crisis walking us through some of the newer characters on the team like Hyperion, Smasher and Captain Universe. The only problem with these books so far is that they aren&amp;rsquo;t really very accessible, especially for someone who would be trying to get into Avengers after watching the movie. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of characters and concepts and history to wrap your head around so I guess it&amp;rsquo;s more easily appreciated by long-time comic book readers. In terms of artwork, I vastly prefer the work of Avengers art team, Opena on pencils and White on colors, they&amp;rsquo;re giving us some terrific panels comparable to the excellent work on the current &lt;em&gt;Thor God of Thunder&lt;/em&gt; series. Not that the New Avengers artwork is bad, it just hasn&amp;rsquo;t given me any flat-out &amp;ldquo;Wow!&amp;rdquo; panels like the other book has. Still, both books books are good to get into for comic fans and based on his FF runs, we can expect that Hickman is preparing the Avengers for what can only be an epic set of crises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for now, more later. :D&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Marvel This Week: Savage Wolverine #1, All-New X-Men #6, Daredevil #22, New Avengers #2
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2013/01/marvel-this-week-savage-wolverine-1-all-new-x-men-6-daredevil-22-new-avengers-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 16:32:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2013/01/marvel-this-week-savage-wolverine-1-all-new-x-men-6-daredevil-22-new-avengers-2/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Here are the first few Marvel comics I read this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Savage Wolverine #1&lt;/strong&gt; by Frank Cho is a fun, action-packed ride. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t explain much of what the heck is going on, but it does feature Wolverine chopping heads off and stabbing dinosaurs in the face so hey, I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll read it for a while!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All-New X-Men #6 &lt;/strong&gt;sees the young X-Men trying to settle into modern day. I found young Scott&amp;rsquo;s trying to wrap his head around mobile phones, bottled water and $5 magazines particularly amusing. The artist duties are temporarily handled by David Marquez (with Immonen still doing the cover) and he does a pretty good job of it too; the panels during the intro sequence with Jean and Logan are very well done. Bendis handles the Angel meet-up well, and Kitty and Storm quickly bond with young Jean&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daredevil #22 &lt;/strong&gt;gives us the first encounter between the new Superior Spider-Man and our favorite blind lawyer slash vigilante. Not even Daredevil&amp;rsquo;s hyper-senses are enough to see through the change in Spider-Man (though the dialogue does give him suspicion!) and as heroes do when they cross paths, they are at each others&amp;rsquo; throats at first. But the convenient appearance of an old enemy breaks their battle and forces them into a team up. Spidey and DD manage to patch things up, and later DD tries to patch things up with another partner&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Avengers #2&lt;/strong&gt; continues Hickman&amp;rsquo;s epic Illuminati story with Reed Richards himself giving us a quick rundown of the multiverse-level crisis our heroes face. Hickman&amp;rsquo;s large-scale scifi storytelling is in full effect here as the heroes consider the terrible options laid out for them; I&amp;rsquo;m curious how this book will intersect with Hickman&amp;rsquo;s ongoing saga over in &lt;em&gt;Avengers&lt;/em&gt; though.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>This Week: All-New X-Men #5
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2013/01/this-week-all-new-x-men-5/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 16:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2013/01/this-week-all-new-x-men-5/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Props:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Beast newly mutating again. It&#39;s not too radical, but I wasn&#39;t really a fan of cat-beast anyway, so I don&#39;t mind something new&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Stuart Immonen&#39;s artwork is still pretty good&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;My favorite panel here has to be the one with Jean finding out about what happened to her from furry Beast. (See below) It&#39;s a nice collage that will be enjoyed by long-time X-fans who will most likely try to identify each and every scene depicted by Immonen in this spread. Terrific reminder of how much history these characters have. This is my new iPad wallpaper :D&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Looking forward to see Kitty handling the team of young X-Men.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;How will Angel (who doesn&#39;t want to stay in this era) react to the current state of his future self?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Slops:
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;Wolverine basically acting like an immature dumbass to young Scott, who hasn&#39;t done anything (yet) that should piss off Logan. Logan should know better.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;When will we see more of the new mutant guys in action (and not just setting up base)? The book is titled &lt;em&gt;All-New X-Men&lt;/em&gt;, so I was hoping there&#39;d be more of the new guys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&amp;nbsp;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2013/01/this-week-all-new-x-men-5/IMG_0131_hu97c229b9201ca1576505bd7f76127a39_5522426_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>This Week: Superman #15
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2013/01/this-week-superman-15/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 13:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2013/01/this-week-superman-15/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Props:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Kenneth Rocafort&#39;s art is as usual the highlight of the book for me. This time he gets to draw a full book of Superman in his &lt;em&gt;Action Comics&lt;/em&gt; shirt and jeans, plus a few panels of the Justice League. Rocafort is easily the best artist DC comics has at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Amazing build-up of Lex Luthor and how much of a genius/threat he is to Superman. It&#39;s terrific that faced with a threat beyond his grasp, Superman&#39;s first move is to consult his arch enemy before the Justice League. This book gives us a glimpse at how far Luthor has come since his days of being a mere military consultant back in &lt;em&gt;Action Comics&lt;/em&gt;, and hopefully we&#39;re soon going to get an epic Lex Luthor arc in one of these books (or maybe in Snyder&#39;s upcoming new Superman book?)&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Justice League! Nice to know that even Superman is smart enough to call for help, although this is apparently the first time he&#39;s done it. Also nice to know that he&#39;s managed to keep at least one secret from Batman!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Slops
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;Superman calling Diana &#34;my beloved&#34; in his head. Really? They&#39;ve kissed a couple of times and gone out to dinner, I hope he doesn&#39;t already think they&#39;re soulmates or anything like that. Sheesh, that single panel of dialogue poured more cheese into the relationship than the last few issues of &lt;em&gt;Justice League&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2013/01/this-week-superman-15/IMG_0130_huad26a3061e0ecd9f7ea3d62b77f407f8_4817685_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Recently in DC and Image Comics: Throne of Atlantis, Saga, etc.
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2012/12/recently-in-dc-and-image-comics-throne-of-atlantis-saga-etc/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 11:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2012/12/recently-in-dc-and-image-comics-throne-of-atlantis-saga-etc/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;DC has an extra week of #15 releases on the first week of January (January 2), since they only had two issues out on Christmas week, which were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Justice League #15 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;and&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Aquaman #15&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Throne of Atlantis)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geoff Johns finally gives us a bit more characterization in the &lt;em&gt;Justice League&lt;/em&gt;, stepping up from the previous issues that seem a bit filler. We get a glimpse of Cyborg&amp;rsquo;s current relationship with his father Clark and Diana on a date in secret identity mode and later saving people together mode (with Lois looking on wistfully maybe?) and a bit of a team-up between Batman, Aquaman and Mera in Gotham as the initial opening salvo of the Atlantis invasion begins. The story continues in &lt;em&gt;Aquaman&lt;/em&gt; and sadly yes, you probably have to be reading both books to follow this little storyline but at least it looks like it&amp;rsquo;s going to be worth it and will help define a new status quo for the League in the run-up to 2013&amp;rsquo;s Trinity War. No Flash or Green Lantern appearances this month though (they&amp;rsquo;re pretty busy!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shazam backup story in Justice League continues this month and leaves us looking forward to the next issue as Black Adam finally catches up with Billy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the DC and Image books I read last week (the week before Christmas):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saga #8 (Image)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ask anyone who follows the comics scene what&amp;rsquo;s currently the best ongoing series then you&amp;rsquo;re going to get a lot of &amp;ldquo;Saga Saga Saga Saga Saga Saga Saga Saga Saga Saga Saga Saga&amp;rdquo;! Brian K Vaughn&amp;rsquo;s newest series, brought to life by the excellent Fiona Staples artwork has me excited to read it whenever it&amp;rsquo;s out. Part space opera, part Romeo and Juliet, part sci-fi vs fantasy, part &amp;ldquo;How I Met Your Mother&amp;rdquo;, the series has a little bit of something for everyone. In this issue, BKV fleshes out Marko&amp;rsquo;s parents a bit more, Marko and his mom fight a giant creature with weird balls, trying to find their ghost babysitter, and the cliffhanger brings back someone from Marko&amp;rsquo;s past. Looking forward to the next issue!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nightwing #15&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Red Hood and the Outlaws #15&lt;/strong&gt; (Death of the Family tie-ins)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still a bit ridiculous how Joker has the time to be in all the Bat-books to harass the Batman family, but that&amp;rsquo;s comics for you ain&amp;rsquo;t it? The interesting bit about the Nightwing book is that Joker busted Raya out of prison so that Dick has to take her down, implying strongly that he &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; know who Nightwing is (and hence the rest of the family) despite Batman&amp;rsquo;s denials. Looks like we&amp;rsquo;re getting a showdown at Haley&amp;rsquo;s circus next month, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how this affects Dick&amp;rsquo;s plans to rehabilitate Amusement Mile. To be honest the Nightwing book has been a bit boring to me, making it not always high on the read pile. Hopefully after the DotF tie-in we get some change in the status quo to make the book more exciting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the RHATO issue the highlights are basically Jason being able to take down the GCPD while wearing only a towel and Joker revealing his role in Jason&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;upbringing&amp;rdquo; so to speak. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been that big a fan of RHATO since Ken Rocafort left this book to work on &lt;em&gt;Superman&lt;/em&gt;, but I am looking forward to what Scott Lobdell does when he crosses over Arsenal/Starfire with the &lt;em&gt;Teen Titans &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Green Lantern #15 &lt;/strong&gt;and &lt;strong&gt;Green Lantern New Guardians #15 &lt;/strong&gt;(Rise of the Third Army tie-in)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Green Lantern &lt;/em&gt;finally shows us proof of Baz&amp;rsquo;s innocence in the terror attack, and with a federal agent at the scene hopefully it gets him cleared. But more importantly, someone from the Green Lantern Corps finally gets in touch with Baz! In New Guardians, Kyle takes on Larfreeze to add the color orange to his arsenal! Seriously, I&amp;rsquo;m not too excited about this whole Kyle learning to be a rainbow lantern thing, I hope they wrap it up soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least they finally encountered the third army, and with the GLC being aware of the Guardian&amp;rsquo;s madness hopefully things start moving along in this Green Lantern crossover next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wonder Woman #15&lt;/strong&gt; - the most significant thing about this issue is that it&amp;rsquo;s the first appearance of Orion of the New Gods in the New 52! (That and I&amp;rsquo;ve finally caught up with reading Wonder Woman) The issue also implies that the New Gods have been aware of Earth for a while now and that Orion is a regular visitor, with his own contacts and all (but one of them is a hobo). Of course, when Diana and Orion meet for the first time they slug it out for a bit (seems to be the standard for two superheroes meeting each other for the first time). The series has been great so far, and mostly stand alone from the rest of the new 52 too. I like the scenes were Hela has to deal with being mortal now lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supergirl #15 &lt;/strong&gt;(He&amp;rsquo;l on Earth) - ugh this crossover has been so boring/mediocre and I feel like Kara is being really stupid in following this He&amp;rsquo;l person around. But then again, we&amp;rsquo;re 15 issues in and she still doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand Earth, still doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand who Superman is and basically still hasn&amp;rsquo;t been able to accept the destruction of Krypton. So it&amp;rsquo;s really a problem of the Supergirl book being unable to settle into a status quo yet. Maybe after this whole crossover concludes we&amp;rsquo;ll finally get that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were also a ton of other DC books I didn&amp;rsquo;t read this week: Blue Beetle (I think this is ending?), Batwoman (art here is still great-looking, seems I should catch up on this), Catwoman (should I even care about this?), Legion of Super Heroes (this book is entertaining, but with so many characters, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to get invested in). I grew up as a Marvel fan, but DC seriously needs to work harder on making their books more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Amazing Spider-Man #700, Avenging Spider-Man #15.1 and Superior Spider-Man
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2012/12/amazing-spider-man-700-avenging-spider-man-15-1-and-superior-spider-man/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 03:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2012/12/amazing-spider-man-700-avenging-spider-man-15-1-and-superior-spider-man/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;When I first heard about &lt;em&gt;Amazing Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt; ending and being replaced by a new &lt;em&gt;Superior Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt; series starring someone other than Peter Parker, my first thought was: maybe they&amp;rsquo;re finally retiring Peter for good. Peter is at a pretty good point in his personal life: he has a good, fulfilling job at Horizon Labs so he doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to miss the bills, Aunt May is well taken care of by Jameson Sr. so he doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about her all the time, and there were even some signs of how he and Mary Jane still cared so deeply for each other. After everything Peter had given to the world as Spider-Man, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too much to ask for him to pass the baton to someone else and ride off into the sunset to live happily ever after (maybe after foiling one last big supervillain plot of course). Peter could still make occasional appearances as a mentor or tech supplier for whoever would be the new Spider-Man. It would be a well-deserved rest and retirement for someone who has had to bear so much responsibility for the past 50 years of &lt;em&gt;Amazing Spider-Man,&lt;/em&gt; an ideal fantasy ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas, when I read ASM #698, the opening shot of the Dying Wish story arc that would end the book, I knew that it would remain just that: a fantasy. The powers-that-be (meaning Spider-man scribe Dan Slott and the Marvel editorial team) had prescribed a darker ending for the dearly beloved Spider-Man hero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve probably read all about it on the internet by now. The ending of &lt;em&gt;Amazing Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt; has been one of the most (if not the most) controversial and divisive story lines not only for the year but maybe for the entirety of the &lt;em&gt;Amazing Spider-Man &lt;/em&gt;run, with the only other possible contender being the deal with the devil in the much-criticized One More Day story arc back in 2007. The difference between 2007 and 2012 is of course the internet is more widely spread and the creators are more accessible, specifically current series writer Dan Slott who is very open and active on Twitter. Many fans have not reacted well to the controversial ending of Dying Wish and the identity of the new Superior Spider-Man, with many lashing out in forums and reddit and social media, some directly threatening Dan Slott via his twitter account. I doubt One More Day writer JMS ever had this amount of vitriol thrown at him over the internet at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fan reaction is understandable (though the threats aren&amp;rsquo;t) - Peter Parker was a well-loved character and to give him an ending like this can feel like a betrayal to fans who have been rooting for him all these years. But not all stories have a happy ending. Sometimes the hero doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it against the overwhelming odds. Sometimes he doesn&amp;rsquo;t get the ending he deserves. Sometimes the villain doesn&amp;rsquo;t get his comeuppance. And maybe, just maybe, sometimes the villain gets the chance to play the hero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And understandably after reading &lt;strong&gt;Amazing Spider-Man #700 &lt;/strong&gt;a lot of people are not planning to pick up the upcoming Superior Spider-Man series, the same way a number of people stopped reading ASM after One More Day. And that&amp;rsquo;s fine; not all stories are for everybody, and for some readers all they want is to read more Peter Parker as Spider-Man; they don&amp;rsquo;t want to read about some villain pretending to be Spider-Man. As comic book fans, we all know that eventually Peter Parker will find his way back to us somehow (if only because he has a movie coming out in 2014!), but for now it&amp;rsquo;s the end of Peter&amp;rsquo;s story and someone else takes over. If one doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to read stories about that, then it&amp;rsquo;s fine and that frees your comics dollars to maybe pick up something new and just come back when Peter eventually does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for the rest of us, the ones who want to keep reading, &lt;strong&gt;Avenging Spiderman #15.1 &lt;/strong&gt;picks up where ASM 700 left off and gives us a glimpse of the new Spider-Man&amp;rsquo;s persona, leading into &lt;strong&gt;Superior Spider-Man #1&lt;/strong&gt; on the second week of January. There are many more stories to be told and to be read and to be enjoyed. And if we don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy them? Then Peter would be coming back sooner than we&amp;rsquo;d expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m curious as to where Slott will take our new hero. Will his be a tale of redemption, of making up for past wrongs? Will he strive to be the hero Peter was and even surpass him, in order to justify his &amp;ldquo;Superior&amp;rdquo; title? How much influence will Peter have over the new pilot? (We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen Peter&amp;rsquo;s instincts and muscle memory reflect in the new protagonist) Will Carlie and/or heaven forbid the Trapster eventually figure things out? Will icky things happen to MJ? Slott says they still have a few tricks up their sleeves and that fans should stay tuned to &lt;em&gt;Superior Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt;. But the new book and the new protagonist have a high standard to live up to and surpass if they are to be worthy of being called &amp;ldquo;Superior&amp;rdquo;. Let&amp;rsquo;s see where this ride takes us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Last Week In Marvel NOW!: Avengers, Thor, All-New X-Men and others
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 16:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Last Week in Marvel NOW!&amp;rdquo; since this is going up on Sunday/Monday. And what a lot of Marvel NOW! we got, since many of the top titles are double shipping this month. Hopefully the schedule normalizes back to monthlies soon, I&amp;rsquo;m already reading far too many books as it is! (Well, that&amp;rsquo;s kind of a good problem to have right?) Luckily Marvel only has two books coming out on Christmas week, gives me some time to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best books this week are the same ones I&amp;rsquo;ve been raving about the past month. We start with &lt;strong&gt;Avengers #2&lt;/strong&gt; by Hickman/Opena/White. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot less action in this issue as Hickman takes the time to do some more scenario-building. We&amp;rsquo;re treated to a bit of a background check on the new villains as well as some flashbacks of how Tony and Cap went around recruiting the new Avengers team.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#cf26b337bcf61d4c7f4112b629c155c0-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/avengers2_hub3dd375c188f9c85c4e2f38613e34129_498736_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;cf26b337bcf61d4c7f4112b629c155c0-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/avengers2.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;23 Dec 2012 4:57pm&#34;&gt;23 Dec 2012 4:57pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening story arc of Hickman&amp;rsquo;s Avengers harkens back to the trope used to introduce a new team in Giant-Sized X-Men #1, with the original team getting captured and only their leader making it back to assemble a new team for a rescue mission. This issue ends with the new team starting the rescue mission, hopefully we&amp;rsquo;re in for an action-packed third issue. Art-wise the issue is still spectacular, although Thor does look a bit ridiculous in the cover:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#ca4d8e53ea5663afa12515c7cff622cf-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/IMG_0125_hu4920d1e88de3e3eee883f98d2d9a1dcb_1398091_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;ca4d8e53ea5663afa12515c7cff622cf-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/IMG_0125.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;23 Dec 2012 4:57pm&#34;&gt;23 Dec 2012 4:57pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internal pages by Opena/White are still top-notch though. I&amp;rsquo;m especially fond of the level of detail and the way they present close-ups of the different characters. I hope they&amp;rsquo;ll be able to stay on the book and maintain such a high-level of quality in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is &lt;strong&gt;Thor God of Thunder #3, &lt;/strong&gt;continuing the god butcher story arc. This issue focuses more on present-day Thor as he tries to track down the god butcher and all he finds are more victims. Hard to predict how Jason Aaron plans to end this thing, since the god butcher is still around at the time of future Thor, we can only assume that Thor either loses (not likely, since that means his death) or he won&amp;rsquo;t be able to come up with a permanent solution. Ribic&amp;rsquo;s pencils and Svorcina&amp;rsquo;s colors seem to be getting more epic with each issue, I&amp;rsquo;ll just leave you with a quick taste:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#93d3d33421a8aa2c83ca93e16daee22c-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/thor3_hub5bbb0ccd1fe4044c2b93c694240a276_684260_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;93d3d33421a8aa2c83ca93e16daee22c-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/thor3.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;23 Dec 2012 4:57pm&#34;&gt;23 Dec 2012 4:57pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All-New X-Men #4 &lt;/strong&gt;was a bit disappointing for me though still pretty good. Okay, the only really disappointing part was that we didn&amp;rsquo;t have a real Scott and Scott confrontation, and Cyclops and Magneto kind of just chickened out and fled. I kinda feel the way young Iceman feels:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#2c36ad9cf62fe638589c5621c9427420-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/anxm4_hu096b4e901aad6172e6f9e54cbed9364f_204672_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;2c36ad9cf62fe638589c5621c9427420-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/anxm4.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;23 Dec 2012 4:57pm&#34;&gt;23 Dec 2012 4:57pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it just feels like we&amp;rsquo;re four issues in and we&amp;rsquo;re barely past the initial premise of the book, the pacing could be a bit faster I guess. Of course it&amp;rsquo;s already amazing that we&amp;rsquo;re at issue 4 when Marvel NOW! isn&amp;rsquo;t even two months old! That being said, Bendis and Immonen are still doing great here in terms of some excellent dialogue and panels and I&amp;rsquo;m still eagerly looking forward to the next issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just some quick hits for the other Marvel NOW! releases this week: &lt;strong&gt;Indestructible Hulk #2 &lt;/strong&gt;sees a skeptical Tony Stark visiting Banner at his new SHIELD laboratories (Tony has been visiting a lot of people recently) and there&amp;rsquo;s a funny panel where Tony tries to reinforce his self-confidence after witnessing just how much of a genius Banner is. This issue doesn&amp;rsquo;t really build up to any story arc but rather cements Banner&amp;rsquo;s role as a SHIELD guy especially with regards to Tony. &lt;strong&gt;FF #2 &lt;/strong&gt;sees an attack on the Baxter Building right after the original Four supposedly should have returned but didn&amp;rsquo;t, and the substitute Four gets to show off a bit. The first two issues of both &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Four &lt;/em&gt;and this book actually form the introductory story arc, broken across the two books so it&amp;rsquo;s better to be following both. Fraction&amp;rsquo;s writing is ok so far, but I&amp;rsquo;m not really a fan of Allred&amp;rsquo;s art style though I know a lot of people are. &lt;strong&gt;Avengers Arena #2 &lt;/strong&gt;tells me that we should be expecting issues focusing on each of Arcade&amp;rsquo;s 16 battle royale contestants which is good - a lot of them look unfamiliar and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether this is their first series. This issue focuses on Deathlocket, who&amp;rsquo;s apprently the daughter of the guy who invents the Deathloks. We also get another death in this issue, but it&amp;rsquo;s one of the new kids and feels a bit like a throwaway. I&amp;rsquo;m still iffy on this series, but let&amp;rsquo;s see where Hopeless takes it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m kind of &amp;ldquo;meh&amp;rdquo; overall on the last three books I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing, they haven&amp;rsquo;t really wowed me so far.&lt;strong&gt; Cable and X-Force #2 &lt;/strong&gt;gives us a more solid look and what&amp;rsquo;s going on and how their team came together, but we still have no idea how they got to the point where the Uncanny Avengers needed to be taking them in. Cable is apparently having prophetic visions of disaster and supposedly this is going to lead the team to more shenanigans. &lt;strong&gt;Thunderbolts #2 &lt;/strong&gt;follows a mostly boring first issue, but gives us a better idea of the kind of missions Ross has in mind for his team. The artwork isn&amp;rsquo;t the best, it seems like the artist is using the same outlines for every unmasked face; there&amp;rsquo;s a panel where Ross just looks like Punisher (in the same panel) except painted red. This is my first time with Steve Dillon&amp;rsquo;s work and I&amp;rsquo;m not impressed. &lt;strong&gt;X-Men Legacy #3&lt;/strong&gt; kinda feels like the writer Simon Spurrier is tripping with us a bit but at least he&amp;rsquo;s bringing some perspective to what it&amp;rsquo;s like to be David Haller. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the next issue where he actually interacts with some X-Men! I get that the book is supposed to be Legion-focused but still, it&amp;rsquo;s X-Men Legacy, not Legion Legacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for Marvel NOW! Next: DC and Image.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/IMG_0125_hu4920d1e88de3e3eee883f98d2d9a1dcb_1398091_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/anxm4_hu096b4e901aad6172e6f9e54cbed9364f_204672_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/avengers2_hub3dd375c188f9c85c4e2f38613e34129_498736_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/last-week-in-marvel-now-avengers-thor-all-new-x-men-and-others/thor3_hub5bbb0ccd1fe4044c2b93c694240a276_684260_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>This Week In Marvel: Hawkguy, Daredevil, X-Factor, X-Treme X-Men and the end of Uncanny X-Force
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2012/12/this-week-in-marvel-hawkguy-daredevil-x-factor-x-treme-x-men-and-the-end-of-uncanny-x-force/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 12:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2012/12/this-week-in-marvel-hawkguy-daredevil-x-factor-x-treme-x-men-and-the-end-of-uncanny-x-force/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s really far, far too many comics I read each week to cover them in one blog post so I&amp;rsquo;ll just cover them in groups. First, the non-Marvel NOW! series:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hawkeye #6&lt;/strong&gt; is the highlight of this week&amp;rsquo;s Marvel releases. The book is consistently funny, down-to-earth and awesome, and this issue is one of the best so far. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about it, the series written by Matt Fraction is one of Marvel&amp;rsquo;s best ongoings right now. The book tells stories of what &amp;ldquo;Hawkguy&amp;rdquo; is up to when he&amp;rsquo;s not out Avenging against alien threats or hydra or whatever. He owns an apartment building and has a dog and Tony Stark comes over to help set up his A/V system so he can watch a DVRed copy of the final season of &amp;ldquo;Dog Cops&amp;rdquo;. David Aja is killing it with the art too. Nothing too hyper-realistic, the art is simple and straightforward but we get excellent panel layouts, especially with conversation pages where there&amp;rsquo;s like 20-30 panels each. This issue in particular feels like a comic strip version of a sitcom; except sitcoms don&amp;rsquo;t usually have gangs of amusing thugs who say &amp;ldquo;Bro!&amp;rdquo; all the time. As in &amp;ldquo;You should really be reading Hawkguy bro!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#9de1dd690b072893760d3e397168f2ad-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/this-week-in-marvel-hawkguy-daredevil-x-factor-x-treme-x-men-and-the-end-of-uncanny-x-force/hawkguy_hue0ffc6846cbef8f1eb9536dd21308853_394171_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;9de1dd690b072893760d3e397168f2ad-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/this-week-in-marvel-hawkguy-daredevil-x-factor-x-treme-x-men-and-the-end-of-uncanny-x-force/hawkguy.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;22 Dec 2012 12:29pm&#34;&gt;22 Dec 2012 12:29pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daredevil #21 &lt;/strong&gt;resolves the Spot and Coyote plotlines (with some threads left dangling), and settles the question of whether Matt has been crazy all this time. The thing with Spot and Coyote was a bit creepy really so I&amp;rsquo;m kinda glad to move on. But the best thing with this issue has to be the bonus appearance of the new Superior Spider-Man!&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#4b52332ab7d58c1c73b8c10769e13b78-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/this-week-in-marvel-hawkguy-daredevil-x-factor-x-treme-x-men-and-the-end-of-uncanny-x-force/daredevil21_hu7c8c96fd8b3591272999a8f8e0b0167f_684328_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;4b52332ab7d58c1c73b8c10769e13b78-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/this-week-in-marvel-hawkguy-daredevil-x-factor-x-treme-x-men-and-the-end-of-uncanny-x-force/daredevil21.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;22 Dec 2012 12:29pm&#34;&gt;22 Dec 2012 12:29pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That exchange really feels like how I&amp;rsquo;d imagine it going with the new &amp;ldquo;person&amp;rdquo; behind the Spider-Man mask and makes me look forward to &lt;em&gt;Amazing Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt; #700/&lt;em&gt;Avenging Spider-man&lt;/em&gt; #15.1 next week and &lt;em&gt;Superior Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt; in January (and of course the next issue of &lt;em&gt;Daredevil&lt;/em&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;X-Factor #249 &lt;/strong&gt;is a prime example of the craziness Peter David brings to these characters&amp;rsquo; lives - Madrox and Layla are married (and apparently she can generate force fields now), M has been possessed by a troll (and she&amp;rsquo;s very angry about it) and all this time they&amp;rsquo;re trying to fight off a horde of demons trying to invade our world. Not that there aren&amp;rsquo;t any other superteams that could be defending our world of course, but one of the great things about X-Factor is that the stories are more or less cut off from the rest of the Marvel universe unless absolutely necessary (well, it seems Alex up and vanished from this book supposedly to join the Avengers, so there&amp;rsquo;s that), which means Peter David is free to have out of this world things happen to the characters. It isn&amp;rsquo;t always the best book Marvel puts out, but it never goes into that boring zone where you&amp;rsquo;d wish you were reading something else. Oh, and as I write this I realize I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Peter David writing X-Factor since the 90s! (Not continuously of course, and only Madrox and Lorna are from the original team he wrote)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;X-treme X-Men #8 &lt;/strong&gt;brings new members of our dimension-hopping Xavier hunters, including a second Dazzler - this might get confusing. Or maybe not, depending on what happens with this issue&amp;rsquo;s cliffhanger. Alternate universes are really great, it gives writers a chance to explore characters in a different light, and XXM writer Greg Pak has brought us a lot of that. We get younger versions, battle-hardened versions, versions with different sexuality and race (is that a black Cyclops?!) as the team jumps across dimensions. I&amp;rsquo;m always looking forward to reading this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncanny X-Force #35 &lt;/strong&gt;marks the end of Rick Remender&amp;rsquo;s critically-acclaimed run as he moves on to &lt;em&gt;Uncanny Avengers&lt;/em&gt; territory. This final issue isn&amp;rsquo;t very action-packed, but it wraps up some dangling threads, with Psylocke clearing things up with her brother, a surprisingly lucid Deadpool talking Evan through how to handle all the stuff he&amp;rsquo;s been through and the fate of Fantomex (is he really dead? Then who&amp;rsquo;s that female version in the Marvel NOW Uncanny X-Force previews?). We also find out what future Wolverine told our current Wolverine and how it relates to Daken&amp;rsquo;s ultimate fate as shown in UXF #34 (I&amp;rsquo;m kinda hoping Daken stays dead - it adds a lot to Logan&amp;rsquo;s character that he has that low point in his history). It&amp;rsquo;s a great ending to a great run, hopefully Sam Humphries&amp;rsquo; new Uncanny X-Force will be just as great.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/this-week-in-marvel-hawkguy-daredevil-x-factor-x-treme-x-men-and-the-end-of-uncanny-x-force/daredevil21_hu7c8c96fd8b3591272999a8f8e0b0167f_684328_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/this-week-in-marvel-hawkguy-daredevil-x-factor-x-treme-x-men-and-the-end-of-uncanny-x-force/hawkguy_hue0ffc6846cbef8f1eb9536dd21308853_394171_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Comics To Look Forward To 2012-12-18
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2012/12/comics-to-look-forward-to-2012-12-18/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 10:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2012/12/comics-to-look-forward-to-2012-12-18/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Well, missed posting about last week&amp;rsquo;s comics due to some technical difficulties with my home computer, let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can&amp;rsquo;t get back on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to look forward to this week on the Marvel side. There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;All-New X-Men #4&lt;/strong&gt; where we&amp;rsquo;ll finally get to see Cyclops face off with his younger/older self. My other favorite so far of the Marvel NOW! books has the second issue this week: &lt;strong&gt;Avengers #2&lt;/strong&gt; continues   the introductory arc to Jonathan Hickman&amp;rsquo;s Avengers epic, let&amp;rsquo;s see how he handles the large cast he&amp;rsquo;s playing with. &lt;strong&gt;Hawkeye #5&lt;/strong&gt; (David Aja returns!), &lt;strong&gt;Daredevil #21&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;X-Treme X-Men #8&lt;/strong&gt; are all out this week, and while none of these are Marvel NOW! titles, they&amp;rsquo;re currently some of the best books Marvel has to offer so they&amp;rsquo;re always on top of my reading list. &lt;strong&gt;Uncanny X-Force #35 &lt;/strong&gt;ends Rick Remender&amp;rsquo;s celebrated run, hopefully &lt;em&gt;Uncanny Avengers&lt;/em&gt; starts to get a lot better now that he has one less ongoing series. Also looking forward to new issues of the better Marvel NOW! books: &lt;strong&gt;Indestructible Hulk #2, Thor God of Thunder #3&lt;/strong&gt; among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DC is still not too exciting for me at the moment, but I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be reading the books that continue their mini-crossovers. That&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Green Lantern #15 &lt;/strong&gt;and &lt;strong&gt;Green Lantern New Guardians #15 &lt;/strong&gt;for &lt;em&gt;Rise of the Third Army&lt;/em&gt; which has been a bit mediocre so far. Then &lt;strong&gt;Supergirl #15 &lt;/strong&gt;for &lt;em&gt;He&amp;rsquo;l on Earth.&lt;/em&gt; And of course there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Nightwing #15 &lt;/strong&gt;and &lt;strong&gt;Red Hood and the Outlaws #15&lt;/strong&gt; for the &lt;em&gt;Death of the Family&lt;/em&gt; tie-ins. I heard Orion is getting introduced in the New 52 in &lt;strong&gt;Wonder Woman #15, &lt;/strong&gt;hopefully I can catch up on that series soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of Marvel/DC, this week also brings us a new issue of Brian K. Vaughn&amp;rsquo;s new masterpiece - &lt;strong&gt;Saga #8 &lt;/strong&gt;should easily be on the top of my reading list. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it yet, &lt;em&gt;Saga&lt;/em&gt; is some strange mix of &lt;em&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/em&gt; meets &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; meets &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; and easily one of the best new series recently so you might want to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Pick of the Week: Avengers #1 (2012-12-08)
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2012/12/pick-of-the-week-avengers-1-2012-12-08/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 15:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2012/12/pick-of-the-week-avengers-1-2012-12-08/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Easily the best comic I&amp;rsquo;ve read this week (and I&amp;rsquo;ve already read a lot!) is the Marvel NOW! Relaunch of the Avengers book. Avengers vol. 5 #1 by Jonathan Hickman and Jerome Opena ushers in a brand new era of Avengers; bigger, bolder and looking to be a lot more epic.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#5bc0e304d79c5f527cded652119fcdef-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/pick-of-the-week-avengers-1-2012-12-08/1354655500_cvr_hu4cf0599bd3ca680782815a3bbac74e8e_315018_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;5bc0e304d79c5f527cded652119fcdef-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/pick-of-the-week-avengers-1-2012-12-08/1354655500_cvr.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;8 Dec 2012 3:49pm&#34;&gt;8 Dec 2012 3:49pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonathan Hickman, fresh off what many consider to be the best &lt;em&gt;Fantastic Four&lt;/em&gt; run in recent history (if not all-time), takes over from former &lt;em&gt;Avengers &lt;/em&gt;showrunner Brian Michael Bendis and immediately shows us how his take on the Earth&amp;rsquo;s Mightiest Heroes is going to set itself apart from Bendis&amp;rsquo; 200+ issue run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book opens with a narrative foreshadowing future events reminiscent of the dire warnings given by future Franklin Richards early on in Hickman&amp;rsquo;s Fantastic Four run. Opena&amp;rsquo;s excellent art and Dean White&amp;rsquo;s color work are at their best in this book, bringing to life Hickman&amp;rsquo;s grand plans for the Avengers in beautiful broad strokes.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#96dee34fb7ab691b0eb3f4b87cfcfac4-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/pick-of-the-week-avengers-1-2012-12-08/avengers1_hu05ce6a670f3356e0ecfd5012f2868cbd_1235473_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;96dee34fb7ab691b0eb3f4b87cfcfac4-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/pick-of-the-week-avengers-1-2012-12-08/avengers1.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;8 Dec 2012 3:49pm&#34;&gt;8 Dec 2012 3:49pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what grand plans they are; we&amp;rsquo;re looking at a larger Avengers roster, dying universes, the terraforming of Mars, an interstellar war and the fall&amp;hellip;of what looks like Iron Men (plural). It looks like Hickman plans to move away from the more &amp;ldquo;street-level&amp;rdquo; adventures that characterized the immediately previous Avengers series and will instead focus on larger-scale events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Bendis&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;Avengers&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;New Avengers&lt;/em&gt; books were marked by witty banter and character dialogue, Hickman&amp;rsquo;s first issue by contrast has a darker tone to it. There is very little banter as the Avengers take the fight to a threat from beyond this world. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how well Spider-man is going to fit in here, this looks to be an Avengers book that&amp;rsquo;s all about getting down to serious business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book starts with the core six Avengers from the recent Marvel movie but soon enough Captain America has to make the call to bring a larger roster into play. Based on the terrific design graphic at the start and end of the issue, we&amp;rsquo;re looking at a full roster of 24 Avengers, at least for the initial Avengers World story arc.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#81664473092512808d3edf6f2684fe9e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/pick-of-the-week-avengers-1-2012-12-08/avengers_hu1f2215385290af2c15e5d252248e52b2_1402774_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;81664473092512808d3edf6f2684fe9e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/pick-of-the-week-avengers-1-2012-12-08/avengers.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;8 Dec 2012 3:49pm&#34;&gt;8 Dec 2012 3:49pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have high expectations for Hickman&amp;rsquo;s Avengers run, and the first issue only serves to whet my appetite. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see what he has in store for us not only in this book, and I&amp;rsquo;m anxiously looking forward to next month&amp;rsquo;s New Avengers #1 as well.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/pick-of-the-week-avengers-1-2012-12-08/1354655500_cvr_hu4cf0599bd3ca680782815a3bbac74e8e_315018_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/pick-of-the-week-avengers-1-2012-12-08/avengers_hu1f2215385290af2c15e5d252248e52b2_1402774_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/12/pick-of-the-week-avengers-1-2012-12-08/avengers1_hu05ce6a670f3356e0ecfd5012f2868cbd_1235473_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The first three comics I’m reading this week 2012-12-04
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2012/12/the-first-three-comics-im-reading-this-week-2012-12-04/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 09:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2012/12/the-first-three-comics-im-reading-this-week-2012-12-04/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s actually kind of a light week this week. There&amp;rsquo;s a couple of Marvel NOW! #1s coming in, and nothing too exciting particularly on the DC side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The #1 I&amp;rsquo;m most looking forward to the most this week has to be Jonathan Hickman and Jerome Opena&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.comicbookresources.com/?page=preview&amp;amp;id=14395&#34;&gt;Avengers #1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (link leads to preview pages). It&amp;rsquo;s a new era for the Avengers as a new creative team takes over from Bendis, and it looks like Hickman will be bringing over his tendency for epic-scale adventures from the Fantastic Four books over to the Avengers franchise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we have&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.comicbookresources.com/?page=preview&amp;amp;id=14401&#34;&gt; Amazing Spider-man #699&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; which continues the Dying Wish story arc and the shocking reveal of the last book. Writer Dan Slott is very excited for the last two issues of the Amazing Spider-man run and has been hyping it up. A lot of fans are worried at where the franchise is going and who the new Superior Spider-Man will be, Dan Slott has two issues left to wrap things up in a satisfactory fashion and provide us an ending that lives up to the hype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing as how I&amp;rsquo;m always gushing about Bendis and Immonen&amp;rsquo;s new flagship X-Men book, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a surprise that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.comicbookresources.com/?page=preview&amp;amp;id=14400&#34;&gt;All-New X-Men #3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; rounds out the top of my list, hopefully the creative team gives us some fresh action this time around, looking forward to the original five coming face-to-face with present day Scott Summers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honorable mentions: &lt;strong&gt;Hawkeye #5&lt;/strong&gt; is also out this week and has been a great book so far. We have another Marvel NOW! #1 with &lt;strong&gt;Thunderbolts #1&lt;/strong&gt;, hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll be getting a good explanation of how this particular team gets together. This week we also get &lt;strong&gt;The Legend of Luther Strode #1&lt;/strong&gt; from Image, the sequel to last year&amp;rsquo;s critically acclaimed and ultraviolent The &lt;em&gt;Strange Talent of Luther Strode&lt;/em&gt;, hopefully the series gives us a bit more story meat this time.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>This Week In Comics 2012-12-01
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 13:09:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s see what the comic book man brought us this week! (Mild spoilers may ensue)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uncanny Avengers #2 (Marvel)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#410070a7e6752923bb67ebfe66d2f233-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/2529963-uncanny_avengers_2_super_huf5e545e8d942bf828d62f3f06ba25a5c_121740_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;410070a7e6752923bb67ebfe66d2f233-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/2529963-uncanny_avengers_2_super.jpeg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&#34;&gt;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest this book was not at the top of my to-read list since I was a bit underwhelmed by the first book. But that may have been a product of reading too many preview pages so that basically the only surprise I got was the shock ending of what Red Skull was doing to Xavier&amp;rsquo;s corpse. The second issue felt a lot better though, there were some scenes that I felt were quite well-written - Havok receiving the old man&amp;rsquo;s thanks, the scenes with the mutants while watching Honest John&amp;rsquo;s broadcasts, how Rogue manages to escape her captors, etc. Also, how great of a villain name is &amp;ldquo;Honest John the Living Propaganda?&amp;rdquo; Heh. (I think he&amp;rsquo;s a new guy introduced by Remender, I can&amp;rsquo;t find any info from before this issue). I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of Cassaday&amp;rsquo;s artwork (which contributed to my being underwhelmed by the first issue) - it feels like he&amp;rsquo;s a bit hit or miss. There are some great panels here, but there are also some that are drawn strangely (Lilandra looks bald in one of the panels - that may have been a colorist problem though). Still, Remender&amp;rsquo;s writing more than makes up for the art, though I do hope Cassaday can keep to schedule so that the book doesn&amp;rsquo;t slip schedules too much (see: &lt;em&gt;Astonishing X-Men)&lt;/em&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to where the Red Skull is taking is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All-New X-Men #2 (Marvel)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#e4829a85d8af806dff2f15de299344bc-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/all-new-x-men-2-561_hudcc67953afc8cd2d65625691e23e992e_115800_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;e4829a85d8af806dff2f15de299344bc-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/all-new-x-men-2-561.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&#34;&gt;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was quite excited for the second issue of Bendis&amp;rsquo; X-Men and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t disappointed. The art team was great on this book, on par with the first. Immonen&amp;rsquo;s pencils look better with the coloring in ANXM compared to his New Avengers run (though that was great too!). Bendis is known for being a great dialogue writer and he doesn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint. There are some great scenes here with Hank trying to convince the young ones to go along with him, Wolverine&amp;rsquo;s reaction to Jean, Iceman&amp;rsquo;s reaction to himself, and that ending - well, you bring five teenagers who are used to saving the world into a situation like that, what did you think they were going to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Hits - Other Marvel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#072bf4fc851018093eac411e7f0714eb-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/a&amp;#43;x2_hu4d86e8271e97ecc9d28133b7c006ac60_1787552_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;072bf4fc851018093eac411e7f0714eb-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/a&amp;#43;x2.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&#34;&gt;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A+X #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a book I read simply because Chris Bachalo was drawing the Rogue/Black Widow story, I&amp;rsquo;m kind of excited to be having Bachalo and Immonen be the regular X-men artists once the new &lt;em&gt;Uncanny X-Men&lt;/em&gt; launches, I really enjoy their work. The other story in this issue is Kitty Pride visiting Stark Resilient with a cold (the cold is relevant to the story!)  &lt;strong&gt;Thor - God of Thunder #2&lt;/strong&gt; shifts the focus back to young viking Thor with only glimpses of what&amp;rsquo;s happening to his future selves. The book is still great and the art is spectacular. &lt;strong&gt;FF #1&lt;/strong&gt; was okay, though I must admit to not being a big fan of Mike Allred&amp;rsquo;s art even though some people on the internet swear by it. Not really my Thing I guess. Heh. Still looking forward to where Fraction takes this book. &lt;strong&gt;New Avengers #34&lt;/strong&gt; is the end of Bendis&amp;rsquo; 232-issue run of Avengers books, and the ending kind of undoes some of the changes he&amp;rsquo;s made during that run. Which is fine, I guess it gives Hickman more space for his upcoming Avengers run. &lt;strong&gt;X-Men Legacy #2&lt;/strong&gt; felt like it had just a bit too much of traipsing inside Legion&amp;rsquo;s mindscape, but at least we finally get to see some of the other X-Men (it&amp;rsquo;s not a solo book, right?) &lt;strong&gt;X-Treme X-Men #7 &lt;/strong&gt;is still a terribly named book, and the art in this issue was a bit off for me. The writing is great though and it looks like we&amp;rsquo;ll be meeting more alternate universe mutants/heroes in the next few issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Superman #14 (DC)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#2b2208b74d542172c9bcc0a04d71ef0f-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/SUPERMAN_14_hu36f7febbf9f34b55ef352b8cb4492aca_230369_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;2b2208b74d542172c9bcc0a04d71ef0f-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/SUPERMAN_14.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&#34;&gt;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the New 52 started out, &lt;em&gt;Action Comics&lt;/em&gt; was the better Superman title, but with the new creative team of Scott Lobdell and Kenneth Rocafort, this book has started to pick up. The main draw for me is the artwork headlined by Rocafort; this issue&amp;rsquo;s pencils and coloring are great, especially with the level of detail. This issue gives us a bit more insight into Clark&amp;rsquo;s current status, especially vis-a-vis his pre-New 52 love Lois Lane. The rest of the book involve Clark and Kara getting beat up by a strange new visitor from their home planet, and it looks like Clark and Kara&amp;rsquo;s relationship isn&amp;rsquo;t going to get better anytime soon. This may be Kara&amp;rsquo;s new status quo for the New 52, maybe they want her be more stand alone from her famous cousin this time around. The issue doesn&amp;rsquo;t resolve the H&amp;rsquo;el on Earth storyline just yet, looks like we&amp;rsquo;re getting another round of this mini-event in the #15 issues of the &amp;ldquo;super&amp;rdquo; books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aquaman #14 (DC)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#84d93284b45ce7d0640a620aa6c242ed-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/Aquaman_14_Full2-665x1024_hu62f30e12f22401bbd153aadb7a83ca6b_296843_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;84d93284b45ce7d0640a620aa6c242ed-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/Aquaman_14_Full2-665x1024.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&#34;&gt;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a prelude to the &lt;em&gt;Aquaman/Justice League&lt;/em&gt; crossover Throne of Atlantis that starts next month (DC has quite a few of these mini-crossovers going on, maybe in preparation for next year&amp;rsquo;s Trinity War?)  and gives us more information about Arthur&amp;rsquo;s New 52 origins. There&amp;rsquo;s even a scene where Black Manta is explaining how strong Arthur is even outside of the seas. Too bad he didn&amp;rsquo;t accept Waller&amp;rsquo;s invite, I think he&amp;rsquo;d be a good addition to &lt;em&gt;Suicide Squad!&lt;/em&gt; I was a bit annoyed by the scenes with Arthur&amp;rsquo;s brother always being drawn as a shadowy figure; if it was just in side scenes that take place outside of the main story that&amp;rsquo;s fine but they did it even in the main scenes with Arthur. Anyway, it looks like Throne of Atlantis is going to involve even those trench creatures from the first story arc, looks like writer Geoff Johns has something big planned for this one!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Hits - Other DC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Batman Incorporated #5&lt;/strong&gt; brings us another view of a future where Damian has taken over as Batman and all hell was broken loose. This future was last seen in Batman #666 (pre-New 52, also written by Morrison). &lt;strong&gt;Talon #2&lt;/strong&gt; was okay, though the art wasn&amp;rsquo;t very good for me. I like that the book basically giving DC a way to flesh out the Court of Owls after Snyder introduced them in Batman, but aside from that they&amp;rsquo;re going to have to grow Calvin Rose into his own character. &lt;strong&gt;Savage Hawkman #14 &lt;/strong&gt;wraps up his crossovers with &lt;em&gt;Green Arrow&lt;/em&gt; and Deathstroke, although everything is told in an unusual chronological order. They probably just put GA and Hawkman together as a prelude to their teaming up in the upcoming &lt;em&gt;JLA&lt;/em&gt; book. From this issue it looks like there are more Thanagarians on Earth than we expected - they were a pretty big deal pre-New 52 so who knows what they have planned for Thanagar these days. &lt;strong&gt;Teen Titans #14&lt;/strong&gt; wraps up the Cassie origin story but to be honest it didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like it resolved very much. The other half of the issue felt like filler until they could lead up into next month&amp;rsquo;s Death of the Family tie-in. And&amp;hellip;that&amp;rsquo;s it for DC this month, I should probably catch up on the other series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Masks #1 (Dynamite)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#a2e93280218f0fcbd4757ce9014df84b-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/masks1_hua3c10341cf3c023c138257f83b375f8e_156314_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;a2e93280218f0fcbd4757ce9014df84b-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/masks1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&#34;&gt;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s non-big two pick is the first issue of &lt;em&gt;Masks&lt;/em&gt; from Dynamite Entertainment. It&amp;rsquo;s a crossover of several pulp heroes/vigilantes - The Shadow, The Green Hornet and his faithful assistant Kato, the Spider and&amp;hellip;is that Zorro on the cover?!? - coming together to oppose a corrupt government that&amp;rsquo;s imposing injustice on the citizenry. The corrupt bureaucracy leads even law-abiding heroes like the Hornet to question their &amp;ldquo;lawful good&amp;rdquo; stance because this time, the law is on the side of the bad guys! The creative team is science fiction writer Chris Roberson and renowned comic book painter Alex Ross, which means we&amp;rsquo;re in for an interesting and pretty good-looking series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panel of the Week - All-New X-Men #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite panel this week is when Iceman meets Iceman in All-New X-Men #2:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#a78176f9dfe2747befbe51b288ac21b7-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/iceman_hu966e83d4bf8cbe1be40d2b67ae8b37ae_1112560_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;a78176f9dfe2747befbe51b288ac21b7-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/iceman.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&#34;&gt;30 Nov 2012 1:09pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/2529963-uncanny_avengers_2_super_huf5e545e8d942bf828d62f3f06ba25a5c_121740_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/Aquaman_14_Full2-665x1024_hu62f30e12f22401bbd153aadb7a83ca6b_296843_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/SUPERMAN_14_hu36f7febbf9f34b55ef352b8cb4492aca_230369_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/a&amp;#43;x2_hu4d86e8271e97ecc9d28133b7c006ac60_1787552_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/all-new-x-men-2-561_hudcc67953afc8cd2d65625691e23e992e_115800_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/iceman_hu966e83d4bf8cbe1be40d2b67ae8b37ae_1112560_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-12-01/masks1_hua3c10341cf3c023c138257f83b375f8e_156314_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The first three comics I&#39;m reading this week 2012-11-27
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2012/11/first-three-comics-im-readin-this-week-2012-11-27/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 04:59:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2012/11/first-three-comics-im-readin-this-week-2012-11-27/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is new comics day! Here are the titles I&amp;rsquo;m most excited for this week:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#95651be4df5f83faeeca6ee1189f3cbe-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/first-three-comics-im-readin-this-week-2012-11-27/all-new-x-men-2-561_hudcc67953afc8cd2d65625691e23e992e_115800_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;95651be4df5f83faeeca6ee1189f3cbe-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/first-three-comics-im-readin-this-week-2012-11-27/all-new-x-men-2-561.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;27 Nov 2012 4:59am&#34;&gt;27 Nov 2012 4:59am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All-New X-Men # 2 &lt;/strong&gt;- I thoroughly enjoyed the first issue of this Marvel NOW! series a couple of weeks ago and found myself excitedly looking forward to the next one. Luckily (or unlucky for your wallet?) many of the top Marvel NOW! #1s are double-shipping so here we are a couple of weeks later with the second issue of All-New X-Men! I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some of the preview pages, looks like Beast is going to have to convince the first five to make the trip back with him, but we already know they&amp;rsquo;re going to be back in present day by the end of this issue. I&amp;rsquo;m not only looking forward to how the young ones react to the present day &amp;ldquo;dystopia&amp;rdquo; but I&amp;rsquo;m also eager to see more of Stuart Immonen&amp;rsquo;s artwork (just writing this part made me go re-read the first arc of New Avengers that he drew.)&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#f7fb0540f483298afce2e67811ed8c74-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/first-three-comics-im-readin-this-week-2012-11-27/thor-god-of-thunder_hub77c64db49cd58485724f39e64aabbaa_80342_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;f7fb0540f483298afce2e67811ed8c74-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/first-three-comics-im-readin-this-week-2012-11-27/thor-god-of-thunder.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;27 Nov 2012 4:59am&#34;&gt;27 Nov 2012 4:59am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thor: God of Thunder #2&lt;/strong&gt; - this series looks to be one of the best new Marvel NOW! titles; the first issue introducing us to the three Thors facing the god killer was very well-written. Since most of my Thor readings have been either Avengers-related or the recent Journey into Mystery, I&amp;rsquo;ve never read any books that tell us the tales of young Thor during the age of Vikings; it gives a refreshing perspective to the God of Thunder. Mark Millar recently called the book&amp;rsquo;s author Jason Aaron &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mrmarkmillar/status/269033384670556161&#34;&gt;the best Marvel writer at the moment&lt;/a&gt; and having read his recent run on &lt;em&gt;The Incredible Hulk&lt;/em&gt; it gives me high expectations for this series indeed. The artwork is also pretty good - I&amp;rsquo;m not that familiar with the penciler Esad Ribic but I can say after reviewing some of his earlier work that his interiors of this book so far look like the top of his game.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#75ce236140d7436abf66e943f5303926-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/first-three-comics-im-readin-this-week-2012-11-27/2722539-sm_cv14_ds_hu971aa9deffae0378a952dbefe21df0a6_955139_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;75ce236140d7436abf66e943f5303926-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/first-three-comics-im-readin-this-week-2012-11-27/2722539-sm_cv14_ds.jpeg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;27 Nov 2012 4:59am&#34;&gt;27 Nov 2012 4:59am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Superman #14&lt;/strong&gt; - it&amp;rsquo;s not that I&amp;rsquo;m particulary excited by the current H&amp;rsquo;el on Earth storyline - the crossover between the &amp;ldquo;super&amp;rdquo; books has been okay so far (and thankfully it looks like Kara&amp;rsquo;s finally going to learn English!) It&amp;rsquo;s just that I always find myself looking forward to Kenneth Rocafort&amp;rsquo;s artwork, and the previews for this issue look spectacular as usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Honorable Mentions: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;X-treme X-men #7, Uncanny Avengers #2, FF#1, X-Men Legacy #2, Aquaman #14, Batman Incorporated #5, Talon #2, Teen Titans #14&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/first-three-comics-im-readin-this-week-2012-11-27/2722539-sm_cv14_ds_hu971aa9deffae0378a952dbefe21df0a6_955139_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/first-three-comics-im-readin-this-week-2012-11-27/all-new-x-men-2-561_hudcc67953afc8cd2d65625691e23e992e_115800_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/first-three-comics-im-readin-this-week-2012-11-27/thor-god-of-thunder_hub77c64db49cd58485724f39e64aabbaa_80342_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>This Week In Comics 2012-11-24
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-11-24/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 08:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-11-24/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s biggest issue was &lt;strong&gt;Amazing Spider-Man #698&lt;/strong&gt;. With three issues before the series finale and Dan Slott hyping up the ending arc and still keeping a tight lid on who may be taking over Peter&amp;rsquo;s role in Superior Spider-Man in January, I was really excited to be able to read the first part of the final Dying Wish arc.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#95ed9a913d85c54ab565fe62600e0b09-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-11-24/asm698_hu48c73b87f2fea98b0c85afc50efffd96_1808518_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;95ed9a913d85c54ab565fe62600e0b09-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-11-24/asm698.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Nov 2012 8:07am&#34;&gt;24 Nov 2012 8:07am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doctor Octopus is dying! But before he does he pulls a whammy on our favorite wall crawler. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t been spoiled by the internet before you read it, the big reveal near the end of the issue comes as a shock and makes you go back and re-read the rest of the issue seeing it in a different light. How&amp;rsquo;s Dan Slott going to write himself out of this one? Or does he really have to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Marvel NOW! side, we have a few new series launching this week. The one I liked most was Waid and Yu&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Indestructible Hulk #1&lt;/strong&gt;, which brings us a Bruce Banner with a new approach to life with the Hulk and of course Yu&amp;rsquo;s amazing artwork. Looking forward to where this book takes the gamma giant. &lt;strong&gt;Captain America &lt;/strong&gt;is the other Marvel NOW! #1 this week and it looks a solid set-up to a big sci-fi arc by Rick Remender. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of John Romita Jr&amp;rsquo;s art (in fact I hated him during his AvX issues), but I can tolerate him to see what Remender does with Cap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journey into Mystery #646&lt;/strong&gt; didn&amp;rsquo;t relaunch with a #1 but the series has a new focus - the Asgardian Sif. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how popular it&amp;rsquo;s going to be compared to Gillen&amp;rsquo;s Loki-focused run as Sif is a much more niche character so they&amp;rsquo;re taking a risk here similar to X-Men Legacy focusing on Legion. Still, Kathryn Immonen&amp;rsquo;s initial story arc seems interesting, and there&amp;rsquo;s some great interior art here by Valerio Schiti, check it out:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#87cca54cace555138cedd00e7ce9e114-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-11-24/jim646_hucdf14dc005dace70138efb9929a52675_1558918_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;87cca54cace555138cedd00e7ce9e114-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-11-24/jim646.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Nov 2012 8:07am&#34;&gt;24 Nov 2012 8:07am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other quick Marvel reviews: &lt;strong&gt;Hawkeye #4&lt;/strong&gt; is still pretty good although Javier Pulido is subbing for artist David Aja in this issue; he does a decent job but I think I&amp;rsquo;d still rather have Aja as a regular. &lt;strong&gt;Daredevil #20&lt;/strong&gt; gives us a supervillain that has a better plan for using his powers than just simply robbing banks and getting beat up by supers on a regular basis. &lt;strong&gt;Avengers #34&lt;/strong&gt; is the end of Bendis&amp;rsquo; run and while the End Times story arc wasn&amp;rsquo;t too spectacular, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fan service in this issue with almost every active Avenger making an appearance, an artist jam session in the final pages (my favorite is the Oliver Copiel page!) and a long essay by Bendis at the end detailing how his Avengers/New Avengers run came about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the DC side, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing I&amp;rsquo;m too excited for this week. &lt;strong&gt;Justice League #14&lt;/strong&gt; concludes the two-parter Cheetah story, but this feels a bit too much like filler for me; Geoff Johns need to up his game if Justice League is going to be one of DC&amp;rsquo;s driving comics the way Avengers is for Marvel. &lt;strong&gt;Red Hood and the Outlaws #14&lt;/strong&gt; still has Rocafort doing the cover art, but the interior art is a bit more&amp;hellip;mediocre. I reckon Rocafort can only handle one full-time gig and right now that&amp;rsquo;s Superman, but it&amp;rsquo;s too bad because the art was one of the biggest selling points for RHATO. &lt;strong&gt;Green Lantern New Guardians #14 &lt;/strong&gt;is just an entire issue of Kyle training to become the rainbow lantern or something, let&amp;rsquo;s see if this actually goes somewhere interesting. &lt;strong&gt;Nightwing #14&lt;/strong&gt; has the lead going toe to toe with Lady Shiva, but that&amp;rsquo;s about the only thing exciting here; the rest of the book is set-ups with the Penguin and the Joker and Grayson&amp;rsquo;s amusement park pet project. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit behind on the other DC books, hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have more DC to rave about next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to read at least one book outside the big two each week, and this week it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Clone #1&lt;/strong&gt; which is released by Image Comics and part of Robert Kirkman&amp;rsquo;s Skybound imprint. I&amp;rsquo;m not too familiar with the creative team, it seems the writer is doing his first book. The art isn&amp;rsquo;t anything to write home about, but I guess it&amp;rsquo;s servicable. The story is okay for a first issue and brings to mind the interesting question: what would you do if you found out you were a clone? I may read the next couple of issues to see where it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it for this week and my first post on this blog!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-11-24/asm698_hu48c73b87f2fea98b0c85afc50efffd96_1808518_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2012/11/this-week-in-comics-2012-11-24/jim646_hucdf14dc005dace70138efb9929a52675_1558918_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>