<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>pet peeves on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/pet-peeves/</link>
      <description>Recent content in pet peeves on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/pet-peeves/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Unsolicited real-life interactions
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/unsolicited-real-life-interactions/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/unsolicited-real-life-interactions/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;One of my pet peeves is people coming up to me cold/unsolicited and trying to sell me things:&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/1085428692442992640/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2019-01-16 06:49:01&#34;&gt;16 Jan 2019 6:49am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;People who try to grab your attention or hand you fliers in a mall are the popup ads of real life&lt;/p&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like my tweet above says, it&amp;rsquo;s like advertising spam in real life. I&amp;rsquo;m sure it bothers other people too, but it annoys me a bit disproportionately. I&amp;rsquo;m an introvert by nature so every unexpected interaction &amp;ndash; even just the effort to shake my head at whatever they&amp;rsquo;re handing out &amp;ndash; takes away from my precious pool of socializing points. In addition to those people trying to flag you down as you walk about the mall, I also dislike it when salespeople in a store approach me unsolicited while I&amp;rsquo;m browsing, offering their help. If I need help, I&amp;rsquo;ll ask for it! If I&amp;rsquo;m interested in what your stall has, I&amp;rsquo;ll approach the stall myself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also probably because most of the time if I&amp;rsquo;m walking around in a mall, I have a specific purpose in mind, whether just to get from point A to point B, or to go to X store to buy Y thing, or trying to catch up on daily walking. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll be in a &amp;ldquo;exploring&amp;rdquo; mode, and will probably be more amenable to that kind of thing, but that&amp;rsquo;s a bit rare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand of course that people need to make a living and that stuff needs to be told and there &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; actually people who could use help or might be interested in that condo flier. I wish there was some way to &amp;ldquo;opt out&amp;rdquo; of unsolicited marketing in real life. Maybe some sort of statement shirt I could wear that says &amp;ldquo;Strangers: Don&amp;rsquo;t talk to me unless I talk to you.&amp;rdquo; Since there&amp;rsquo;s not, I just try to avoid contact and maybe have a scary expression on my face. It rarely works though.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>