<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>changelog on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/changelog/</link>
      <description>Recent content in changelog on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/changelog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Site Migration from Hugo to Django
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/site-migration-from-hugo-to-django/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/site-migration-from-hugo-to-django/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;h3 id=&#34;leaving-hugo&#34;&gt;Leaving Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit under two years since &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-migration-to-hugo/&#34;&gt;I migrated the site from Wordpress to Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. As discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/one-year-with-hugo/&#34;&gt;this post one year ago&lt;/a&gt;, I was very happy with the general workflow of managing posts through markdown files in git, but had big problems with the Hugo build time, largely a consequence of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/archive-of-my-own/&#34;&gt;my social media archiving&lt;/a&gt;. At that time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to invest effort into migrating to a different backend, but the problem has only gotten incrementally worse since then, so I decided to take the jump and started working on it last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;migration-goals&#34;&gt;Migration goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main goal is to get rid of the unnecessary build time. I also don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to store all the pre-generated HTML files. It&amp;rsquo;s fine for a small site, but with the large number of posts here, there&amp;rsquo;s a large amount of unnecessary duplication, considering listing pages and such. That means reverting to a system where each page is generated on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to retain the current workflow of managing content via markdown files, so that rules out something like Wordpress. Still, I figured I needed some kind of database for indexing, so that things like listing and archive pages work properly. Given that we would be migrating away from a static site, I fully expect a performance hit, at least initially, but ideally it&amp;rsquo;s not too bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d also like to retain the current content written for Hugo as much as possible. This means the new system will need to be able to parse the custom Hugo shortcodes I&amp;rsquo;d set up for the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also be migrating to a new server which I would be managing myself, which means I would need to set up the deployment myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-django&#34;&gt;Why Django&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I naturally fell back on Django, it&amp;rsquo;s my ORM+backend framework of choice, and the one I&amp;rsquo;m most familiar with. Also, I already had a handful of small Django apps that I needed to migrate to the new server as well, so no matter what I needed to have a Django app on the server anyway. I also had a bunch of Python scripts that were doing already doing support functions for the site like search and ingestion of social media content, so that&amp;rsquo;s something to fold into the new backend as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-bother&#34;&gt;Why Bother?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will fully admit I spent far too much effort unnecessarily doing this, but the realization is that it&amp;rsquo;s actually work I enjoy. This site is primarily a project for myself, and I enjoy the time working on it and learning stuff and improving things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, the effort wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much. There was a lot of code to reuse and migrate, so most of the effort was testing and making sure things worked. Most of the new code was for parsing the markdown files to render the hugo shortcodes as HTML; I basically wrote Django templates for each Hugo shortcode to be supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;changes&#34;&gt;Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The migration was largely done in-place: site design remains mostly the same, post URLs should be more or less retained. I did take the opportunity to make one nontrivial change: Photos are now under &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt; category. I really only had a separate photos category before because in Hugo I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a way to query posts that have attached images. Even with everything under Notes, since I have a database now, I can do silly things like show &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/photos/random&#34;&gt;random photos&lt;/a&gt;. Also, now the notes section is closer to a microblog/tumblr-like feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source for the site content will still be &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roytang/blog&#34;&gt;available publicly via Github&lt;/a&gt;, as it was before. Unfortunately, I am not ready to make public the source for this site, because (a) a lot of it is old code that I reused so it looks terrible; and (b) some level of security by obscurity I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that the site needs to be secure; there isn&amp;rsquo;t actually any critical/important data being stored anywhere. But the fact that a database now exists means I need to follow some kind of security practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The server is now hosted on DigitalOcean. Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/6c2e6b11b260&#34;&gt;my affiliate link&lt;/a&gt;. Since I&amp;rsquo;m on a self-managed VPS now, that means Github webhooks now work, so whenever I push new posts, they take less than a minute to now appear on the site. This is a vast improvement over the old system where it would take anywhere between 30-60 minutes depending on how Travis was feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Travis, I set up a new mirror, Travis now publishes to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net&#34;&gt;https://mirror.roytang.net&lt;/a&gt; once a day, hosted on Netlify. The mirror is still generated using Hugo! I don&amp;rsquo;t know how long I can keep up having the content generate correctly for both builds, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this actually went out much smoother than I thought it would. Took less effort than expected, deployment was a breeze. The listing pages have slightly worse performance, but individual pages are hitting 100 on Pagespeed, so that&amp;rsquo;s mostly fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was just the overview of the site changes. There&amp;rsquo;s still a bunch of technical notes to be written up, so that&amp;rsquo;s stuff for a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time I used a Django backend for my website was &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/12/roytang-net-site-update/&#34;&gt;waaaay back in 2008&lt;/a&gt;, and that didn&amp;rsquo;t last more than a year before I switched to Wordpress. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how long this one holds out!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-10-25
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-25/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-25/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Server migration update: I had encountered some trouble with the Travis-CI -based Hugo build generating this here website last week. Luckily, most of the migration work to the new backend was already done, so I went ahead and switched over the servers. So this site is no longer plain-old deployed HTML, but rather powered by a Django backend. The site should be mostly the same, though I did take the opportunity to move some stuff around. There&amp;rsquo;s probably some bugs floating around, and maybe some secrets even. Probably need a longer blog post writing about the migration itself, though it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too complicated. I also have a bunch of notes about the server setup that I&amp;rsquo;ll also carve into a blog post when I have time. Things should be mostly done for this site, but I have one other domain I have to migrate, and I have scheduled that for the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means that hopefully all my apps/domains will be on the new server after the first week of November. My account at the old webhost is paid until Nov 15th, and I&amp;rsquo;ve already indicated I don&amp;rsquo;t plan to migrate to whatever new system they have, so it&amp;rsquo;s just in time I think. Hoping things go smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming: I did &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1318238520251621377/&#34;&gt;the 120 stars &amp;ldquo;completion&amp;rdquo; for Super Mario Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;, although that&amp;rsquo;s really more like half of actual completion. I put down the Switch for a few days after that to cool down on it for a bit, as I have been playing it a lot since I got it. Still deciding whether to play Odyssey next or try Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming: I haven&amp;rsquo;t played &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal/&#34;&gt;Eternal Card Game&lt;/a&gt; in months, which meant falling behind on the collection as new sets came out and such. But they&amp;rsquo;re running an event right now where all accounts have access to all cards, and there are qualifiers for their worlds event. I figured why not and gave it a shot, running a deck I got from their recent tournaments, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1319794495395745793/&#34;&gt;managed to qualify for the LCQ on my first try&lt;/a&gt;. Eternal has always been a fun game, but the past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve preferred playing on MTG Arena. The timing of this Eternal event was pretty nice, as it came up just after Arena got a patch that severely downgraded the UX, with bugs being reported everywhere and general laggy performance. The Eternal client was, as always, snappy and had no issues. Arena dev team needs to get their act together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still ongoing: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober2020&#34;&gt;the Inktober thing&lt;/a&gt;. Still haven&amp;rsquo;t missed a day! This week is the final stretch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not ongoing: Hacktoberfest. I mentioned before that I was planning to do it, but&amp;hellip; I haven&amp;rsquo;t. Less than a week to go, so doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem likely I can get into it, especially since other things have come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my current webhost finally decided to give me a deadline, the long and short of it is that my new server needs to be ready by December the 9th, giving me a bit under a month to get things in order. I&amp;rsquo;m already in the middle of setting up the new server, so I think I&amp;rsquo;ll be ready by early November anyway. Most of the code to run the new blog is also mostly ready (who knows how many bugs there are though!) I am (re-)learning a lot about server setups though, so hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have quite a few blog posts to write the migration is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching lately: Mostly old NCIS seasons still, and I&amp;rsquo;m just past the halfway point on The Expanse season 4. Slow going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward to November, and am awaiting the outcome of the US presidential elections with morbid interest.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Location, Location, Location
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/location-location-location/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/location-location-location/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A while back I got an export of my Foursquare/Swarm data. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, these were a pair of apps that were used for &amp;ldquo;checking-in&amp;rdquo; to particular locations, with a sort of gamification system where if you checked in at a place often enough, you would earn points and eventually become &amp;ldquo;Mayor&amp;rdquo; of the venue. The idea being that owners of those venues might give some benefits to those who check-in often at those locations (AFAIK, this never really caught on in the Philippines). I wasn&amp;rsquo;t a super active user of Foursquare/Swarm, I had maybe 500ish check-ins from 2010-2017 when I stopped using it. Some people are still using it up to now and have thousands of check-ins, although as far as I can tell it&amp;rsquo;s no longer very popular in the Philippines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I thought having this data would be handy so I put it up as location data on this site. It also gave me an excuse to figure out how to render OpenStreetMap. (The location pages are one of the few pages that have JavaScript on this site.) The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/locations/&#34;&gt;locations page&lt;/a&gt; shows a map of all the visited locations and a listing of the locations grouped by country, and for the Philippines, by city (where available). You can click through to individual locations to see how often I&amp;rsquo;ve checked in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, one of the venues with the most number of check-ins for me is &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/locations/4d27f36c8292236a41e814bb/&#34;&gt;BBQ Chicken&lt;/a&gt;, a now-closed Korean-themed BBQ chicken place in Ortigas near where I used to work. Another one with a lot of check-ins would be &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/locations/4bbbfea5ed7776b032413f51/&#34;&gt;Murphy&amp;rsquo;s in Makati&lt;/a&gt; where we did a lot of quiz nights from 2011-2013. Obviously, the location data isn&amp;rsquo;t complete and doesn&amp;rsquo;t capture all my visits, since I didn&amp;rsquo;t use Foursquare/Swarm that religiously anyway. I&amp;rsquo;m certain I&amp;rsquo;ve eaten at BBQ Chicken more than the 18 times I checked in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-about-privacy&#34;&gt;What about privacy?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually telling the internet where you are all the time might seem a bit anathema to the more privacy-conscious modern world, but I do like having a history of where I&amp;rsquo;ve been. I even have location tracking enabled on my phone via Google Maps so that I can have a timeline of where I am on a day-by-day basis. I&amp;rsquo;ve used it more than once to answer queries like &amp;ldquo;do you know if we went to &lt;place&gt; in &lt;month&gt; of last year?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;When did you last go to &lt;store&gt; ?&amp;rdquo; Obviously it&amp;rsquo;s not for everyone and I fully understand the privacy ramifications of Google having all my location data and feeding the mightly global surveillance capitalism machine, but for me right now it&amp;rsquo;s an acceptable tradeoff. As for the foursquare data, I was using foursquare back when I was less privacy-conscious that I am now, so I my attitude is like, that particular dataset has been out in the world for years, I can&amp;rsquo;t put the toothpaste back in the bottle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, I did scrub some old check-ins from this data (and the corresponding data on Swarm and on Twitter if it was cross-posted)) that was a bit too close to home. I know this data potentially allows bad guys or assassins or whatnot to figure out where I live, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d at least make it a tiny bit more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-now&#34;&gt;What now?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just a neat little thing that probably only I will care about, as it lets me see some of the places I&amp;rsquo;ve been to. And I probably won&amp;rsquo;t be using 4sq/Swarm again, so the dataset probably won&amp;rsquo;t be growing. That being said, I do want to add some future features like grouping the check-ins according to trips, so I can see all the particular places where I went to on particular trips. Many of my trips are missing data though; for example, my only check-in in France was in the airport, and not at any of the touristy places we went to. I may try to supplement this data with selected extracts from my Google Maps location history (hopefully it&amp;rsquo;s easy to figure out!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also don&amp;rsquo;t know where to put the locations page in the menus lol. I&amp;rsquo;ll figure it out sooner or later!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Redesign
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/redesign/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/redesign/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;During recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/weeknotes&#34;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a site redesign. The planned redesign had three objectives, more or less:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rework the navigation links so that new pages like the blogroll etc were more easily accessible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the homepage less messy and highlight blog posts more. The previous &amp;ldquo;stream of everything&amp;rdquo; home page mixed the blog posts in with everything else like the notes, and photos and links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General redesign to improve the layout etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had already done most of #1 and #2 (easy), but during the past few days, I found it difficult to decide on a direction for #3. (This is what happens when you set a vague goal.) It didn&amp;rsquo;t help that I found myself browsing Tumblr themes in the early mornings after recently &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/tumblr-cloudflare/&#34;&gt;having to debug Tumblr stuff&lt;/a&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself especially good at web design, but I do enjoy browsing themes, whether it&amp;rsquo;s Wordpress or Tumblr or Hugo themes. This is the reason why even when I was using Wordpress, I would be switching themes way too often. I&amp;rsquo;m not one of those guys who can be happy running the same Blogspot template for ten years. Given all of that I don&amp;rsquo;t know if the redesign would ever finish if I insisted on a general redesign. So, I&amp;rsquo;m deploying #1 and #2 first, and maybe worry about the other stuff in the future. So: more incremental, less big, drastic change, I find that always works out better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do get some general changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sidebar added for the navigation links, replacing the previous hero section at the top of the pages. The sidebar ploops to the bottom on lower display widths. Main links still up top.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tightening up the spacing in the header&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Menus and Home page summary lists externalized to JSON data files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably some kinks to work out here and there since I decided to cut the cord on the redesign abruptly, but should be nothing we can&amp;rsquo;t fix as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is tradition for &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/changelog&#34;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt; posts, I&amp;rsquo;m attaching a screenshot of the new design here. And I just discovered right now that the latest Firefox has built-in functionality for taking a screenshot of the whole page. No more need for Fireshot!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/redesign/screenshot_hu3dc9b57bd765a9d1e536f8f432b62c36_1091848_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-01-12
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/weeknotes-2020-01-12/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/weeknotes-2020-01-12/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking for a while about doing regular weeknotes. This is a type of post I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in some blogs where they recap the things that&amp;rsquo;ve happened to them during the past week. I&amp;rsquo;ve actually been doing these privately for a while, and now I&amp;rsquo;m going to try making them public. I think the advantages are obvious in terms of (a) having notes to recall what you were doing over a certain time period; and (b) guaranteeing regular writing output on the blog. One disadvantage over the private weeknotes is that in private I can usually include some more personal items (usually family visits and concerns, stuff like that), that aren&amp;rsquo;t part of what I usually make public. I may end up having both public weeknotes and private weeknotes? We&amp;rsquo;ll see. Another concern is for a lot of the examples of weeknotes I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, they usually write about work-related concerns/issues. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been inclined to be too specific about work-related concerns in public, mostly out of respect for my employers who usually don&amp;rsquo;t expect me to write openly for internal matters. In reality, I expect my weeknotes to lean less towards technical things, and more towards hobby stuff, movies and tv shows watched, and so on. Again, we&amp;rsquo;ll probably figure this out as we go along. Let&amp;rsquo;s get on with it then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was asked to give a presentation about a certain blockchain platform, mostly on the strength of me being a technical consultant on a previous blockchain project for a previous client. Two things were notable: (a) the audience was composed entirely of Chinese investors, mostly nontechnical people, so I had to have a translator, and I felt like most things I said went over their head, and it was weird being the only one in the room who didn&amp;rsquo;t understand what was going on when they did the Q&amp;amp;A in Chinese; I could tell that the Q&amp;amp;A wasn&amp;rsquo;t technical, and some of it was asking about my background; and (b) For some reason after the speech, the audience members all wanted to take photos with me, in groups, like a celebrity! It all felt a bit surreal. My contact who set up this talk said that happened with the previous project too, they always want to get pictures taken with the technical guy. I now consider this my first public speaking gig, which makes for an interesting story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I did my regular backup of my data from third-party services (mostly social media), some notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook has a decent data export tool, but one thing they don&amp;rsquo;t include is an export of photos I&amp;rsquo;m tagged in, which I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to keep if their service goes kaput or I get suspended or such. I had to use a Chrome extension (and I&amp;rsquo;m a Firefox user!) to export those pictures. The export isn&amp;rsquo;t in a format I&amp;rsquo;m too happy with, but I can worry about that later, maybe even modify the extension for my own preferences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s export was the largest as usualy, clocking in at around 38GB total, in 2GB chunks. (There was one whole chunk that was just &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vf1JUqYd0ZA&#34;&gt;one Youtube video&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Google, I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to taper off my reliance on them to &amp;ldquo;reduce my global surveillance capitalism footprint&amp;rdquo;, as I said to a friend. So this week I started a &amp;ldquo;great GMail exodus&amp;rdquo; to move my third-party services to another email instead of using my GMail account. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the GMail as my primary since &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/09/377902329975930880/&#34;&gt;Yahoo Mail became terrible&lt;/a&gt;, so this has been a bit of a daunting task, involving updating dozens of accounts on various services. (It&amp;rsquo;s scary how many don&amp;rsquo;t even have email confirmation.). I suspect this will take the better part of the year, and even then I&amp;rsquo;d have to be using both old and new emails heavily in parallel to make sure I don&amp;rsquo;t miss any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weeknotes also provide an avenue to log some recent website changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of my regular blog readers (are there more than one?) complained about my paragraphs not being justified so I added in &lt;code&gt;text-align: justify&lt;/code&gt; in the CSS. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it looks better though? I don&amp;rsquo;t think this is something bloggers usually do, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be accused to not be listening to my readership (no matter how small), so we&amp;rsquo;ll give it a try, and I&amp;rsquo;ll roll it back if/when I get annoyed with it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;general revamp of the pages under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; section. This includes a stats section. I love stats! As with everything on the site, this is an ongoing renovation. I&amp;rsquo;m generally thinking of adding more &amp;ldquo;static&amp;rdquo; pages to complement the &amp;ldquo;sequential&amp;rdquo; nature of the blog, since some things don&amp;rsquo;t align well with that model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I added &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/feed.json&#34;&gt;JSON feed&lt;/a&gt; support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I imported &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/miiverse&#34;&gt;entries from Nintendo&amp;rsquo;s now-defunct MiiVerse service&lt;/a&gt;. A lot of these are just random stamp images my niece posted, but whatever. Maybe someday I&amp;rsquo;ll run out of content from third-party services to import into this site, but not today!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A while back I got thinking about mortality again, and for some reason I decided that if something happened to me, I want this website to outlive me, so I set up on offsite mirror over on &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.github.io/&#34;&gt;roytang.github.io&lt;/a&gt;, in case I ever just forget to pay for the domain/hosting or something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After discussing &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/my-top-tens-of-the-2010s/&#34;&gt;my top tens of the 2010s&lt;/a&gt; with friends last week, I realized I missed so many good movies over the past decade. I am planning on watching one movie per day this year, for a total of 366 movies. New movies, not any I&amp;rsquo;ve seen before. This effort hasn&amp;rsquo;t been going too well, as I&amp;rsquo;m only up to 4 movies so far, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem insurmountable. I&amp;rsquo;ll put up a list somewhere when I feel like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same friends also recommended I watch Kim&amp;rsquo;s Convenience, a sitcom about an Korean immigrant family in the US. I finished all 3 seasons on Netflix already, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. The great thing about sitcoms is that they&amp;rsquo;re easy to binge since you can usually watch them while doing something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This coming week I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://magic.wizards.com/en/products/TherosBeyondDeath&#34;&gt;new MTG set&lt;/a&gt; dropping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrowverse Crisis on Infinite Earths finale!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like there&amp;rsquo;s some other new release/event this week I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to that I&amp;rsquo;m forgetting about. Law of surprise!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for now. I actually managed to write more than I expected!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Indieweb Updates and Thoughts
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/indieweb/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/indieweb/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/move-fast-break-things/&#34;&gt;mentioned before&lt;/a&gt; that I was looking into indieweb stuff. There&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/&#34;&gt;whole wiki of information&lt;/a&gt; about it if you&amp;rsquo;re into that sort of thing, but also &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jvt.me/posts/2019/10/20/indieweb-talk/&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s a recent post&lt;/a&gt; which kind of serves as an overview. I have some comments on the content of this post, more on that &lt;a href=&#34;#later&#34;&gt;later&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indieweb things I&amp;rsquo;ve already implemented on this site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have a personal domain (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/02/welcome-to-roytang-net/&#34;&gt;since 2006&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://microformats.io/&#34;&gt;microformats&lt;/a&gt; (h-card and h-feeds and h-entrys), though I would have to be using some sort of microformats reader to make sure everything there is hunky-dory (no concrete plans for this yet)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;webmention support, via &lt;a href=&#34;https://webmention.io/&#34;&gt;webmention.io&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, I&amp;rsquo;m not actually interacting with anyone else on the indieweb yet, so this is mostly experimental and untested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/POSSE&#34;&gt;POSSE&lt;/a&gt; (partially): blog posts are syndicated to Twitter and Mastodon, but I&amp;rsquo;m also still posting content on those platforms (and to Instagram)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;owning my content: (almost) all posts I make to other social media channels now get backfed into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/archive-of-my-own/&#34;&gt;archive on this site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things I hope to be able to implement (no timetable):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;POSSE (full) - currently for notes and photos I still mostly post using Twitter and Instagram because their native posting features are more convenient (especially on mobile) compared to my current workflow of &amp;ldquo;push a markdown file to git&amp;rdquo;. This is largely contingent on me implementing the next item:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A web interface for posting to the site. A web interface should be sufficient convenient for mobile use. Optionally using the next item:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Micropub. I&amp;rsquo;m still iffy whether I really need the protocol. It could be handy in certain situations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also been &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.technology/@roytang/102954512082445097&#34;&gt;digging into ActivityPub&lt;/a&gt; lately. My hope is to eventually have this site itself serve as an ActivityPub server, such that one would be able to follow me on Mastodon via something like &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:roy@roytang.net&#34;&gt;roy@roytang.net&lt;/a&gt;. Similar to how &lt;a href=&#34;https://aaronparecki.com/aaronpk&#34;&gt;Aaron Parecki has done it&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve already done some exploratory work on this but it might be a ways off (low priority I guess.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archive Mastodon posts into this site (this is kinda ironic for some reason)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatic sending out of webmentions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&#34;later&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Anyway, back to the post I linked above. My main criticism for the indieweb movement at the moment is that I don&amp;rsquo;t see a path to mass adoption, especially for the purposes of moving people away from silos like Facebook. Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s not really one of the goals. My main issue is with two of the principles outlined in the post above (read the post again for more details):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Make What You Need / Scratch Your Itch&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Use What You Make / Dogfood&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing about these concepts is that there is a lot of work involved and there are significant barriers to entry for getting involved. I mean, most people aren&amp;rsquo;t going to (won&amp;rsquo;t be able to) bother with the first step (getting your own domain), much more be able to &amp;ldquo;make what you need&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s ok for people like me who are comfortable with the highly technical and have a bunch of free time, but for the average person it seems unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can imagine there might be created a service that supports most of the Indieweb features and can easily be adopted by the mass market, although that has a lot of its own challenges as well, and it&amp;rsquo;s kind of like replacing one kind of silo with another? At least it would be a more open silo I guess? I think &lt;a href=&#34;https://micro.blog/&#34;&gt;micro.blog&lt;/a&gt; already supports the indieweb stuff, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet looked too closely into that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still moving forward with the indieweb stuff, and I am hopeful that it manages to coalesce into something that can challenge the way the modern internet works, but that may be a long way off. As far as I can tell, adoption is not yet very widespread, and AFAICT the main people driving the effort with their &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/events/2019-11-13-homebrew-website-club&#34;&gt;Homebrew Website Clubs&lt;/a&gt; are in Western countries. It&amp;rsquo;s even possible that I&amp;rsquo;m the first in the Philippines looking into this Indieweb stuff. :)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/removed-webfont/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 23:18:49 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/removed-webfont/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;FontAwesome has been fun and all, but in the interest of reducing load time and external dependencies, I removed the FA dependency on this blog and switched to SVG icons instead. Icons are from &lt;a href=&#34;http://svgicons.sparkk.fr/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, specifically the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dribbble.com/shots/1934932-77-Essential-Icons-Free-Download&#34;&gt;set by Bryn Taylor&lt;/a&gt; and the Special Social Icon Set #9. Not all the icons carried over, especially some of the social ones (Mastodon, etc). Workarounds had to be made. Hopefully nothing breaks!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/switch-stream-to-frontend/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/switch-stream-to-frontend/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I made a 3AM decision to switch over the site&amp;rsquo;s front page to show what was previously under &amp;ldquo;Stream&amp;rdquo; and now the &amp;ldquo;Posts&amp;rdquo; section is listed in the menu as &amp;ldquo;Blog&amp;rdquo;. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if I like this better. Also, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/index.xml&#34;&gt;root RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; now includes everything from &amp;ldquo;Stream&amp;rdquo; as well. IDK how many people were following this site via an RSS reader (I would like it if you guys told me!), but for those of you who do: surprise, you are in for a firehose! If you only want the longer-form traditional blog posts, an &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/post/index.xml&#34;&gt;RSS feed for that is still available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also moved the fanfics from before into a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/fiction&#34;&gt;new &amp;ldquo;Fiction&amp;rdquo; section&lt;/a&gt;. I had previously tried moving them under posts but it felt weird that the archive said I had posts from before 2002 since technically the blog hadn&amp;rsquo;t existed yet. So that this section isn&amp;rsquo;t made up entirely of old fanfiction, I also put up a short story I had written a couple of years ago. I probably have some more fiction hidden somewhere. If not, I&amp;rsquo;ll make some!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smaller site updates like this will probably just be under &amp;ldquo;Notes&amp;rdquo; in the future, instead of full-length blog posts. All changes can still be followed using the changelog tag.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>An Archive of My Own
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/archive-of-my-own/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/archive-of-my-own/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A post about making a guy &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zachleat.com/web/own-my-tweets/&#34;&gt;making an archive of his twitter data&lt;/a&gt; made the rounds lately, so I figured I should make my own post about my ongoing efforts in this regard. I mentioned in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/ephemeral-social-media/&#34;&gt;earlier post&lt;/a&gt; that I like being able to use social media to dig through my own history. But as the first link above says, these social media sites can go away since nothing lasts forever. In the spirit of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/own_your_data&#34;&gt;Indieweb principle to own your data&lt;/a&gt;, for the past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on archiving most of my social media content on my own site. I also intend to cut down on my social media accounts and activities, and having a backup of all the data on my own site helps with that effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requirements and considerations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted my content from external sites to appear on this site, not necessarily as a post. I would create new content types as necessary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy: I would only import content that I considered okay for public consumption. Actually almost all of my social media accounts are fully public, except for Facebook, where I restrict access because I use it to post pictures of family. More on this when I talk about importing from facebook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comments and reactions: Ideally I would be able to preserve comments and reactions to my content as well (tweet replies/likes, fb comments/reacts, quora comments, etc), but that kind of runs afoul of the privacy requirement, since technically those commenters did not consent to me publishing their comments on my own site. I decided to be more conservative with this regard. Also it would have required a massive effort, since most of the backup data exports did not include third party comments. Only selected comments from certain sources are included in this site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syndication links: As much as possible, I wanted to retain links to where an entry originally existed. Many of my older entries have been cross-posted across different social media platforms, so they will have multiple syndication links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another question is if I were to import content from Twitter, Facebook, etc, how would they appear on the blog? Would they be imported as posts and it will all be one giant mess, etc? I decided to maintain my traditional blog posts as the primary focus of the site, and the content from social media would largely be confined to some new sections (these are meant to map to &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/posts#Types_of_Posts&#34;&gt;Indiweb post types&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes/&#34;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt;: microblog-like status updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/photos/&#34;&gt;photos&lt;/a&gt;: photos, sketches, screenshots, and definitely memes. Basically anything with an image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/links/&#34;&gt;links&lt;/a&gt;: links and bookmarks shared from various places&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/replies/&#34;&gt;replies&lt;/a&gt;: replies to content on other sites. This is mostly just twitter replies at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/reposts/&#34;&gt;reposts&lt;/a&gt;: reposts/shares of content on other sites. This would include twitter retweets and tumblr reblogs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also wanted two types of home page: one is the more traditional homepage listing only the most recent posts, while another would be a firehose of all posts+the above content, currently &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/stream/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t (yet) figure out how to paginate this page with Hugo, as the pagination support is limited to the homepage and listing pages and not to custom pages. Maybe someday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, I wrote a hodgepodge of different python scripts to import data from various social media sources into this hugo blog. It has been a huge effort, and frankly the sort of thing I only expect someone as insane as me would do. The scripts are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roytang/blog/tree/master/utils/importers&#34;&gt;available on this blog&amp;rsquo;s own repo&lt;/a&gt;, but they are not portable at all and highly specific to my use cases and require certain temp files I keep around on my local filesystem that are unavailable in the repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some technical challenges I encountered:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link rot. As much as possible I wanted to preserve the intent of the original items. This meant following and resolving link shorteners so that the original URL would be preserved in the archive here (instead of say, the t.co URL twitter uses or bit.ly that twitter used to use). But those shorteners didn&amp;rsquo;t always resolve to the same URL as they did before. Some sites have changed their structure so that the original URLs are no longer available and they just redirect to their homepage, etc. Some sites like imgur deleted old images from when they were starting out (they no longer delete any images as of now), so their links would resolve to something like &amp;ldquo;imgur.com/removed&amp;rdquo;. Some URL shortener services are no longer around (like ping.fm), so for those entries crossposted using ping.fm, the contexts are forever lost. Some reposts What is archived here now represents a &amp;ldquo;best effort&amp;rdquo; at trying to reconstruct the original content as it was.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Permalink scheme. Given the link rot issue above, I needed to make sure I chose a reasonable permalink solution for the new content types, since I would want to avoid changing the permalinks in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deduplication. Since I had a lost of content cross-posted across different social media sites, I had to do some amount of duplicate detection. i.e. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want the same content to be posted under two separate entries, one from twitter and one from tumblr. This involved some rudimentary matching based on content and date posted. The matching was challenging since the date posted wouldn&amp;rsquo;t always be consistent across platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hugo performance and limitations. With all this data imported, the number of content pages shot up from around 1000+ to roughly 15,000+, pushing the Hugo static generation to its limits. Generation time shot up from &amp;lt; 10 seconds to &amp;lt; 2 minutes. For a while, it was even reaching as long as 5-10 minutes, forcing me to do some template optimization to keep the performance reasonable. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how much further I could optimize my templates; I tried switching to some other themes to see if they fared any better with this amount of content, but the generation times were generally in the same ballpark. Perhaps I will revisit this again in the future. I&amp;rsquo;m also starting to miss some features of dynamic sites, like the ability to create custom queries, something like &amp;ldquo;list all replies tagged #mtg&amp;rdquo;, which are proving difficult if not impossible to do with Hugo. There&amp;rsquo;s also that limitation on the homepage pagination I mentioned earlier. I do still like having the entire site be statically generated, perhaps in the future I will explore my options for more versatile lists and searches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll also discuss each import source a bit, and the particular challenges each one posed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/quora&#34;&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;: I had already been planning to stop using Quora since I spoke about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/quora/&#34;&gt;in a previous post&lt;/a&gt;. Since Quora has no concept of exporting a backup of your data, importing my Quora posts involved a little bit of JS console sorcery and a little bit of web scraping as well. I imported each answer I had as a post on this site. After this import, I expect to no longer be using Quora. I&amp;rsquo;ve also unsubscribed to all their summary emails. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad, there&amp;rsquo;s often some interesting content there, but more and more it feels like Experts Exchange.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/goodreads&#34;&gt;Goodreads&lt;/a&gt;: For a while I used to use Goodreads to track my reading and post book reviews. Although Goodreads did provide a data export, it was kind of barebones, and importing required a lot of manual work. Luckily, there weren&amp;rsquo;t that many entries to import. I imported all of the book reviews into this blog as posts, and any further reading I can just talk about on the blog directly. I do not expect to be using Goodreads again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/plurk&#34;&gt;Plurk&lt;/a&gt;: Plurk is an old social media site that I used around 2010-2011, mainly because a certain friend group of mine was very active there. Looks like everyone stopped using it around 2012-2013ish though. Their data export was very good, and I was able to import all the plurk content (most of it crossposted from twitter via ping.fm) and I included the plurk comments too. (Those comments were all public anyway.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/tumblr&#34;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;ve had the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net&#34;&gt;tumblr blog&lt;/a&gt; since 2008! I enjoyed using the Tumblr account mainly because there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of memes there and there&amp;rsquo;s content I follow, but I realized a while back I could just follow them via RSS. All my tumblr blog content has been imported either as notes, links or reposts. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect to be using tumblr much moving forward, although I still like it as a syndication endpoint; I may eventually re-enable syndicating my content to tumblr. I also have a second (currently inactive) &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;tumblr blog focused on comics&lt;/a&gt; that I have not yet imported, as the content there is primarily comic book covers and excerpts. I may do so in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/pocket&#34;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt;: I use Pocket mainly for link sharing, so all the stuff from Pocket gets imported as links. I still intend to use Pocket moving forward, and there is an active script that imports new links I&amp;rsquo;ve shared.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/ireadcomicbooks&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;: My blog was previously running on Wordpress before migrating to Hugo of course, so no importing of the original posts was necessary. I did, however run a short-lived comic-book focused Wordpress blog (a predecessor of the Tumblr) from 2012-2013 on the ireadcomicbooks.com domain (no longer active). I imported the posts and comments from that old blog into this one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/youtube&#34;&gt;Youtube&lt;/a&gt;: I imported a selection of videos uploaded to my Youtube channel, mostly game videos and sketch timelapses. That account also had some videos uploaded by my niece, but those are her content not mine, so they were not migrated into this blog. I expect to still occasionally use Youtube for video uploads (since it&amp;rsquo;s very convenient for general internet sharing), but very sporadically so I don&amp;rsquo;t have any automated migration set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/flickr&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;: I don&amp;rsquo;t use this much anymore, but I did have a few photos uploaded here, so they are now merged into this site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/roywantsmeat&#34;&gt;roywantsmeat&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/royondjango&#34;&gt;royondjango&lt;/a&gt;: roywantsmeat was the blogger incarnation of this blog. &lt;a href=&#34;http://roywantsmeat.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still up!&lt;/a&gt;. I mostly did this import to get syndication links since presumably all the posts from that blog had been imported to Wordpress and then to this blog. But that was not true! Apparently there were some missed posts, so some content gets to live again. &lt;a href=&#34;http://royondjango.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Roy on Django&lt;/a&gt; was a second short-lived blogger blog I had, focused on Python/Django, now the posts from their contain syndication links back to blogger as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;: Twitter is still my most actively used social media channel, so a whole bunch of tweets have been imported as notes, replies and reposts. A lot of the past content was cross-posted from other sites though. I have a script that actively imports new tweets as notes, replies and reposts. I also had a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roy_mtg/&#34;&gt;second twitter account dedicated to mtg&lt;/a&gt;, tweets from that account have been imported as well. If you reply or like a tweet that points to one of my blog posts, they are also automatically imported as comments to that post. (This is not retroactive.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/instagram&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;: Instagram was challenging to import. This was actually the first import I attempted. There was a data export, but the problem was it did not provide any way to derive the original instagram URL. For a while I researched on how the instagram slug was derived, thinking maybe it could be algorithmically determined. Eventually I gave up and looked for other means. Since there is currently no public API access, I had to use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/realsirjoe/instagram-scraper&#34;&gt;scraper library&lt;/a&gt; to get the instagram URLs then used some matching algorithm to combine them with the data export, and voila I was able to import all the entries as photos. I still plan on using Instagram moving forward (primarily for sharing sketches), but currently there is no viable way to automatically import newer entries. I tried using &lt;a href=&#34;https://ownyourgram.com/&#34;&gt;OwnYourGram&lt;/a&gt; for a while, but that &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/aaronpk/OwnYourGram/issues/85&#34;&gt;ran into some trouble&lt;/a&gt; after some Instagram changes broke their scraping algorithm, so we&amp;rsquo;re stuck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/facebook&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;: Ah, this was the most challenging import of all. The challenges were (a) first, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want all of my FB content to be publicly available on this blog, so there was a lot of manual vetting/review that had to be done; and (b) Facebook&amp;rsquo;s data export (both JSON and HTML formats) did not make it easy to get the URL for any given post, I had to do some scraping to get the correct URLs; and (c) the data export wasn&amp;rsquo;t even very complete; among other things it didn&amp;rsquo;t include visibility settings (would have helped with the manual review) or the application used to post (would have helped with deduplication); and (d) the data model wasn&amp;rsquo;t straightforward, since a given URL could refer to a post, a photo album, a single photo, etc and some items wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even have a single canonical URL, multiple URLs could be pointing to the same thing. I actually ended up rewriting the import script completely (you can see in github I have an fb2.py) after I&amp;rsquo;d already imported some posts. While I will still be probably using FB moving forward (for sharing family photos mostly), I do not intend to import any further Facebook posts into this blog. (Any content which could be public will be cross-posted elsewhere instead)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you weren&amp;rsquo;t keeping track, moving forward I generally still intend to still be regularly using Twitter, Instagram, and sometimes Youtube, and somehow syndicate that content back to this site. In some future update, I will probably attempt to reverse this. That is, change it so that I post on this site, and the content automatically gets syndicated to Twitter/Instagram/etc as appropriate. This is &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/POSSE&#34;&gt;Indieweb POSSE principle&lt;/a&gt;, which makes a lot of sense, assuming I am able to overcome the technological hurdles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, the archive is available for your perusal.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Perpetually under renovation
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/perpetually-under-renovation/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/perpetually-under-renovation/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Perhaps unsurprisingly, I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying tinkering with the site layout at the moment. I give up on expecting a &amp;ldquo;stable version&amp;rdquo; of the site anytime soon and readers can expect incremental updates unannounced going forward. This site is now perpetually under renovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current layout image (this image is recursive):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#f2e3e1914830725e83fb5b79348d924f-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/perpetually-under-renovation/roytangnet_201908_hu40fd9de379095d1e23664d7bd47e40cd_106634_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;f2e3e1914830725e83fb5b79348d924f-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/perpetually-under-renovation/roytangnet_201908.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;14 Aug 2019 12:00am&#34;&gt;14 Aug 2019 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone called me out for not using a dark theme, so now here we are with a garish gray and green and orange theme, you&amp;rsquo;re welcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generally moving around of content and UI and adding of navigation items and such&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comment system revamp! I&amp;rsquo;ve removed Disqus, since that was a bit of a loading problem. Comments are now saved in the repo as static files; it took me a bit to figure that out, &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io/t/static-comment-for-hugo/1944/17?u=roytang&#34;&gt;I described my approach on the Hugo forums&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately this means that for now there is no way to comment directly on posts. I will be adding that back later, hopefully in a matter of days. Having the comments be a separate post type means you can now &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/comment/&#34;&gt;browse them directly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Webmentions! I set up &lt;a href=&#34;https://webmentions.io&#34;&gt;webmentions.io&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://brid.gy&#34;&gt;brid.gy&lt;/a&gt; so this site now accepts webmentions. Currently only Twitter webmentions are enabled on brid.gy (see the samples in the screenshots above).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search! Previously the search widget was only sending you to a &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;site:roytang.net&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; search on DuckDuckGo. I changed it to perform indexing on the server, via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://whoosh.readthedocs.io/en/latest/intro.html&#34;&gt;Python Whoosh library&lt;/a&gt;. Then any search request is sent via Javascript to a Flask server I have running, which queries the index and returns the relevant results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also joined a webring! So 1990s lol. It&amp;rsquo;s a webring for Indieweb people, I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying browsing other people&amp;rsquo;s sites. Brings me back to the early 2000s internet. Links are in the footer!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are almost certainly broken things still around, but I wanted to push the initial changes for now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/perpetually-under-renovation/roytangnet_201908_hu40fd9de379095d1e23664d7bd47e40cd_106634_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Move Fast, Break Things
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/move-fast-break-things/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 03:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/move-fast-break-things/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;As is my wont, I&amp;rsquo;m almost never satisfied with a website&amp;rsquo;s layout, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been tinkering with this blog&amp;rsquo;s layout on the backend. To make a long story short, I decided to start working on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roytang/hugo-theme-exhale&#34;&gt;a Hugo theme&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s still largely a work in progress, as there&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of things I wanted to implement. But it was good enough to replace the old one so I went ahead and deployed it, so maybe some bugs here and there on some pages. And I&amp;rsquo;m still tinkering, so probably some minor/major changes as we go along in the next few weeks. Or months. Who knows how long it will take? There were some conflicts with the old theme and the new theme which meant I had to modify some of my main blog files to support the new theme and the amount of uncommitted changes I had was getting unwieldy, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d just &amp;ldquo;move fast and break things&amp;rdquo;, as it were. (I realize that a more sensible programmer would have done the theme work on a branch to avoid this nonsense, but we are who we are.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s a snapshot of the current appearance, for posterity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#9dfb00422375d1175176707e45e020c3-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/move-fast-break-things/hugo-theme-2019_hu680d47cc17b9018b3f8d4884f72b4e8d_70639_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;9dfb00422375d1175176707e45e020c3-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/move-fast-break-things/hugo-theme-2019.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;30 Jul 2019 3:06am&#34;&gt;30 Jul 2019 3:06am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also back-updated some of the older posts where I updated the site theme/layout with a tag &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/changelog/&#34;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt;, so that I can reference them when I update the about page sometime soonish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from my general finnickiness about wanting a new theme approximately every 17 days, another reason I wanted to change the layout was I wanted to try out CSS grid layouting, as it seemed neat and boy I wish this existed back in the IE6 days. Would&amp;rsquo;ve made things a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also kind of gone down the rabbit hole of &lt;a href=&#34;https://indieweb.org/&#34;&gt;Indieweb&lt;/a&gt; stuff. The core message of having your own website that contains all your content appeals to me and also aligns with some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about implementing like importing all of my off-site content into this site as a central repository. Those things are yet to come but with the theme change I&amp;rsquo;ve also started looking into stuff like microformats (should be supported as of now), webmentions, POSSE, and so on. Might be a while before those other things get done though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I full technical breakdown of the theme features belongs in &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roytang/hugo-theme-exhale/blob/master/README.md&#34;&gt;the theme&amp;rsquo;s README&lt;/a&gt; and probably in a separate colophon post later on, but we&amp;rsquo;re not there yet and we&amp;rsquo;ll get there when we get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, enjoy if you will my obsession with the color green.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/move-fast-break-things/hugo-theme-2019_hu680d47cc17b9018b3f8d4884f72b4e8d_70639_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Site Migration from Wordpress to Hugo
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-migration-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 03:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-migration-from-wordpress-to-hugo/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;h3 id=&#34;leaving-wordpress&#34;&gt;Leaving Wordpress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Wordpress for this blog since circa 2006 I believe, but as I mentioned in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2018/10/django-blog-application/&#34;&gt;earlier blog post&lt;/a&gt; that I was not 100% happy with using Wordpress for this blog. I have a few issues with Wordpress, none of them a major dealbreaker, but collectively enough to make me consider something else:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.org/gutenberg/&#34;&gt;Gutenberg editor&lt;/a&gt; set to become standard in 5.0 was in my experience, very clunky and kinda annoying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the code structure of Wordpress is very deep and complex, sometimes making it difficult for me to make changes I want. I can usually figure it out, but it feels like things are unnecessarily more complicated than they need to be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordpress&amp;rsquo;s rich plugin library is a plus, but it also means having to figure out how to have multiple plugins interoperate with each other. An easy example is that I was using a queueing plugin that didn&amp;rsquo;t work great with the Gutenberg editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordpress requires a lot of maintenance, including needing to regularly update plugins for security purposes, and comment moderation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;static-site-generators&#34;&gt;Static Site Generators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, while reading across some blogs over the past few months, I had ran into the idea of static site generators, which intrigued me as a Wordpress alternative. SSGs offered several advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I could compose my posts offline and using any &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2018/11/my-history-in-text-editors/&#34;&gt;text editor&lt;/a&gt; I wanted, using a simple format like Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page load performance is better since Apache will simply serve up the static files, no processing or database hits of any kind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static sites don&amp;rsquo;t require security updates of any sort - there&amp;rsquo;s no database or admin backend to be hacked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy backups. In WP I was using a custom plugin for backups. With an SSG, I can simply have the raw content stored in Github, then the static content &amp;ldquo;built&amp;rdquo; from there. The content always exists in at least three places - the actual site, Github, and my local computer I use for posting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-hugo&#34;&gt;Why Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s quite a lot of static site generators available right now actually. The most popular one seems to be &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; which is ruby-based. I first decided to try &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.getpelican.com/&#34;&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; because I preferred Python over Ruby. However, it turned out problematic on my Windows machine, I encountered some interoperability problems with pandoc for the WP migration. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have too many dependencies and issues with dependencies because I would later want to deploy the generator itself to my hosting on Webfaction for automated deployments, so I wanted the setup to be as easy as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I stumbled upon &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, which offered two main advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the MSP was performance. I wanted to migrate over the entire history of the blog, which was almost 900 posts at this point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no external dependencies - all I needed was to download the hugo executable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading up and testing a bit of Hugo, I had a fit of &amp;ldquo;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep, I&amp;rsquo;ll just go ahead and do the site migration now&amp;rdquo; that I would later regret since it completely screwed up my sleep schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wordpress-export&#34;&gt;Wordpress Export&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SchumacherFM/wordpress-to-hugo-exporter&#34;&gt;Wordpress to Hugo plugin&lt;/a&gt; to convert my Wordpress content for Hugo. Many posts had reported problems with this plugin, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any issues with its basic operation. I had a two problems with it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when exporting existing Wordpress comments, it didn&amp;rsquo;t include the commenter&amp;rsquo;s URL, which I felt I should include&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all the posts were exported into a single &lt;code&gt;posts&lt;/code&gt; folder. While this didn&amp;rsquo;t create any permalinks issues due to each post having the &lt;code&gt;url&lt;/code&gt; attribute in the frontmatter, it made the entire folder look very unorganized since I had almost 900+ posts. I preferred that the posts be grouped by year and month, matching the &lt;code&gt;/yyyy/mm/slug/&lt;/code&gt; format of the permalink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I had the source for the plugin, it was straightforward to fix both issues myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting the export from the plugin, I still had a bit of post-processing and cleaning up of the posts to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one thing, all the single-quotes in the exported posts seem to have been converted to HTML entities for that smart quote thing, so I had to reverse that. Luckily, it was a simple find and replace across text files. The format for embedding posts such as Twitter, Youtube, etc was different as well, I had to correct those files one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cleaning-up-the-taxonomies&#34;&gt;Cleaning up the taxonomies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had always wanted to clean up the categories in the blog, but I never got around to it with Wordpress because I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like figuring out the SQL I would have needed to do it. (I&amp;rsquo;ve never liked Wordpress&amp;rsquo;s table structure.). With Hugo, all I had to do was update a bunch of text files, which I was much more comfortable with. This involved simply importing a Python library to &lt;a href=&#34;https://elbauldelprogramador.com/en/how-to-parse-frontmatter-with-python/&#34;&gt;parse frontmatter&lt;/a&gt;, and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roytang/blog/blob/master/utils/clean_categories.py&#34;&gt;script&lt;/a&gt; to do the conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;generating-the-archive-pages&#34;&gt;Generating the archive pages&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo doesn&amp;rsquo;t have built-in support for archive pages, so I had to create them myself. I followed the setup described in &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.atj.me/2017/10/generate-yearly-and-monthly-archive-pages-with-hugo-sections/&#34;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; and wrote a python &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roytang/blog/blob/master/utils/create-archives.py&#34;&gt;script&lt;/a&gt; to generate the individual year/month archive pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bigger problem was the archive listing (the page that would link to the individual archive pages). Because the blog has been running for 15 years, there&amp;rsquo;s a whole lot, so I preferred to organize them in a table like this:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#bc6ffeab2c0e919e9cfc9edeb1084a63-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-migration-from-wordpress-to-hugo/archive-grid_hue4b4a2fae19a0f11e617fa08057e7adf_25861_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;bc6ffeab2c0e919e9cfc9edeb1084a63-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-migration-from-wordpress-to-hugo/archive-grid.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;14 Nov 2018 3:06am&#34;&gt;14 Nov 2018 3:06am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a decent Wordpress plugin that did this for me exactly, so I wrote my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roytang/wp_grid_archive/&#34;&gt;own plugin&lt;/a&gt; for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Hugo, I struggled with this a while and was close to figure out when I finally got the approach right. CHeck &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/archives&#34;&gt;my archives page&lt;/a&gt; for how it turned out. The upside is I got to become a bit familiar with &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/,&#34;&gt;https://golang.org/,&lt;/a&gt; particularly the way content is parsed and processed in Hugo templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;custom-shortcodes&#34;&gt;Custom shortcodes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had some custom-formatted code in Wordpress that wasn&amp;rsquo;t exported properly by the plugin. This required I create some new shortcodes for Hugo and replace the corresponding calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoilers. I had only recently added this WP plugin, and only one post was using it so this was straightforward. I created the spoiler shortcode and added some simple jQuery-backed code to toggle the spoiler content. I would have preferred doing this with vanilla JS so as to avoid the jQuery dependency, but I decided to put off learning how to do that for another day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/categories/magic-the-gathering&#34;&gt;MTG&lt;/a&gt; Decklists and card links. Individual card links wasn&amp;rsquo;t an issue - I just generated an anchor as needed, and had to clean up some of the pages that used it. The decklist part was more challenging, as it involved a lot of text parsing. I managed to get it working to a point where the decklists were formatted correctly, but individual cards weren&amp;rsquo;t linked, before deciding to give up. The main issue is I haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out how to parse each line to split the card count and the card name, if the card count exists, i.e. &amp;ldquo;3 Lightning Bolt&amp;rdquo;. I considered just adding JavaScript to format the contents post-load, but the current behavior will do for now. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll even revisit the Hugo parsing issue later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;redirects&#34;&gt;Redirects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to minimize changes in the URLs of older content, so the permalinks for the old posts were kept in place. Another issue was the RSS feed, generated at &lt;code&gt;/index.xml&lt;/code&gt; by Hugo, which I wanted at &lt;code&gt;/feed/&lt;/code&gt; so that feed readers don&amp;rsquo;t need to be updated. A simple redirect in .htaccess was enough to get this done. I&amp;rsquo;m not much good at regexes, so I had to reference another &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.philipphauer.de/moving-wordpress-hugo/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; for this one. The RSS feeds for categories/tags has changed, I think that&amp;rsquo;s fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;automatic-deployment&#34;&gt;Automatic Deployment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I referenced another &lt;a href=&#34;https://gomakethings.com/automating-the-deployment-of-your-static-site-with-hugo-and-github/&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; for setting up automatic deployment. The main difference was my host was Webfaction while his was Digital Ocean, which did cause me a bit of trouble when I was trying to set up a Github webhook to automatically deploy on every push. It turns out Webfaction doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow me to set an env variable in .htaccess to be read by the PHP script (as was in the blog post linked above). It took me a while to figure out this was the issue, so I just gave up on the Github webhook for now and just set a cron job to periodically pull and redeploy the site. I needed the cron job anyway, if I wanted to support future publishing and possibly some form of queueing later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments&#34;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legacy comments from WP are imported directly into the markdown of each page. Future comments are now handled using Disqus. I already had a Disqus account before, I forgot why I stopped using it. That being said, outsourcing the comments makes a lot of sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we lose the site search for now. There are some workarounds, including Google SiteSearch (I believe it has ads) or building a JSON index and searching on the client-side (seems impractical given the number of posts). I believe I&amp;rsquo;m the only one using the site search anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ll revisit this at another time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the markdown engine allows raw HTML in the content, but if you have any line breaks in between, your structure breaks, so that required some cleanup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;theme&#34;&gt;Theme&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not much of a CSS/site design guy, I&amp;rsquo;m more a &amp;ldquo;find an existing theme and tweak it to your liking&amp;rdquo; guy, so I browsed Hugo&amp;rsquo;s available themes for a while and settled on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/enten/hyde-y&#34;&gt;Hyde-Y&lt;/a&gt;, which I proceeded to modify a bit, adding a picture to the sidebar and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s simple and clean and straightforward, nothing too fancy. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll revisit the theme later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For posterity&amp;rsquo;s sake, a screenshot of the new layout/theme:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#860b271077bc60f75bc0ebe8bec296c9-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-migration-from-wordpress-to-hugo/blog-hugo-2018_hu3440e873d4f85fe686378e137aba5439_180987_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;860b271077bc60f75bc0ebe8bec296c9-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-migration-from-wordpress-to-hugo/blog-hugo-2018.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;14 Nov 2018 3:06am&#34;&gt;14 Nov 2018 3:06am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of it, it turned out a bit more effort than I expected. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be cleaning up the exported older posts every so often because I&amp;rsquo;m OC that well. The theming/templating turned out to be a bit more complicated than I expected, but I think it was easier to manage than Wordpress. The last time I tried to use a custom blog engine, I got tired of maintaining and upating it so I switched back to Wordpress, hopefully that doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen here. Not having to maintain a web interface is a pretty good indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the effort, the great thing is that I did learn a few things, so at the minimum it&amp;rsquo;s already a win:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a bit of GoLang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to create Github Webhooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more .htaccess stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;usage of pathlib.Path in Python3 (no more os.glob for me!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-migration-from-wordpress-to-hugo/archive-grid_hue4b4a2fae19a0f11e617fa08057e7adf_25861_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-migration-from-wordpress-to-hugo/blog-hugo-2018_hu3440e873d4f85fe686378e137aba5439_180987_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-theme/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-theme/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;What the site theme looked like before the migration from Wordpress to Hugo&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-theme/screenshot_hu579ee3572063a95226f926712982fe59_84305_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>roytang.net site update
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/12/roytang-net-site-update/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 16:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/12/roytang-net-site-update/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Previously I hosted two separate WordPress blogs on roytang.net, the old one I&amp;rsquo;ve had since forever, and a separate one that discussed only magic related articles. It was a bit bothersome to have two WordPress installs though. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve migrated to a Django backend, I decided to merge the blogs back into one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blog now has the following sections/categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://roytang.net/magic/&#34;&gt;Magic the Gathering&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; for posts related to MTG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://roytang.net/dev/&#34;&gt;Software Development&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; for posts related to Software Development (hopefully I can write more about this topic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://roytang.net/games/&#34;&gt;Gaming&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; originally I didn&amp;rsquo;t have this category, but looking at previous contents of the blog and my delicious links, this is one of the things I write about the most, so I made it a separate category&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://roytang.net/blog/&#34;&gt;Weblog&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; everything else I can think of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each category has a separate RSS feed you can subscribe to &amp;ndash; so that if you&amp;rsquo;re only interested in MTG posts you can subscribe to the MTG category feed, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s also a master feed that syndicates all the posts in all categories, available at the top of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;flockcredit&#34; style=&#34;text-align: right; color: #ccc; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;
  Blogged with the &lt;a style=&#34;color: #999; font-weight: bold;&#34; title=&#34;Flock Browser&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flock.com/blogged-with-flock&#34; target=&#34;_new&#34;&gt;Flock Browser&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;!-- technorati tags begin --&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size: 10px; text-align: right;&#34;&gt;
  Tags: &lt;a href=&#34;http://technorati.com/tag/meta&#34; rel=&#34;tag&#34;&gt;meta&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- technorati tags end --&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Transition to 2009
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/12/transition-to-2009/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2008 15:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/12/transition-to-2009/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Well, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit early. But if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this then I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully migrated the roytang.net website to a new host. See you after the jump!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merry Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New WordPress Theme -- Thematic
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/07/new-wordpress-theme-thematic/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2008 04:55:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/07/new-wordpress-theme-thematic/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Changed to&lt;a href=&#34;http://themeshaper.com/thematic/&#34;&gt;Thematic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- [if gte mso 9]&gt;&lt;xml&gt; &lt;w:LatentStyles DefLockedState=&#34;false&#34; DefUnhideWhenUsed=&#34;true&#34; DefSemiHidden=&#34;true&#34; DefQFormat=&#34;false&#34; DefPriority=&#34;99&#34; LatentStyleCount=&#34;267&#34;&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;0&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;Normal&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;9&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;heading 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;9&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;heading 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;9&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;heading 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;9&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;heading 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;9&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;heading 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;9&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;heading 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;9&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;heading 7&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;9&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;heading 8&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;9&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;heading 9&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;39&#34; Name=&#34;toc 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;39&#34; Name=&#34;toc 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;39&#34; Name=&#34;toc 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;39&#34; Name=&#34;toc 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;39&#34; Name=&#34;toc 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;39&#34; Name=&#34;toc 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;39&#34; Name=&#34;toc 7&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;39&#34; Name=&#34;toc 8&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;39&#34; Name=&#34;toc 9&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;35&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;caption&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;10&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;Title&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;1&#34; Name=&#34;Default Paragraph Font&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;11&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;Subtitle&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;22&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;Strong&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;20&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;Emphasis&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;59&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Table Grid&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Placeholder Text&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;1&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;No Spacing&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;60&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Shading&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;61&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light List&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;62&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Grid&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;63&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;64&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;65&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;66&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;67&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;68&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;69&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;70&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Dark List&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;71&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Shading&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;72&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful List&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;73&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Grid&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;60&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Shading Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;61&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light List Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;62&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Grid Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;63&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 1 Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;64&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 2 Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;65&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 1 Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Revision&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;34&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;List Paragraph&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;29&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;Quote&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;30&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;Intense Quote&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;66&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 2 Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;67&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 1 Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;68&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 2 Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;69&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 3 Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;70&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Dark List Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;71&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Shading Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;72&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful List Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;73&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Grid Accent 1&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;60&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Shading Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;61&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light List Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;62&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Grid Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;63&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 1 Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;64&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 2 Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;65&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 1 Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;66&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 2 Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;67&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 1 Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;68&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 2 Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;69&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 3 Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;70&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Dark List Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;71&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Shading Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;72&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful List Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;73&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Grid Accent 2&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;60&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Shading Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;61&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light List Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;62&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Grid Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;63&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 1 Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;64&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 2 Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;65&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 1 Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;66&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 2 Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;67&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 1 Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;68&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 2 Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;69&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 3 Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;70&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Dark List Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;71&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Shading Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;72&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful List Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;73&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Grid Accent 3&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;60&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Shading Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;61&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light List Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;62&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Grid Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;63&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 1 Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;64&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 2 Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;65&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 1 Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;66&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 2 Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;67&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 1 Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;68&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 2 Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;69&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 3 Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;70&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Dark List Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;71&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Shading Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;72&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful List Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;73&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Grid Accent 4&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;60&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Shading Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;61&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light List Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;62&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Grid Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;63&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 1 Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;64&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 2 Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;65&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 1 Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;66&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 2 Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;67&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 1 Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;68&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 2 Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;69&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 3 Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;70&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Dark List Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;71&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Shading Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;72&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful List Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;73&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Grid Accent 5&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;60&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Shading Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;61&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light List Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;62&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Light Grid Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;63&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 1 Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;64&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Shading 2 Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;65&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 1 Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;66&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium List 2 Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;67&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 1 Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;68&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 2 Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;69&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Medium Grid 3 Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;70&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Dark List Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;71&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Shading Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;72&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful List Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;73&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; Name=&#34;Colorful Grid Accent 6&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;19&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;Subtle Emphasis&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;21&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;Intense Emphasis&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;31&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;Subtle Reference&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;32&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;Intense Reference&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;33&#34; SemiHidden=&#34;false&#34; UnhideWhenUsed=&#34;false&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;Book Title&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;37&#34; Name=&#34;Bibliography&#34; /&gt;  &lt;w:LsdException Locked=&#34;false&#34; Priority=&#34;39&#34; QFormat=&#34;true&#34; Name=&#34;TOC Heading&#34; /&gt; &lt;/w:LatentStyles&gt; &lt;/xml&gt;&lt;![endif]--&gt;
&lt;!-- [if gte mso 10]&gt;





 &lt;![endif]--&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color: #3366ff;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; zroytang&lt;/span&gt;: yung current na wordpress theme ko parang ang crowded&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #ff0000;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; (Anonymous)&lt;/span&gt;: baka it&#39;s the font...  or less ugn spacing&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #3366ff;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; zroytang&lt;/span&gt;: papagalitan mo ko pag pinalitan ko e&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #3366ff;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; zroytang&lt;/span&gt;: haha&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #ff0000;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; (Anonymous)&lt;/span&gt;: haha hindi naman a&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #ff0000;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; (Anonymous)&lt;/span&gt;: sabihin ko lang na you&#39;re fickle like a girl&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #ff0000;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; (Anonymous)&lt;/span&gt;: haha&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #3366ff;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; zroytang&lt;/span&gt;: tsk!&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #ff0000;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; (Anonymous)&lt;/span&gt;: it&#39;s nice to be female.. if magpaka-fickle ako, i&#39;ve an excuse&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #ff0000;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; (Anonymous)&lt;/span&gt;: if magsungit ako, i&#39;ve an excuse din&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #ff0000;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; (Anonymous)&lt;/span&gt;: if i get irrational, meron ulit excuse&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #3366ff;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; zroytang&lt;/span&gt;: and you can make sexist remarks freely!&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #ff0000;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; (Anonymous)&lt;/span&gt;: yup&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #ff0000;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; (Anonymous)&lt;/span&gt;: cool nuh&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #ff0000;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; (Anonymous)&lt;/span&gt;: and pag ako sabihan ng sexist remarks...  i can freely take offense din bigla&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color: #3366ff;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; zroytang&lt;/span&gt;: women :p
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;flockcredit&#34; style=&#34;text-align: right; color: #ccc; font-size: x-small;&#34;&gt;
  Blogged with the&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a style=&#34;color: #999; font-weight: bold;&#34; title=&#34;Flock Browser&#34; href=&#34;http://www.flock.com/blogged-with-flock&#34; target=&#34;_new&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Flock Browser&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Bear With Me
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/05/bear-with-me/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2008 16:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/05/bear-with-me/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Someday I will find a WordPress theme that I could bear with for more than 2-4 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or I will make one.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Modified MistyLook
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/01/modified-mistylook/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2007 22:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/01/modified-mistylook/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The original is&lt;a href=&#34;http://wpthemes.info/misty-look/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Yeah, I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the header image so I removed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m tired of moving themes around, so I&amp;rsquo;ll settle on this for a while. Simple and clean. I&amp;rsquo;ll just fuss around with the plugins later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m also changing the categories around. There should be a plugin to search posts and assign multiple posts to new categories at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My vacation time is almost up&amp;hellip; I still have too many things to watch&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Welcome to roytang.net
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/02/welcome-to-roytang-net/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2006 18:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/02/welcome-to-roytang-net/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Yeah, so I was bored and went ahead and got a domain name. ^_^I&amp;rsquo;m wondering if I&amp;rsquo;ve wasted money, but webhosting is really cheap nowadays anyway. Thanks to the nice folks at&lt;a href=&#34;http://pinoywebhosting.com&#34; title=&#34;pinoywebhosting.com&#34;&gt;pinoywebhosting.com&lt;/a&gt;for their quick service!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I hope you&amp;rsquo;ll pardon me if some parts of the site aren&amp;rsquo;t fully up-and-running (the about page is still the wordpress template for one), I haven&amp;rsquo;t had much time to play around with wordpress yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farewell, Blogger. You have served me well, but it&amp;rsquo;s time to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Done so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imported posts and comments from Blogger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go through every single post and assign categories (that took a while =p)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated many links / images in the posts to point to this server (There should be no more broken links&amp;hellip; I hope)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still gonna play around with WordPress, PHP and MySQL a bit later, see if I can get something nice going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers ^_^&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Moving Things Around A Bit
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/12/moving-things-around-a-bit/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2005 16:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/12/moving-things-around-a-bit/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I was getting a bit bored with the place, so I spruced it up a bit, switched some colors, moved stuff around. You know, just to pretend something&amp;rsquo;s happening. And to showcase my sorely lacking UI design skills. :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screenshot captured for posterity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#4e12ef5f0f5f68a43cfc33c92fc3b8dc-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/12/moving-things-around-a-bit/layout20051211_hu5dbe1a024c29619e3242eb7b97fb3198_141552_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;4e12ef5f0f5f68a43cfc33c92fc3b8dc-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/12/moving-things-around-a-bit/layout20051211.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;11 Dec 2005 4:08pm&#34;&gt;11 Dec 2005 4:08pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also cleaned up some of the global files that were being accessed from fateback, since I will eventually drop that host completely. Right now, the external files used by this site are hsoted on my geocities account (which I should also organize/clean up in some way.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the curious, this site is maintained in several layers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the blogger template &amp;ndash; ideally, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to change this too often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an external javascript file &amp;ndash; ideally, if I want to do small changes to the site, I&amp;rsquo;ll just modify this and use DHTML to do it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an external stylesheet &amp;ndash; ideally, if I want to make changes to layout, I just adjust this one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while back I was also wondering if it was viable to use XSL transformations for a blogger blog&amp;hellip; but I&amp;rsquo;m too lazy to try to figure it out now.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/12/moving-things-around-a-bit/layout20051211_hu5dbe1a024c29619e3242eb7b97fb3198_141552_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>