<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>tv on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/tv/</link>
      <description>Recent content in tv on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 13:59:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/tv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/wandavision/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 13:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/wandavision/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;#WandaVision spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall, I really liked it, and I think they did well with the one-episode-per-week format. The show certainly would not have been this hyped if it all came in one drop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Really difficult to not spoil. If you have somehow avoid being spoiled by the internet until it all dropped, good for you!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A very emotional story of Wanda dealing with the aftermath of Infinity War/Endgame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;good usage of the sitcom tropes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fantastic performance by Elisabeth Olsen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lots of fan service for comic book fans to dig into. Maybe too much even; don&amp;rsquo;t overthink or overhype it to yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;most of the episodes have something like 5-6 minutes of credits. Episodes 7 and 8 have a mid-credits scene. Episode 9 has both mid and post credits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to Falcon and Winter Soldier next!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Perfect Strangers
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/perfect-strangers/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 12:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/perfect-strangers/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;While digging through some old stuff recently I found a copy of the late 80s/early 90s US sitcom &lt;em&gt;Perfect Strangers&lt;/em&gt; and decided to binge through all 8 seasons of it (really more like 6 and a half, since seasons 1 and 8 were an abridged 6 episodes each).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up watching this series, on live tv even, before we had cable or Netflix or anything like that. During the binge-watch I remember a good number of the episodes from the first season all the way up to the end of season 7, which implies almost all of it was broadcast on local TV, kind of a rarity I think? Of course, given the primitive nature of broadcast tv (i.e. needing to be there at the time the show is on), a lot of the episodes were new to me too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, the premise of the show is simple: Balki Bartokomous, an immigrant from the small Mediterannean island-nation of Mypos, comes to America to pursue his dreams and somehow convinces his distant-cousin-that-he-has-never-seen-before Larry Appleton, who himself has just moved to the windy city of Chicago, to take him in and let him live with him. The series largely relies on the contrast between the two leads for its humor: Balki is portrayed as a naive, unassuming foreigner, honest and open and prone to hugging strangers, while &amp;ldquo;Cousin Larry&amp;rdquo; sees himself as this street-wise, savvy guardian who must introduce Balki to the realities of modern American life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, Larry is actually terribly neurotic, deceptive and manipulative, even to his closest friends. He often gives Balki advice that gets both of them into trouble; he typically overreacts to the situations they find themselves in; he is prone to being taken over by his greed when the opportunity presents itself. And when he does get the two of them into some trouble, his first instinct to try to lie and cheat his way out of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember enjoying the series a lot when I was young, and have a fond recollection especially of the theme song, which I consider one of the best TV show theme songs of all time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8vbnLYROCj8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, the show isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly deep, as can easily be seen during a binge-watch. Most episodes will have a plot along the lines of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balki says/does something naive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larry says &amp;ldquo;Balki, Balki, Balki&amp;rdquo; and gives some advice or some other action that gets them into trouble&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hijinks ensue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optionally: Larry overreacts to the hijinks and lies or something getting them into even deeper trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d say Larry is at fault maybe 80% of the time, though he does have some good/redeeming moments too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show&amp;rsquo;s overall story arc follow the two cousins as they grow both in terms of careers and relationships; they start out working as clerks in a used furniture store, and later move on to jobs at the presitigious Chicago Chronicle. Along the way, they form relationships with a pair of flight attendants (with decidedely 80s hair) who live in their apartment building, whom they eventually marry and have kids with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last part is a bit problematic for me, as I feel like Larry&amp;rsquo;s fiancee and eventual wife Jennifer deserves much better; Larry constantly lies to her and have put their group in mortal danger more than once. Although, once they are married, Jennifer does exhibit many of the same neurotic behaviors Larry has, including trying to lie her way out of bad situations, so maybe they deserved each other. I would guess this character arc is largely a product of its time, a time when society (and thus TV shows) focused on values such as building a career and a stable relationship and eventually a family (as opposed to the Friends era, where the characters would often be jumping across relationships constantly.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I did learn during this binge-watch run (and the accompanying Wikipedia check) is that &lt;em&gt;Perfect Strangers&lt;/em&gt; spawned a spin-off show, &lt;em&gt;Family Matters&lt;/em&gt;, that went on to be one of the longest-running shows on US tv. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that show ever aired on local tv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, it was a reasonable binge-watch, good enough for watching in the background while doing other stuff. My nostalgia is not damaged, I never assumed it was a deep show. The best part remains the theme song, which I still somehow feel compelled to sing out loud with each episode.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately, Feb 2020 - Not Much Apparently
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/watching-lately/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/watching-lately/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;2020 Movies&lt;/a&gt; update: 7 movies watched in Feb. Probably the best movie I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this month was &lt;strong&gt;Knives Out&lt;/strong&gt;. (&lt;strong&gt;Jojo Rabbit&lt;/strong&gt; close second.) The goal of 200 movies for the year is getting farther!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for TV, I think most of my watching time was spent rewatching &lt;strong&gt;Rick and Morty&lt;/strong&gt; for quiz purposes lol. Well, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/criminal-minds/&#34;&gt;Criminal Minds&lt;/a&gt; ended, so there&amp;rsquo;s that. Arrowverse has been meh, though I did enjoy &lt;strong&gt;Supergirl&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;s 100th episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hm, I guess I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually watched a lot of stuff in the past month. There&amp;rsquo;s a ton of stuff that I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to watch but haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to: The Expanse, Star Trek Picard, new season of Jack Ryan, Birds of Prey/Harley Quinn, and so on. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if things get better next month maybe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus, since this entry was kinda short: Here&amp;rsquo;s three movies I started watching but didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to finish:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/strong&gt;. It started off with like 20 minutes of some monkeys shouting at each other and a mysterious black box and I kind of lost interest. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that kind of thing was fine in 1968 when the movie came out and the people whose butts were already in the theatre were like &amp;ldquo;this is strange, but we&amp;rsquo;re already here, so we might as well sit through it&amp;rdquo;, but it&amp;rsquo;s 2020, I kind of need something to hold my internet-broken attention span more easily. It&amp;rsquo;s also one of the most renowned and highly-praised movies of all time, so I&amp;rsquo;m probably losing something here. Will try to resume it sometime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Conjuring&lt;/strong&gt;. We have a horror-movie themed quiz category coming up so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d watch a horror movie. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve voluntarily done so since having been mentally scarred by &lt;strong&gt;The Gate (1987)&lt;/strong&gt; as a kid. I picked The Conjuring, it was first on Netflix&amp;rsquo;s list of horror movies. I sat through the appropriately-creepy intro, then one of my quiz teammates told me he&amp;rsquo;d already unwillingly seen it before and couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep for a week after, and I was like &amp;ldquo;You just gave me an excuse not to watch it.&amp;rdquo; so I stopped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carrie (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to give up on horror movies just yet, so I picked another title from Netflix. I chose this one because it had Hit-Girl. It started out with typical teenage bullying stuff before she manifested her mutant powers and after that I kept thinking they needed to contact Professor Xavier, and couldn&amp;rsquo;t take it seriously after that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Criminal Minds
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/criminal-minds/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/criminal-minds/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;In 2010 I took a short work hiatus which meant I was often home for most of the day. Back then Netflix wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a thing, so I would often have local cable TV playing in the background of whatever I was doing. And it was because of this that I started regularly watching police procedurals. They&amp;rsquo;re not the cleverest or most highbrow of shows, but they&amp;rsquo;re more like a guilty pleasure. Most of it was &lt;strong&gt;NCIS&lt;/strong&gt;, which the cable channels loved showing for some reason, but during that time I also picked up other shows like the quirky &lt;strong&gt;Bones&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Castle&lt;/strong&gt;. But the best of these shows by far, was &lt;strong&gt;Criminal Minds&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Criminal Minds, or CM for short (as the very small group of office friends who also enjoyed the show called it), was a cut above the rest for a number of reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a strong, solid cast of interesting characters, my favorite was the &amp;ldquo;nerd&amp;rdquo; of the group, Dr. Spencer Reid, played by Matthew Gray Gubler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s serious stuff, the crimes in investigation almost always being of the serial killer variety; the other shows often sprinkled some light comedic moments across the episodes, such a thing was rare in CM, especially considering the subject matter they dealt with. What other shows would have as special season finale villains would be mere unsubs-of-the-week for the CM team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a focus on behavioral science and profiling in order to catch their unsubs. While I did read somewhere a while back that profiling isn&amp;rsquo;t held in as high regard nor considered as scientifically rigorous as the show makes it out to be, it&amp;rsquo;s still a reasonably good conceit for a TV show, and the framework helps the show establish villains with understandable motivations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;these shows tended to have the trope of having an &amp;ldquo;ridiculously powerful tech guy&amp;rdquo; providing support for the team. The most egregious of these is NCIS&amp;rsquo; Abby, who is somehow able to do anything with a computer while at the same time being a top of the line forensic scientist. (NCIS is also famous for idiotic tech scenes that work nothing like IRL, such as the famous one where &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u8qgehH3kEQ&#34;&gt;they have 2 people working one keyboard trying to stop a hacker&lt;/a&gt;). The best one is CM&amp;rsquo;s Penelope Garcia; like most such characters she can do basically anything with a computer, but this is a lot more believable than the rest because she is a complete nerd who was access to all the FBI databases. (Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, you definitely still have to suspend your disbelief a lot of times!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, I&amp;rsquo;m writing about this show because their series finale ended this week, after 15 seasons. I started watching this show around the 3rd or 4th seasons (after Mandy Patinkin&amp;rsquo;s Jason Gideon had already left), and never stopped. (I later borrowed some DVDs from one of the office friends to back-watch the first few seasons). The series finale was reasonable, not the best I could have imagined (more on that later), and centered mostly around Reid and Garcia, appropriate since they were the only characters who had managed to stick around from season 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recurring villain for the final season was one carried over from season 14, and was kind of a disappointment. He was kind of hyped up to be a really big threat, the FBI&amp;rsquo;s Most Wanted, but he went out in just the most ridiculous way to somehow justify a spectacle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the perfect idea a while back for how this show would end: it would involve Aaron Hotchner. He was one of the original CM FBI team members and head of the BAU (Behavioral Analysis Unit) from the time Mandy Patinkin left until he was written off the show in 2016 due to the actor Thomas Gibson having an altercation with someone from the crew. Because of the way he left, this suggestion would never have been viable, but I would have wanted Hotch to be the series&amp;rsquo; final unsub, finally breaking down after one last horrible event that forces him to relive all the trauma from all the previous seasons. And he would be the BAU&amp;rsquo;s greatest nemesis - someone who knows how they work and operate, who can counter all their moves and even use their profiling against them. In my head, it would have been glorious. Alas, it was not to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CM is actually the last of the police procedurals I was still watching. Others that I liked because of their quirkiness, such as Castle and Bones, had ended years ago.So it&amp;rsquo;s kind of an end of an era for me, not just the era of Criminal Minds, but the era of watching police procedurals in general. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more stuff to watch now, so I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;d ever pick up such a show again. I did enjoy the show a lot during the course of the last ten years, despite the heavy subject matter, so I look back at it fondly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last time, wheels down.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately, Jan 2020: Arrow, The Good Place, The Witcher, Kim&#39;s Convenience, The Expanse
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/watching-lately/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/watching-lately/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if I should continue this &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately&#34;&gt;watching-lately&lt;/a&gt; series since I already set up a separate page for &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/lists/2020/movies&#34;&gt;listing my 2020 movies watched&lt;/a&gt;. It might have been more consistent to have a list for the 2020 TV shows also? But then again, TV shows are a much different beast, since each show/season is broken into an episode and sometimes you watch them all in one go or sometimes over the span of a few months. So maybe let&amp;rsquo;s keep this going for the while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, movies. From the list for January, I think the best one was Parasite. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any expectations on what this movie was about yet somehow I still feel like it subverted those expectations anyway. I only saw 15 movies in January, which is below rate if I&amp;rsquo;m targetting 200 for the year. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s one of those NYR things that peters out after a month or so. Too early to tell, and besides, that&amp;rsquo;s not an insurmountable deficit. And 200 isn&amp;rsquo;t a hard target either so let&amp;rsquo;s just see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the realm of TV, this kind of explains why my movie-watching trailed off in the second half of the month, since the regular TV series started coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/arrowverse-crisis-on-infinite-earths/&#34;&gt;wrote about the Arrowverse crossover&lt;/a&gt; when the back half aired. This month the last two episodes of Arrow aired. The first one was a backdoor pilot for a new spinoff series, Green Arrow and the Canaries, starring Mia Queen. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what to think about the spinoff or whether I&amp;rsquo;ll even try it out. The whole time travel thing seems so convoluted as a way to bring Mia, E2 Laurel and Dinah together. The second episode was the series finale, basically a retrospective on the entire series. They pulled out all the stops, bringing back supporting characters from all 8 seasons of the show (Except for Malcolm Merlyn, apparently John Barrowman was busy reappearing in a different series), and even surrendering to some long-time fan wishes such as Digg picking up a mysterious green object dropped from space. In spite of all my complaints about the poor writing on this show (and the related ones) through the years, I will admit the finale was pretty good and they stuck the landing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the rest of the Arrowverse, some comments that I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where else I can post, mostly on the post-crisis set up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently in the rebooted universe, there was still a multiverse (since E2 Laurel exists, and doppelgangers showed up in Supergirl), but then the other universes were destroyed in a crisis (probably similar but different than the one we actually watched.) This is totally different from the &amp;ldquo;it became one universe from the very start&amp;rdquo; ending of the original CoIE and took away from the crossover a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was mildly annoyed when Jonn turned out to be able to restore pre-crisis memories. This only makes sense if what he&amp;rsquo;s restoring are part of his own memories, but not events he never knew about, otherwise, where did those pre-crisis memories come from? This annoyance was exacerbated by the GAatC backdoor pilot introducing a &amp;ldquo;device made by Cisco that replicates&amp;rdquo; Jonn&amp;rsquo;s powers so now anyone can restore pre-crisis memories, even from people Jonn has never met like future JJ. And in the Arrow finale, it seemed like everyone at the funeral was aware of the previous universe, did Jonn reset them too?? Seemed wholly unnecessary, but I suppose then we get difficult to explain things like Tommy wondering why E2 Laurel seems different&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fun fact: at Oliver&amp;rsquo;s funeral, Dinah is from before the GAatC episode (since in that episode she says she vanished after the funeral), Mia is from after that episode, and presumably so is E2 Laurel, although this isn&amp;rsquo;t explicitly specified. Timey-wimey!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Good Place&lt;/strong&gt; is also ending this week. As the time this post goes live, I will not have yet watched the season finale, but I did binge the rest of the seasons leading up to it, so maybe I can share some thoughts anyway. The Good Place was a weird series. It&amp;rsquo;s highly acclaimed and covers a lot of interesting topics philosophically, and puts its cast through a lot of interesting situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main issue with TGP is that I don&amp;rsquo;t find it particularly funny. Not like other Schur-influenced shows such as Brooklyn Nine Nine and Parks and Recreation. The characters can be charming sure and ridiculous sure. But their situations are rarely sitcom funny. I think part of it is that the situations they face are always so dire. I mean, their consequences somehow ramped up from eternal torture and damnation to the erasure of earth and all of humanity during the course of the series. Not very light-hearted topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another part of it might be the severe &lt;a href=&#34;https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/Flanderization&#34;&gt;Flanderization&lt;/a&gt; of the most of the characters. Typically this is a process that happens over the lifetime of a show, but with TGP, the characters&amp;rsquo; most annoying traits are highly focused on from the start: Eleanor is an asshole, Jason is an idiot, Tahani is a name-dropping socialite and Chidi is an anxious, undecisive philosopher. Eleanor and Chidi get a bit of character growth through the series (more Eleanor than Chidi), but Jason and Tahani are kind of still the same people by the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I like the show, but more for the questions it raises about how the afterlife could possibly work, rather than for pure comedic value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some friends somehow convinced me to watch &lt;strong&gt;Kim&amp;rsquo;s Convenience&lt;/strong&gt; (it was on NF). I have no regrets. It&amp;rsquo;s a smart, funny show about a Korean immigrant family in Canada. There were 3 seasons to binge on NF and it was very easy to side-watch since it&amp;rsquo;s a sitcom. The best character is the father of the family, a first-generation Korean immigrant who owns a convenience store (hence the show title). My only complaint is that it&amp;rsquo;s challenging my suspension of disbelief that the first generation immigrants still speak in English when among themselves, but as a friend said, it was probably for the sake of avoiding subtitles. Also, I wanted to see what the future Shang-chi actor looked like. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it kind of weird that he&amp;rsquo;s Chinese but he&amp;rsquo;s playing a Korean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A shorter series I saw on Netflix was &lt;strong&gt;The Witcher&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty good, and I much prefer Henry Cavill as Geralt in this show rather than as Superman. (Although he looks nothing like W3 Geralt). I wish I had seen this series before playing the games, as it sets up a lot of the character back stories that I kind of just accepted in the games. Looking forward to future seasons!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I managed to watch the first half of The Expanse season 3. It takes me a whole to catch up with this show because each episode is heavy and a lot of things are always happening, so it always needs my full attention. It&amp;rsquo;s so good, and it&amp;rsquo;s not like those shows where you never get any answers, things actually get resolved at a reasonable pace. One and a half more seasons to catch up on!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Arrowverse: Crisis on Infinite Earths
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/arrowverse-crisis-on-infinite-earths/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/arrowverse-crisis-on-infinite-earths/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So the back half of the CW Arrowverse&amp;rsquo;s epic Crisis on Infinite Earth&amp;rsquo;s crossover finally aired this week, and I promised more words about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/watching-lately-december-2019/&#34;&gt;the Arrowverse and the crossover last month&lt;/a&gt;, so here we are. Spoilers abound!&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1217311777035366401/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2020-01-15 05:05:18&#34;&gt;15 Jan 2020 5:05am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;#CrisisOnInfiniteEarths spoiler free review: low budget, pacing and writing issues, but idc because all the dc comics fan service kept making me smile&lt;/p&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First the bad: as noted above, writing and pacing and budget issues plague the crossover, but this is typical of the Arrowverse as a whole. TBH sometimes I question why I still follow (most of) the shows. This has been CW&amp;rsquo;s problem with trying to make their superheroes shows more appealing to a mainstream audience, they end putting in a lot of nonsense and drama that often don&amp;rsquo;t make sense or just pad the runtime. It&amp;rsquo;s been a problem since Smallville even. This crossover in particular had a lot of things that felt like they were just there to pad the runtime to make sure we got to have five shows represented by one episode each. I feel like they could have covered what they wanted to cover with just four episodes. The Batwoman episode in particular was pretty weak, and the whole chasing Oliver around the afterlife into purgatory only for him to become the Spectre was pretty weak as well. I loved the Beebo bit in Legends, but that also felt inessential and was there just to pad the time and give the heroes something to do until the Big Bad showed up again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good: All the DC comics fanservice and shoutouts and callbacks and cameos, everything was great and made me smile every time. Personal highlights for me were the &amp;lsquo;89 Batman theme, Kevin Conroy speaking as Batman before appearing as Broken Bruce Wayne, Smallville Clark just yeeting the Kryptonite out of Lex&amp;rsquo;s hands, and of course, surprise Ezta Miller cameo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The execution and adaptation of the Crisis storyline itself is a mixed bag. While understandably they don&amp;rsquo;t have access to the whole multiversal cast of the comic book and had a limited budget, there are still some poorly explained points like why are these seven people the paragons? (Particularly Ryan Choi!). Lex Luthor even showed that the paragons are replaceable - he was not originally the paragon of truth! Couldn&amp;rsquo;t Pariah have sent more people to the Vanishing Point? Still, they did manage to hit the major plot points of CoIE:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;universes dying one by one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;heroes assembled to fight the anti monitor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;harbinger betrayal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;showdown at the dawn of time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;multiverse reborn as a single universe (kind of&amp;hellip; they walked it back at the end!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rewriting of the Arrowverse as a single, shared universe was probably something they wanted to do as soon as Supergirl got adopted by the CW, but I can&amp;rsquo;t help think of what a mess this does to existing storylines. I suppose we&amp;rsquo;ll see when the shows resume, but there are so many questions raised, with Supergirl and Flash status quos being the ones that suffer the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All flaws aside, we have to give it up for the CW Arrowverse for doing something that&amp;rsquo;s never been done on TV before. While technically only a crossover between 5 (maybe 6) shows, it also pulls in references to dozens of comics, shows and movies from the whole history of DC comics. It&amp;rsquo;s something that couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been done by a single show like Smallville or Justice League Unlimited, or a small set of films like the DCEU. Make no mistake, this is an accomplishment of Endgame proportions, even though it didn&amp;rsquo;t have Endgame&amp;rsquo;s budget and writing quality. If you&amp;rsquo;d asked me ten years ago, I would never have imagined that a Crisis on Infinite Earths adaptation is something that I would have seen in live action, small screen or no, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have been proven wrong!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>My Top Tens of the 2010s
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/my-top-tens-of-the-2010s/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/my-top-tens-of-the-2010s/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Apparently I&amp;rsquo;m not done looking back at the 2010s yet. I had some &amp;ldquo;top tens of 2010s&amp;rdquo; discussions with some friends recently, here are my personal lists, each in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-top-ten-movies-of-the-2010s&#34;&gt;My Top Ten Movies of the 2010s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers Endgame (2019).&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m keeping only one slot per franchise, so I had to choose an MCU movies for this. Runner-ups for this slot were &lt;strong&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Captain America Winter Soldier&lt;/strong&gt;, and individually either one of those movies might be around the same or better than Endgame, but Endgame is the culmination of a decade&amp;rsquo;s worth of movies and gave me the most enjoyment as a comic book fan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue One (2016)&lt;/strong&gt;. I really liked &lt;strong&gt;The Force Awakens&lt;/strong&gt; too, but Rogue One is easily the best of the Disney Star Wars era.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interstellar (2014)&lt;/strong&gt;. The top ten discussions led to an extended debate about some of the science in this movie, all in good fun. It requires some suspension of disbelief is needed, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a pretty good sci-fi movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Martian (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;. This one was my favorite sci-fi movie of the decade though, I&amp;rsquo;ll read the book someday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inception (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;. The fact that this movie spawned so many memes and so many debates and discussions was an indication of how good it was.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: Into The Spider-Verse (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;. The MCU was a series of great movies based on comic books, but Spider-Verse was the best movie that really feels like a comic book. (I suppose the comparison is slightly unfair since Spider-Verse has the advantage of being animated!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One Cut of the Dead (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a Japanese film I saw at Eiga-sai. If you can overcome the one-inch barrier of subtitles it&amp;rsquo;s easily one of the funniest movies I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in the past decade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logan (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;. Easily the best of Fox&amp;rsquo;s X-Men films, and among the top echelon of comic book films overall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mad Max Fury Road (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;. This was my first Mad Max film, I really enjoyed the performances and the stunts and the ridiculous vehicle scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Baby Driver (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;. Makes me want to imagine what Edgar Wright&amp;rsquo;s Ant-Man would have been like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-top-ten-tv-shows-of-the-2010s&#34;&gt;My Top Ten TV Shows of the 2010s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parks and Recreation (2009-2015)&lt;/strong&gt;. I know it started before the 2010s, but this might be appropriate anyway since the show didn&amp;rsquo;t really pick up until the third season. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of other notable comedies of its class that I really enjoyed during the last decade, such as &lt;strong&gt;30 Rock&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;, but I tip the hat to PnR because I really like the characters of Ben Wyatt and Ron Swanson and Andy Dwyer. (Apparently I really like all the male main characters except for Tom lol)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brooklyn Nine Nine (2013-)&lt;/strong&gt;. B99 is just my kind of ridiculous, similar to PnR, super quotable, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Young Justice (2010-)&lt;/strong&gt;. Young Justice is the true successor to the excellent JL/JLU of the 00s, with a deep plot full of conspiracy and betrayal, a large cast of characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daredevil (2015-2018)&lt;/strong&gt;. The Netflix shows had great promise, and Daredevil seasons 1 and 3 were among the best of them. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad that they fell to the IP disputes of their time, but who knows maybe we get to revisit them again some time in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Who (2005-)&lt;/strong&gt;. The DW revival started in the 00s, but I only started watching it in 2012, when Matt Smith was already the Eleventh. There have been some weaker seasons and episodes, but overall I enjoyed the general campiness and sci-ifi silliness of the series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black Mirror (2011-)&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m actually still not caught up with the latest season, but I have greatly enjoyed the near-future what-ifs posed by this popular show. (It&amp;rsquo;s too bad we are unlikely to heed its warnings!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breaking Bad (2008-2013)&lt;/strong&gt;. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s generally regarded as one of the best series of all time right? I haven&amp;rsquo;t even bothered watching El Camino because for me the ending of BB was already prefect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Orville (2017-)&lt;/strong&gt;. 2017 was a great year for Star Trek (-like) content, with the more serious &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; and more lighthearted The Orville both debuting. I enjoyed both shows, but the Orville&amp;rsquo;s sci-fi sitcom brought us something a lot more unique.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game of Thrones (2011-2019)&lt;/strong&gt;. Say what you will about the quality of writing (or lack thereof) for the last couple of seasons, but this was a TV series that got people obsessed and following every episode and arguing about spoilers and forming fan theories, book readers or otherwise. It pretty much defined the decade of TV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-top-ten-games-of-the-2010s&#34;&gt;My Top Ten Games of the 2010s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starcraft 2 (2010-2015)(PC)&lt;/strong&gt;. Got all 3 parts on release, and still playing it to this day (mostly coop missions - I don&amp;rsquo;t really have the heart for the stress of ladder matches anymore!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Last of Us (2013)(PS3)&lt;/strong&gt;. There are games where you&amp;rsquo;re saddened that you can&amp;rsquo;t play them again for the first time, and the Last of Us was one of the best of those.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild (2017)(WiiU)&lt;/strong&gt;. The defining Zelda of modern times. I loved the exploratory nature similar to the original NES LoZ and the cel-shaded graphics were fantastic. The sequel may yet convince me to get a Switch!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persona 5 (2017)(PS4)&lt;/strong&gt;. Easily the best JRPG of its era (sorry, Final Fantasy XV!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fallout: New Vegas (2010)(PC)&lt;/strong&gt;. Obsidian&amp;rsquo;s part of the Fallout franchise had much improved writing and questlines over it&amp;rsquo;s predecessor Fallout 3, good enough for multiple run throughs, and I even managed to finish all the DLCs as well!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Elder Scrolls: Skyrim (2011)(PC)&lt;/strong&gt;. I came late to this series with Oblivion in 2008, but it&amp;rsquo;s one of the few RPGs in this decade that I&amp;rsquo;ve replayed and finished multiple times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Witcher 3: The Wild Hunt (2015)(PS4)&lt;/strong&gt;. Easily the best PC RPG of the past decade, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t even played the expansions yet! Runner-up: Divinity Original Sin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultra Street Fighter IV (2014)(PS3)&lt;/strong&gt;. Technically, the base game came out in the 00s, but all the later revisions came out in the 2010s. This game started a fighting game resurgence that&amp;rsquo;s going on to this today. I was never super good at it, but I sure played a lot of hours and bought multiple copies of each version that came out even. The next version, SFV, hasn&amp;rsquo;t been as well received, but the franchise and the fighting game resurgence is still going strong up to now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eternal Card Game (2016)(Multiplat)&lt;/strong&gt;. This one is actually my most played Steam game of all time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sid Meier&amp;rsquo;s Civilization V (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;. Been playing this series since &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/ancient-pc-gaming/&#34;&gt;the olden days&lt;/a&gt;! Civ5 brought a pretty big change to the series with one unit per tile, and at 395 hours it&amp;rsquo;s still currently among my most played games on Steam. (Civ6 is about a hundred hours behind)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: December 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/watching-lately-december-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/watching-lately-december-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Been watching a lot of things this December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally got back on &lt;strong&gt;The Expanse&lt;/strong&gt; after finishing S1 more than a year ago. I only finished S2, but it was already a vast improvement over S1. S1 felt like a lot of meandering around until the characters actually ran into the plot. S2 was stronger, faster-paced, and there&amp;rsquo;s always a lot of things going on in each episode. I really like this series now, looking forward to S3 and S4 when I have the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix-wise, I enjoyed their recently-added &lt;strong&gt;Jeopardy&lt;/strong&gt; series (always a great show to have playing in the background), the new documentary &lt;strong&gt;The Movies That Made Us&lt;/strong&gt; (loved their selection of movies to feature), and the second season of &lt;strong&gt;Final Space&lt;/strong&gt; (a fun sci-fi space romp if ever there was one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of crazy sci-fi, &lt;strong&gt;Rick and Morty&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve caught up with the recently released S4 as well. This series seems a lot more self-aware now, and a lot more unafraid to make fun of tropes and genre conventions. I liked the heist episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broadcast-wise, I enjoyed the front half of the Arrowverse&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Crisis of Infinite Earths&lt;/strong&gt; crossover. It had that same feeling as Avengers Endgame where I knew what was likely to happen based on comic book knowledge, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t think they could do it, but they did it! Whenever discussion of this crossover leaked over to the mainstream TV subreddits/forums, there was a lot of criticism of how it looked so low-budget, but I think any expecations of them being able to provide Avengers-quality costumes and effects on a broadcast TV show budget are unrealistic. The Arrowverse shows certainly have a lot of flaws, but this type of multiversal crossover isn&amp;rsquo;t something that could have been achieved without all the setup of the past eight years (and even beyond, considering older shows like Smallville and 90&amp;rsquo;s Flash), and that&amp;rsquo;s something comparable to what the MCU has built, even at a fraction of the budget. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll have more words for this series and the Arrowverse in general when the back half airs in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend also somehow tricked me into watching &lt;strong&gt;Sky High&lt;/strong&gt;, a rather old and campy and totally predictable superhero-type movie. I did finish it so I guess I enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nieces were over this weekend so I finally got to watch &lt;strong&gt;Toy Story 4&lt;/strong&gt;. I was a bit skeptical that they decided to add another installment when I felt the trilogy was already pretty tight. I have to admit I was surprised with the direction this movie took and the ending it gave, which leaves an opening for future movies in the franchise, though they might already be quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;Star Wars: Rise of Skywalker&lt;/strong&gt; before Christmas, here are &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/star-wars-rise-of-skywalker-spoilers/&#34;&gt;my thoughts on the film and the trilogy&lt;/a&gt;. WHile I wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely happy with it, I did enjoy watching the film and I recognize that it was a good retelling of Star Wars for new/modern fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also rewatched &lt;strong&gt;The Last Jedi&lt;/strong&gt; for the first time about a week later, it was still pretty good, especially that third act. (Casino subquest still felt superfluous). I did come out a bit more disappointed that ROS didn&amp;rsquo;t follow through with some of the themes of TLJ. I can only assume there are a couple of alternate universes out there where both Rian Johnson&amp;rsquo;s direction and JJ Abrams direction came true for the Skywalker saga ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Star Wars, I enjoyed the ending of &lt;strong&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/strong&gt;, although it did have a couple of weaker episodes in the middle that felt like filler (or maybe just there to seed characters for the eventual second season). The final two episodes are pretty good, and we get the payoffs of actualy learning the Mandalorian&amp;rsquo;s history and all. I do find it ridiculous that the Jedi and the Force are still unknown enough that the Mandalorian has never heard of them considering it probably hasn&amp;rsquo;t even been more than 30 years since Palpatine took down the Republic, which had literally an entire council of Jedi as an advisory body to the Senate and featuring prominently in the Clone Wars. Do they not have recorded history? Lol. In any case, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to season 2 whenever it lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THat&amp;rsquo;s it for the decade!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: November 2019: Broly, Justice League, Arrowverse, Mandalorian
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-nov-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-nov-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Nothing in the cinema this month (going to the cinema is expensive!). I did watch a couple of animated movies this month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dragonball Super: Broly. I have some vague recollection of watching the original Broly movie, and I believe this one is much better. DBS Broly is a slightly more nuanced character than just &amp;ldquo;random raging monster&amp;rdquo; from the previous non-canon movie. The animation was okay, you could tell the animators were having fun with some of the battle parts. Also, I watched the English dub, and I just realized Goku&amp;rsquo;s voice is super annoying, so I pity the Americans who had to grow up with that voice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Justice League vs the Fatal Five. I&amp;rsquo;m still a bit behind on the DC animated stuff. I liked this one because I think it handled Jessica Cruz fairly well, and it got me backreading Justice League Odyssey for more Cruz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, since I got a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/new-video-card/&#34;&gt;new video card&lt;/a&gt; and have a second monitor again, side-watching is back on the menu, so I was able to catch up with some of the ongoing series: Modern Family (meh), Simpsons (meh), Rick and Morty (ok so far, only 3 eps in).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caught Season 3 of The Toys That Made Us on Netflix. Not as fun as S2 for me since that one had Transformers, and I only have secondary interest at best in the toylines for S4, but some of the stories here were pretty interesting, like they say that the giant robot from Japanese Spider-Man was the one that inspired sentai robots! What! The TMNT ep was also pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrowverse is still going on (somehow), with their upcoming big-deal Crisis crossover kicking off in mid December. Surprisingly, Arrow itself has been pretty good this season (perhaps because no Felicity? lol), followed by Flash, with Supergirl dead last. I am not fond of Lena&amp;rsquo;s heel turn in Supergirl, I felt like it was a disservice to the character who when introduced was desperate to get out of her brother&amp;rsquo;s shadow. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been watching Batwoman, even though it&amp;rsquo;s part of the crossover, we&amp;rsquo;ll see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to watch the first ep of Mandalorian, but haven&amp;rsquo;t had time yet for the most recent eps. It&amp;rsquo;s not the sort of thing I&amp;rsquo;d side-watch, so I have to dedicate time for it. I better do that before the spoilers catch up with me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next month I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crisis on Infinite Earths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Wars: Rise of the Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-nov-2019/broly_hu4d06564a23f2e71ac7d3766ad33b0777_2995425_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: October 2019: Joker, Scorsese, Stuber, Bloodlines, Brotherhood
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-oct-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-oct-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Actually watched something in the cinema this month: &lt;strong&gt;Joker&lt;/strong&gt;. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t originally sure if I wanted to see it, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t hyped for it at all in the months prior. But as the showing date came nearer, there was a lot of buzz around it so I decided to go anyway. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like it lived up to the hype and the warnings about promoting incel stuff, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s one of the higher-grossing DC movies, so maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll have more to come in that vein. MCU movies all have kind of same-y tone and feel, so probably DC can differentiate itself by doing these heavier movies with a different kind of style. My spoiler-free review of this movie is &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/10/1180086308963618816/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching Joker and also reading Scorsese recent comments about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/film/2019/oct/04/martin-scorsese-says-marvel-movies-are-not-cinema&#34;&gt;MCU movies not really being cinema&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to watch one of his movies and decided on &lt;strong&gt;Goodfellas&lt;/strong&gt;. (The only other one I had seen prior to this was &lt;em&gt;Shutter Island&lt;/em&gt;, which for a long while I thought was a Nolan flick.) Goodfellas was pretty good, definitely nothing like an MCU movie. They are obviously different kinds of &amp;ldquo;cinema&amp;rdquo; altogether, with the MCU movies leaning more towards the &amp;ldquo;popcorn&amp;rdquo; side of the spectrum. I did find it a bit hard to take Joe Pesci seriously here since I only really knew him from &lt;em&gt;Home Alone&lt;/em&gt;. I believe this is also the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen Ray Liotta in a film, so now I know who he is. I definitely enjoyed the &amp;ldquo;slice-of-life&amp;rdquo; look into the old-school gangster lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also watched &lt;strong&gt;Stuber&lt;/strong&gt;, mostly because this movie kept being advertised when I was in the US and it reminded me of Deadpool and that taxi driver friend of his. I was only expecting Batista, but Karen Gillan is also here (briefly!), so there&amp;rsquo;s a tiny GotG reunion there. Indian taxi driver dude was cool, the movie was ok, moderately funny, nothing too genre-busting. More popcorn movies for scorsese to snub his nose at, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catching up on my backlog of DC animated films, I decided to watch &lt;strong&gt;Wonder Woman: Bloodlines&lt;/strong&gt;. Plot spoilers, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a gaggle of WW villains (Silver Swan, Doctor Poison, Doctor Cyber, Cheetah, Giganta) plotting to invade Themyscira, I suspect to make them more well-known among the DC animated viewers. Coincidentally, I had also recently read the WW Rebirth story arc where a gaggle of WW villains tried to trick her into revealing the location of Themyscira, so I had a fresh point of comparison. In the comic book arc, everything was masterminded by Veronica Cale, a pharmaceutical CEO who had been created in the early 2000s with the intent of being the Lex Luthor to WW&amp;rsquo;s Superman. In the movie Cale works with WW for a while, and along I was waiting for the reveal that she was behind everything, but that never came. I would guess they have some bigger plans for Veronica Cale down the line in the DC animared film-universe. Otherwise, the movie was ok. Nothing too spectacular, missable, but also good enough to watch. EDIT: I found out after I wrote this that Bloodlines had a mid-credits scene where WW figures out Cale was behind everything all along!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, not much to say right now. The fall shows are back, that means the Arrowverse is in full swing again (except for Legends, they&amp;rsquo;ll be back in January). The &amp;ldquo;science&amp;rdquo; on &lt;strong&gt;Flash&lt;/strong&gt; is still ridiculous. The flash forwards on &lt;strong&gt;Arrow&lt;/strong&gt; are still boring (I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why they want to make a spinoff for Mia Smoak!), &lt;strong&gt;Supergirl&lt;/strong&gt; is also a bit meh. I&amp;rsquo;m really only looking forward to the Crisis crossover this season (and of course, &lt;em&gt;Legends of Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;.) Haven&amp;rsquo;t watched Batwoman yet, maybe I should since she has one of the five Crisis episodes. Also been following some of the regular stuff: The Good Place, Modern Family, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s also a lot of superhero shows still on the backlog, some of which I may never get to watch: Runaways, Cloak and Dagger (cancelled!), Krypton (cancelled!), Legion (finished!), Doom Patrol, Titans S2, etc. Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a point where there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;too much&lt;/em&gt; content for comic book fans? Lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix: I saw that Jenny Slate has a standup special out and I tried watching it, but eh, not for me, found it very boring and stopped about a third of the way through. I also found myself re-watching the end of &lt;strong&gt;Full Metal Alchemist: Brotherhood&lt;/strong&gt;, mostly because I was envious of a friend who was watching it for the first time. Was surprised to learn the anime is 10 years old as of this year! Still held up well, possibly my favorite anime of all time. The final confrontation and fight scenes were great, although the epilogue episode was a bit anticlimactic and awkward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for this month. Maybe next month we manage to dent the ever-growing backlog? Maybe?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: September 2019: Dark Phoenix, The Ranch
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/watching-lately-sep-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/watching-lately-sep-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I finally got around to watching &lt;strong&gt;X-Men Dark Phoenix&lt;/strong&gt; which I skipped when it came out mainly because (a) poor reviews, and while normally I&amp;rsquo;d have watched it anyway since I have not missed any of the X-Men movies in the cinema, not even the horrendous Wolverine Origins, there was also to consider that (b) I was in the US at the time and was only willing to spend my precious dollars on one expensive American cinema and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/&#34;&gt;Spider-man Far From Home&lt;/a&gt; won out. The movie wasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; bad really, at least I felt better about it than the aforementioned Wolverine Origins. Here are &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes/2019/09/1171737237135867906/&#34;&gt;some of my nitpicks&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not what would&amp;rsquo;ve been the best ending for the X-Men series which was really one of the pioneers of the superhero movie revolution (alongside Raimi&amp;rsquo;s Spider-Man), but that&amp;rsquo;s what we got. At least it ended with a big fiery bird explosion in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also watched Part 7 of &lt;strong&gt;The Ranch&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. The Ranch is one of those weird family comedy/drama shows that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally seem to be in my spheres of interest, especially since the show is probably a lot more appealing to conservative/right-wing viewers. (It&amp;rsquo;s often punctuated by country music and the characters regularly criticize Hillary Clinton and mock the idea of climate change.) I will not admit that I got into it mostly because of Elisha Cuthbert. It is a moderately enjoyable show, the kind you don&amp;rsquo;t mind having run in the background while you&amp;rsquo;re doing something else, although it did lose a bit of its comedy punch with the firing/writing off of Danny Masterson (&amp;ldquo;Hyde&amp;rdquo; from the 70s show) last season due to #MeToo issues, and the guy they replaced him with hasn&amp;rsquo;t been super impressive thus far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow month again this time. The lull should pick up in October once the fall US shows start off. And there&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of movies I want to watch too but some combination of laziness and lack of time always puts them off.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: August 2019: Young Justice, The Boys, Fleabag, One Cut of the Dead
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/watching-lately-aug-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/watching-lately-aug-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Hmm, surprisingly I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched too much stuff this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eigasai&#34;&gt;Eigasai&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched a Japanese film at Eigasai in UP Diliman for the first time ever, upon the invite of some friends. We saw &lt;strong&gt;One Cut of the Dead&lt;/strong&gt; a comedy zombie film. It was great and it was hilarious, although you must make sure not to lose patience with the first thirty minutes. I went in blind not knowing anything about it other than &amp;ldquo;Japanese comedy zombie movie&amp;rdquo;, so you should too! Easily one of the funniest movies I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;young-justice&#34;&gt;Young Justice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back half of Young Justice Outsiders finished this week. I&amp;rsquo;ve honestly been a bit whelmed for this half of the season as I feel like they&amp;rsquo;re all over the place and there&amp;rsquo;s too many plot threads going on at once. Still an enjoyable watch especially for DC fans of course. The thing about having such a large cast is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to focus on any one of them too long, but this season was all about Halo, Geoforce and Cyborg so the arc endings pretty much revolved around those three. It feels like so many status quo changes happened in the last episode though, felt a bit crammed. Also, some spoilers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like the Light declaring at the end that their gains were sufficient vs Luthor&amp;rsquo;s original plans seemed ridiculous (i.e. controlling Markovia vs controlling and registering all superhumans). They already had one puppet nation under their control (Queen Bee is right there!) and they&amp;rsquo;re literally planning to go against Darkseid, how does controlling Markovia help? Feels like a very post-facto justification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did like that they chose not to complete their Judas Contract re-telling in a similar manner and we get a &amp;ldquo;redeemed&amp;rdquo; Tara to contrast with the &amp;ldquo;fallen&amp;rdquo; Geoforce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fleabag&#34;&gt;Fleabag&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about this Amazon Prime series going in either, only that it was a comedy and it was well-reviewed. I did enjoy watching it, although it&amp;rsquo;s more of a tragic comedy than anything else. Basically about how people deal with absurdly difficult situations in their daily life. The story is well-told, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I get all the hype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-boys&#34;&gt;The Boys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Amazon Prime series. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read the source material, and I was a bit turned off by the first episode, but I powered through. I knew it would be dark going in, and possibly gratuitous in terms of the sex and violence at some points, so not many surprises there. The plot seems in my head to be &amp;ldquo;What if superheroes were driven by a greedy corporation&amp;rdquo;, which certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t help address my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/capitalism/&#34;&gt;misgivings about capitalism&lt;/a&gt;. The plot also reminds me of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s book Reckoners, which was also a story about a resistance trying to oppose a superhuman regime led by a Superman-like figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking over the Wikipedia entry for the comic book series, it seems the TV show had some significant divergences, which is understandable, so I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll be seeking out the comic books. The series was enjoyable enough to binge over a few days, although some parts are a bit predictable. I did like the treatment given to Hugh and Annie/Starlight. The cast is pretty good too, I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize Simon Pegg (because it was such a serious role) and Elisabeth Shue (because&amp;hellip;I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen her in anything in a while?). Oh and Gus Fring is also here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I ended up enjoying the season overall, as it tackles a lot of issues I relate with. I will probably be watching Season 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rockos-modern-life-static-cling&#34;&gt;Rocko&amp;rsquo;s Modern Life: Static Cling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix tried to bring Rocko into the modern era, although strangely none of the characters have aged at all. Although they are cartoon characters so I guess that makes sense? The special is about as ridiculous as the old cartoon was, unsurprisingly, although it does try to convey a message about how change is an inevitable part of life. I did like that they had a reference to my favorite episode, R-E-C-Y-C-L-E Recycle~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More next month! Maybe!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: June and July 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/watching-lately-june-and-july-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/watching-lately-june-and-july-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I was travelling for most of the past two months, so this covers both June and July, and I guess I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to watch too much. Maybe? IDK, we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was in the US, I took the opportunity to finish watching &lt;strong&gt;Voltron: Legendary Defender&lt;/strong&gt; which only had two seasons available on PH Netflix. Pretty good adaptation, lots of fun callbacks to the old series. Some annoying filler eps, especially in the middle seasons onwards. I like how they spent the entire series going through the main Voltron villains one by one: first Zarkon, then Lotor, then a little bit of Sendak, then finally Hagar. It got a bit too hocus pocus magicky BS near the finale for me, but overall a pretty good watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were staying with relatives in the US, it turns out they&amp;rsquo;re really fond of watching Filipino movies. I&amp;rsquo;m not big on Filipino movies, most of them seem either uninspired, formulaic or outright ridiculous. I did enjoy a couple of the ones that I sat through, at least enough to comment on them, coincidentally both starring Eddie Garcia (RIP). The first one was &lt;strong&gt;Rainbow&amp;rsquo;s Sunset&lt;/strong&gt;, which has Eddie Garcia playing a senior citizen ex-politician who comes out as gay and explores the repurcussions to his children and grandchildren. This movie had a strange ending that came out of nowhere though. The second movie was &lt;strong&gt;Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Waiting&lt;/strong&gt; where Garcia portrays an old man who has died and finds himself in a waiting area before he can be sent to heaven, basically purgatory. In this place he finds an old flame of his from his youth, who has secretly been waiting for him all this time, refusing to advance to heaven. The movie explores themes of life and death and love and regret and commitment, but in a context outside of the typical Filipino love team movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a bunch of other Netflix movies watched - these folks didn&amp;rsquo;t have that much to do at home - but the only other one I remember sitting through was &lt;strong&gt;Murder Mystery&lt;/strong&gt; starring Adam Sandler and Jennifer Aniston. Basically a comedic whodunnit, it was entertaining enough to sit through, but nothing too special. I did like the car chase scene at the end though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from watching on Netflix, I also tried out an American cinema and watched &lt;strong&gt;Spider-man Far From Home&lt;/strong&gt; with a friend. I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/&#34;&gt;separate blog post&lt;/a&gt; for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murder Mystery might not have been too special, but it did inspire me to watch the copy I had of &lt;strong&gt;Murder on the Orient Express&lt;/strong&gt; when I got back home. It was my first exposure to Hercule Poirot, and I was pleasantly surprised by the star-studded cast. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of movie where you can&amp;rsquo;t watch it twice though; I suppose all whodunits are like that, but now I can&amp;rsquo;t watch the older movie based on this book. There&amp;rsquo;s supposedly a sequel coming out next year, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll watch that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the trip, there was a whole lot of shows to catch up on. The only one I managed to complete was &lt;strong&gt;Jessica Jones S3&lt;/strong&gt;, the final season among the erstwhile Netflix-Marvel shows. I liked this season, mostly because it went way more dark than I expected and had a very &amp;ldquo;Criminal Minds&amp;rdquo;/procedural kind of vibe since her main antagonist here was a serial killer, and one of the themes is how a hero has to play by the rules and can&amp;rsquo;t just do whatever he wants like killing criminals. (This kind of message always resonates with me now because of where the country is.) While I feel like it might have been better to cap the Netflix-Marvel venture with Daredevil&amp;rsquo;s fantastic season 3, this one isn&amp;rsquo;t a bad ending either. I suspect I will do a more detailed look back on these shows soonish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I have a ton of shows to catch up on. Good Omens, Stranger Things, Doom Patrol, Legion, etc to name a few. And I missed out on a few movies though, like Dark Phoenix, which I was tempted to watch in the cinema despite the bad reviews, because I&amp;rsquo;ve never missed any of the prior X-Men movies, not even Wolverine Origins. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have time to catch up on all of this stuff before the Fall TV season comes in!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: May 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/watching-lately-may-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/watching-lately-may-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The big TV thing of May 2019 was of course, the much maligned finale for &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve written about that separately &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/game-of-thrones/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the US TV series also ended their runs in May. Arrowverse show seasons were littered with poor writing as usual. I rank the seasons in this order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;best is &lt;em&gt;Legends of Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt; season 4. The reason Legends is the best is that they&amp;rsquo;re not afraid to be outrageous. My favorite moment was from before the midseason break, Puppets of Tomorrow!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;second best is &lt;em&gt;Supergirl&lt;/em&gt; season 4. I don&amp;rsquo;t like that Supergirl always felt very preachy about modern-day issues like feminism and diversity and immigration, and this season amped that up a lot, but I still enjoyed it because (a) Lex Luthor was great; and (b) they adapted a couple of my favorite DC Superman storylines, namely Manchester Black and the Elite and Red Son (Red Daughter in this case).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;third best is &lt;em&gt;Flash&lt;/em&gt; season 5. Cicada was a terrible villain and the rules of when and how the dagger works were just screwy, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad Eobard gets to come back in the ending (though I still don&amp;rsquo;t know why he has Wells&amp;rsquo; face)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;last is &lt;em&gt;Arrow&lt;/em&gt; season 7, just poor all-around writing, including an episode where Roy Harper flat out murders two innocents and everyone else on Team Arrow is like &amp;ldquo;Huh, okay, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover this up so the police don&amp;rsquo;t find out&amp;rdquo;, and a poorly explained road to Star City&amp;rsquo;s future. The season finale tellss us that Oliver dies during the upcoming Crisis of Infinite Earths. Arrow had a good run, but a few of the seasons were really week. It didn&amp;rsquo;t get as many seasons as Smallville did, but it has a legacy of its own (and arguably Smallville lasted a couple of seasons too long as well). More on this when Arrow&amp;rsquo;s abbreviated eighth and final season finishes later this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all my complaints, I&amp;rsquo;m still looking forward to this year&amp;rsquo;s Crisis crossover!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of DC TV series, &lt;em&gt;Gotham&lt;/em&gt; also ended its 5-season run, and although the show diverges significantly from the traditional Batman mythos, I still liked it. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t spectacular or anything, but there were some nice portrayals of many Batman characters and events. We never get to see Bruce don the cape and cowl, although it is heavily foreshadowed in the last episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Bang Theory also had its series finale, and I liked it. Overall as a series it had its flaws, and at many times promoted smart-shaming and nerd stereotypes, but its a sitcom, so I don&amp;rsquo;t take it too seriously. I think the ending of Sheldon getting his nobel prize (with Amy) and finally acknowledging how difficult he has been as a friend is an appropriate ending for the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my attempt to watch/read more &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/manga/&#34;&gt;manga&lt;/a&gt;/anime again, I started watching &lt;em&gt;Boku no Hero Academia&lt;/em&gt; on Netflix a few months ago, but only got two episodes in. This month I finally binged the rest of the anime and for good measure caught up with the manga as well. This series feels like some cross of One Punch Man (for the superpowers and the modern society) and Naruto (for the kids being supervised by adults), except I&amp;rsquo;d say the depth of the lore so far is not that much, more OPM than Naruto. Still a fairly enjoyable read/watch, since I usually enjoy shonen manga/anime, and it got me thinking that Marvel should make a shonen version of an X-Men comic someday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much movies-wise this month, though I did do a rewatch of &lt;em&gt;Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt; the other day, mostly because I had watched some videos ranking the MCU movies now that Endgame is done. Winter Soldier was always in my #1 slot, and the rewatch basically affirmed that. I had only meant to watch a little bit before going off to do something else, but the pacing of the movie was so great I just ended up watching it to the end. I think the themes of freedom vs security also really resonate with the liberal in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for this month! Next month I&amp;rsquo;ll be travelling, so who knows what I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to watch! I&amp;rsquo;ll have access to US Netflix!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game of Thrones
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/game-of-thrones/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/game-of-thrones/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After a much-maligned eighth and final season, HBO&amp;rsquo;s Game of Thrones is done. Unmarked spoilers follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eighth season was so notoriously bad, we got petitions asking for rewrites. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I explained it to a friend after the notorious episode 5:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not about characters being killed, it&amp;rsquo;s about bad writing because they&amp;rsquo;re cramming. The writers were determined to finish the show in 2 smaller seasons so they&amp;rsquo;re skipping a lot of necessary character development and characters just do stupid things because the plot demands it. The most recent episode (spoilers follow, no apologies) has Dany do something really bad and out of character. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been so bad if they had spent maybe 5-6 episodes building up to it, but there&amp;rsquo;s nothing, she just decided out of nowhere, fuck it, let&amp;rsquo;s do this. The show was already very simplified compared to the books, which had a lot of plot threads and character arcs that never carried over to the show, which is understandable given the volume, and season 8 basically dumbs it down even more so they can hit their target number of episodes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final episode aired today, and I was mostly whelmed. A big meh. It&amp;rsquo;s always challenging to finish in a satisfying manner an epic story with many intersecting character arcs, especially something this popular. You are almost always not going to please everybody. Some endings made sense, some I could see that GRRM was probably planning for all along, some came out of nowhere (Arya the Explorer comes to mind). Like many things about season 8, so much of it feels crammed and unearned. The season might have been better received if they had stretched things out more. As it is, they had to do things like have Tyrion justify Dany&amp;rsquo;s madness in a speech to Jon after the fact, instead of building up to it organically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experiencing the series as a book reader was interesting, since we knew what was going to happen for basically the first five seasons. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not the only book reader who was excited to see how TV viewers would react to things like the execution of Ned Stark and the Red Wedding. Once the series overtook the books, we then fell into this weird position of having the show spoil the books. Not that we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t still read the books, but the show leaving out certain elements changes their importance in the books. For example, the absence of the Lady Stoneheart and Young Griff in the shows implied those plot threads were actually irrelevant to the show&amp;rsquo;s ultimate ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think the poor writing in season 8 makes me look forward to the books more, if only to see if and how GRRM is able to deliver a better and more satisfying ending. I think the ending for the Starks is probably what he had in mind all along (or very close to it); in his initial outline for the entire series, it was always about the Starks. Whether he sticks to that plan or pivots after seeing the reactions to the show, we shall see. I read a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dsilvermint/status/1125856091261136896?s=21&#34;&gt;great thread on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; describing GRRM as a &amp;ldquo;pantser&amp;rdquo; kind of writer, i.e. he writes by the seat of his pants, letting the characters and events drive the story forward instead of strictly following an outline. It makes for good narrative, but is probably also why he&amp;rsquo;s taking forever to finish. And we hope he will finish! Maybe someday, when the books are done, we eventually get a better and more faithful remake series (cue the &amp;ldquo;Game of Thrones: Brotherhood&amp;rdquo; jokes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall though, I think history will look kindly on the entire series of Game of Thrones for what it did. It brought epic fantasy to the forefront of pop culture. People talked excitedly about every episode as it came out and speculated about what would happen. Even my dad got into it, even though I often had to explain some bits to him, and he didn&amp;rsquo;t like watching the show without subtitles. They failed to stick the landing, so they don&amp;rsquo;t belong in the same conversation as series like &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;, but there were a lot of epic moments and some very good television in those eight seasons, and the show ultimately deserves its places in the cultural zeitgeist. Because of this show, we are getting other epic fantasies as TV series moving forward. I&amp;rsquo;m most looking forward to Amazon&amp;rsquo;s upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/wheel-of-time-new-spring/&#34;&gt;Wheel of Time&lt;/a&gt; series, hopefully they don&amp;rsquo;t screw it up. (That one would take maybe two decades to finish!)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: April 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/watching-lately-april-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/watching-lately-april-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve already written extensively about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/more-thoughts-on-avengers-endgame-and-the-mcu/&#34;&gt;Avengers Endgame&lt;/a&gt;, but there are other things I watched this month too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shazam&lt;/strong&gt; came out early this month, and while it was unfortunately sandwiched between MCU blockbusters, it was a fun adventure romp and surprised me in a few ways. I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/183916511215/shazam-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;short spoiler-free review&lt;/a&gt; over on Tumblr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a rewatch binge of &lt;strong&gt;30 Rock&lt;/strong&gt; that unfortunately started with season 4 due to Amazon Prime&amp;rsquo;s weird way of presenting things. I&amp;rsquo;ve already blown past the series finale and wrapped around to the start and currently at season 2, so close to completion. The series is as great and insane as I remember. It&amp;rsquo;s like a more outrageous version of ensemble comedies like Parks and Recreation, and though I am fonder of PNR, I can see why 30 Rock is the more award-winning show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;The Orville&lt;/strong&gt; finished their second seasons this month. Discovery closed off their time loops neatly and sent the Discovery into an unknown future, meaning they get to start season 3 now no longer bound by Star Trek history and free to forge their own path. The season was ok, I enjoyed the classic Trek references and all the timey-wimey stuff. The Orville had a great season, with the introduction of a new enemy empire and possibly one of the best TV space battles of all time. They ended their season with a timey-wimey episode as well, looks like that&amp;rsquo;s a trend for April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/strong&gt; final season started up in April of course, and its only halfway through. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have a lot more to say about it when the season ends in May.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: March 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/watching-lately-march-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/watching-lately-march-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The big one this month was &lt;strong&gt;Captain Marvel&lt;/strong&gt;. I posted &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/183266384975/captain-marvel-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;the usual spoiler-free review over on Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, but I have some more spoiler-y thoughts over here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I thought the movie was ok, I was underwhelmed by the third act and specifically the lack of any serious threat for Carol to defeat towards the end of the movie. As this &lt;a href=&#34;https://mabeloni-sandwich.tumblr.com/post/183645870983/the-biggest-problem-with-every-single-bad-review&#34;&gt;tumblr post explains&lt;/a&gt; more clearly than I ever could, perhaps the issue is that the narrative is not something targetted towards me as a man, who has not experienced the emotional gaslighting IRL that many women are exposed to. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting way to frame the narrative, and probably explains why some movies (i.e. chick flicks) really don&amp;rsquo;t appeal to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did enjoy most everything else about the movie, especially most of the comic book tie-ins and links to other MCU movies. I appreciated how they re-told the &amp;ldquo;Carol getting her powers from an explosion&amp;rdquo; and Mar-vell still being there. I appreciate the surprise that Annette Benning was Mar-Vell all along. I appreciate their reimagination of the Kree Supreme Intelligence. I appreciate that by the time Avengers Endgame or any potential Captain Marvel 2 rolls around, Monica Rambeau will be old enough to be her own superhero as well. I appreciate all the little things connecting this movie to the first Iron Man, the first Avengers, and even to Infinity War itself. I also appreciated that their depiction of the Kree did not rule out the Agents of SHIELD versions existing! (That being said, I would have appreciated an explanation for why some Kree are blue and some are not!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much else to report. The Arrowverse is limping along. Recent episodes of &lt;strong&gt;Supergirl&lt;/strong&gt; have been great, I loved Jon Cryer as Lex Luthor, and I love how they&amp;rsquo;ve been able to adapt multiple comic book storylines this season such as &lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s So Funny About Truth, Justice, &amp;amp; the American Way?&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;American Alien&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Red Son&lt;/em&gt;. (Excuse me, red daughter.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In more sci-fi land, &lt;strong&gt;The Orville&lt;/strong&gt; has been fantastic, with their surprise twist to the Isaac storyline culminating in one of the best space battles portrayed on TV. &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; is not as good, but I still like it, as it feels a lot more classic Trek than S1 and the overarching S2 plot is more interesting to me too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next month is looking packed. The big headliners to look forward to are of course &lt;strong&gt;Avengers Endgame&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Shazam&lt;/strong&gt;, and the final season of &lt;strong&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Netflix and Amazon Prime: An abundance of content
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/netflix-and-amazon-prime-an-abundance-of-content/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/netflix-and-amazon-prime-an-abundance-of-content/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t figured it out yet, I watch a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately/&#34;&gt;lot of TV shows&lt;/a&gt;, rarely on TV itself though. I outgrew scheduled television maybe more than a decade ago. I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of this because I was going through some old disks and found burned episodes of stuff like &lt;em&gt;Smallville&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Heroes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Simpsons&lt;/em&gt;, various anime, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those were from the days before streaming though. These days an abundance of content is available online via the streaming services, no need to store all those episodes yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first tried out Netflix during my three-month London stint back in 2015 (which I now realized I never wrote about). Netflix wasn&amp;rsquo;t available in the PH yet, so I took the opportunity to take a free month trial which led to binge watching of shows like &lt;em&gt;House&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt; when I had the opportunity to work from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months after I got back from the trip, Netflix became available in the PH, January 2016! I initially figured it might not be feasible at all given how terrible the internet here was, but it performed well enough even with our old 4Mbps BayanDSL. The content library was as expected, a lot smaller than the US one was, but it was a pretty good start. It meant a lot of the Netflix original content, including the Marvel shows, were available to me on demand so it was great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people like to use a VPN so they get access to a larger library, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried that. Honestly, there is already so much content in Netflix PH anyway, and if there&amp;rsquo;s any non Netflix content I wanted to watch, there are other ways rather than a VPN. (The old ways still worked of course.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Netflix is a staple in our household, even my nontechie dad uses it a lot, thanks to the LG smart tv we bought a while back. And the kids section helps entertain the nieces and nephews whenever they&amp;rsquo;re over. For me personally, aside from the old movies and shows I&amp;rsquo;m happy with a lot of the standup content and original shows. I think even with the limited content library, Netflix PH is still pretty good value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not content with Netflix though, I also subbed to Amazon Prime around six months back. Well, back then my primary goal was to get Twitch Prime in order to get some &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal-or-eternal-primer-for-mtg-players/&#34;&gt;Eternal&lt;/a&gt; loot (LOL), Amazon Prime was a nice bonus. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used it too much though. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the new Jack Ryan series, it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/october-2018-watching-lately/&#34;&gt;pretty good&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve also watched a few old movies there, and they have a bunch of comedy series I like such as Community, The Office, Parks, etc. I&amp;rsquo;m coming up on six months for my sub though, which means I&amp;rsquo;m about to lose the discounted new subscriber rate. I don&amp;rsquo;t use Amazon Prime nearly as often as I do Netflix, so I&amp;rsquo;m not yet sure whether I should keep it around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s definitely still a lot of holes in the streaming content available locally though - we don&amp;rsquo;t have Hulu for one thing. And the new services like DC Universe and Disney+ probably won&amp;rsquo;t be available here for a while. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping those companies choose to have Netflix distribute internationally in the meantime. For the regular network shows like the Arrowverse shows, I still have to use traditional less legal methods to keep up weekly. Hopefully we&amp;rsquo;re moving towards a future where international viewers have the same legal streaming options available as the Western world does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I really should cut down on my TV shows though&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/10157291363398912/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 21:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/10157291363398912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Star Trek fans: You&amp;rsquo;re probably already watching Discovery, but if you&amp;rsquo;re not also watching The Orville, you&amp;rsquo;re really missing out!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: February 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/watching-lately-february-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/watching-lately-february-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;Alita: Battle Angel&lt;/strong&gt;, with the friend who introduced me to the series in the first place. The movie looked fantastic and the fight scenes were great. Plot was supercondensed, several books&amp;rsquo; worth of story combined into one. Ended in a weird place, kinda? Easily the best western live action anime adaptation by far.&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2019-02-07 14:06:10&#34;&gt;7 Feb 2019 2:06pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&lt;/p&gt;

        









  



&lt;a href=&#34;#18a9e28c111c6e73a78bad7b0dd717a5-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/1093511652643762176-DyzvBZ9W0AAC1JS_hu8c01b3250c12dfdca724a95257de8ea7_116708_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up
After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&#34; title=&#34;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up
After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;18a9e28c111c6e73a78bad7b0dd717a5-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/1093511652643762176-DyzvBZ9W0AAC1JS.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up
After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;7 Feb 2019 2:06pm&#34;&gt;7 Feb 2019 2:06pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;







    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another volume of &amp;ldquo;catching up with older films to improve my geek cred&amp;rdquo;, I watched &lt;strong&gt;The Usual Suspects&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. The movie was still really good, despite the internet having spoiled the Keyser Soze twist for me (and countless others) many years ago. I can see why Spacey won an Oscar for his performance here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;strong&gt;Ralph Breaks The Internet&lt;/strong&gt; with the nieces last weekend. The younger one really enjoyed the scenes with the Disney princesses. Movie was pretty good, despite losing the novelty of the first film. Many tropes were visited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over on the Netflix side, I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying &lt;strong&gt;The Patriot Act with Hasan Minaj&lt;/strong&gt;. Highly informative about a wide range of topics, I thought it would be solely about politics, but there were some surprising discussions on things like, uh, shoes? Conservatives may be annoyed by the liberal bias, but otherwise the show does a good job of breaking down complicated topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also had a few seasons of &lt;strong&gt;Family Guy&lt;/strong&gt; up recently, and it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good series to have running in the background while I&amp;rsquo;m working on other stuff so I managed to watch all of it fairly easily. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s good for my mental health though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Seth MacFarlane shows, I&amp;rsquo;ve caught up with &lt;strong&gt;The Orville&lt;/strong&gt; recently, and this show has been great. It&amp;rsquo;s basically &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; for a newer generation, but with a different (and sometimes more interesting) mythos and history and so on. The show is much more willing to tackle complex ideas relevant to the modern world as well. I hope it does well and goes on for many seasons to come.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Subtitles
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/subtitles/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/subtitles/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/s/the-upgrade/why-gen-z-loves-closed-captioning-ec4e44b8d02f&#34;&gt;Interesting article on closed captioning&lt;/a&gt;, or as I like to call them, subtitles. My first exposure to subtitles was anime of course, but these days I vastly prefer having subtitles on any show, even if it&amp;rsquo;s dubbed in a language I do understand. From the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do you have captions on?&amp;rdquo; I asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps me with my ADHD: I can focus on the words, I catch things I missed, and I never have to go back,&amp;rdquo; she replied. And I can text while I watch.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have ADHD, that&amp;rsquo;s not something diagnosed very often over here, though I&amp;rsquo;m sure I exhibit a certain lack of focus. But I can relate to how subtitles help me avoid having to rewind a show for something I missed. The subtitles act like a kind of fallback to the verbal/audio cues, helping me when I get distracted (quite easily) and when I&amp;rsquo;m multitasking. They also help with accents and murmured words and things like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are people who don&amp;rsquo;t like subtitles when they aren&amp;rsquo;t necessary, complaining that having to read distracts them from the film. I imagine those people are the same kind of people who don&amp;rsquo;t like reading books or reading in general.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: January 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/watching-lately-january-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/watching-lately-january-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bumblebee&lt;/strong&gt; only came out over here in January (thanks to the usual MMFF shenanigans), and I decided to watch it on a whim. Pretty decent soft reboot, read my &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/181926569205/bumblebee-spoiler-free-review-attached-image&#34;&gt;spoiler-free review over on the Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first half of &lt;strong&gt;Young Justice Outsiders&lt;/strong&gt; is out, and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. Focus is back on a smaller group after the larger team in YJ season 2. A few new characters are introduced and I learned about a couple of DC heroes I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with before. Probably still the best animated superhero show to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Netflix side, season 2 of &lt;strong&gt;Punisher&lt;/strong&gt; is out as well. I finished watching it but didn&amp;rsquo;t bother posting a spoiler-free review this time. It was okay, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have much commentary. Not as strikingly good as the first one was, but pretty decent. It feels weird now watching these shows knowing they are likely to end soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 2 of &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; has also started! Only two episodes in so far, but still very good. Feels a lot more classic Trek than the previous season, and a much lighter tone, not just because their captain isn&amp;rsquo;t afraid of the light anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Netflix history also says I watched Bird Box, which became a bit viral early this month for some reason, but that was just my niece making my mom watch it with her, even after I warned her she would get scared (she did).&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: December 2018
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/watching-lately-december-2018/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/watching-lately-december-2018/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I very much enjoyed &lt;strong&gt;Elseworlds&lt;/strong&gt;, the Arrowverse crossover this year. I mean sure, a lot of it didn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense, but it was like a love letter to DC fans. I actually consider myself more of a Marvel fan than DC, but I still loved it! I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/181046297550/aquaman-spoiler-free-review-i-came-in-with-low&#34;&gt;a spoiler-free review over on the Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;strong&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/strong&gt; on a couple of &amp;ldquo;Best TV of 2018&amp;rdquo; lists so I decided to catch up with it since it was on Netflix. I was actually two seasons behind. This series is great, and I really enjoy Bob Odenkirk&amp;rsquo;s portrayal, but it might be just a bit overhyped for me. We already know where Jimmy/Saul, Mike, the Salamancas, and Gus Fring end up given &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;, so that kind of takes away a bit of tension. Still, it&amp;rsquo;s a fine TV show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got caught up with &lt;strong&gt;The Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a weird show for me to watch given how hillbilly it is, but I find the perspective strangely refreshing. Also, Elisha Cuthbert really helps. I was surprised that they had killed off Danny Masterson&amp;rsquo;s character (oops spoilers), apparently it was a #MeToo thing or such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Into the Spider-Verse&lt;/strong&gt; was great, especially for a fan of the comics. You can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/181171084805/into-the-spider-verse-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;my spoiler-free review on tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;Aquaman&lt;/strong&gt; with a friend at UPTC, my first time watching at the theaters there. I had low expectations, but the movie was a surprisingly fun spectacle. You can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/181046297550/aquaman-spoiler-free-review-i-came-in-with-low&#34;&gt;my spoiler-free review on tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At home, I watched &lt;strong&gt;Incredibles 2&lt;/strong&gt; with the niece, who has a bad habit of spoiling things for movies she&amp;rsquo;s already seen. To the tune of &amp;ldquo;Oh, did you know &lt;code&gt;Character&lt;/code&gt; is actually &lt;code&gt;Villain&lt;/code&gt;?!?&amp;rdquo;. Still, the movie was nice, exceeded my expectations. It expanded the Incredibles&amp;rsquo; superhero universe and there was even some surprise Bob Odenkirk!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also watched &lt;strong&gt;Solo: A Star Wars Story&lt;/strong&gt; on Christmas eve (since we didn&amp;rsquo;t get a Christmas Star Wars film this year). We didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to finish it before we went to mass though, so I finished the movie myself a couple of days later. I had skipped watching this in the theater given the mediocre ratings, but now that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it, that&amp;rsquo;s a decision I&amp;rsquo;ve come to regret. It&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable movie with a servicable plot, especially given it&amp;rsquo;s basically meant to expound upon a couple of throwaway lines from the original trilogy. The plot even leaves some dangling threads that could have picked up in succeeding movies, had Disney not decided to scrap (at least for now) the Star Wars spinoff movies. The movie compares unfavorably to &lt;em&gt;Rogue One&lt;/em&gt;, which had the far superior heist scheme. In both movies we expected many of the introduced characters to be killed off, but the Rogue One deaths were much better than the Solo ones. Still, it&amp;rsquo;s an okay addition to the Star Wars universe. I read that it also has some tie-ins to the various animated series, which I&amp;rsquo;m not too familiar with. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get into those someday.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/181046069605/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 13:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/181046069605/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Arrowverse Elseworlds crossover spoiler-free review!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- if you&amp;rsquo;re not aware, episode 1 - Flash S05E09, episode 2 - Arrow S07E09, episode 3 - Supergirl S04E09&lt;br/&gt;- I don&amp;rsquo;t usually review TV show crossovers but TBH I can&amp;rsquo;t recall any other any TV show crossovers and I just really, really enjoyed this one&lt;br/&gt;- basically a love letter to DC comics fans, a celebration of dc comics/TV/movies from the past four decades, and apparently a prelude of things to come. Non-comicbook fans might not be as happy as me lol&lt;br/&gt;- all three episodes were great (middle episode slightly worse because Arrow lol), I was smiling all the time and apploauding all the references&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
- frankly not everything made sense, but I&amp;rsquo;ll forgive it (I mean, have you *read* crisis on infinite earths? lol&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- bonus: for more zaniness, also watch this week&amp;rsquo;s Legend&amp;rsquo;s of Tomorrow, they didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be outdone! &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- I also watched Aquaman today, and that was fine (review later) but I decided to write a review of this crossover first!&lt;br/&gt;- tonight&amp;rsquo;s reading list (image attached)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/181046069605/_hu09aaccecce2cd0dcc2679dff333c1672_195765_9461faa3da2567b7b4bb4566edb3516e.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: November 2018
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/watching-lately-november-2018/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/watching-lately-november-2018/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, I watched two biopics this month. The first one is &lt;strong&gt;Hidden Figures&lt;/strong&gt;, about three black women who were instrumental during the early days of NASA leading up to the Friendship 7 mission piloted by John Glenn. The movie is fairly interesting if you are even remotely interested in either the challenges faced in black history or math and science or the early days of the space program competition between the USA and Russia. It feels even more appropriate to have watched this since it helps me appreciate the recent Insight mission. (The Oatmeal has &lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/insight&#34;&gt;a fun preview of this event&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second biopic was &lt;strong&gt;Bohemian Rhapsody&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a magnificent film, both for the music and the Freddie Mercury story. I guess it appeals more to those who are familiar with Queen music though. I&amp;rsquo;ve read that the movie isn&amp;rsquo;t super accurate especially with regards to the timeline, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s fine. Both the liberties they take and the music serve to construct a compelling narrative. The movie ends with a ten-minute recreation of the 1985 Live Aid concert and they do a good job of communicating the insane energy at Wembley Stadium back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In less-biographical movies, I also watched &lt;strong&gt;Teen Titans Go To The Movies&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of Teen Titans Go, it&amp;rsquo;s way too silly and it&amp;rsquo;s obviously for kids, I much preferred the previous Teen Titans series. I only got a copy of this movie because my niece said they watched this all the time back home, so now they can watch it when they&amp;rsquo;re over here either. I did enjoy the ridiculous plot and the Stan Lee cameo, but this isn&amp;rsquo;t something I would have watched in the theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In rewatch land, since I finished the Spider-Man PS4 game lately, I also watched &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man 2&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man 3&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Amazing Spider-Man&lt;/strong&gt;, they&amp;rsquo;re nice movies to have playing in the background while you&amp;rsquo;re working on other stuff. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/07/movies-spiderman-2/&#34;&gt;Tobey 2&lt;/a&gt; was pretty good and I think it aged well, I&amp;rsquo;d say comparable with Tobey 1 even. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/05/spider-man-3/&#34;&gt;Tobey 3&lt;/a&gt; was trying to do way too much what with Venom and Sandman and Harry-Goblin. Andrew 1 had a lot of potential, but I think this series leaned too much into the dark and mysterious and sinister plot route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, nothing much other than the usual superhero series, though I&amp;rsquo;m still behind on Gifted and Doctor Who. I caught Trevor Noah&amp;rsquo;s new Netflix special, it was okay, but too exceptionally. Netflix also added a couple of &amp;ldquo;best of&amp;rdquo; seasons of Jeopardy which I thoroughly enjoyed. Watching these makes me think I&amp;rsquo;d never be able to win an episode of Jeopardy, but of course I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s fair to compare myself to some of Jeopardy&amp;rsquo;s all-time champions.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: October 2018
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/october-2018-watching-lately/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 05:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/october-2018-watching-lately/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s Jack Ryan (on Amazon Prime)&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; surprisingly good, even if I&amp;rsquo;m not too familiar with the Jack Ryan stuff. I only know John Krasinski from &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoilers for Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s Jack Ryan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The story starts with Ryan tracking down Suleiman&amp;rsquo;s network via financials, but they never follow-up on who was financing his group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what was the point of the whole drone pilot side story (including the weird trip to the casino and the night with the couple), although it was admittedly kind of entertaining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daredevil season 3 (on Netflix)&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I enjoyed the season a lot. I posted a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/179331448050/daredevil-season-3-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;spoiler-free review over on the ireadcomicbooks tumblr&lt;/a&gt;. Over here I can post spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Murdock&amp;rsquo;s parentage from the comics, so the Maggie reveal came as a surprise to me. A+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sad that there was no Bullseye namedrop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ending kind of flubbed it a bit, could have used an explanation of at what point Matt decided not to kill Fisk. It&amp;rsquo;s not clear if it was something he decided on the spot or if the compromise was part of a plan he devised after interrogating Manning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venom&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I initially wasn&amp;rsquo;t planning on watching this given the terrible early reviews, but eventually I was like, hey I watched &lt;em&gt;X-Men Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt; so might as well watch this too. It turned out not so bad (low expectations helped), although I find the movie&amp;rsquo;s enhancements to the symbiote abilities a bit disconcerting. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/179008685600/venom-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;Read my spoiler-free review here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Batman Ninja &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/179485492410/i-found-out-batman-ninja-is-on-netflix-so-i&#34;&gt;I found out this was on Netflix and went ahead and watched it&lt;/a&gt;. The animations and character designs are nice, but the plot is just ridiculous lol. Feels like someone wrote a Batman fanfic.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Superhero shows being political
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/superhero-shows-being-political/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 05:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/superhero-shows-being-political/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Comic books and superheroes have always tended to skew towards liberal philosophies, given how writers and artists tend to support ideals like individualism and free expression. So it&amp;rsquo;s not surprising that the derivative shows tend to lean the same way. Not only do many of the shows promote diversity, but many are becoming overtly political as well. Some recent examples. (Spoilers for current seasons of Supergirl, Legends of Tomorrow and Daredevil follow)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The current season 4 of Supergirl seems to be focusing on anti-alien sentiment, a thinly-veiled allegory towards the anti-immigration movement propagated in far right &amp;ldquo;nationalist&amp;rdquo; circles. Similar to real-life, hatemongers are portrayed riling up crowds frustrated with losing jobs and threats to law and order due to the presence of &amp;ldquo;aliens&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pilot episode of Legends of Tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s season 4 includes a short segment where one of the characters visits her mother, a Muslim immigrant in the US, and wishes she could warn her to move to Canada before &amp;ldquo;this country turns against her.&amp;rdquo; Do the Legends know about things to come? (Of course, during the previous season, the showrunners &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2017/aug/4/dcs-legends-of-tomorrow-producer-admits-muslim-cha/&#34;&gt;admitted that the Muslim character in question was introduced precisely as a response to Trump&amp;rsquo;s election&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally, in the fantastic Daredevil season 3, Wilson&amp;rsquo;s Fisk&amp;rsquo;s being billeted in the &amp;ldquo;Presidential Hotel&amp;rdquo; and his calling out his supposed crimes as politically-motivated &amp;ldquo;fake news&amp;rdquo; reminds a lot of people of the current American president. If that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, &lt;a href=&#34;http://boundingintocomics.com/2018/10/18/daredevil-season-3-showrunner-compares-wilson-fisk-to-donald-trump/&#34;&gt;even the showrunner compares the Kingpin to Trump&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though it&amp;rsquo;s not a completely new thing I&amp;rsquo;m glad the showrunners are willing to make their political opinions known. This, despite the existence the so-called ComicsGate movement among a minority of superhero fans, which is a self-described revolt against &amp;ldquo;liberalism&amp;rdquo;. I wonder if these ComicsGate people also hate the TV shows?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Michael Scott
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/michael-scott/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 03:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/michael-scott/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been re-watching The Office (US) lately (it&amp;rsquo;s a good show to leave running in the background while you&amp;rsquo;re doing other stuff), and I just find the character of Michael Scott fascinating. He&amp;rsquo;s funny and well-written and basically just a big bag of human flaws that somehow bumbles his way into managing an office. He&amp;rsquo;s self-centered, attention-hungry, easily distracted, and refuses to acknowledge any bad news, yet despite all of that he loves his workmates like a family.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#dfb6cc8c63b0be98f1f267fa0f1b1869-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/michael-scott/980x1_hu1a0a2599cf64709dac29c32aa84062aa_641246_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;dfb6cc8c63b0be98f1f267fa0f1b1869-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/michael-scott/980x1.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;26 Oct 2018 3:00am&#34;&gt;26 Oct 2018 3:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing I find most relatable is his complete self-confidence that he can be good at everything. Not just his job as a manager and as a salesman, but everything he chooses to do. As an example, he auditioned for a play (&lt;em&gt;The Demon Barber of Fleet Street)&lt;/em&gt; and automatically assumed he was getting a part. He also made a movie which fell into the so-bad-its-good category (&lt;em&gt;Threat Level Midnight&lt;/em&gt;) and was pissed off that his girlfriend didn&amp;rsquo;t care much for it. He also claims to have written a business book and an HBO comedy special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find the above relatable because I have this similar flaw of wanting to do everything and yet feel bad when I fall short. Like Michael Scott, I often don&amp;rsquo;t have the patience for grinding through the beginner stages of some new thing I&amp;rsquo;m trying out &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;m working on improving. I&amp;rsquo;m sure both Michael Scott and I could stand to learn from &lt;em&gt;Adventure Time&lt;/em&gt;s Finn the Dog:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#18146aac51bad4c07df68d7e4201f521-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/michael-scott/6dc1_hu8f65fa2b813a6e0d245ffd14060ee390_574493_300x0_resize_box.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;18146aac51bad4c07df68d7e4201f521-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/michael-scott/6dc1.gif&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;26 Oct 2018 3:00am&#34;&gt;26 Oct 2018 3:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;




&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/michael-scott/6dc1_hu8f65fa2b813a6e0d245ffd14060ee390_574493_300x0_resize_box.gif&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/michael-scott/980x1_hu1a0a2599cf64709dac29c32aa84062aa_641246_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Spoiler Alert!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/05/spoiler-alert/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 01:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/05/spoiler-alert/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;When Game of Thrones entered its sixth season in 2016, it was true spoiler territory for those of us who had read the GRRM books before HBO&amp;rsquo;s TV adaptation turned the property into a worldwide phenomenon. Due to the author&amp;rsquo;s glacial writing pace, at this point the TV series went past the point that the novels had reached. Thus nobody &amp;ndash; book readers or tv viewers &amp;ndash; knew what events would unfold in the story. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t watch the episodes until a few days after they air. On the day the first episode aired I found while scrolling through my social media feeds that one of my friends (who shall remain nameless) posted what turned out to be the resolution to the cliffhanger ending of both the previous TV season and the last available book. It was of course followed by immediate comments of &amp;ldquo;Spoiler!&amp;rdquo; from me and a few other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people might say, what&amp;rsquo;s the big deal? When you&amp;rsquo;re invested in a story, getting unintentionally spoiled as to future plot points is a terrible feeling. It robs of you of the the experience, as you now go into the story with certain expectations. You only ever get one chance to watch/read/experience a story for the first time. If you enjoyed that experience, you should be considerate of others and not take that same experience away from them. (Unless they ask for it of course.) Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s just a story. But hey, life is stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The need to talk about what happened in a story is certainly understandable. You&amp;rsquo;re excited about the story and you can&amp;rsquo;t wait to talk to people about it and tell them what you think and speculate about what happens next and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s akin to coming back to school/work on Monday and discussing what happened in your favorite TV shows over the weekend. (Back in high school we probably had multiple Monday morning conversations along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Can you believe Goku is still running down the snake road?&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when it&amp;rsquo;s you and your buddies talking about it over the water cooler after everybody&amp;rsquo;s seen the episode in question that&amp;rsquo;s fine. But in the modern age, we have social media, and with social media comes the tendency to broadcast your thoughts to the world. If you&amp;rsquo;re not careful you&amp;rsquo;re going to accidentally spoil everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing about this because of Avengers Infinity War of course. I normally post a spoiler-free review on Facebook after watching a movie, but there&amp;rsquo;s so much to unpack in this movie I had to get down my thoughts and write &lt;a href=&#34;http://nedstarkdies.com/avengers-infinity-war/&#34;&gt;a spoiler-filled review over on NedStarkDies.com&lt;/a&gt;. Marvel themselves were well aware of the dangers spoilers poised in ruining people&amp;rsquo;s experience of the movie. In the weeks running up to the movie, they ran a campaign to encourage people to avoid spreading spoilers using the hashtag &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23ThanosDemandsYourSilence&amp;amp;src=typd&#34;&gt;#ThanosDemandsYourSilence&lt;/a&gt;. The campaign included a letter from the Russo brothers and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NhLsx3BzsvY&#34;&gt;video message from the cast&lt;/a&gt;. The campaign seems to have been largely successful, which is amazing to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note: I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to watch the movie on the opening day, so it was a bit brave for me to still be scanning my feeds in the days before I was able to watch. But I think I got away mostly unscathed. I will say however, that I do consider as mild spoilers reactions like &amp;ldquo;I need a hug&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;that wasn&amp;rsquo;t good for kids&amp;rdquo;. I mean, that already implies the tone of the ending. But then again, I&amp;rsquo;m probably more finicky about spoilers than most &amp;ndash; these days I tend to avoid all but the first trailer for any movies I plan to watch since I feel that succeeding trailers already tend to spoil too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last spoiler-related anecdote: my brothers and I are big fans of profession wrestling (WWE). We used to follow all the storylines and whatnot. Back in 2005, up-and-comer Dave Batista (who also happens to appear in Infinity War) got his first title shot at Wrestlemania 21. One of my brothers was unable to watch the show at the time that it aired on local TV. But he didn&amp;rsquo;t want us to spoil the match outcome for him until he got a chance to find a copy that he could watch. We didn&amp;rsquo;t want to download it because it would have taken too long on our very slow internet back then. It took him a couple of months to find a store that had DVD copies of the event. As the lady behind the counter handed him the DVD she commented something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Batista was so good in this event sir, he became the champion!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/02/963020367366205440/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 12:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/02/963020367366205440/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Discovery had a great S1 ending, especially since I&amp;rsquo;m currently watching TOS as well&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/956110174942457856/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 10:23:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/956110174942457856/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I had put off watching PUNISHER (on Netflix) since i wasn&amp;rsquo;t really too hyped about it. But now that I finally got around to it, I really like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pacing was good throughout the season (which was one of the weakness of the recent MCU Netflix seasons such as Luke Cage, Iron Fist and Defenders) and it didn&amp;rsquo;t falter halfway through and stuck the landing.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/956110174942457856/10156364192608912/26951855_10156364192278912_5642854889001680642_o_hue94152431d30d931539ccfef1a7fde6d_2687_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/954698443770937345/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 12:53:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/954698443770937345/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re an X-Men fan and you&amp;rsquo;re not watching The Gifted, you&amp;rsquo;re really missing out. It&amp;rsquo;s a more serious, street-level take on &amp;ldquo;the mutant problem&amp;rdquo; than the movies could ever handle.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/950759791676219392/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 16:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/950759791676219392/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Black Mirror S4 spoiler-free review! (episodes listed from most enjoyed to least):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.6. Black Museum (reminds me of White Christmas)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.1. USS Callister (fun, but I was annoyed by how infeasible the technical premise was)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.4. Hang the DJ (kind of telegraphed the ending)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.3. Crocodile (felt like a police procedural)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.5. Metalhead (would have probably appreciated it more if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a Black Mirror episode)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.2. Arkangel (kinda boring and draggy)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I liked S3 a lot more&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/12/947110656934690816/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 14:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/12/947110656934690816/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;RT &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/williamsmeatsix/&#34;&gt;@williamsmeatsix&lt;/a&gt;: Brooklyn Nine-Nine might get cancelled so here&amp;rsquo;s a few reasons why you should start watching this show (spoiler-free,&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/917632384299704322/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 06:06:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/917632384299704322/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;(Watching Star Trek Discovery) Why are there no seat belts in the future?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/917632384299704322/10156097632488912/22281669_10155730816258610_3223380786557521070_n_hu3a5de050da7a7f16a985855ac2b14bd0_2941_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/917632384299704322/10156097632893912/22366720_10155730816748610_5185044216320856850_n_hub81e4a5b9510369d51349f79b44ff2fb_3821_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/10155967044973912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 09:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/10155967044973912/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;DEFENDERS spoiler-free review and episode guide:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Okay, maybe a teensy little spoiler in that image - but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist lol)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this series moves forward each of the four protaganists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you get to see most of the supporting cast come back and maybe even get a teeny bit of development in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the plot is reasonably tight, i had a few minor nitpicks but now i can&amp;rsquo;t even remember most of them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just the fanboy in me, but I was really excited when they met each other for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jessica Jones still the best character&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iron Fist still the weakest point (see the image), but it&amp;rsquo;s not as bad as it was in his own series. It helps that he&amp;rsquo;s not surrounded by the weird Meachum family and has a better ensemble to work off of. I also really enjoyed how enthusiastic he was at getting a team together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fight scenes are pretty good (at least better than in the Iron Fist series - also it&amp;rsquo;s still weird that Daredevil fights a lot better than Iron Fist. He must have been a real slacker during that decade in Kun&amp;rsquo;Lun)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I suspect you can come in cold without watching any of the previous series, they do bring up their backstories a lot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m disappointed that there was no title drop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Episode guide:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ep1 ok
ep2 great
ep3 great
ep4 great
ep5 draggy, this was the weakest ep for me
ep6 ok
ep7 good
ep8 great. there&amp;rsquo;s a post-credits scene&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/10155967044973912/_hu4e7d27c853f54c65f8317ae1939d6c29_32987_3a9d20fe0f5abca9410659301152a9ef.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/893056454671740928/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 10:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/893056454671740928/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Watching NCIS Los Angeles: Kahawig ni LL Cool J si Bato&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/10155222048823912/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/10155222048823912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Finished watching Westworld. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. Once you get introduced to the premise of the show, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to imagine where it goes from there - these types of stories tend to go in that particular direction. Where the show shines is the narrative, the way the events unfold, everything is very well done. Some things from the earlier episodes are quite vague, unclear or sometimes downright contradictory, but things clear up pretty well near the end of the 10-episode run, though a number of things are still left hanging (including the fates of the surviving characters) for the presumptive season two to help clear up.  Not for kids. Lots of violence and nudity and whatnot.  Also, there&amp;rsquo;s a post-credits scene.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/10/10154956006193912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 22:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/10/10154956006193912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Luke Cage spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this is an unapologetically very black show. It highlights black culture, black music, black history, and so on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gang violence, sleazy politicians, corrupt cops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;most of the cast give great performances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rosario dawson&amp;rsquo;s role seems to get bigger with each additional series&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lots of great easter eggs for comic book fans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;might have been an episode or two too long&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did not like the ending too much, though I can see why they might have gone that way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/10154613586538912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 06:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/10154613586538912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Finished Legends of Tomorrow S1. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t always the best, and their time travel logic is terribly inconsistent, but I think it was a fun ride overall and finished strong with a great cliffhanger for S2. Mike Ross ftw!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/10154612072203912/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 15:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/10154612072203912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I wonder if they&amp;rsquo;re going to try to merge Supergirl universe with the Arrowverse somehow. With Flash and Supergirl there, we have the proper elements for a crisis on infinite earths :p  &lt;a href=&#34;https://ew.com/article/2016/05/19/cw-crossover-arrow-flash-legends-tomorrow-supergirl/&#34;&gt;https://ew.com/article/2016/05/19/cw-crossover-arrow-flash-legends-tomorrow-supergirl/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/10154599193333912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2016 00:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/10154599193333912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Finished watching all 5 seasons of the BBC Merlin show. Lots of Game of Thrones actors making an appearance lol. I like how they flipped the trope of Merlin being a wise old wizard advising Arthur, but of course the series ending was way too predictable (it can&amp;rsquo;t be helped given the Arthurian legend)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/04/10154510824138912/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 23:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/04/10154510824138912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;So I watched a couple of eps of the new Criminal Minds spin-off Beyond Borders featuring Gary Sinise&amp;rsquo;s FBI team intervening in crimes with American victims in other countries. I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to keep watching solely for the eventual episode set in the Philippines where there are militant leftists protesting against imperialist interference in local affairs&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/02/701680813302087680/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 08:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/02/701680813302087680/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Finished watching the Battlestar Galactica 2004 series. Really great space opera throughout the series but that ending was weaksauce&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/12/10154251989328912/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2015 01:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/12/10154251989328912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Finally finished watching Jessica Jones. It started out a bit slow, but the pace picked up after a few episodes. It&amp;rsquo;s a different kind of grimdark than Daredevil was, but everything about the plot was great and tight. I was worried about what they planned to do with Kilgrave but it turned out he might have been a better villain here than Fisk was in Daredevil&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/08/10154021732108912/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 01:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/08/10154021732108912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I started watching House. I like it when he calls people idiots&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/08/10154001263203912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2015 23:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/08/10154001263203912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Finished watching Avatar: The Last Airbender. Season One felt a bit slow and I was thinking maybe the show was overhyped, but things picked up around season two and I can say the finale was fairly satisfying&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/07/10153928222268912/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2015 00:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/07/10153928222268912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;After seven months of watching Deep Space Nine, I watched the last episode tonight. A very satisfying series and finale. Overall while TNG was a lot more iconic and well-known I feel like DS9 had a much better story to tell and a much more satisfying ending as well&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/01/556830918568972288/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 15:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/01/556830918568972288/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I just finished watching all 3 seasons of Batman Beyond. This was easily the best part: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GdLCDHMGuv0&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GdLCDHMGuv0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/06/473497861489836032/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2014 16:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/06/473497861489836032/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;HE DIED!&amp;rdquo; - how I know my brother was watching Game of Thrones&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>