<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>birthday on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/tags/birthday/</link>
      <description>Recent content in birthday on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/tags/birthday/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Forty Two
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2020/08/forty-two/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2020/08/forty-two/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Forty two is of course the &amp;ldquo;Answer to the Ultimate Question of Life, the Universe, and Everything.&amp;rdquo; (if you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet read the 5-book Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy trilogy, I suggest you do so, you are in for a treat.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason I imagined I would be able to take at least a couple of days off of everything else I&amp;rsquo;m doing to chill and actually craft a well-written, deep, introspective post for the occasion, but alas, various things I&amp;rsquo;m working on and all the usual distractions means I am here in the early morning hours of the day itself typing this out. Likely to just rant a bit here instead of putting out anything coherent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s weird celebrating your birthday in the middle of a worldwide pandemic, when most of the usual celebration trappings are inaccessible. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the reasons why the &lt;a href=&#34;https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1275013/sinas-other-police-officials-in-mananita-to-face-criminal-case-palace&#34;&gt;birthday mananita debacle&lt;/a&gt; was such a big deal to a lot of people. While these supposed &amp;ldquo;public servants&amp;rdquo; flaunt their privilege, the rest of us are deprived of things like seeing our friends and loved ones in person, celebrating milestones, or even the simple pleasures of eating out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve actually written quite a few of these &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/tags/birthday/&#34;&gt;birthday posts&lt;/a&gt; by now, though not as regularly as I&amp;rsquo;d have liked. I read through a few of them to help me decide what to write for today (didn&amp;rsquo;t really help). My favorite has to be the one with &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2016/08/thirty-eight/&#34;&gt;thirty eight lessons I’ve learned through the years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s for the best, maybe even if I had gotten a few days off I still wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been able to come up with anything satisfying enough. I mean, the point of taking time off for myself was to get away from the world for a bit and be all introspective and to spend time with my own thoughts, but with this pandemic, I might have been doing far too much time doing that already. Perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m not really complaining about the spike in busy-ness I&amp;rsquo;ve had over the past month or so. It&amp;rsquo;s sort of a welcome respite from all the self-reflection this pandemic time has given me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that this is the first birthday after I quit Facebook, I am expecting much, much fewer birthday greetings this year. Interesting how a lot of people are probably dependent now on Facebook to tell them when other people are having birthdays. It is no big loss; the people who are important will remember. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I&amp;rsquo;m not grateful and amazed if someone unexpected should remember. A couple of days ago someone I&amp;rsquo;d only known for less than five years actually remembered to greet me, except the greeting came two days early due to uncertainty about the exact date. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to be remembered, no matter how stoic we pretend to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I almost impulse-bought a Switch yesterday, luckily a friend talked me out of it. Would have made a fine self-birthday gift, but my gaming backlog is still pretty ridiculous as it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit ironic that in last year&amp;rsquo;s post &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/08/forty-one/&#34;&gt;I complained about an uneventful 365 days&lt;/a&gt; and look what we have now (&lt;em&gt;waves hands around&lt;/em&gt;). I hope I didn&amp;rsquo;t jinx 2020. Next year is a more boring number, maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll have a better year?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Forty One
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/08/forty-one/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/08/forty-one/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Such an uninteresting number. And it hasn&amp;rsquo;t really been an exceptional 365 days around the sun either, but this has become a bit of a yearly tradition now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things I considered doing today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spend the entire day offline (Hah! As if.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go out for a walk at the old university (unlikely to push through, given the gloomy weather recently)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;go to the mall and buy a new external hard drive and a new monitor and eat at Yabu (I like Yabu) and maybe watch a movie in the cinema (I don&amp;rsquo;t really feel like going to the mall on a Friday, and there aren&amp;rsquo;t any good movies to watch apparently)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;play through &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/237630/DuckTales_Remastered/&#34;&gt;Ducktales Remastered on Steam&lt;/a&gt;, which I bought last night because it was about to be removed from the store, and stream it live on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;Twitch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;binge one of the shows on my TV backlog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;read through a book. Or maybe books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spend the day drawing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;work on some personal projects, some updates to this site even&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sleep all day (not likely I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to do this)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;get some more dental work done (&amp;hellip; I think I&amp;rsquo;ll push this off to next week)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day a friend who has his birthday a couple of days away from mine told us he&amp;rsquo;d prefer not to celebrate and not to be greeted, as around this time of the year he always has certain troubles. Birthdays don&amp;rsquo;t mean as much to grownups. Pretty much just another year, and most years are not enough different from one another that they all kind of blend in together. I still like to do the blog post though, just as a marker of sorts. An increment to a counter. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any particular deep thoughts or reflections prepared for this one though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year though! Next year is life, the universe and everything!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Forty
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2018/08/forty/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 02:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2018/08/forty/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &#34;Life begins at forty&#34; -- Walter B. Pitkin
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be a milestone of some kind, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Like any other birthday though, I don&amp;rsquo;t feel much different. I still feel like a kid (hence the &amp;ldquo;kid-at-heart&amp;rdquo; in this blog&amp;rsquo;s header), no more an adult than I was twenty years ago. More or less still the same person. I still enjoy the same pursuits, prefer the same foods, have the same hobbies, appreciate the same things. I would like to believe that despite the harshness of the world I still remain mostly an idealist. That in the face of chaos I remain stoic and committed to reason. That I can still step forward into the world with faith in humanity. (Though the past few years have been challenging to say the least.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everything is the same of course. What is humanity if not change? Perhaps a little bit wiser, maybe a bit more battle-scarred, almost certainly a tiny bit less optimistic and a tiny bit more cynical. Knees a little bit more wobbly. A tiny bit more forgetful. Traveled more of the world. Learned more about people. Maybe even understood them a little bit more. Hoped, dreamed, disappointed, challenged, failed, got back up again, got hurt, hurt people back, achieved victory, suffered defeat. Seen more, lived more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still hold a lot of the aspirations I had when I was young. When you are young, you tend to dream ambitiously. This is the benefit of youth, your world is yet unbounded by harsh realities, you are invincible and everything is within your reach. These days, I think I still hold to the same hopes and dreams, but I have a better acceptance of what their probabilities are. And right now I&amp;rsquo;m at a stage of life where my priority is mainly to enjoy life and not to stress myself too much. Do things that I want. Work on projects that make me feel alive. Sleep in on rainy mornings. Read good stories. Enjoy the company of family and loved ones and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life and age and time, they come and go. This is supposed to be some kind of midpoint isn&amp;rsquo;t it? But who knows how much time we really have in this world? (Or how much time this world has at all?) Life and age and time, they creep on you slowly, in an almost unnoticeable manner. Days and months and years pass by quickly and fade to memory. All the more for us to cherish each moment as it comes and it passes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to the next forty.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Thirty Nine
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2017/08/thirty-nine/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 01:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2017/08/thirty-nine/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t had much time to write recently. Been busy. (I&amp;rsquo;ll write about that some other time.) But I&amp;rsquo;ve kind of been posting regularly on this date for a while, so here we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, time. And the inexorable passage thereof. There&amp;rsquo;s some kind of big milestone for me in around three hundred and sixty-five more solar cycles. Well, I don&amp;rsquo;t personally consider it big, since that&amp;rsquo;s kind of arbitrary. But as people are wont to say, life begins&amp;hellip;  maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, kind of at a crossroads. Considering where to go and the way forward. Trying out some things. Figuring out what&amp;rsquo;s important and what&amp;rsquo;s not and what one would be willing to give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all honesty there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance that in another year&amp;rsquo;s time, I still wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have figured anything out. Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s what life is though. A constant struggle of figuring out where to go next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it goes.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Thirty Eight
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2016/08/thirty-eight/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 01:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2016/08/thirty-eight/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Thirty eight lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned through the years, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not be beguiled by pretty things; not all that glitters is gold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remain true to yourself in the face of adversity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t help people who aren&amp;rsquo;t willing to change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People will believe what they want to believe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to do what everybody else does&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Happiness often comes from small things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be thankful for what you have and appreciate the people who are there for you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other people think about you a lot less than you think&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time you enjoy wasting isn&amp;rsquo;t wasted time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend some time alone with your thoughts regularly; solitude has its benefits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In most situations, a balanced approach will serve you well. Extreme or fanatical views will rarely be good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Occasionally try again things you earlier dismissed, in case that they have improved or your own tastes have changed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When in doubt and things are urgent, pick one option randomly and go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to speak your mind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Life is too short to waste time on things that you don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy or don&amp;rsquo;t help you grow or people who don&amp;rsquo;t appreciate you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s never too late to be who you were meant to be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it&amp;rsquo;s important to you, keep track of it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The world is too amazing to be bored&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to be weird and/or random every so often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Life has no meaning except what meaning you give it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All things, whether good or bad, shall eventually pass. Enjoy the good while it lasts, persist through the bad until you make it through&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid doing or saying things in anger or hatred&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Things change and people change, sometimes for reasons we can&amp;rsquo;t ever explain. Learn to roll with life&amp;rsquo;s punches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The world is filled with people who are terrible, cruel, or manipulative. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean there aren&amp;rsquo;t good people out there and that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you should mistrust everybody. &amp;ldquo;Do not let the world make you hard&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry too much about things that you can&amp;rsquo;t understand or can&amp;rsquo;t change. Focus only on things you can affect and that matter to you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality is nice, but quantity often works too. Many failed or mediocre attempts will eventually converge towards a quality success&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to accept when things need to end. Let go or be dragged&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes you just need the courage to power through the difficult parts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For many things, the best way to improve is with time and practice and effort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn from the past, look to the the future, but live in the present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Life isn&amp;rsquo;t fair. Just because you&amp;rsquo;ve done all the right things doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you&amp;rsquo;ll get what you want, even if you feel like you deserve it (the converse is also true &amp;ndash; even if you do all the wrong things you won&amp;rsquo;t necessarily get punished for it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strive to be fair and honest with people you deal with. Give credit where credit is due&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In order to learn, teach. In order to lead, follow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you are ahead, strive for stability and balance. When you are behind, be willing to gamble&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always keep learning and improving. Every day, try to improve yourself or learn something new&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every once in a while, expand your horizons with new things or different points of view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Words are wind. Reinforce your words with deeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Age is merely a state of mind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Thirty-Seven
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2015/08/thirty-seven/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 06:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2015/08/thirty-seven/</guid>
            <description>
            
            










&lt;a href=&#34;#acc388179e835b19767ab66f448e7bad-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2015/08/thirty-seven/11846797_10154003060973912_2930333303287459805_n_hu09304814d2748f585adad844f3c8f3de_42719_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;acc388179e835b19767ab66f448e7bad-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2015/08/thirty-seven/11846797_10154003060973912_2930333303287459805_n.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;9 Aug 2015 6:39am&#34;&gt;9 Aug 2015 6:39am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to be optimistic, or at least to try to. And to believe the best of people, or at least try to. It&amp;rsquo;s not always easy. Sometimes people disappoint you. Sometimes you feel lost. Or stressed. Or stuck in a rut. And you don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to be able to look within yourself to find your own drive, to find the ability to move forward in spite of the tough times. And to be able to appreciate the good things in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite some bad spots, I&amp;rsquo;ve still had a pretty good twelve months though. I&amp;rsquo;ve traveled a lot, and plan to travel more before the year ends. I&amp;rsquo;m still learning new things. I&amp;rsquo;m still blessed with good family and friends and a means to sustain myself and my wants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My birthday always feels like a good opportunity to step back and take a breather and find some perspective. And to re-affirm the choice to keep moving forward &amp;ndash; one step at a time&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2015/08/thirty-seven/11846797_10154003060973912_2930333303287459805_n_hu09304814d2748f585adad844f3c8f3de_42719_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Thirty-Six
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2014/08/thirty-six/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 11:47:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2014/08/thirty-six/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Thirty-six is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semiperfect_number&#34;&gt;semiperfect number&lt;/a&gt;, meaning it is the sum of some subsets of its natural divisors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like thirty-six, life isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect either. But there&amp;rsquo;s still much to be thankful for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am grateful that I have a roof over my head and am able to eat at least three square meals a day (if I so choose).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am grateful that I have wonderful parents and siblings who are always ready to support me no matter what shenanigans I get into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am grateful for friends who are interesting and who share my interests and are more than willing to put up with my particular insanities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am grateful for having a well-paying job that affords me luxuries and opportunities most people are not able to avail of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am grateful for the prospect of a possible brighter tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my birthday wishes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish for clarity of vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish for serenity of heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish for less hatred in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish for more honesty in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish for less traffic in Metro Manila.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish for better internet in the Philippines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish for good health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish for more free time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish for more wishes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let the future come and bring what it will.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Fifth Power
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2010/08/the-fifth-power/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 16:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2010/08/the-fifth-power/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I maybe getting older but as anyone can attest, I&amp;rsquo;m still a child at heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As they say: life is a journey, not a destination. I still don&amp;rsquo;t know what my destination is, but I&amp;rsquo;ll keep moving forward one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to the next power of two.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Thirty One
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2009/08/thirty-one/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2009 12:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2009/08/thirty-one/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Days seem to fly by at such an unforgiving pace. Has it really been thirty-one years now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a lot to be thankful for the past thirty-one years. Family, friends and other wonderful people that provide love and support; a roof over my head, three square meals a day minimum and a nice, stable and well-paying job. For all of these, I am thankful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One would think that at such a point in my life, I would be very satisfied for having been so blessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was never one for being so easily satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember when I was in high school, I made a bet with a classmate that I would be able to become president of the country before he could. Our wager was worth one cubic meter of solid gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years back, I made a wager with an officemate who was about to leave my company to go independent; I bet that I would become famous before he would. To win the bet, one would have to be named person of the year by a major international publication such as Time or Newsweek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still a dreamer, I always have been. Since I was young I&amp;rsquo;ve dreamed of accomplishing something great. I think everybody has a dreamer inside them, especially when they&amp;rsquo;re young. But as we grow older and face the different trials and tribulations of life, they start to chip away slowly at our dreams. Everyday we make some simple decision that trades a part of those dreams for something pragmatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But dreams have a way of being overtaken by real life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tell ourselves we&amp;rsquo;d just be working for a year or so, until we figure out what direction I wanted my life to take. We have so many options in this day and age; never has the barrier for entry into freelancing, entrepreneurship or innovation been so low. One year passes, then another and then yet another. But we still don&amp;rsquo;t know where we want to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We say to ourselves; it&amp;rsquo;s okay, I can work on my dreams in my spare time. I&amp;rsquo;ll write a chapter a day. I&amp;rsquo;ll code a few portions of my revolutionary web service after I get home. I&amp;rsquo;ll do design work on my game on weekends. I&amp;rsquo;ll brainstorm business ideas on the way to work. But when we come home from our daily grind, we&amp;rsquo;re dead tired and just want to relax, or surf the web, or play games on our consoles. &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll start tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;, a familiar mantra. And days turn into weeks and turn into months and into years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I need to get some experience first. I just need to save up some more money. I&amp;rsquo;m already doing pretty well, why ruin it? I&amp;rsquo;m pretty lucky to have a well-paying job in this economy, I&amp;rsquo;d be foolish to take risks now. I have bills to pay.&lt;/em&gt; These are the lies we tell ourselves when we find ourselves wondering what happened to our dreams, when we wake up to find ourselves trapped in the loop of ordinary life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we end our days, humble and simple, having lived an ordinary life. Just another statistic in human history, just another cog in the great wheel of destiny. And we tell ourselves more lies. I could&amp;rsquo;ve been great. I never had any opportunities. If only I had gotten a break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many people, this ordinary life may be enough, and that&amp;rsquo;s great for them. They will live out their ordinary lives with their ordinary ending and grow old and raise their kids and enjoy the company of their grandchildren and they&amp;rsquo;ll be completely happy and satisfied with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, I was never one for being so easily satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thirty-one years now. Days flying by at an unforgiving pace. How will I find myself spending the next thirty-one?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>First Birthday Outside the Country
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2007/08/first-birthday-outside-the-country/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2007 03:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2007/08/first-birthday-outside-the-country/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Check. Yeap, I turned 29 a couple of days ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a typhoon signal no. 8 over HK right now as I type this. For people in the Philippines, that&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine since our local indicators only go up to storm signal no. 4. But it&amp;rsquo;s really a bit calm where I am right now, some wind but not much rain. I&amp;rsquo;m not inclined to go out though, I&amp;rsquo;m running out of clothes as it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m flying back next Tuesday, hopefully the storm has dissipated by then. I miss my own bed. :p&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>I&#39;m Back. And I&#39;m 27.
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2005/08/i39m-back-and-i39m-27/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2005 08:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2005/08/i39m-back-and-i39m-27/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Yeah, so there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an impromptu hiatus anyway. Unplanned and whatever. Work has been hell lately. Not a tedious kind of hell though. Just the sort that sucks up a lot of time. I spent more than 15 hours in the office on my birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty-seven huh? I wish I had more to say, but birthdays seem to matter less and less as I get older. I&amp;rsquo;m in a good place right now, but I&amp;rsquo;m still not where I ultimately want to be. I have a long road ahead of me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe someday I&amp;rsquo;ll get around to it.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>14-AUG-2003: Quarter-Life Crisis
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2003/08/14-aug-2003-quarter-life-crisis/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2003 01:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2003/08/14-aug-2003-quarter-life-crisis/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well, not exactly. But I am now 25, in any case. Looking back, there are many things I might have regretted, but my life philosphy tells me that there can be no regrets. The past is past, and the future is yet to come. Somehow, I&amp;rsquo;m only a few steps closer towards achieving my lifetime goals, but my gut tells me to keep on dreaming. Such is the folly of a dreamer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering, my lifetime goals include becoming an accomplished indie game developer, and world domination. There are more, but these are the ones that are most constant. Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m serious about the world domination part!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I finally got some free time. Work&amp;rsquo;s been a bitch lately, but I had to call in sick today due to an unfortunate (or fortunate?) case of LBM. Filipinos in the audience know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. Truth be told I would&amp;rsquo;ve taken the slightest excuse to get off work. It&amp;rsquo;s better to be absent today since the workload is rather light while we&amp;rsquo;re waiting for the UAT results, rather than being absent when we have to cram for deadlines. Gee, I wonder if my officemates are reading this. ^_^&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Birthday #24
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2002/08/birthday-24/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2002 04:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2002/08/birthday-24/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I turned 24 yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generally uneventful birthday, as usual. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I got the whining done in the last post. Spent the night before at David&amp;rsquo;s (whose birthday is a couple of days before mine). Dave, Mon and I played approximately seven hours of CvS2, watched a Jet Li flick then played around eight hours of Warcraft III. WC3 is the bomb! (And it further highlights my craving for a new computer) Anyway, went home the next morning, got some sleep. Then the usual birthday food in the evening, and some new pants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had forgotten to go to Church that morning (curse you Warcraft III!!!) so I decided to go to Church this morning. Before going I was stiull a bit down about being a 24-year old bum, but somehow going to Church gave me back a bit of hope. Funny how although I&amp;rsquo;m not a very good practicing Catholic, a few quiet moments with God are enough to change my perspective on things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, this is the start of a new year, hopefully one better than the last. I don&amp;rsquo;t know where fate will take me this year, but I will face life with open arms, overcome all challenges and spit in the face of destiny. All things happen for a purpose, hopefully soon i will know mine.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>