<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>gaming on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/gaming/</link>
      <description>Recent content in gaming on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 05:37:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1368435737884909568/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 05:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/1368435737884909568/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;[Team Camote] - StarCraft 2 Showmatch - hungryroy (me) vs tzia_n #starcraft2 #gaming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1bINjaPjt1M&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1bINjaPjt1M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of our games are in this youtube playlist: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL5c1J8DcHGjdzou13Vcn9eydWENvFb652&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PL5c1J8DcHGjdzou13Vcn9eydWENvFb652&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game Review: Knightin&#39;
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 04:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A while back, on a whim I purchased this indie game &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/922710/Knightin/&#34;&gt;Knightin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; on Steam. I forget how I came across it and why I decided to buy, but no regrets. It&amp;rsquo;s a tightly-focused dungeon crawler in the style of original Legend of Zelda/Link to the Past dungeons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each dungeon is a set of rooms you clear one at a time, until you get  to the dungeon boss and beat him. Clearing rooms involves defeating  enemies, solving puzzles, avoiding obstacles and opening chests. It&amp;rsquo;s a  short game, there are only four dungeons to clear each slightly more difficult than the last. There is no plot at all. The game itself openly admits this by painting the thinnest of flavors. You play Sir Lootalot and you want to beat the evil dark lord at the end of the fourth dungeon. For treasure! No princess to save or anything like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I say &amp;ldquo;tightly-focused&amp;rdquo;, I mean that the game is barebones and does only what it says, but it does it very well. I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of how well-designed it is. It&amp;rsquo;s entirely predictable, you know what you&amp;rsquo;re getting into, but each part is executed really well. Each dungeon consists of multiple floors. Each floor has exactly twelve rooms, arranged in the same 3x4 rectangle shape every time. There&amp;rsquo;s a minimap that never changes shape, but maps room paths as you go. The minimap has a nice notation that indicates things like stairs up, stairs down, a merchant, a warp point, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combat is simple and straightforward as well. You don&amp;rsquo;t get a plethora of weapons like Link does in the Zelda series. You start out with a sword (obviously) and later you get access to a wand that lets you shoot fireballs, and those are your only weapons ever. Later you also learn to dash (which hits enemies with the sword), fire dash (which leaves a trail of flames as you dash), and learn a spin attack (a la Link to the Past). You only ever have to remember four buttons: swing sword, shoot wand, dash, and raise shield (and I very rarely use the shield).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obstacles in your way include enemies of course, and the difficulty ramp is great here as well. You start out with enemies that just walk around randomly and they damage you if they bump you. As you progress you meet more complicated foes. Enemies with ranged attacks. Enemies that chase you. Enemies that can move faster. Enemies that can pop out from under your feet. Enemies that can reproduce. And so on. They are always introduced one new enemy at a time so you get to know their shtick before you meet them in more difficult rooms. Rooms can also have obstacles, such as blades that suddenly jut out of the ground, rotating saw blades, pillars that shoot projectiles, and so on, all adding to room difficulty. Some rooms will have a merchant who sells stuff (you get gold from enemy drops), or chests you can open. Everything is pre-placed, no procedural generation here.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#d621fbf9a9ac70145a465c88aca90db5-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/enemies_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_274814_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Later rooms contain multiple enemies of different types and some dungeon mechanisms too.&#34; title=&#34;Later rooms contain multiple enemies of different types and some dungeon mechanisms too.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Later rooms contain multiple enemies of different types and some dungeon mechanisms too. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;d621fbf9a9ac70145a465c88aca90db5-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/enemies.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Later rooms contain multiple enemies of different types and some dungeon mechanisms too.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&#34;&gt;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#5c60eaefaea532db8744b8b2555edad4-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/merchant_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_266631_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Each dungeon has a merchant named Mr Businessmage, he sells healing and various upgrades.&#34; title=&#34;Each dungeon has a merchant named Mr Businessmage, he sells healing and various upgrades.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Each dungeon has a merchant named Mr Businessmage, he sells healing and various upgrades. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;5c60eaefaea532db8744b8b2555edad4-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/merchant.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Each dungeon has a merchant named Mr Businessmage, he sells healing and various upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&#34;&gt;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#417cc9be1594a07faeeea9d035ef8475-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/obstacles_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_274074_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Later floors will have pillars which act as obstacles that you have to unlock to progress.&#34; title=&#34;Later floors will have pillars which act as obstacles that you have to unlock to progress.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Later floors will have pillars which act as obstacles that you have to unlock to progress. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;417cc9be1594a07faeeea9d035ef8475-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/obstacles.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Later floors will have pillars which act as obstacles that you have to unlock to progress.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&#34;&gt;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also some puzzle rooms, which come in two types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;switch rooms, where you need to figure out which switches to turn on to access a chest or unlock a path. These are handled well enough. Although there&amp;rsquo;s no dialog anywhere, hints for the correct switch positions are scattered visually throughout the same floor of the dungeon where they are found. When you encounter a switch room, it&amp;rsquo;s usually just a matter of going back to previous rooms to see what the hints mean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;block rooms, where you need to push blocks around (only push! no pull!) to get them into the correct positions. I enjoyed the block puzzles more. They are relatively well-designed, and some took me a bit more time than I expected (maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just dumb? Lol)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#8224cb04a6260f2b792a0f75907c4557-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/switch_hints_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_305792_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;An example of a hint for a switch puzzle room, found by moving blocks around.&#34; title=&#34;An example of a hint for a switch puzzle room, found by moving blocks around.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;An example of a hint for a switch puzzle room, found by moving blocks around. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;8224cb04a6260f2b792a0f75907c4557-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/switch_hints.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An example of a hint for a switch puzzle room, found by moving blocks around.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&#34;&gt;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#98b1448dad6c41585b92343a1a6f3f67-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/block_puzzle_hu1f2dd98c9ff3be7f12f615c9c8d56277_336070_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This particular block puzzle gave me some trouble. You have to push the blocks onto the lighted tiles.&#34; title=&#34;This particular block puzzle gave me some trouble. You have to push the blocks onto the lighted tiles.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;This particular block puzzle gave me some trouble. You have to push the blocks onto the lighted tiles. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;98b1448dad6c41585b92343a1a6f3f67-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/block_puzzle.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This particular block puzzle gave me some trouble. You have to push the blocks onto the lighted tiles.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&#34;&gt;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;. Completion in this game is largely straightforward as well. Most of the achievements are geared towards acquiring all the upgrades, opening all chests, and beating all the dungeons. The only two I didn&amp;rsquo;t get (and probably won&amp;rsquo;t bother to) are for doing a speedrun under 90 minutes and for doing a no death run. I tried a couple of post-game runs, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I can do both of those after some number of tries, but I think I&amp;rsquo;m way too lazy for that. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it installed and maybe someday I&amp;rsquo;ll get around to it.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#1394a46888e9f689dcc126a7335f3eb1-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/achievements_hu225459d6feb8400b5b3b99c1ac215ed9_174374_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;So close.&#34; title=&#34;So close.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;So close. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;1394a46888e9f689dcc126a7335f3eb1-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/achievements.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So close.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&#34;&gt;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall&lt;/strong&gt;: A very tight, focused, well-designed and quick indie game experience (my total play time so far is less than 3 hours). It&amp;rsquo;s relatively cheap on Steam too. It&amp;rsquo;s not super groundbreaking or anything, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it for a couple of hours of entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/achievements_hu225459d6feb8400b5b3b99c1ac215ed9_174374_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;So close.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/block_puzzle_hu1f2dd98c9ff3be7f12f615c9c8d56277_336070_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;This particular block puzzle gave me some trouble. You have to push the blocks onto the lighted tiles.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/enemies_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_274814_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Later rooms contain multiple enemies of different types and some dungeon mechanisms too.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/merchant_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_266631_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Each dungeon has a merchant named Mr Businessmage, he sells healing and various upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/obstacles_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_274074_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Later floors will have pillars which act as obstacles that you have to unlock to progress.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/switch_hints_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_305792_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;An example of a hint for a switch puzzle room, found by moving blocks around.&lt;/p&gt;
    



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Digital Boardgames Review: Scythe
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-scythe/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 07:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-scythe/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been regularly playing digital boardgames online on Steam with one of my friend groups, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do reviews of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second review is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/718560/Scythe_Digital_Edition/&#34;&gt;Scythe: Digital Edition&lt;/a&gt;. Scythe is a competitive game where you play one of seven factions in an alternate history post-war Eastern Europe. Players vie to control territories, hire workers, build mechs, accumulate resources, accomplish secret objectives, and other such goals. Accomplishing secret objectives, winning combats or maximizing one of the several metrics (workers, money, popularity, military power, recruits, structures, mechs, etc) earns you stars, and the game ends when at least one player has six stars. Having six stars doesn&amp;rsquo;t guarantee victory, as points are then tallied up depending on various factors including stars, territories, money, popularity, and so on. Having separate victory and end conditions creates a bit of tension and a balancing act between progressing stars and earning points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Players play as one of seven available factions, each with preset locations on the board. The board is preset and consists of hex tiles, each with different movement limitations and resources that can be produced. The board also has &amp;ldquo;encounters&amp;rdquo; on certain tiles, basically roleplaying opportunities where you get the choice of an action to take, typically trading one type of resource for another, usually a good deal, if you can pay the costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The board is fixed, but each player is randomly assigned a mat that determines the actions available during their turn. The mat is split into top actions (produce, move, bolster, trade) each paired with one of the available bottom actions (upgrade, deploy mech, recruit, build structure). During your turn, you may play one top action followed by the corresponding bottom action, and you cannot do the same action pair on successive turns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weird action structure makes the game challenging. Typically, the top actions generate resources, while the bottom actions consume them to advance your goals. If you get a mat with pairings that are poor for your particular situation, it may take a while for you to get into a regular rhythm of production to actually get anything done. Other players can also interfere with you by sending their character and/or mechs to attack or harass your territory or workers. I usually find that I need to plan ahead 2-3 turns to accomplish a simple goal like building a mech. Beyond the 3-turn window, who knows what the board looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combat is kind of straightforward - you can attack a hex with one or two combat units, and up to two combat units will defend it. Each side can spend up to 7 military power, plus play one combat card per unit on their side, each card adds 2-5 to your total. The attacker wins all ties, favoring aggressors. Due to the way military power and combat cards are accumulated, it&amp;rsquo;s risky to initiate combat unless you have at least 14 military power (this ensures you have a fighting chance against a counterattack). Furthermore, each faction can only gain up to 2 stars from winning combats, so you want to make them count. In our games, we find that typically the winning faction will use two combats to try to earn 2 stars in one turn and end the game, and often those will be the only combats that happen in the entire game. Not sure if we are playing this optimally!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games tend to go at least an hour long, roughly 20 or so turns in our experience. Because of the game&amp;rsquo;s pacing and action structure, you can have games where it feels like I haven&amp;rsquo;t accomplished much by then. Usually this creates a bit of snowball effect as well - the player who gets his act together earlier will tend to pull ahead and be difficult to catch up to. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/ComebackMechanic&#34;&gt;comeback mechanism&lt;/a&gt; we&amp;rsquo;re missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The display is literally just the actual board, and the camera can be a bit finicky sometimes. In my last game I accidentally rotated the view and took a minute to figure out how to get it back. The UI is also fairly sparse and a lot of information or options can be hidden in the weirdest places. Like, figuring out where your faction is allowed to cross rivers can be challenging for new players. I&amp;rsquo;ve attached some screenshots to this post, but they&amp;rsquo;re nothing special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably just relevant to my playgroup, but because of the slow pace, we tend to play a second metagame on top of the endgame scoring, where we consider the player who has spent the least amount of time on his turns (as seen via the turn clock) as &amp;ldquo;winning by time&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the digital board games we&amp;rsquo;ve played, this is the one where we have the least amount of playtime. Unsurprising given how slow the pace is and how difficult it is. For this reason, I think it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to recommend to any boardgame newbies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-scythe/20210220223716_1_hua872809a2f8536b39dff7422d14bd553_386462_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-scythe/20210220224938_1_hua872809a2f8536b39dff7422d14bd553_333187_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-scythe/20210220232853_1_hu165c50b18f1565768a5dbf7205c829d0_351856_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Digital Boardgames Review: Sentinels of the Multiverse
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-sentinels-of-the-multiverse/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 07:34:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-sentinels-of-the-multiverse/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been regularly playing digital boardgames online on Steam with one of my friend groups, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do reviews of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one is &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/337150/Sentinels_of_the_Multiverse/&#34;&gt;Sentinels of the Multiverse&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;ve played the IRL boardgame of it before during one of our sporadic in-person meetups. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, it&amp;rsquo;s a comics-themed coop game where up to 4 people play as a group of heroes to beat a villain (basically comic book shenanigans).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a large variety of heroes available to play, each with unique abilities and play styles. Some of them are straightforward and some are super complicated and fiddly to play. The villains you have to beat vary from super simple to really difficult, with advanced variants for even more challenge. The game also provides a &amp;ldquo;weekly one-shot&amp;rdquo; challenge which provides a fixed scenario/villain and set of heroes to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve played a lot of games of Sentinels, and probably only won something like 60-70% of them. Each game takes around an hour or so, maybe more if it was super difficult. Usually we lose when we choose some combination of random heroes just to try them out then get beaten terribly by the villain. Then we go on a revenge run using one of the simpler heroes like Legacy or Tachyon (or we just put in a healer like Dr Medico).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital version has the advantage that it automates a lot of the ability triggers and checks that the boardgame requires, which would usually be a lot of work. On the other hand, it has a UX disadvantage for those scenarios where an ability triggers multiple times and you want to make the same decision every time. In the real board game, you can just handwave it off by saying &amp;ldquo;Ok, we choose X is every time&amp;rdquo;, but in the digital version you have to click through every confirmation dialog every time.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#9b343c2c14c495c5a8dd6b1afec25ba2-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-sentinels-of-the-multiverse/sentinels_hu55ebca5d49dfa13d3a35dca65e2ada62_322159_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;9b343c2c14c495c5a8dd6b1afec25ba2-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-sentinels-of-the-multiverse/sentinels.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;15 Feb 2021 7:34am&#34;&gt;15 Feb 2021 7:34am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game&amp;rsquo;s aesthetic is very much classic comic books, even multiplayer games are joined by entering a code in the format of a comic book issue like &amp;ldquo;Justice Comics #153&amp;rdquo;. The art isn&amp;rsquo;t the most elaborate and could be better; in fact, they are planning a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.polygon.com/2021/1/27/22250963/sentinels-of-the-multiverse-definitive-kickstarter-street-date-price&#34;&gt;Definitive Edition of the boardgame&lt;/a&gt; that has even better art that is closer to the old-school comic book aesthetic. It looks like a signficant upgrade, so I expect if they ever release a digital version of the new version it would be a completely new game on Steam. Our group has enjoyed our Sentinels games though, so I fully expect we will be getting the new Steam version when it does come out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-sentinels-of-the-multiverse/sentinels_hu55ebca5d49dfa13d3a35dca65e2ada62_322159_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game Review: Super Mario Odyssey
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After playing through &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/mario-3d-all-stars/&#34;&gt;Super Mario 3D All Stars in October&lt;/a&gt;, I borrowed a copy of Super Mario Odyssey for the Nintendo Switch from my brother and played through it for most of November. Odyssey was the main reason I actually got a Switch; I played through a few worlds at a friends house during a single session and loved it, so I had been meaning to get the console just for Odyssey alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game deviates a bit from the formula established by Mario 64, Sunshine and Galaxy; Instead of a single hub that leads to small mission worlds, there are a number of different kingdoms, each of which have different residents. The plot is standard Mario fare; Bowser kidnaps Peach because he wants to marry her against her will (and apparently there&amp;rsquo;s nothing she can do about it?! You can say no girl!) You visit each kingdom in turn as you chase Bowser across the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each kingdom is a self-contained &amp;ldquo;open world&amp;rdquo; where there are many challenges you can complete to advance the story. Completing challenges earns you Power Moons (the analogue to 64/Galaxy&amp;rsquo;s stars and Sunshine&amp;rsquo;s shines) which ostensibly power your ship, the Odyssey. Examples of the Kingdoms are the Metro Kingdom featuring New Donk City, whose mayor is the girl you rescued from Donkey Kong so long ago; the Woodland Kingdom is populated by flower-growing robots; the residents of the Seaside Kingdom are slugs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  




&lt;a href=&#34;#0e296a63e8c5317e383ba1adf72d06a3-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/new-donk-city_hud58de80b5c48a33903c4e78adf89972c_330126_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;It&amp;#39;s so weird when you&amp;#39;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&#34; title=&#34;It&amp;#39;s so weird when you&amp;#39;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so weird when you&amp;rsquo;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;0e296a63e8c5317e383ba1adf72d06a3-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/new-donk-city.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s so weird when you&amp;#39;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#e484a0deecbc15a71ffd6173d9c64579-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/woodland_hu39148852bfe8193ef55eed0344c3d387_349647_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is the woodland kingdom&#34; title=&#34;This is the woodland kingdom&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;This is the woodland kingdom (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;e484a0deecbc15a71ffd6173d9c64579-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/woodland.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is the woodland kingdom&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#84526be5a48128edac1b70b29da91719-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/beach_hucc1160ff1649688cbfe46fb4ddd33ef0_299952_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&#34; title=&#34;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Mario wearing a parka at the beach (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;84526be5a48128edac1b70b29da91719-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/beach.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually finished the main story after around a week of play. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly straightforward, not especially challenging.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#7ba08eb041f1571ff133f4ee17ae133b-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/credits_hub108851206b98ce5466a0d64971ceaa1_272556_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&#34; title=&#34;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;7ba08eb041f1571ff133f4ee17ae133b-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/credits.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is however, a lot of post-game and completion stuff to do, that took me another couple of weeks and change. Odyssey&amp;rsquo;s completion revolves around collecting a rather large number of Power Moons. A good chunk of them are only available after beating the main story, though I did try to get as many as I could even before beating Bowser. And some worlds like Peach&amp;rsquo;s Mushroom Kingdom and the more challenging Dark Side/Darker Side of the Moon are available only in the post-game.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#313a380fa8b81e6d69b10f94691c3c60-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/mushroom-kingdom_hu0d6d184ea89cff2c96204967b79d565d_305312_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&#34; title=&#34;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;313a380fa8b81e6d69b10f94691c3c60-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/mushroom-kingdom.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite parts of the game are these segments where Mario becomes a 2D Mario and you have to play 2d Mario stages in 8-bit style, they appear in the open world as murals, often hidden, and they&amp;rsquo;re really nice throwbacks. They even made 8-bit versions of each Mario costume!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completion is a real challenge. There are much more difficult platforming challenges involved, and some moons like the Koopa racing ones will require you to master advanced moves and jumps to beat them. There&amp;rsquo;s also a whole lot of minigames to complete, moons hidden using art-based clues, and a whole lot of collectibles (including hats and costumes for Mario) that you can purchase from stores using coins and regional currency that you collect. I played most of the game in handheld mode, but there are some moons that are easier to get using motion controls, which requires you detach the joycons, so that&amp;rsquo;s something I sometimes had to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  




&lt;a href=&#34;#afa7f811401cc0b4aa2ed14482ff2296-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/clue_hu5c03d63d75cc02a67f36228a0ae744c9_163462_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;There&amp;#39;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&#34; title=&#34;There&amp;#39;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;afa7f811401cc0b4aa2ed14482ff2296-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/clue.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#8743a48562a1c5ef53ff66112e0af0d2-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/space-koopa_hu5a04ad347ee2589302cf1ada3c228395_130058_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mario doesn&amp;#39;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&#34; title=&#34;Mario doesn&amp;#39;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Mario doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;8743a48562a1c5ef53ff66112e0af0d2-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/space-koopa.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mario doesn&amp;#39;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#cf3c150025add34858ebdc88dd0872a9-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/hats_hu0fc2897e727a2efd79695b17b87b2564_246730_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Maybe there&amp;#39;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&#34; title=&#34;Maybe there&amp;#39;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team? (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;cf3c150025add34858ebdc88dd0872a9-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/hats.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maybe there&amp;#39;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get all but 7 of the unique 880 collectible moons. The 7 I missed were 5 for minigames (100 jumps in jump rope, 100 volleys in beach volleyball, and 3 bound bowl races) and 2 stage moons (for Breakdown Road in Dark Side). While none of these seem impossible to do, they all seem like they require much more patience than I am willing to give, so I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with this completion rate for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  




&lt;a href=&#34;#97e0ebef995f25880cec449204a6d666-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/874-moons_huac9045153cdd9a41641854a98f87ad17_219394_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;It&amp;#39;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&#34; title=&#34;It&amp;#39;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;97e0ebef995f25880cec449204a6d666-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/874-moons.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#3116ac381049afd75bad589d6cc5a45d-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/thank-you_hu7f88aae91c13a4ffff71119166449a0c_73671_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&#34; title=&#34;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;3116ac381049afd75bad589d6cc5a45d-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/thank-you.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only complaint is that at some point I found going for completion to be super tedious, especially with those last few moons. 880 moons is a ridiculous number, compare that to a paltry 240 stars in Galaxy. This might be a case of there just being too much stuff? I realize this is a weird thing to complain about. Overall it&amp;rsquo;s still a fun and engaging game, though I&amp;rsquo;m waffling over whether this one or Galaxy is the better game. (I probably still like Super Mario 3D World over either though!)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/874-moons_huac9045153cdd9a41641854a98f87ad17_219394_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;amp;rsquo;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/beach_hucc1160ff1649688cbfe46fb4ddd33ef0_299952_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/clue_hu5c03d63d75cc02a67f36228a0ae744c9_163462_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;There&amp;amp;rsquo;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/credits_hub108851206b98ce5466a0d64971ceaa1_272556_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/hats_hu0fc2897e727a2efd79695b17b87b2564_246730_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Maybe there&amp;amp;rsquo;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/mushroom-kingdom_hu0d6d184ea89cff2c96204967b79d565d_305312_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/new-donk-city_hud58de80b5c48a33903c4e78adf89972c_330126_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;amp;rsquo;s so weird when you&amp;amp;rsquo;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/space-koopa_hu5a04ad347ee2589302cf1ada3c228395_130058_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Mario doesn&amp;amp;rsquo;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/thank-you_hu7f88aae91c13a4ffff71119166449a0c_73671_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/woodland_hu39148852bfe8193ef55eed0344c3d387_349647_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;This is the woodland kingdom&lt;/p&gt;
    



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game Review: Super Mario 3d All-stars
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/mario-3d-all-stars/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 14:03:35 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/mario-3d-all-stars/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/nintendo-switch/&#34;&gt;got a Nintendo Switch last month&lt;/a&gt;. One of the first games I had gotten for the system was the recently released Super Mario 3d All-Stars. I had really been wanting to play Super Mario Odyssey instead, but my brother had a copy of that game that I could borrow later, so I decided to get 3dAS first, as I had never really played the 3 games on the collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly played the 2d Mario games prior to this, with the exception of 3d Land (3DS) and 3d World (WiiU), although both of those games were closer in style to the the 2d mario games than to the games in this collection. The three games here share the same style of having a hub-like world from which you visit other worlds to accomplish missions to get stars/shines. The other worlds have multiple &amp;ldquo;episodes&amp;rdquo; so you have to replay each of them a bunch of times (doing different things each time) to get all the stars/shines available in those worlds. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a clever world to save on level design resources - each world is essentially multiple stages sharing the same maps and objects and so on. It can also mean the player might get tired of repeating the same worlds over and over, but the hub system means they can visit other worlds for a while if that happens. As you gather stars/shines, you unlock more areas of the hub world and thus more worlds/stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t optimistic about SM64 going in. I played a little bit of it on the DS when it was released there, didn&amp;rsquo;t really enjoy it. Released in 1996, I know it&amp;rsquo;s regarded as a classic and revolutionized 3d platforming in its day, but for me it hasn&amp;rsquo;t really aged very well. My problems with the title are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poor camera handling. You don&amp;rsquo;t have smooth right-stick control of the camera (since the N64 did not have a right analog stick), and the camera angles are often limited in how you can rotate them around. There&amp;rsquo;s a button to toggle the camera from Lakitu perspective to Mario perspective, which is annoying for me since I don&amp;rsquo;t find the over-the-shoulder Mario perspective useful, and I accidentally keep hitting the toggle button. There is a setting to disable the Mario perspective altogether (such that the toggle button now fixes the camera to a given position instead), but the setting resets every time you load your game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even when the camera is in Lakitu mode, it will often turn or rotate far too quickly for my taste, and for me this means if I play the game for around an hour or so I start getting dizzy, and this is the main dealbreaker for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I find it quite difficult to control Mario in this game as well. His normal movement is to run, not to walk, so a simple flick of the left analog stick moves him farther than I&amp;rsquo;d like, and the same goes for his jumps. I think it&amp;rsquo;s because this was their first 3d game, so they hadn&amp;rsquo;t really calibrated yet what would be a good walk/run speed and jump distance. Adding to that, some actions like turning Mario in a new direction combined with jumping can cause him to jump in a different direction/distance, it&amp;rsquo;s something to get used to. You don&amp;rsquo;t have much jump control once you are in mid-air either. So for difficult platforming segments, I often found it challenging to position Mario for precise jumps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many of the worlds/stages are also quite frustrating. You will be dying quite often. This is unsurprising for a Mario game, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that many of the sequences are a bit long so it can be annoying to re-do them. Combined with the finnicky controls and the often weird camera angles, it can cause unnecessary frustration. Even worse, when you die, you are not just kicked back to the start of the stage, but most of the time you are kicked out of the stage altogether and back to the hub world. A minor inconvenience, but it still means additional friction in the try-fail-retry cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of try-fail-retry, a lot of the missions really require you to spend multiple lives dying and trying again. This isn&amp;rsquo;t unexpected, but a lot of them can be extremely challenging. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking in particular of that one mission where you have to race a penguin down a twisty icy slope, where veering off the slope means death. Trying to get to the end of the icy slope is bad enough - it&amp;rsquo;s going to take you a lot of trial and error to do so - but then you have to make sure you get there ahead of the penguin too. I feel like a lot of the more challenging missions carry over some of the &amp;ldquo;Nintendo hard&amp;rdquo; mentality from the NES/SNES generation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to even finish SM64 yet, so I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are a lot more challenging stages ahead. As of this writing, my progress stands at a pitiful 17 stars obtained (out of a possible 120). The dizziness due to the camera is the main problem for me. I may try to come back to it later, but for now there are better games to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Super Mario Sunshine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released in 2002 for the GameCube, Sunshine is the mainline Mario I&amp;rsquo;ve never even tried before. I later found out that Sunshine is considered one of the most difficult 3d Mario games to date. I will tend to disagree; I think the average SM64 stage is more difficult than Super Mario Sunshine, given that I was actually able to beat Sunshine. I will concede that 120-shine completion is probably very difficult for Sunshine though, but more on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunshine provides some improvements over SM64:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most significant upgrade is graphically. It&amp;rsquo;s a huge jump over SM64&amp;rsquo;s blocky polygons, and Mario&amp;rsquo;s appearance here is already pretty close to his latest modern appearances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still find walk/run controls a bit slippery, but there is significant improvement in jump control since this game gives you FLUDD (the water jetstream firing thing), which has hover functionality making it easier to make difficult jumps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsurprisingly, the most challenging parts of the game are the &amp;ldquo;secret&amp;rdquo; platforming stages where Mario is denied the use of FLUDD. These secrets usually have to be accessed at a certain point in the composite worlds. Although these secret stages are difficult, the blow is kind of softened by two things: if you die, you are returned to the start of the secret stage (instead of kicked out to the containing/hub world); and most of the stages will have one or more 1-ups available, with one easily available near the start of the stage. You&amp;rsquo;re still going to need to grind a lot to finish these secret stages, but at least you&amp;rsquo;re not likely to run out of lives doing so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also most of the game&amp;rsquo;s worlds and settings are a lot more fun in terms of ambience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, I did manage &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1314224120490389504/&#34;&gt;to beat Super Mario Sunshine a couple of weeks ago&lt;/a&gt;. I finished with around 77 shines (out of a possible 120). I may eventually come back to it for completion, although that looks challenging. The main challenge would probably be completing the blue coins in each world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Super Mario Galaxy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally released in 2007, Galaxy is easily the best game in this collection. I tried playing this back when I first got a WiiU (by borrowing the game and a couple of WiiMotes from a friend). At the time I wasn&amp;rsquo;t thrilled with the WiiMote control scheme, especially with having to use the WiiMote as an imprecise pointer, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t get far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m obviously much happier with the Switch version. In handheld mode, you use touch controls on the screen to do the pointer stuff (like to collect star bits), which is much easier and more precise than using the WiiMote (or pointing the joycon in TV mode), so that&amp;rsquo;s my preferred mode of playing the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some stages that require motion controls, where I find I need to switch to TV control. Examples are the ones where you have to control a Mario riding a rolling ball, or Mario riding a manta ray surfing along a water track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game itself is very beautiful and significantly easier (or at least, less frustrating) than the first two games. You don&amp;rsquo;t have FLUDD this time, but Mario gets a spin jump that gives him additional jump control. And longer stages now have checkpoints in between so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to start over from the beginning if you die. Many of the stages are fun to play and do a lot of innovative things like playing around with gravity and such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still some challenging stages. Two of them specifically come to mind: The first one is Galaxy&amp;rsquo;s Greatest Wave, which is one of the aforementioned ray-surfing stages. The race course is very twisty and challening, and if you take each turn too fast or don&amp;rsquo;t turn just the right amount, you&amp;rsquo;re going to be falling off. There are a number of 1-ups along the course, and I managed to get to 99 lives in trying to finish the course. My personal estimate is that I probably re-did the course at least a hundred times. The second one that comes to mind is Luigi&amp;rsquo;s Purple Coins, a stage only available after beating the game the first time. It&amp;rsquo;s a stage where you have to be constantly jumping across disappearing platforms while collecting purple coins all within a time limit. It took me a lot less tries than the ray-surfing one, but each try was exhausting since you&amp;rsquo;re jumping all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I wish they would have done for this port was add more button support for the menus, instead of having to use tap/motion control for many of them (such as when retrying a level).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1317023064555548672/&#34;&gt;finished Galaxy for the first time&lt;/a&gt; last week, and completed the bonus Purple coin missions a few days later. That makes it the first game of this trilogy where &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1318238520251621377/&#34;&gt;I hit the goal of 120 stars&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike the first two games though, Galaxy has an additional &amp;ldquo;second quest&amp;rdquo;, an additional 120 stars to be earned while playing as Luigi. Again, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably come back to this at another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Switch is a great console for these games, since I can easily pick it up at any time and play a couple of stages in handheld mode. I was worried whether this purchase would be worth it, since to be honest I&amp;rsquo;m getting a bit old and am not as good as the platforming stuff as I used to be. Platforming in 3d only adds an additional level of difficulty for me personally. But overall, it was a good purchase. I somehow managed to beat two of the games, and it was nice to see how the 3d Mario games evolve through the years. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad they didn&amp;rsquo;t include Galaxy 2, which by all accounts is as good as Galaxy was. My fingers and wrists are tired from all the jumping though, so maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll put down the Switch for a few days before I get started with Odyssey.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Late Game Review: Uncharted 4: A Thief&#39;s End
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 09:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I finished Uncharted 4: A Thief&amp;rsquo;s End yesterday, and I felt like making a post about it, since I had a bunch of screenshots. Late game review because the game came out in 2016. I think I got it from PS+? Certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first played the original Uncharted trilogy back in 2010-2011, but I found out just now while writing this post that I never finished Uncharted 3 (started yes, apparently), so that explains why some story elements seemed unfamiliar in the 4th game. (I think I may have also gotten the trilogy remaster via PS+, so maybe I should play the 3rd game too? Maybe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually have to thank the Uncharted series for getting my into this kind of single player adventure game in the first place. After Uncharted, I played some kinda similar games like Infamous, Tomb Raider etc, I was never that into the genre before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main complaint with the series is the sheer suspension of disbelief it requires to imagine a person like Nathan Drake could exist: basically a human at peak physical ability, able to fearlessly leap off high cliffs and cling onto walls with unbelievable grip and upper body strength, barely ever getting tired, while at the same time good enough at gunplay to go up against armies of battle-hardened mercenaries and come out on top. Oh, and he has an intimate knowledge of archaeology and is also able to find ancient lost treasures and cities all the time apparently. And also he&amp;rsquo;s pretty good at sketching. It&amp;rsquo;s fine, after all what are video games but power fantasies right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncharted 4 gives us a deeper look at Nathan Drake&amp;rsquo;s background and how he grew up to be like this, and we find out that not only is he this human at the peak of physical ability, he also has a brother who, despite 15 years rotting away in some backwater prison, is also at peak physical ability and also has all the rest of Nathan&amp;rsquo;s abilities (except the sketching though). (Cue Star Wars prequel meme &amp;ldquo;This is getting out of hand, now there are two of them!&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from that minor complaint, the games are pretty great though. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, the games are highly linear and story-driven, consisting of set pieces and sequences that are either platforming/exploratory (figure out how to get from point A to point B) or combat/stealth vs the aforementioned armies of battle-hardened mercenaries. Oh, and there&amp;rsquo;s the occasional puzzle too. Uncharted 4 adds some new elements such as letting you drive a car (4 wheel drive) around in what seems like an open world (it really isn&amp;rsquo;t), but it&amp;rsquo;s still mostly the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a big action game player, so I dislike the combat parts and I die a lot there. You can see in one of the screenshots later that my shooting accuracy rate was like 49%. For this reason, I&amp;rsquo;m not inclined to go for achievement completion on this one (or any of the Uncharted games for that matter), since there are many combat-related and difficulty-related trophies, and even one that requires me to finish the game with like a 70% accuracy rate. Good luck with that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dying a lot isn&amp;rsquo;t a problem, as the game is very forgiving. There are a generous number of checkpoints, and there&amp;rsquo;s really no penalty for dying too much. (Again, you can see in the stats screenshot that I failed checkpoints 105 times.) It&amp;rsquo;s kind of unavoidable with on-rails games like these - there are plenty of spots where if you don&amp;rsquo;t climb or run or jump in just the exact way the game wants, you&amp;rsquo;ll die and fail the checkpoint. It&amp;rsquo;s not super frustrating since you never really have to repeat too much, but it&amp;rsquo;s that kind of game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I guess Nathan Drake is famous now, because people know about his discoveries from the first 3 games, but I feel like he should be richer than he is portrayed. Not that he&amp;rsquo;s poor, but surely he got away with a few valuable trinkets here and there during his adventures right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Story-wise it feels like they planned this to be Nathan Drake&amp;rsquo;s final run, given the epilogue, but who knows? I mean in their universe, Sully is pretty old but he still also does ridiculous stunts with the rest of the gang. And they did introduce some new characters, so it&amp;rsquo;s not far-fetched there&amp;rsquo;ll be another Uncharted game later on, possibly with someone else as the lead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, game is pretty good, play it if you can, happy to have ticked it off the backlog! Have some screenshots:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200819161627_hue6c3d46fad30247253f2f08750550326_281237_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200819164051_hu46b1ea91c7bf31829b8523e65817aed1_284669_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200819171018_hu3cbaffc4a9258d8ccdc9fe76ff5ef790_353542_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200820145613_hu403aa6f2b7883be608292b34d31f0541_228256_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200820161032_hue6f0fc6e9cab95271fa5e49312e151f2_213537_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200821005232_hu77a464efa196223d535d5d166edbd702_249841_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824132714_hu393eb55f5daa77aa9578e357f0d401ab_256211_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824134711_hu60f27add9b976eaa32a0786b0fafffc3_359095_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824141635_hud98938188e653e52bd358edaf3726a73_235308_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824141841_hucb6379a5c5ac429b1d02a79d5e9bb792_219355_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824150416_hud82d76a20e0c21ff6f033155e898b0db_286617_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824153812_hu5c87c70b5272ab6a51e76853fd77ce96_516803_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200902155328_huc18a971ba541a72d57dc6c5d98f39d47_471881_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200902160409_hu9a09840b91ff174991e32f7dea81452a_328014_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200903175039_hu3c2c7a92b0c11ba087adae7a561ba05a_189250_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200904175427_hucb32ea5bdc2fb02d76116f411fec83b6_250565_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200907153040_hu32ec07853396cc30d7bf98038969beb3_483247_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200907154245_hu6d68b18cefb9e51e808b08e5061bdd28_382391_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200907160038_hu4b332f6f1c50aa46c7ba742bd2bd28af_353812_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200908161345_hu5166799124c3a256c98bdb0c7f9f6e6e_269790_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200908163738_hu06619873d0347acf0d171102042ab812_261645_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150307_hufe632e9a13baf3e08bccb13204b3cdd9_47663_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150314_hu1ba1ae46a319d73a2e0edad4107da04e_244973_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150318_hubbb4574ac2bcf446e9289a64bdadae3a_308505_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150405_hu9ff76feff73fe703f85ed92600715c00_113648_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150418_hu05256f8c3514656b4b5432360c346062_112211_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150432_hua574e1f093b45b31822fd1746cdf0fbb_113862_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150504_hu10f0f7c57b129ddae527f21ecafb9522_115195_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/1301222471568297984/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 18:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/1301222471568297984/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Just finished Disco Elysium. This game is fantastic&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/1301222471568297984/1_1301222471568297984_Eg7e4IYUcAADWW0_hua76e0710e968f976ea23893f5cda1dc5_127116_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/1301222471568297984/EhARAQzUcAAbS0b_hu8d807c74dc2b2922ede02aa05f7147b0_457106_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The PS3 Collection
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/ps3-collection/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 23:07:38 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/ps3-collection/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;We first got a PS3 &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/12/ps3/&#34;&gt;waaaay back in 2008&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/ps3-collection/20200826_161252_hu5ea66ec305465941528d8b86e8e14dda_1364137_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/ps3-collection/20200826_161301_hu6e6077aa3780f24640c058eb2c29ac7e_1363262_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/ps3-collection/20200826_161419_hue9fefe784ae03208e96d59f789607819_1463567_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1293051269129486337/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 05:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1293051269129486337/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Finally finished Divinity Original Sin 2. Not sure if I should do a review since due to character choices and party comp, I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve only scratched the surface of the content, and it might take a couple more runs to alleviate that. But it&amp;rsquo;s a great turn-based RPG!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1293051269129486337/1_1293051269129486337_EfHW_5QU4AA6u6i_hu56e1ca3720402fa985d25e6aa86fe8d8_125161_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Final Fantasy VII Remake
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r-review/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r-review/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Just in time for #JRPGJuly, I finally managed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/1285149646650671105/&#34;&gt;complete my platinum run for Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/a&gt;! Spoiler-free review first, then the rest of the sections are no-holds barred.&lt;/p&gt;








    
    
        
    
    
    
        
            
            
            
            
              
            
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#68003576ded7df0da42b67b1c030ba41-lightbox&#34;&gt;
                &lt;figure&gt;
                  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608080319_1_hu91758edb64f264ab371beeb7797c201b_400164_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
                  &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
                &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;68003576ded7df0da42b67b1c030ba41-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608080319_1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
              &lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;22 Jul 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;22 Jul 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;            
        
    

&lt;h3 id=&#34;spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;Spoiler-free review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is a fantastic retelling of the original FF7&amp;rsquo;s Midgar section. The plot largely tracks the original, except greatly expounded. More plot details are added to expound on character details and backstories, especially for supporting characters like Biggs, Wedge, and Jessie, and even for Shinra corporation itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game isn&amp;rsquo;t open world like FFXV kind of was; that would have been difficult given the plot they were trying to adapt, but it&amp;rsquo;s not entirely linear either. The story is divided into 18 chapters, and some of them are entirely linear, while some provide an open area littered with sidequests that you can optionally do before advancing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t much else to say story-wise without being spoiler-y, especially if you&amp;rsquo;ve played the original. If you&amp;rsquo;re new, then I can say you are in for a treat; the storyline is certainly better and less confusing than, say, FFXIII.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the original, the game is peppered with mini-games that you can indulge in and are sure to annoy completionists like me (more on that later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The combat system is something like FFXV&amp;rsquo;s real-time combat (with you controlling a single character and the others controlled by AI) mixed with some elements from FFXIII, namely the use of the Active Time Bar in order to spells or items or other special moves, and the additional stagger element around which most of the more difficult fights revolve. Unlike FFXV where you&amp;rsquo;re always controlling Noctis, you can switch controlled characters freely, or you can also issue ATB commands to the AI without shifting control. It all works very fluidly, a fun and satisfying evolution to the real-time version of the FF battle system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My one complaint would be the game limiting you to three playable characters at once, even though there are points where four are available. It&amp;rsquo;s not like their graphics engine can&amp;rsquo;t handle four player character models at once (see: FFXV), maybe it was an issue of balancing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The materia system is back! It was one of my favorite FF equipment systems, and I enjoyed it again this time around. This time however, the game is much more stingier with its special materia. For example, you can only ever get two copies of Elemental Materia (since having too many means you can abuse it against bosses), and only one copy of Magnify (equivalent to All in the original), which means only one character can use Curaga on everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normal difficulty is&amp;hellip; a bit easy. Most of the mob encounters are &amp;ldquo;mash attack, rinse and repeat&amp;rdquo;; most of the bosses are &amp;ldquo;mash attack, target weakness, repeat until staggered, use stronger attacks, repeat until victory&amp;rdquo;. Many of the bosses you can walk into the fight with your default materia settings and you&amp;rsquo;ll be fine. Maybe you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to exploit weaknesses, but the fight will still be manageable. Some of them are a bit more creative, requiring you to make use of space to avoid certain attacks and so on. Only a few boss fights were ever really troublesome. Beating the game once unlocks hard mode, more on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beating the game also unlocks chapter select, which makes it easier for completionists, since you can just replay specific chapters if you missed something. There are also additional challenges only available in hard mode post-game. I believe this is the first instance of a &amp;ldquo;mainline&amp;rdquo; (such as it is) FF game providing post-game content and chapter select.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had gotten &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/ff7r/&#34;&gt;the Deluxe Edition&lt;/a&gt;, which was only delivered to me by May 1 due to quarantine shenanigans. The steelbook is gorgeous! A worthy addition to my Final Fantasy steelbook collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My completionist run took just under 90hrs, a bit above the median according to &lt;a href=&#34;https://howlongtobeat.com/game?id=57686&#34;&gt;HowLongToBeat.com&lt;/a&gt;. I started on Jun 8th, so it&amp;rsquo;s just about a month and a half too. (Average of an hour per day!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I enjoyed the game, enough to go for the platinum trophy, despite the annoying minigames. A worthwhile retelling and addition to the FF7 universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(End of spoiler-free section)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;image-gallery&#34;&gt;Image gallery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game looks great, especially when it shifts to cutscene models. Speaking of which, the cutscene transitions are also great, they&amp;rsquo;re hardly noticeable. And your hard mode run goes much faster since there&amp;rsquo;s an option to skip the cutscenes! As always, I took a lot of screenshots along the way! &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/ff7r/&#34;&gt;Image gallery is here&lt;/a&gt;, very spoilery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;expanded-plot-and-content&#34;&gt;Expanded plot and content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who played the original will no doubt remember the major plot points. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of new scenes and story bits that weren&amp;rsquo;t in the original. Some felt a bit filler-y, like the section where you have to figure out how to get to the reactor from the underplate, or the section where you have to make your way out of the sewer. They weren&amp;rsquo;t boring or anything like that, but it did feel they were there mostly to pad the time. I mean, Shinra is about to drop the plate, but first we have to deal with these ghosts?!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of dropping the plate, the damage here felt a lot more memorable than in the original. In fact, I only remembered this happened in the OG by the time I got to that part of the story in the remake. The impact here is more severe because you spent a lot more time with the residents of the sector 7 slums, and with Wedge, Biggs, and Jessie. Their supposed deaths weighed more heavily upon me than in the OG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some plot points in this game that I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if they were in the original&amp;hellip; namely Shinra deliberately sabotaging the reactors and using Avalanche as a scapegoat to incite pro-war sentiment against Wutai. Perhaps it was intended in the OG but got lost due to translation issues? Or did they add that new detail for the remake?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I remember to be the more confusing and less-explained plot points of the original was the existence of the numbered clones; they also make an appearance here, but I&amp;rsquo;m disappointed that they weren&amp;rsquo;t really explained very well. While I understand why that is - in the OG the party doesn&amp;rsquo;t find out about Sephiroth/Jenova until near the end of the Midgar section, and the reunion part is never fully explained - I wish they could have added a bit more detail. As it is, people who are new to FF7 or don&amp;rsquo;t otherwise have context will probably be confused about who or what these numbered and hooded people are supposed to be? And why is this Sephiroth guy here, isn&amp;rsquo;t he supposed to be dead? These things are never really explained in-game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I disliked is that we didn&amp;rsquo;t get a playable Red XIII. I was wondering how they would handle this since I knew beforehand that he would be available in Midgar. I guess I can understand the decision, pacing-wise it&amp;rsquo;s weird to have a playable character only available in the last 2 chapters of the game. At least they gave us Red as an AI character and someone who can helpfull wallrun to pull levers, so that&amp;rsquo;s something I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also understand the limited number of summons we get. But we have Shiva and Ifrit but no Ramuh? Instead we get two Chocobos? Shrug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least I got to see the only enemy I really wanted to see in the remake: THE HELL HOUSE! (Now promoted to boss fight!)&lt;/p&gt;








    
    
       
    
    
    
        
            
            
            
            
              
            
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#5ea36238f8ee54ed7dfcdde426d9f813-lightbox&#34;&gt;
                &lt;figure&gt;
                  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615125524_1_hu0ce9f348cbdc7aa00ba59ae0400ebbfb_368256_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This was seriously one of my favorite random encounters in the OG due to how ridiculous it is.&#34; title=&#34;This was seriously one of my favorite random encounters in the OG due to how ridiculous it is.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
                  &lt;figcaption&gt;This was seriously one of my favorite random encounters in the OG due to how ridiculous it is. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
                &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;5ea36238f8ee54ed7dfcdde426d9f813-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615125524_1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
              &lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;This was seriously one of my favorite random encounters in the OG due to how ridiculous it is.&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;22 Jul 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;22 Jul 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;            
        
    

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hard-mode&#34;&gt;Hard mode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard mode is&amp;hellip; appropriately hard. Even normal encounters can be troublesome if you&amp;rsquo;re not careful. And boss fights are much more dangerous, and it&amp;rsquo;s much more imperative that you prepare before hand with the appropriate materia for eevery fight. The most crippling factor here is the fact that you can&amp;rsquo;t use items and can&amp;rsquo;t recover MP within a chapter. Which is a bit weird since quests and loot boxes still award you items. I understand the mode is balanced around not having items, it&amp;rsquo;s just weird. And I feel like the game could have used an intermediate difficulty step where the enemies are on hard mode difficulty but you can still use items. In fact, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have minded if that was what Normal mode was like, and Easy becomes what the actual Normal mode was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of the hard mode fights are frustratingly difficult though, as long as you are sufficiently prepared. I did have to repeat some boss fights a few times, but hard mode didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel too tedious. I guess it helped that I enjoyed the combat system?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most difficult fight in the game is a simulator fight available only in Hard Mode, called Top Secrets. This one took me a while, as I kept dying at the Bahamut+Ifrit fight when using conventional strategies. I finally managed to clear this fight using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9dYWl2PFPYc&#34;&gt;the methods outlined in this video&lt;/a&gt; (Yes, I had to Youtube), except my materia wasn&amp;rsquo;t as levelled up as his was apparently and I kept running out of MP. It still wasn&amp;rsquo;t as easy as he made it look; it took me a few tries, but once I managed to clear Bahamut+Ifrit, I was able to beat the last fight as well, albeit with only Aerith remaining alive with almost no MP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I played hard mode chapters 1-17 before grinding a bit so I could beat the Top Secrets fight, then proceeded to chapter 18 for the hard mode final boss. Having the limit break accessory from the Top Secrets fight doubtless made Sephiroth a bit easier, but it still took me a few tries, mostly because of his tendency to spam Heartless Angel in the last phase. I had Cloud, Tifa and Barret for that final boss fight, and basically configured only with HP UPs and healing abilities. I finally took Sephiroth down when I realized I should be using Magnify+Regen in the final phase and to be careful to not be in an attack animation when he starts Heartless Angel (otherwise you can&amp;rsquo;t avoid it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;platinum-completion&#34;&gt;Platinum completion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The combat was great, but the most troublesome part of completion for me were the annoying dexterity-based minigames. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason I play RPGs and not rhythm games or twitch shooters! Anyway, there&amp;rsquo;s two minigames I skipped during my first run (mostly out of frustration): the first was the darts minigame in the Seventh Heaven bar, the second was the pull-ups challenge at the Wall Market gym.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The darts minigame was easy enough when I got back to it and figured out I needed to finely control the L stick with like three fingers in order to aim the dart. The Pull-ups minigame was much more frustrating, since you basically had to make no mistakes and even then you still might not beat Jules. The Top Secrets and Sephiroth battles probably took more time, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure pull-ups took a lot more attempts.&lt;/p&gt;








    
    
       
    
    
    
        
            
            
            
            
              
            
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#88078917a8b10a4aebddf369c04ba99f-lightbox&#34;&gt;
                &lt;figure&gt;
                  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200720141722_huc36150545c942ff5f220658442dd500b_213495_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tifa when Cloud tells her to challenge Jules for the 200th time&#34; title=&#34;Tifa when Cloud tells her to challenge Jules for the 200th time&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
                  &lt;figcaption&gt;Tifa when Cloud tells her to challenge Jules for the 200th time (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
                &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;88078917a8b10a4aebddf369c04ba99f-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200720141722.jpg&#34; /&gt;
              &lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Tifa when Cloud tells her to challenge Jules for the 200th time&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;22 Jul 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;22 Jul 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;            
        
    

&lt;p&gt;I realized that the key was focus, and that meant getting rid of distractions like reducing the speech volume so you can&amp;rsquo;t hear the inane cheering (&amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s this close!&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; bro, we just started!) and not looking at your count or Jules&amp;rsquo; count during the pullups. You&amp;rsquo;re not really competing against Jules, you&amp;rsquo;re competing against yourself, so he&amp;rsquo;s only a distraction. I ended up focusing on the round timer instead of looking elsewhere to avoid distractions. Even then I was still having trouble. Finally, I took drastic measures to avoid getting distracted by Jules: I covered half the TV with a towel:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#349c9cfc2c906bf2574607e2bd6b9a90-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r-review/towel_hu13f2a9b7c18e8388634832a0453f0538_204975_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;349c9cfc2c906bf2574607e2bd6b9a90-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r-review/towel.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;22 Jul 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;22 Jul 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to beat Jules on the very first attempt after putting the towel. This was my very last trophy for completion!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;that-ending&#34;&gt;That ending&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the main story tracks the OG&amp;rsquo;s Midgar section, we get an additional boss fight that kind of mirrors the Sephiroth boss fight in the OG. I was actually worried about how they planned to do this, since restricting the story to Midgar meant the final boss would have been&amp;hellip; Rufus? Or that big robot on the highway? Either would have been lame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That ending though&amp;hellip; not going into detail, but it heavily implies that although this is a retelling of the OG FF7, events may or may not unfold as we expect. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to how they do this &amp;ldquo;Unknown Journey&amp;rdquo; moving forward. Some outcomes have already changed, as implied by several scenes in the ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;overall&#34;&gt;Overall&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, very happy with the way this remake turned out, and looking forward to the succeeding installments and how they adjust the plot from here. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping they do a good job of fleshing out the other characters like Red XIII, Cait Sith/Reeve, Cid, Yuffie, and Vincent. (Not looking forward to having to do more dexterity-based minigames at the Gold Saucer!) It&amp;rsquo;s likely that the next installment will be a next generation game; this lets Square put off an FF16 lol.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r-review/towel_hu13f2a9b7c18e8388634832a0453f0538_204975_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Final Fantasy VII Remake Image Gallery
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/</guid>
            <description>
            
            


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608080306_1_hu66f65ad081e64d8cb4a24b23f6c26d48_391437_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608080319_1_hu91758edb64f264ab371beeb7797c201b_400164_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608080513_1_hu6384f84023f00cdcc6c35283ba1b529b_428995_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608080826_1_hubf9ad5dc6af8b3f91e67018cd7533e6a_342549_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608080911_1_hu18fdd11671e4efb3474538bf897df553_343169_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608081217_1_huce3f381fcf7bc157bcf06fa812fbfa42_217385_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608081254_1_hu0c3238bbb10c99fd0a8422042744ae68_266639_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608081636_1_hu7b9ed680bdd84904787a118578d870ef_162514_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608081707_1_hu0454a26311b63acb043f5bd47682abca_212062_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608081853_1_hu1eb6e4975d654c885bbf44586a0a0497_151986_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608082133_1_hue38382e790211cf454ff0591c2b45af0_215029_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608083655_1_huba2300569a0525497dc2fcec974cb435_458562_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608083734_1_huff8b12c22aa678f1aa41ecbbf3efa454_520737_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608090036_1_huc9c45332d0f36846e80fabe50b1888b1_67324_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608090712_1_hub73cb2031e09e61f24e687978e6f11ef_190767_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608090944_1_hubecf558e9020dfa2f27bd538a40d3093_341798_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608091059_1_hu97b19a63c926f6c532c62359058ac6ce_191573_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608091450_1_hu1bef0f574fdc5dd4ae1e315f1243fc23_241872_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608091610_1_hu95f5655cf68fe61f77065de2ad839e2e_226543_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608100801_1_hu69d1a4d5e8a6b3bfdf77e2f5ab103876_293933_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608101828_1_hu28e8ead3c2f311417681e8ec16bad7e3_171634_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608102031_1_hub4339e109bc081422d15d1888a9284f1_222448_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608102306_1_hu06348419cecdf201a1f6502954522667_67529_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608103831_1_hu0bc4b97dbf12e58e8223ae73373a8301_434956_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608111339_1_huad9fb7b7afb8f4e433264dfd9abe02e8_280700_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608111958_1_hu13ab329258ae62997c974522e0b9f6c2_141631_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608112537_1_hud27654bee65f246cfbdf48099a267206_422109_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608121122_1_hu965a5fc63c9c6a6bbba9b2e0c54e48be_184908_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200608123200_1_hu01cd0550684ceb68bb79976de6d15208_252258_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609070457_1_huccb44c9e8daa14f2c5e1ddfa6dd0988f_185079_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609070535_1_hu96957d545e1da3f30faee40c4df8a006_339937_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609071214_1_hue9f87b3926dd78045c8f25481486c9b2_216797_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609071332_1_hudc52531ae04a3aff1e0f509cd6f3156e_367300_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609071341_1_hu592083b1fe1efba0f1b734a6400943a2_69340_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609071530_1_hu8810a16b572eccf5160fad26e15d44d0_235994_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609074336_1_hu40729733e6f90517a5d1ff1491a9b6f9_154085_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609074711_1_hu11ca546095aa38c4959725a05678e1fa_160246_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609074924_1_hu8319d6f8a1da533cbe52cc7a342f7256_154139_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609075044_1_hub456ac4d2166fe3c77876e4c73250315_262803_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609075548_1_hu5d9cd07d061d171effcbcf9a69829ddc_278195_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609080044_1_hue1c6d21873730939d8f35c159fdd7731_286293_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609081438_1_hue9bbb8c5bfb340c28737453def8eebc7_172425_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609081841_1_hu24c4c306737cba38bfbdfd4be09ae915_252416_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609081855_1_hubce30d8735223232242bdb161d5dd130_154927_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609081944_1_hu38903d5ce3ceed3eebaf9a8a06d1c381_177485_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609082305_1_hu0f8bf32107cdfe808f8317407157bb91_189965_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609082807_1_hu0f961e3845b953daee5ef618f0c49103_127043_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609084958_1_hu3b1f4c7a0adf42288636e592112e2ba4_185099_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609085025_1_hu14b4424d4e6eb83720ba3c7461b14f7f_244462_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609085037_1_hu049a4a57f9f3553e3ee7c73b210da309_68445_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609123426_1_hu789ccb9ed961e7d95c077ec52972d231_203590_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609123950_1_hu9b6f4863c55e421798c9d8529be0eda4_177595_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609125139_1_hud19f64a52ff4272f70a31c80a7917c13_301964_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609125927_1_huaf39244795422b0d13664e475d535cbe_346239_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609133556_1_hua99ee5312d60deeeff03b1879d90274f_66520_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609135216_1_hu14ea83ff61bc501f75b1016ef7bd05c5_268406_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200609135719_1_hu278e2209a05335fb9ec595002922a837_330262_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200610074536_1_hu4f0fe57c7d4a98dd79fcce4e27d1058f_303962_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200610074846_1_hu52a74073b72a05017f874adf98c8591c_261483_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200610081332_1_hu50f41f4c7b9981779ceb63a29725bfa7_333641_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200610081808_1_hub358ae519363695fdba7f5fc43138ef0_352726_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200610082712_1_huc71cc11a74c5291d91fc860fef1aa20b_67026_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200610091920_1_hu33f4dae2fbf204b311d9b3ff8ae5dd9e_242923_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200610094037_1_hu8874151e6d53df0eba40bde79996df82_69821_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611074342_1_huf02407c75b11183c72ca5dffa5f20637_334010_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611074350_1_hu7193689335fc52747f08800fdb5fa798_380895_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611075707_1_hubb20194474a86bcfc36600a5df3ab0bb_414954_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611081244_1_hub7902b3ea67524239ac83d4f30dd0cd1_406935_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611082754_1_hu7782e2813225cb67eef7d55508107a53_455883_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611083126_1_hufea70cda53a46aabf603d18fa5feb0c2_410919_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611084330_1_hu037a90d2b0ec221b2b4fc2167e31702c_510062_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611084836_1_hufdb065bd1c1cf12e6e5b2a5e0e3e53ee_486062_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611084937_1_hua5f13002251851b8d32fccaaa81f75b8_576158_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611091104_1_hu57dc29f3b971610df7a17918a9bd4330_304499_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611121151_1_huab04603bb37ad5f4fe473b66b3493bec_302454_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611121308_1_hu5b5a6699686c36a5123cd8b66e180c3a_539757_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611122006_1_hu9737a72b2e97f5a3f8e6637b9bf73473_261455_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200611131403_1_hued9d5dc96f1ba52310dd8a8192b1b539_359835_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615103241_1_hub5c4b2b589179f9d7996c1e5a32bddf6_477144_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615103901_1_hu8447c2ff696539da961af74dcba36f7a_270257_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615104131_1_hub5164694efc62188e8e5c690957870e9_270791_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615104217_1_huab19781f9ed9e7723cf7a0b63f2686b2_210085_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615112854_1_huea2ab232818eb8ee3936c479ea60ed43_147081_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615113301_1_huc3fb60d80a5024a85ff4855e2fc2f101_149805_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615113621_1_hua706bd520e145294356ce4c74cbb2a5b_361285_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615114559_1_hu9fe705894c60dcc40a48bd9edade5ba4_327265_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615120519_1_hucbd3e175fe70e37a77962bf234bdfcfe_247389_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615123244_1_hu69dd05d621be61c87ec9fa974f8d75b6_233375_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615123751_1_hu1259a5fe214b59ca996fb002c6877310_213316_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615124428_1_hue7d0a4c8d09abe868b696c1a4787862f_231317_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615124644_1_hu6a9a01565d8c4c61d5ad51157ca07ed2_404617_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615125524_1_hu0ce9f348cbdc7aa00ba59ae0400ebbfb_368256_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615130344_1_hu070e2541b56870d75f5681389438896c_407557_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615130648_1_hudcb2218d9857819e8832a4cf212fe846_334916_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615131559_1_hu9d583e3a895b59b09a11f9eab97d04ef_319256_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615131623_1_hu1d82cf3a7a77f877143de29d40fcd40f_201915_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200615131800_1_hufca90f0891d6ee64694a9a482ab36fde_243062_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616074428_1_hu994b55af6b2f237e64716d435040b2bc_278609_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616082744_1_hu23e39974c3dc43300eca3f3725de566b_260018_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616083952_1_hu484b59c430a5f4d79d5eaf9d27f5f83c_205481_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616083959_1_hu7750207bc0a70d426d700e7c0d0075e9_259700_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616084017_1_huf4b6fcbd42e366f453f172070964f1d2_181961_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616085100_1_hu89276a1a68c28d6d8c978766f84fbd1c_294237_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616085242_1_hueee0c39b8e3f4923f86f38cfc8154a19_254463_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616090153_1_hufacabd56cbb3f8dae3c30776c3e8652a_247733_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616090408_1_hua01404838347eacefed1190256e678bb_298941_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616091519_1_huf9c5365129544b631069bccbb1f32c8e_68152_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616121425_1_hu6eab2b462d531aa58b0eb7dafeec8fb4_217959_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616124110_1_hu1591c848b10ccea16d873728e1def71c_67451_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616124847_1_hu44f3ea5d8985509b6a8aaa7f4e9a8479_605329_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616125649_1_huba3bb20821a01e9679a8f229ad72d13b_209739_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616172857_1_huec527b59ff0aabca837977f1948ef9a6_203796_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616174440_1_hu4649bb37e7b24053ded87486f728b543_144311_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200616181530_1_hueb5fbf9e18884afb5255b4f60f262710_69767_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617120323_1_hua8eb829639a739ee740e14b670a890b4_178773_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617121115_1_hu0e9d9626f23bae093135af3ad6ab6707_129756_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617123100_1_hu80d72fe3890d74ff8c9dbc8eb9ff954f_137310_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617124012_1_hu052629074049dceba42f7151c591ab27_183131_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617124416_1_hu7a5004536536c08532fd4df42b3ba7ba_200462_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617124507_1_hu5eb89a4b3897a6741133d6b40cb6f697_171332_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617125231_1_hu0d29ab8e7eda5f6c898b9998c99a22bf_347859_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617125556_1_hue195bb6e5589e0d0b4ca80d7e922badd_139363_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617125922_1_hu7379bff4883117ffc7a7d50f54fbaca6_164315_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617125955_1_hu52b20491c5994e025b77ffb6f37bc403_67421_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617130340_1_huc3689d4ad5d741051db300bd9b099986_295138_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617131707_1_hue7c6fbd14b94e65ba4e8255730abc253_219264_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617134947_1_hu0dd7055d3d19f9a42fce496326cd0134_238876_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617140429_1_hu8895428bd14301a2d740f7becd5cf22b_98749_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617141822_1_hu61e6f97d3a5af6389bf73b72285f647b_300803_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617144433_1_hu9f56d196d386108618294ffe0cea02e8_166491_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617144536_1_huc69ea3556156a944fe0c7ba2553f1ce6_164564_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617144639_1_hu04a76bdb3950eeb9ba71529d8fc69a9a_68642_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617144942_1_hu36c295d319015b6e35fb65a85b720da1_207520_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617145021_1_hue7687d3fd6c7fe6044da19c1dd82d7f2_247046_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617145214_1_hubf89a6f96562f2c37eb33f52e17d3c23_133425_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200617145514_1_hu2f7bdf05111b9349b1c291c9e14c798c_197840_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200618072026_1_hu27ef5fbf975d2a7aceb79b264ae2ae58_257308_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200618093046_1_hufdc9b77406eb4cbf87e27af00249b074_334962_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200618133840_1_hu3cfbf7ab7c760400d328fbd1f2083ee1_359548_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200618133901_1_hue1f5f46eb530618d2e39fb70d6b61251_389691_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200618143513_1_huc5eb9b28cc4cfc75b6a1f7bcfc77b0ff_400609_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200619075440_1_huf095f403de41db4c56c9f3558abc751e_464583_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200619092954_1_hue7873f49a888c8fc567c34eb720f3fa7_311297_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200619161129_1_hu262154b10f7c686307402d8f544ab423_349515_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200620094711_1_huddb65d50a26db3cf1266721cbd6fda50_69138_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200620094742_1_hu1f5b928ce6378ce393f36b8819db5989_181217_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200620101141_1_hu697bee6824b158f92bf503059c26ff19_482349_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200620101201_1_hu9fb7ca594ac1c53f8efddc5aba63dcc3_394813_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200620101217_1_hu5bd6cfdf3a6fe03aa5701074d196229d_383075_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200620101254_1_hue2d23c11bdefc71702f0d07ca680f875_356036_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200621135955_1_hu5bfba70a187d14dcb8476e8a51d6775b_271829_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200621140017_1_hu00793857bc0cf8d031b7b551e253be9b_178594_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200621141134_1_hud1e657612dbdf3d1040ca5171794b781_254202_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200621141147_1_huc1227a48a1c13298b8465e545e7c28ee_68858_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200621141228_1_huc568091f91b5996588d76347bceb4fc3_192620_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200621141254_1_huff96a1c973a8c005bd3683a2baa45bef_225872_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200621144110_1_hud5c9ae6576488786e24c4b26e4bd5e4e_191766_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200621150300_1_hu867d91040400a2ee1ac1ea9714fd58c9_184208_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200622081915_1_hu1fbf985b8daf5ad59302ddaec681be58_260641_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200622082307_1_hudccac70690723f1aef4bdb627820fd46_334957_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200622082446_1_hu2bab8ffe2d39c3cd2ed78ede150db3d6_227408_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200622082643_1_hu4b52192eec7de8172b21ef995c92a994_353108_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200622082948_1_hufdfa2341e47961b3ce99a9e3558e9175_280328_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200622085213_1_huba34135fac57bc83d8d5c4faae80a8d7_234079_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200622114510_1_hu505e8e964ba6a26dd070fa204daa165a_384092_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200622122328_1_hucde036cac136dffd5072ad2840d4c8e5_281996_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200622215748_1_hu1513c58c5c90cd92fdafdeedfa89dbf1_229647_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200622220226_1_hucaa1ca1effb09929fecd1d8c30c48789_292947_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200622220750_1_hu82b0023dd33ac83bd09ad72b9426dd6e_325634_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200622221900_1_huc9bf4fa0e19664c888de02bf83f995f7_219657_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200622222135_1_hu89f904e10b60ef68d97d7775566fe03a_251660_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200623125821_1_hu138514dee063c5f1666cbce1ac14fbf0_134555_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200623132702_1_hue3682108f557ceb132c41f5a12997ace_177890_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200625011248_hude1d1f6e019bbae4259dd38cf7341908_380220_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200628093406_hub2808ae44af398423bc4ddff56bd7d8a_250607_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200629130820_hua5cf19b3260f63a895e0b63727ceed78_320162_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200630125217_huc75edaf804d0b7d5992805f2f4677750_288019_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200630125446_hua2b6eb4daf7beb73c8677a9876c69b2b_126017_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200630125627_hu5aa7f3a19ffd977bf643a3c2824ef9ef_156868_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200630125705_hu8e5ac24ef6cbfa4c520f8acc5f151b9c_125431_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200701120333_hu4457329514d36071f98f3fd28634c885_415693_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200701124943_hud251d99a5ff352e7169d2adbccde0d76_235913_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200701131607_hu85b1cdcd03eb00288935669955c3458b_330366_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200701132801_hue4f43eff07fdfcfac08f259911ce0e21_391304_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200702022532_hu708682bcdbb516a5ee856548604d2845_316537_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200702124319_hudb083841ccf439b0f020d61ce5477890_146267_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200702124404_hu1b3f2dd85852a22cf95f4045b8d57499_129306_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200702124424_huaf86e079f09b6aa265cafebd33604bd3_149957_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200702132843_hu3851f594865fd34ac26ce4c2d38f2d8d_334737_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200703114725_hu6dbfb73ff3015fc0133c2abf05f702fb_474743_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200703115104_hud54cf535c1391267153e609532a39461_291810_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200703150235_hu2344b4c2a92297215dc8eb174cc003d3_335868_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200703165705_hu37c65f04421af1c850e4b64e2f83b06c_365024_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200712150801_hu697e1583b13ef485bb2d32a641158b9c_211297_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200712152029_hu6b67e8b0e961dd58ac216efe9bb1ecfd_190511_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200713150852_hu7f233976bc281e00726ee08c62f62451_225770_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200713171408_hua8a0b4ae2058953f1274143747f680c9_158656_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200713171536_huec7381999f263def6a3c204742dc1e0e_161249_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200715010824_hu2f3c2cbeb83d85e506f53daaa9344475_317881_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200716152707_hua5c3e7c3bbe535450382e4c04cd01602_221159_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200720141722_huc36150545c942ff5f220658442dd500b_213495_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200720141918_huf9c97d2841500c91ca56e1bbb59c9322_208515_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200720142643_hu112633607ad708e92f4e8f8b5909d5be_306947_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200720174635_hu0b43d70a6a5c4b6295db68f0f5ad5e59_267218_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r/FINAL%20FANTASY%20VII%20REMAKE_20200720174640_hu98926894e1d9124eb102f746b92681dd_264215_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>In Which I Review Everything I Purchased from the iTunes App Store
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/itunes-purchases/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/itunes-purchases/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I was going through some old emails and found some receipts for things I had purchased from the iTunes App Store for my iPad, and I wondered how much have I actually spent on apps/games on the App Store? I went through all the receipts and decided to write mini-reviews for each item as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purchase Date&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Price (USD)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Still Available on App Store?&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010/10/30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alien Blue HD - Reddit Client (Unofficial), v1.1.0, Developer: Morrissey Exchange Pty Ltd (17+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wow, my first ever App Store purchase was a Reddit app! Appropriate since I reddit a lot. This app was much better than the official client available at the time. Eventually Reddit bought the app and phased it out in favor of a new, official Reddit client.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010/11/24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Covers of Spider-Man, v1.0, Developer: Philipp Lenssen (4+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This was some lame app that just showed you a lot of Spider-Man covers. It was an accidental purchase and the only one I ever had refunded from the app store. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I said to the support: &amp;ldquo;Someone gave me a promo code for this application (Promo code: KAP3KXHM7HH3) and I was trying to figure out how to use it from the app store and accidentally bought the app. &amp;quot; (Noob!)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010/11/27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Settlers HD, v1.0.4, Developer: Gameloft (9+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wow, I don&amp;rsquo;t remember this one at all. One of those &amp;ldquo;eh, why not it&amp;rsquo;s cheap&amp;rdquo; purchases I guess?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010/11/27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Zombie Neighborhood for iPad, v1.0, Developer: Mo-Star Information Technology Co., Ltd. (12+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;As above&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010/11/30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Secret of Monkey Island: Special Edition, for iPad, v1.1, Developer: Lucasfilm International Services Inc. (12+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the LucasArts adventure games, so I was willing to pay for the chance to play these classics on the go. As is typical of me, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I ever got around to it.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010/11/30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Monkey Island 2 Special Edition: LeChuck&amp;rsquo;s Revenge for iPad, v1.1, Developer: Lucasfilm International Services Inc. (12+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;As above.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010/12/18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Instapaper, v2.3.2, Developer: Marco Arment (4+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still using this app occasionally. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty nice, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really fit into my flow, since I tend to just read things immediately instead of setting them aside for later. That being said, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I have a bunch of still unread stuff saved here.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010/12/18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SCRABBLE for iPad, v1.1.55, Developer: ElectronicArtsBV (4+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Scrabble app situation is always a mess since the rights to Scrabble are complicated internationally. I grew up with Scrabble, but these days I just play Words with Friends.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010/12/18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Enigmo 2, v2.2, Developer: Pangea Software, Inc. (4+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I think this was some kind of physics sandbox puzzle game, sorta like Incredible Machine? I can still download it, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get back into it.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010/12/18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Heroes 2 HD!, v1.2, Developer: Pavel X (9+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lol this was some port of the original PC Heroes 2, I suspect wholly unlicensed so it wasn&amp;rsquo;t surprising that it got kicked off the store.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010/12/23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Words With Friends HD, v3.14, Developer: newtoy, inc. (4+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The original version of the app is no longer available; I believe I paid to get rid of ads. I have version 2 now, which I still play regularly, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have a record of paying for it.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010/12/25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Battle for Wesnoth HD, v1.5, Developer: Kyle Poole (9+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I was looking for some tactical battle game to play on the go, and this seemed promising, but I never got into it. It&amp;rsquo;s still available on the App Store, but might be a different SKU, as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize my previous purchase.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010/12/27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;iCab Mobile (Web Browser), v4.2.1, Developer: Alexander Clauss (17+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I believe I got this at the time because I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use Safari, and it had a download feature that other browsers didn&amp;rsquo;t have? It&amp;rsquo;s still available, but there&amp;rsquo;s Firefox on iOS now so that&amp;rsquo;s what I use.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/02/02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Penultimate, v2.2, Developer: Cocoa Box Design LLC (4+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The first of several note-taking apps I had purchased in hopes I could be a productive note taker. It was not to be. This was pretty neat though. It&amp;rsquo;s linked to EverNoteso if you use that this might be good.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/02/07&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SketchBook Pro, v1.3.1, Developer: Autodesk (4+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;There is a free Autodesk Sketchbook app still available on the store, can&amp;rsquo;t find the pro version anymore. I tried this for a bit, but had trouble with the learning curve. I eventually settled on using the Procreate app for my sketching instead; it&amp;rsquo;s really good and IDK if it&amp;rsquo;s free, but there&amp;rsquo;s no record of me ever paying for it. It&amp;rsquo;s too good to be free! Here are &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/procreate&#34;&gt;some of my sketches using Procreate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/02/11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;STREET FIGHTER IV, v1.00.06, Developer: CAPCOM Co., Ltd (12+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for Street Fighter things so I tried this out. Don&amp;rsquo;t remember much about it though.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/02/11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;World of Goo HD, v1.2, Developer: 2D BOY (4+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kinda boring for me, but my niece liked playing around with it while she was growing up, so that&amp;rsquo;s something.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/02/21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tilt to Live HD, Full Version 2.0, Developer: One Man Left&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Probably my all-time favorite iOS game, well worth the purchase. It&amp;rsquo;s simple and easy to play, but hard to master, and you can play it in short bursts easily at any time. You can hand the game to someone with minimal explanation and they&amp;rsquo;ll grok the game quickly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/02/26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Battleheart, v1.0.5, Developer: Kelli Bordner&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Maybe my second-favorite iOS game, I played this a bunch. Basically it&amp;rsquo;s party battles where you click and use abilities etc.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/05/08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Notes Plus - Handwriting, Note Taking, Shape Drawing, and Sound Recording, v2.3, Developer: Viet Tran (4+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Another note-taking app! I think I liked this one best, as I had a bunch of notes in it, but it looks they made some sort of breaking format change in 2019 and now my older notebooks can&amp;rsquo;t be viewed as notebooks in the app? Maybe I can figure it out later. I remember it had some neat features like handwriting recognition so it can automatically convert your handwriting to text? Not sure how well that worked with my chicken-scratch handwriting though.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/05/19&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Infinity Blade, v1.3, Developer: Chair Entertainment Group (9+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This was a big deal when it came out, as it was one of the first iOS games with true 3d rendering. I think I only played it a little bit.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/06/30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;STREET FIGHTER IV Volt, v1.00.00, Developer: CAPCOM Co., Ltd (9+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t remember much, purchased because Street Fighter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/07/30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;X-Men, v1.0.2, Developer: Konami Digital Entertainment (9+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I believe this was a port of the old-school X-Men arcade game. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I played this version much.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/08/26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aralon: Sword and Shadow HD, v3.12, Developer: Crescent Moon Games LLC (9+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;For a while I was hoping to find a good RPG to play on the go, but never really found the time to get into any of the ones I tried.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/08/28&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rimelands: Hammer of Thor, v1.31, Developer: Crescent Moon Games LLC (9+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;As above&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/10/13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Avadon: The Black Fortress HD, vv1.0.2, Developer: Spiderweb Software (12+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;As above. I was a fan of the SpiderWeb games back in the day, but haven&amp;rsquo;t really managed to play any of their newer games to a finish. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve outgrown them?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/10/13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dungeon Hunter 2 HD, v1.0.0, Developer: Gameloft S.A. (12+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t remember playing this at all.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/10/29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sid Meier&amp;rsquo;s Pirates! for iPad, v1.0.4, Developer: 2K Games (12+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I played the PC version of this a bunch, the iPad version not so much I think.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/12/21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Civilization Revolution for iPad, v2.2.8 (12+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Big fan of the Civ series, and getting this version was cheaper than the alternative which was on NDS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2011/12/29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Puzzle Quest 2, v1.2.0 (12+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This was a match-3 type puzzle game with a thin veneer of fantasy role-playing flavor on top of it. I played this a bunch.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2012/01/07&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MONOPOLY for iPad, v1.0.6 (4+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I think I only got this because a friend wanted to try playing remotely. However, Monopoly is a terrible board game.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2012/01/21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Comic Zeal Comic Reader, v5.0.36 (12+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Second most expensive purchase here, but one I&amp;rsquo;m still using up to now! I used to use some free open-source comic reader app whose name I can&amp;rsquo;t remember now, but I liked Comic Zeal because it had support for uploading files via web browser&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2012/02/04&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Notability, v4.1 (4+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;yet another note-taking app. Maybe someday when I actually get into a decent habit of note taking I&amp;rsquo;ll actually review them.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2012/08/05&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Another World - 20th Anniversary, v1.2 (12+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I played the original on PC back in the day. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I finished this version.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2012/12/26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;STREET FIGHTER X TEKKEN MOBILE, v1.01.00 (9+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;N&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yet another &amp;ldquo;purchased because Street Fighter&amp;rdquo;. The Vita version has served me better.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2013/01/02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Scribblenauts Remix, v2.6 (9+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Can be fun, but gets boring after a bit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2013/01/11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Baldur&amp;rsquo;s Gate: Enhanced Edition, v1.0.2007 (12+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The most expensive purchase on this list! I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished this version though.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2013/01/14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ascension: Chronicle of the Godslayer, Return of the Fallen expansion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ascension was one of the original deckbuilding games, so I wanted to try it. I played the iOS version a fair amount, since I had some other friends playing it too. Enough to justify purchasing a couple of expansions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2013/01/14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ascension: Chronicle of the Godslayer, Storm of Souls expansion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;As above&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2013/01/18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ascension: Chronicle of the Godslayer, Promo Pack 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;As above&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2013/05/28&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rebirth of Fortune 2, v1.02 (9+)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.99&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Y&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yet another &amp;ldquo;hoping I could play RPGs on the go&amp;rdquo; purchase. Don&amp;rsquo;t remember it at all.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I first got an iPad in 2010, and still use one (not the same one) up to this day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all prices are in USD because these purchases were made on the US app store; I believe there was yet no PH app store at that time. All checking of whether they are still available however, is done on the PH app store, since that&amp;rsquo;s where my Apple ID is currently linked. So maybe that causes some inaccuracy somewhere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;total amount spent over 3 years: $89.59. Which is not too bad, considering that&amp;rsquo;s roughly one and a half brand new PS4 games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;majority of the purchases (31 out of 41) are games. A lot of these games were &amp;ldquo;impulse purchases&amp;rdquo; too, unsurprising since most mobile apps are priced so low. The tradeoff for this low price is the high risk of the games going unmaintained and getting delisted. My roots as a PC/console gamer work against me, as I am apparently less inclined to play through RPGs and such on a tablet. These days I really only play free multiplayer games like Words with Friends on the iPad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;22 out of my 41 purchases are no longer available on the App Store as of today. This is one of the reasons I stopped paying for App Store things altogether: the pace of development for mobile OSes is very quick and backwards compatibility is not a priority, so apps and games can easily be out of date or no longer compatible with newer versions of the OS. For apps/games with low prices/profit margins, it&amp;rsquo;s simply not worth it to keep updating these apps/games every time, so they simply delist them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have any purchases on the Google Play store, mostly because I don&amp;rsquo;t like gaming on the phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Final Fantasy VII Remake Deluxe Edition
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/ff7r/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 12:52:14 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/ff7r/</guid>
            <description>
            
            


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/ff7r/20200501_124616_hu58879a1070aa04429423c4d88a4c2ad9_1467927_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/ff7r/20200501_124739_hub69295dfb15b65ffb7262d2886b95e69_1086150_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/ff7r/20200501_125432_hu4866b3d15f82b13fac3e326b3110ff4c_1805920_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/ff7r/20200501_125457_hu2b70ed2ea7cab83381f6391a24c91ebe_1381552_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1243803632912359424/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 07:34:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1243803632912359424/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I recorded myself struggling to beat the Cyclops boss from Megaman 1: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MiWhBlrGiK8&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MiWhBlrGiK8&lt;/a&gt; #gaming&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Upcoming Gaming Things
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/upcoming-gaming-things/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/upcoming-gaming-things/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some gaming things I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to in the coming weeks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 Mar: Historic anthology 2 and return of Historic ranked in &lt;strong&gt;Magic Arena&lt;/strong&gt;. Looking forward to new cards being added to the Historic pool!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18 Mar: Release of Federations DLC for &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/stellaris-review/&#34;&gt;Stellaris&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not planning to get the DLC, what I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to is the accompanying free patch since one of the promises is improved late-game performance, something which made playing this game very annoying during the past year. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of how Paradox does continuous content updates for their titles, even now almost 4 years after release. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably eventually get this and the other DLC at some point in the future, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I haven&amp;rsquo;t even experienced everything the base game has to offer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;31 Mar: &lt;strong&gt;Mount and Blade Bannerlord&lt;/strong&gt;. I have a friend who can&amp;rsquo;t shut up about this game and he&amp;rsquo;s been looking forward to it forever so I&amp;rsquo;m kind of looking forward to it as well. I&amp;rsquo;m not planning to buy it on release, but I hope to see if it&amp;rsquo;s good. I&amp;rsquo;ve played Mount and Blade Warband for a nontrivial amount of time, and I really enjoyed the simulation and overworld stuff, but was really bad at the combat, especially mounted combat. I hope the combat gets easier for people like me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 Apr: &lt;strong&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/strong&gt;. I recently had a convo with a friend group where one guy said we played FF7 in the summer of 95 and I was like wasn&amp;rsquo;t it summer of 96? But when I looked it up, the game actually came out Sep 1997, so we actually played it in summer of 98! Memory, how does it work? I lent out my PS4 recently and won&amp;rsquo;t get it back before April so I don&amp;rsquo;t get to try the demo, but I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the remake and already have it preordered for PS4!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I was originally planning to include this in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-08/&#34;&gt;last weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;, but I thought to separate it so it&amp;rsquo;s purely a gaming post.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Late Game Review: Tales of Berseria
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;For the past month, most of my gaming time was spent on the Steam version of Tales of Berseria, which I got from a Humble Monthly Bundle back in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary: One of the best entries in the Tales series. Has fun combat, a great cast, a darker story and a really good aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the Tales series of games, ever since Phantasia on the SNES and Destiny on the PS1, and I take the opportunity to play them whenever they come out for a console I actually have. I&amp;rsquo;m especially a fan of how their real-time battle engine has evolved over the years, and version in the Berseria may be one of my favorites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The combat balance is slightly tilted in favor of the heroine Velvet, but the rest of the party members are reasonably fun to play as well and each have their roles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I played majority of the first run on Hard difficulty, I think I dropped to Moderate a couple of times in the bonus dungeon, just to get things over with. Hard difficulty had a reasonable balance: if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t paying attention to random encounters, there was a nontrivial chance I could just die. (And I did, more than once!). You have to look out for Risky Encounters (back attacks!) or Dangerous Encounters (when you trigger more than one mob groups at the same time), as both those encounters give the mobs serious advantages. And then, there&amp;rsquo;s the Dire Foes, boss-type mobs with invincible minions that show up unannounced at the end of battle if you&amp;rsquo;re doing too well in a certain area. They&amp;rsquo;re great for farming grade later on, but the first few times I encountered one led to a game over due to me being unprepared. As you can tell, I like a bit of challenge in my random encounters, I like that if I&amp;rsquo;m not focused, I might die. For the second achievement-focused run, I played all of it on the highest difficulty (Chaos), though that was blunted by the XP boosts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the game&amp;rsquo;s cel-shaded aesthetic as well. I took a whole bunch of screenshots, you can see them later in this post!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the story is a bit atypical of Tales games where you&amp;rsquo;re usually some chosen hero out to save the world. In this case you start out more as a villain/anti-hero and are out for revenge in a Count of Monte Cristo kind of way. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely darkier/edgier than most Tales games, although there are still light-hearted moments along the way. You spend most of the story as fugitives opposing the dominant authority of the era. The rest of your party members are mostly in the same boat: rogues and escaped criminals and pirates and rebels and whatnot. It&amp;rsquo;s a refreshing change of pace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Berseria also acts as long-ago prequel for Tales of Zestiria, though the world map is mostly different (due to certain in-game events vastly changing geography at the end of Berseria), it was fun to revisit that world and remember how everything lines up with what happened in Zestiria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did two runs for the achievement completion. Total playtime came out to 119 hours, which seems like a lot, but for comparison, when I finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/01/690206344666750976/&#34;&gt;Tales of Zestiria back in 2016&lt;/a&gt;, my playtime clocked in at a whopping 472 hours (where did I find the time?!?), so Berseria actually took a lot less time. Tales games typically have a lot of super-grindy achievements, Berseria had some, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as bad as it usually was, I would guess my overall grinding specifically for achievements took less than ten hours total.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Happy to see Milla and Jude appear as cameo characters in this one, as Xillia was one of my favorite ones, and Milla may be my favorite character design in the Tales series overall. (They&amp;rsquo;re in a bunch of screenshots below!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the screenshots below, you can see that I had everyone wear Normin suits for the second run lol. I like how the Tales series has introduced cosmetics with the advent of 3d models. It&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable as DLC, since they&amp;rsquo;re not really essential, but they can also be fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what RPG I&amp;rsquo;m playing next - FF7R is coming out in April, and I already have it preordered; there might not be time to squeeze in another long one in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screenshots follow!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200119133747_1_hu1d2c80cc970471dace658b6ac2a41bb2_464824_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200119141136_1_hu4e005adfa1d1a91371c21c04df199980_319970_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200119142026_1_hu874f80eba19d8121efebb5c17e91851a_229363_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200119142305_1_hu581c9bba1e090b1cbd9c0d7028b589f0_190344_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200120203302_1_huff86b701f5770e6b23036fa0064aed9a_336105_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200120203432_1_hucf5fed4689bb210726056b5737286ee5_332179_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200120211659_1_hua80a8c243bbec4fa0702a4b9bcb930b0_293737_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200121150954_1_hu8d15ee1786434bff44d8dec98f68f171_504460_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200121152406_1_hu2ac909e448aaa2099febd666442d1672_211524_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200122173436_1_huf34c93c8dbff552a3686338b4e9e1eac_310639_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200123120108_1_hu513f1f74d7bc4a517e49c78db2433c56_375612_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200123120813_1_huf96a45fd5a873897e6c7c19f9f8d6b73_209115_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200124133522_1_hu8a11f3ac32bfa1b16baa02e0c03913c3_255082_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200125054927_1_hud0f68d0003d54cbff3dfc0d0d6c00212_285321_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200125145624_1_hue08f724f98722f60aa26e5b8d60e74cb_189828_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200125151108_1_hu9280f92a0fa67087b83ad78dd8802d84_352763_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200128070656_1_hu7511a5faf1eace5d2540a587048008a0_450370_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200130174531_1_hu508c3c03615bf6c694cf9c1d7dd51cd3_202440_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200130174719_1_hud781dd899493dd7b8d8e5d8673d8f413_303122_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200130181715_1_huc94043054c5b2f8940dd9e496b953ce4_329295_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200130182133_1_hu8089eb8ad2da63bc119f423d2e9428f7_239972_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200203203222_1_huebc408151ab625a3e6d00e692b819db8_264282_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200206082547_1_hu02ef7e1a110e77d5ab3cc033407efbbb_240360_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200206083707_1_hu602687dc5f92c2d7cc1158f3d81c201c_241323_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200206083843_1_hu18f587825f469555a810eaed8d7b091f_218543_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200206084107_1_hu91eb4f6c8808412b83706cf205eb881f_263405_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200206161636_1_hub67820f2cf24900ef628ec6cbed3271a_243381_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200207140147_1_hu2058801b3329a1257660ace75f66c9f0_235785_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200207150124_1_hu54d8cdc74906ace82acb09821eaca35b_203560_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200207172509_1_hu37c039e72fe6fd144d986d7197bb29d2_199705_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200208194905_1_hu32738891796ffbe37944b8817c45b3a8_442551_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200208201042_1_hu8cde7d1aefbc40310adea6c2930164dd_392629_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200212132521_1_hu2e0215a511bd01d3cf90705b9d6612f0_286051_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200214075418_1_huc1c3d29f7772b36a2e8d9811bb85171e_293868_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200214080236_1_hu2fac34c18e5b4754337e0d5ea4ab26bc_268254_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200214203948_1_huec88b2380f1465a248799e9519e3f765_296667_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200221133346_1_hu33a05d867b94303cea4c2f9333fde8fa_255716_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200221133458_1_hud30b746e6f7995ed434882dae57f76c6_314165_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200223175232_1_hua4ddf96d598c04ab883798f881180a8f_215855_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200223212154_1_hudc7ed94fab9faf19ebbb2b61a71ff891_332582_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200223213931_1_hu82c5c68c6ca0c391a5f583215426a868_230201_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200223233424_1_hu9d19d52c85e14aa3e905b2aad2aee917_640561_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200223234151_1_hu3390985eb6407167b8071a70b1acbdf0_463312_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200229034647_1_huf7ed2fbd5345ec82c9f1f082927e872b_282992_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200301155038_1_hu3e816b3922058584d99d90c5b6dc4081_292905_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/steam_hu72697dad1b69a28909d5d9bc3290c7bb_666314_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1235920529233776640/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 13:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1235920529233776640/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Streaming: Blind Frostpunk Run &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt; #twitch #gaming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YT mirror: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ey81Sqwoq0w&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ey81Sqwoq0w&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1227946258880499714/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 13:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1227946258880499714/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Streaming Theros Ranked Draft &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Draft went 1.5 hrs. Did I finally get to 7 wins?? &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=krWFUfJ2Cs8&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=krWFUfJ2Cs8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1227196241261551616/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 11:42:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1227196241261551616/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;More Theros Ranked Draft &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stream went 2hrs, and I completed two drafts, so you know they didn&amp;rsquo;t do well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YT mirror: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gi6RBkFutpU&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gi6RBkFutpU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1226145212956860418/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 14:06:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1226145212956860418/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Streaming even more Theros Ranked Draft &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stream recap: 1.25 hrs. Finished the prior draft 5-3, then started a new one and almost immediately lost 1-3 lol. More next week! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r43NOh1vwlA&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r43NOh1vwlA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1225047084497350656/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 13:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1225047084497350656/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Streaming some more Theros Ranked Draft &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t finish the draft, only went 5 games: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rBKgKoKxOEU&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rBKgKoKxOEU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jedi mind trick highlight: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aoKjDs1d_fg&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aoKjDs1d_fg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1224317918034481152/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 13:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1224317918034481152/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Streaming some more Theros Ranked Draft &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.5 drafts again in 2 hours for this one: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fZ5vQneGrfE&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fZ5vQneGrfE&lt;/a&gt;. Still yet to get to 7 wins, too many misplays!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1223551964446887940/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 10:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1223551964446887940/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Streaming some Theros Ranked Draft: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did one and a half-drafts for this stream, so it went 2 hours again. First draft was terrible, 2nd was much better, but ran out of time to finish it, stopped at 3-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YT mirror: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k-dheAwc4i8&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k-dheAwc4i8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Dreams: Verythepast
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/dreams-verythepast/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 01:25:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/dreams-verythepast/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I rarely tell other people my dreams anymore because it feels kind of weird, but this one was too good to pass up. It involves pro streamers and the fighting game community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in the dream for some reason I found myself attending some sort of fighting game conference and ended up in a convo with a Guilty Gear pro streamer named &amp;ldquo;verythepast&amp;rdquo; about a recent patch that nerfed a particular character. The discussion was somewhere along the lines of &amp;ldquo;why would you practice a follow-up combo after an astral chain when the astral chain always kills the enemy?&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;Astral chain&amp;rdquo; here probably refers to an instant kill move that doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually exist with that name, as that name is a different game). I commented that since the recent patch, in some instances this particular character would be able to survive against such a move and you would need a followup to finish him off. I basically got called a scrub and verythepast said that was ridiculous and he sent me a link of a video showing him upgrading to the latest patch and peforming the &amp;ldquo;astral chain&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went home a bit humiliated and decided to review the video. But when I checked the video, I saw that he only upgraded to patch 7.x.10, when the latest version was patch 7.x.12. I was a bit miffed and spent some time trying to decide whether I should just let it go or call him out publicly or what. Then the next morning I woke up and found that he had tweeted and said he had tried it out and there was indeed a bug in the latest patch that could cause the character to survive the &amp;ldquo;astral chain&amp;rdquo; and he tagged me and a couple of other guys who had pointed it out and in effect apologized to me in public, so all&amp;rsquo;s well that ends well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dream ends and I wake up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I wrote it out that doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem much. (There was some other inconsequential stuff I don&amp;rsquo;t remember like going to the toilet during the conference and there was this one guy sitting on a suitcase blocking the doorway and everyone had to walk around him, etc), but I was amused because of a few things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the username my subconscious came up with: &amp;ldquo;verythepast&amp;rdquo; (a pun on &amp;ldquo;bury the past&amp;rdquo;). I had to double check when I woke up that Google showed no such streamer. Now I want to use this username somewhere!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there was actually a detailed discussion of Guilty Gear game mechanics during the &amp;ldquo;conference&amp;rdquo;. Of course, most of it was probably inaccurate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The apology tweets by verythepast the next day were very detailed when I read them in the dream, enough for me to remember most of the text when I woke up (except verythepast tagged me as @roy instead of @roytang). It&amp;rsquo;s always nice when I&amp;rsquo;m able to read text inside a dream, because as anyone who has seen the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Perchance_to_Dream_(Batman:_The_Animated_Series)&#34;&gt;Batman:TAS episode &amp;ldquo;Perchance to Dream&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; knows: you can&amp;rsquo;t read inside a dream!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been amazed by the complex and sometimes convoluted plots that your subconscious can come up with for dreams. This one is relatively simple by comparison, but I still felt amazed at it when I woke up, enough to write this post immediately after! (Or perhaps the amazement is part of the dream??).&lt;/p&gt;


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1221047704253542400/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 12:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1221047704253542400/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Streaming some casual Theros Sealed: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt; #twitch #gaming #mtg
Stream lasted 2+ hours, but I finally managed to 7-2 a sealed, even with a crappy pool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Youtube mirror: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EU4a553Jo2o&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EU4a553Jo2o&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&lt;/a&gt;
Highlight: NIGHTMARE HORSE!! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EU4a553Jo2o&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EU4a553Jo2o&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1220722383302090753/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 14:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1220722383302090753/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Trying out some SC2 Coop Brutation &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Youtube mirror:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sbFTKVi16A0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1220674891445428225/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 11:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1220674891445428225/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Casually streaming Magic Arena with Standard Bogles &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4eKEjvQpnqQ&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1218479294990692352/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 10:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1218479294990692352/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Streaming Theros Sealed on MTG Arena again: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x-nWk7LlZJo&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1218137730519117824/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 11:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1218137730519117824/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Gonna stream some Theros Sealed, come watch me be terrible, if you like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Youtube mirror:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/L53LFr05-Yw&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1217666179646418944/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2020 04:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/1217666179646418944/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;i set up my pc for streaming and recorded did a test stream with a Slay the Spire run with the new Watcher class: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dvuTGE1lYLo&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dvuTGE1lYLo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>My Top Tens of the 2010s
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/my-top-tens-of-the-2010s/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/my-top-tens-of-the-2010s/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Apparently I&amp;rsquo;m not done looking back at the 2010s yet. I had some &amp;ldquo;top tens of 2010s&amp;rdquo; discussions with some friends recently, here are my personal lists, each in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-top-ten-movies-of-the-2010s&#34;&gt;My Top Ten Movies of the 2010s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers Endgame (2019).&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m keeping only one slot per franchise, so I had to choose an MCU movies for this. Runner-ups for this slot were &lt;strong&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Captain America Winter Soldier&lt;/strong&gt;, and individually either one of those movies might be around the same or better than Endgame, but Endgame is the culmination of a decade&amp;rsquo;s worth of movies and gave me the most enjoyment as a comic book fan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue One (2016)&lt;/strong&gt;. I really liked &lt;strong&gt;The Force Awakens&lt;/strong&gt; too, but Rogue One is easily the best of the Disney Star Wars era.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interstellar (2014)&lt;/strong&gt;. The top ten discussions led to an extended debate about some of the science in this movie, all in good fun. It requires some suspension of disbelief is needed, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a pretty good sci-fi movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Martian (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;. This one was my favorite sci-fi movie of the decade though, I&amp;rsquo;ll read the book someday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inception (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;. The fact that this movie spawned so many memes and so many debates and discussions was an indication of how good it was.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: Into The Spider-Verse (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;. The MCU was a series of great movies based on comic books, but Spider-Verse was the best movie that really feels like a comic book. (I suppose the comparison is slightly unfair since Spider-Verse has the advantage of being animated!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One Cut of the Dead (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a Japanese film I saw at Eiga-sai. If you can overcome the one-inch barrier of subtitles it&amp;rsquo;s easily one of the funniest movies I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in the past decade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logan (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;. Easily the best of Fox&amp;rsquo;s X-Men films, and among the top echelon of comic book films overall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mad Max Fury Road (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;. This was my first Mad Max film, I really enjoyed the performances and the stunts and the ridiculous vehicle scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Baby Driver (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;. Makes me want to imagine what Edgar Wright&amp;rsquo;s Ant-Man would have been like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-top-ten-tv-shows-of-the-2010s&#34;&gt;My Top Ten TV Shows of the 2010s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parks and Recreation (2009-2015)&lt;/strong&gt;. I know it started before the 2010s, but this might be appropriate anyway since the show didn&amp;rsquo;t really pick up until the third season. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of other notable comedies of its class that I really enjoyed during the last decade, such as &lt;strong&gt;30 Rock&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;, but I tip the hat to PnR because I really like the characters of Ben Wyatt and Ron Swanson and Andy Dwyer. (Apparently I really like all the male main characters except for Tom lol)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brooklyn Nine Nine (2013-)&lt;/strong&gt;. B99 is just my kind of ridiculous, similar to PnR, super quotable, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Young Justice (2010-)&lt;/strong&gt;. Young Justice is the true successor to the excellent JL/JLU of the 00s, with a deep plot full of conspiracy and betrayal, a large cast of characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daredevil (2015-2018)&lt;/strong&gt;. The Netflix shows had great promise, and Daredevil seasons 1 and 3 were among the best of them. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad that they fell to the IP disputes of their time, but who knows maybe we get to revisit them again some time in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Who (2005-)&lt;/strong&gt;. The DW revival started in the 00s, but I only started watching it in 2012, when Matt Smith was already the Eleventh. There have been some weaker seasons and episodes, but overall I enjoyed the general campiness and sci-ifi silliness of the series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black Mirror (2011-)&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m actually still not caught up with the latest season, but I have greatly enjoyed the near-future what-ifs posed by this popular show. (It&amp;rsquo;s too bad we are unlikely to heed its warnings!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breaking Bad (2008-2013)&lt;/strong&gt;. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s generally regarded as one of the best series of all time right? I haven&amp;rsquo;t even bothered watching El Camino because for me the ending of BB was already prefect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Orville (2017-)&lt;/strong&gt;. 2017 was a great year for Star Trek (-like) content, with the more serious &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; and more lighthearted The Orville both debuting. I enjoyed both shows, but the Orville&amp;rsquo;s sci-fi sitcom brought us something a lot more unique.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game of Thrones (2011-2019)&lt;/strong&gt;. Say what you will about the quality of writing (or lack thereof) for the last couple of seasons, but this was a TV series that got people obsessed and following every episode and arguing about spoilers and forming fan theories, book readers or otherwise. It pretty much defined the decade of TV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-top-ten-games-of-the-2010s&#34;&gt;My Top Ten Games of the 2010s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starcraft 2 (2010-2015)(PC)&lt;/strong&gt;. Got all 3 parts on release, and still playing it to this day (mostly coop missions - I don&amp;rsquo;t really have the heart for the stress of ladder matches anymore!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Last of Us (2013)(PS3)&lt;/strong&gt;. There are games where you&amp;rsquo;re saddened that you can&amp;rsquo;t play them again for the first time, and the Last of Us was one of the best of those.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild (2017)(WiiU)&lt;/strong&gt;. The defining Zelda of modern times. I loved the exploratory nature similar to the original NES LoZ and the cel-shaded graphics were fantastic. The sequel may yet convince me to get a Switch!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persona 5 (2017)(PS4)&lt;/strong&gt;. Easily the best JRPG of its era (sorry, Final Fantasy XV!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fallout: New Vegas (2010)(PC)&lt;/strong&gt;. Obsidian&amp;rsquo;s part of the Fallout franchise had much improved writing and questlines over it&amp;rsquo;s predecessor Fallout 3, good enough for multiple run throughs, and I even managed to finish all the DLCs as well!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Elder Scrolls: Skyrim (2011)(PC)&lt;/strong&gt;. I came late to this series with Oblivion in 2008, but it&amp;rsquo;s one of the few RPGs in this decade that I&amp;rsquo;ve replayed and finished multiple times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Witcher 3: The Wild Hunt (2015)(PS4)&lt;/strong&gt;. Easily the best PC RPG of the past decade, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t even played the expansions yet! Runner-up: Divinity Original Sin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultra Street Fighter IV (2014)(PS3)&lt;/strong&gt;. Technically, the base game came out in the 00s, but all the later revisions came out in the 2010s. This game started a fighting game resurgence that&amp;rsquo;s going on to this today. I was never super good at it, but I sure played a lot of hours and bought multiple copies of each version that came out even. The next version, SFV, hasn&amp;rsquo;t been as well received, but the franchise and the fighting game resurgence is still going strong up to now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eternal Card Game (2016)(Multiplat)&lt;/strong&gt;. This one is actually my most played Steam game of all time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sid Meier&amp;rsquo;s Civilization V (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;. Been playing this series since &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/ancient-pc-gaming/&#34;&gt;the olden days&lt;/a&gt;! Civ5 brought a pretty big change to the series with one unit per tile, and at 395 hours it&amp;rsquo;s still currently among my most played games on Steam. (Civ6 is about a hundred hours behind)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: XCom 2
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/xcom2/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/xcom2/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Kind of a late game review since this game came out in 2016, but XCom 2 is the game I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing the past couple of weeks. (the newer one, not Terror from the Deep, though that was fun too). I finished my first run yesterday, just on normal (Veteran) difficulty, nothing special, but here are my thoughts on the game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall: a fantastic follow-up to the 2012 game adding more mission variation, more unique soldier roles, more unique items, more enemies, and a more involved geoscape&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The story conceit is a lot more original than TFTD was (&amp;ldquo;Ooh, it&amp;rsquo;s like UFO Defense, except now the aliens are &lt;em&gt;underwater&lt;/em&gt;!&amp;quot;). At the start of the game, XCom is on the run in a mobile helicarrier-style base, while the world governments have struck an alliance with the invading aliens. That&amp;rsquo;s right, in this game, instead of defending the earth from the invading aliens, you are leading a plucky resistance group to liberate an already invaded earth!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the turn-based part is still pretty sweet. There are a lot of new types of missions to mix things up. Rescue missions, missions with a timer, missions where you have to avoid damaging certain things, &amp;ldquo;capture alive&amp;rdquo; missions, defense missions, escape missions, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Geoscape part is a lot more interactive now, as there is a subgame where you have to build a global resistance communications network to gain more income, at the same time responding to alien events and guerilla tactics opportunities. The aliens also trigger &amp;ldquo;Dark Events&amp;rdquo; which give them bonuses against you, and you have to complete certain missions to prevent those Dark Events. There is also a global countdown timer towards the aliens&amp;rsquo; nefarious master plan, so you always know how far you are from losing. Completing crucual missions will set back the timer, and allowing certain Dark Events to complete will move it forward faster, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of aliens, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more variation on the enemy soldier types, including new mech types, a new berserker unit (sometimes helps you if you can get it to go into a blind rage!), and a varied set of human-soldier hybrid officers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the learning curve is a bit harsh, even on the normal difficulty. I spent a few months in-game figuring things out, not really building avenger facilities optimally, not really prioritizing scientists and engineers, and getting most of soldiers wounded after every mission and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The game gets much easier as you level up and they gain new abilities, like the ability to hack enemy mech units (I was using this all the time when my soldiers got high enough hack levels), the ability for your sharpshooter to fire multiple shots as long as she keeps killing, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was of course, a ton of savescumming on my part. Maybe someday I&amp;rsquo;ll be good enough at this game to avoid that. It&amp;rsquo;s easier on the missions where there&amp;rsquo;s no timer, since you have all the time to advance your squad slowly and set up favorable ambushes, but the timed missions are a lot more challenging to get through unscathed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These feel great:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Killing an entire enemy squad with a single sharpshooter&amp;rsquo;s turn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sniping an enemy from across the map using squadsight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking control of two enemy mech units at the same time and charging them into other enemy squads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up an corridor of death where the enemies just run into my soldiers on overwatch and ambush them. I finished the final mission during the enemy turn this way (see image below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The run took me about 30 hours over two weeks (stats below). I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I have the energy for a second run right now, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll let the game rest for a while before coming back to it. I considered buying the &lt;em&gt;War of the Chosen&lt;/em&gt; expansion immediately as well, but I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll do that when I have the energy for a second run.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/xcom2/20191226125254_1_hu364901da099c20e8ea9cc68a6b6f89b4_442006_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;The corridor of death where I finished the game. Probably around 15-20 aliens died in this area&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/xcom2/20191226125703_1_hu843766f7dd0cc695b8678a552cfad71f_460266_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/xcom2/20191226125712_1_hu6d43729bd922aa93925fb07f1dbf97a6_470902_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/xcom2/20191226125732_1_hua350731eb7d057caa26691adc4a35b1c_486530_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;Final Humble Monthly Bundle &amp; First Month of Humble Choice Games Announced!&#39; on /r/Games at https://reddit.com/r/Games/comments/e72ly8/final_humble_monthly_bundle_first_month_of_humble/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/f9wl8d4/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 04:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/f9wl8d4/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;Final Humble Monthly Bundle &amp;amp; First Month of Humble Choice Games Announced!&amp;#39; on /r/Games at https://reddit.com/r/Games/comments/e72ly8/final_humble_monthly_bundle_first_month_of_humble/:

            &lt;p&gt;Are there any region restrictions for these? I&amp;rsquo;m still bitter over not getting SOULCALIBUR VI&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;Name your bot teammate&#39; on /r/gaming at https://reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/e6w3q6/name_your_bot_teammate/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/f9ti4jc/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 09:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/f9ti4jc/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;Name your bot teammate&amp;#39; on /r/gaming at https://reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/e6w3q6/name_your_bot_teammate/:

            &lt;p&gt;Someone once messaged me in Words with Friends to ask if I was a bot lol&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: The Outer Worlds
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I bought the Outer Worlds &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/b4op_a_h17a/&#34;&gt;earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;, mainly because I had been without both my graphics card and my PS4 for a bit and I kind of wanted to play a relatively new game. I got the PS4 version because I hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet replaced my video card at the time and besides, the game was not available on Steam. I guess minor spoilers follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary: A reasonable Fallout-esque RPG from the makers of Fallout: New Vegas. It&amp;rsquo;s not as expansive or quite as nonlinear as their previous games, but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty serviceable and there&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable amount of stuff to do. A decent purchase, though I chafe at buying games at full $60 price these days lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setting is a far future corporate dystopia in a remote human colony. Or at least, a caricature of a corporate dystopia. Your main enemies are evil corporations, which appeals to my recent disdain for capitalism. There are no intelligent alien races to interact with, but plently of wild animals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the space map shows something like 6-7 inhabited planets in the cluster, but you really only interact with 3-4 of them so that&amp;rsquo;s disappointing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are some gorgeous environments on those planets though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feels a bit like Fallout, with the general aesthetic hewing closely to Fallout&amp;rsquo;s 40s/50s vibe. Even the loading screens and movie advertisements are throwbacks to monster flicks from that era.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also feels a bit like Mass Effect, mainly with you getting a ship and the shuffling between worlds and the companion system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would say the companions are not as fleshed out as the Mass Effect ones though. Some of them are a lot less fleshed out than others. One of them is basically just a cleaning robot that you stuck a gun to, and he has no further storyline. Also, tbere is no companion romance option, but completing companion questlines unlocks an extra perk for them (though this isn&amp;rsquo;t clearly indicated when it happens, you have to check their status screen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phineas Welles gives a strong Rick Sanchez vibe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t a true open world, more like a forest of smaller open world areas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are a lot of quests to do, at least at the start, and they do a good job of putting the other quests in your path so that you naturally feel like you&amp;rsquo;re running into them. Towards the last third of the game, new quests seem to taper off though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actually, by the last third of the game, everything felt a bit same-y. I was definitely less enthused to play towards the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combat especially doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much variation. Either enemies run at you with melee weapons or shoot at you from afar etc. I wish I used a more sniper-rifle style with scoped hunting rifles, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t. There is a version of VATS (which only you can use so somehow its a superpower), but it&amp;rsquo;s more like a bullet time effect to help you aim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like the voice acting, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty decent, although as always it&amp;rsquo;s noticeable when multiple NPCs have the same VA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load time between areas can be a bit horrendous, sometimes as long as 1-2 minutes, or does it only feel that way?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It feels like you earn a lot of money, but there isn&amp;rsquo;t really anything to spend it on. There&amp;rsquo;s no reason to buy anything from shops, you&amp;rsquo;ll get more than you ever need just from looting and picking up stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a respec machine on your ship, which is cool, since it means you can commit skill points without too much fear of screwing up. However, I never really felt the need to respec during my run. I did respec after finishing the game to do some achievements though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level cap is 30. I did all the quests I could and I got to the cap before the point of no return, so that was annoying. I even went with nonviolent solutions a lot of the time, so if you were one of those guys who like to kill all the enemies instead, you&amp;rsquo;ll hit the level cap even earlier. You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to max a lot of skills. I like to be a &amp;ldquo;jack of all trades&amp;rdquo; kind of guy, so my skill distribution was fairly spread out and I was only able to max one skill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For some reason, the game has a plethora of consumable items. I suspect these are mainly to support the hardest difficulty (supernova), as on normal difficulty there was never any reason to use a consumable other than the standard &amp;ldquo;Heal X HP&amp;rdquo; item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished the game yesteday, on normal difficulty. I actually started out on hard, but then, surprise, I had a hard time at the start. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be too stressed so I downgraded to medium for the rest of the run. I got the &amp;ldquo;good ending&amp;rdquo;, that is to say, the one where you &amp;ldquo;defeat&amp;rdquo; the corporate master class, such as they are. Normal difficulty is relatively stress-free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually want to go for 100% achievement completion, but this game had one that requires finishing on the highest difficulty, so that&amp;rsquo;s another run altogether. Presumably the second run would be much faster since I don&amp;rsquo;t have to do everything any more. I might get around to it someday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screenshots follow!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191109171057_hu663911b70b599acb7dd198baad5634c6_454848_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191109171134_hu14460175ab9ae97c97ea443584b227b3_484835_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191109173940_hu932b1a776ae595da714c3d7295c6e1e7_356657_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191109175703_hu8ace86fdd648c1669655d5d96d533940_374896_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191109184407_hua2f7a771f97cd431e24e9a1dcb1acacb_230578_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191111095932_hu9845485e4e91ab77d5d0f79879d111ad_480484_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191111120508_hu9c31d2e12f3be6f643c41f7ec1fe0a77_236016_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191113135554_hu754cf09587d3ba5fff2970042949cd95_448388_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191114154024_hu3aae469688cad8acbabb23e4b6997cce_558086_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191115072134_hu7b373da2ffc62c7bcd253f78e499759b_509298_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191115083418_hu3564a94a499bcd16ee2e85eb131662cb_237712_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191115083933_hu8386a5886f9414a7e5d7f87af0b48321_419345_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191115090658_huc07df1a213adb0e17bc21feb79350fa5_322282_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191115203007_hued757f342709b6500649990f3a4735ac_489036_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191116112318_hud03d118e39fedb4b21900583a17de55e_587006_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191116113510_hubf261a83ab84e6950eb2700cf2daccba_284411_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191116213022_hufaaed7f1ba876af49468c5e2e9045199_228224_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191118160138_hua0f77c4f5de9b90567778da64a5906cf_200045_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191118161506_hu0ff18eddf89513573915c98db0cabace_230999_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191118163846_huee2155bb180d28214542ae4f698b7197_199251_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191119113909_hu436b725e52a12b1acd50b2f4f77ada8e_239969_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191119113929_huca52c3ab6ceb988c0bc883e29b7e93cb_502125_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191119172857_huc8dd2d2403a377c6363af479644b90f7_238307_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191120115503_hu90f0737629bc8dba5534c81c30b2e51e_261000_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191120122947_huca04fbb95b6167d2a05e76ef2e88bcd2_227799_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191120123338_hufa7cb37de4198bde3fb4802790017038_278669_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191120124351_hu1cebe49681508d34b841969428f1dab7_458665_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191120130229_hu6da4c1bd287c8b8b943d806a407a8431_404136_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191120131209_hu5682342c930fd4b453d4f5f1836d3f35_441576_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191122154310_hufe2f23568001ea38905fe484ba673ca7_637229_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191122155947_hu3c820036788856129a5fe4119f3a9cf3_225428_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191122162411_hud3692ddcfe015eabded72b3dbd9721a7_183723_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123114645_hu2276e9dd957e0d52ed0cd34950b07e27_231153_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123115759_hu08fb87ae3957848d04e4a9b830694bc3_461115_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123123630_hubc1f3809512569f1495c841924215bfd_484421_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123124235_hub9db9276f37e4552a625f46c995145d9_419966_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123182832_hu72c1e309067c92702a5925f4d96d3c41_214556_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123185642_hufa739780ca0ffd14f8668638758ba816_462145_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123195521_hu24d3c88812df506f00fd67a5ba758049_463457_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123201044_hu1b288dee1672b7712c67d4710b524a29_297596_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123210637_hu4266b9819f8cc7d34d0879f6bfe393ea_196410_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125073019_hude301703c3fa9d4566ba172969c22ce2_401104_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125073338_hu772253fce186037a95c081e999c113f8_223083_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125081214_huca414546823899a4cf4a11a71cab8eef_548485_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125145910_hu85f8334fde878031c87851aab935b58a_206279_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125151654_hu9a198a09c8e52cc3996353b8dc8e83db_289349_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125152306_hu8b8f8a12a5a772cbd1e79d456ef202fa_407402_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125152847_hua75e5dfe1f1c2426960be6c856d826bf_385317_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125153218_hu0c68d568336e6733e21f1387015b7d45_375720_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125155836_hu0da743e185f522f908cf1daa51404b78_579717_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125161516_hud308931bbe9fec99c21a397811bf8936_368844_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125162751_hu6e65543f24f8914de84fdd63e2c1f298_271572_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by TRN_WhiteKnight on &#39;Just cancelled my preorder for Overwatch on Switch&#39; on /r/gaming at https://reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/dfh5sf/just_cancelled_my_preorder_for_overwatch_on_switch/f33otuh/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/f33pdk8/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 17:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/f33pdk8/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by TRN_WhiteKnight on &amp;#39;Just cancelled my preorder for Overwatch on Switch&amp;#39; on /r/gaming at https://reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/dfh5sf/just_cancelled_my_preorder_for_overwatch_on_switch/f33otuh/:

            &lt;p&gt;they banned and revoked the prizes for a hearthstone player who spoke a slogan in favor of the hong kong protests during a livestreamed postmatch unterview&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>A Tale of Two Backups
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/two-backups/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/two-backups/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Despite my desktop PC being generally more stable after the events of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/the-great-memory-scare-of-2019/&#34;&gt;Great Memory Scare of 2019&lt;/a&gt;, I was still encountering occasionally crashes when playing games. And by crash I mean the displays dying although the PC continues to run for a short while thereafter and after which they proceed to apparently stop operating completely. It only happens when playing games, and most often when playing Magic Arena and sometimes (rarely) when playing Starcraft 2 or Borderlands 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to try swapping out the video card just yet, and I had already tried doing all the driver updates during the previous episode, I decided it was time to try a more extreme approach. I was going to re-install Windows 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say &amp;ldquo;extreme&amp;rdquo; even though reinstalling my OS is not something I wasn&amp;rsquo;t used to. Back in the days of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/12/today-is-a-good-day-to-nuke-your-xp-install/&#34;&gt;Windows XP&lt;/a&gt; I used to reinstall my OS multiple times in a year, if not in a month. It&amp;rsquo;s only unusual now because Windows 10 managed to go four whole years without giving me even a hint of a bluescreen or any sort of issue like this, so props to MS for improving the stability of their OS. That being said, running an OS over such a long period means a significant amount of cruft has probably been installed and uninstalled and reinstalled over the years, with most of the details long forgotten which leads to a sort of OS rot. So in any case, I figured a reset was due anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did the research first, and apparently Windows 10 provides the reset option itself, I didn&amp;rsquo;t need to make an install USB or anything like that. And the reset happens &amp;ldquo;in place&amp;rdquo;, theoretically without needing to reformat your partitions or displacing your user files, which was good. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t put much stock in theory, so of course for safety, I had to make a backup first. If I had needed to reset Windows 10 two weeks ago I would have been out of luck because I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have had any space to backup critical stuff. Luckily, there was a bit of coincidental foresight.&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/1172359392714358784/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2019-09-13 04:00:35&#34;&gt;13 Sep 2019 4:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I had been waffling on getting a new external HD for a while, but a couple of days ago one of my friends posted about her backup drive failing at 6yo and I was like &amp;ldquo;all my drives are older than that&amp;rdquo; lol&lt;/p&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So around last week I purchased a 2TB Seagate Backup Plus, so I had a bunch of space available for backups. Now, there is a generally recognized backup rule where any critical data should be backed up using a &amp;ldquo;3-2-1&amp;rdquo; rule; that is: 3 different places, 2 different media types, and 1 offsite. This is a bit too much for a home-based setup where my critical backups consist mostly of documents, family photos, mail archives, old chat logs and such, so I figured having two copies of the stuff I wanted backed up would be sufficient. One copy would remain on my secondary HDD on the desktop, and a second copy on my new Backup Plus. (And yes, that means I was living without the second copy before, which spoiler alert for the end of this story, was very dangerous.) In theory for anything that I didn&amp;rsquo;t mind backing up to the cloud for privacy reasons, I already had a third copy there via Google Drive and/or Dropbox, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t been too religious with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, backups created, we proceed with Operation Fresh Start:&lt;/p&gt;








    
    
        
    
    
    
        
            
            
            
            
              
            
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#4a83c7ac30ee244d164999938df27714-lightbox&#34;&gt;
                &lt;figure&gt;
                  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/1174123501470408704/EEtTGYIUwAAu1jV_hu370031b005503e42e8d76ab384a1fb83_19213_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;I am almost certainly going to regret this lol&#34; title=&#34;I am almost certainly going to regret this lol&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
                  &lt;figcaption&gt;I am almost certainly going to regret this lol (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
                &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;4a83c7ac30ee244d164999938df27714-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/1174123501470408704/EEtTGYIUwAAu1jV.png&#34; /&gt;
              &lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;I am almost certainly going to regret this lol&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;20 Sep 2019 12:00pm&#34;&gt;20 Sep 2019 12:00pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/1174123501470408704/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;            
        
    

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;20 minutes or longer&amp;rdquo; was pretty much a lie (or a programmer&amp;rsquo;s estimate, as you will), and it took more like half a day. But it went smoothly more or less. Afterwards I had to reinstall a bunch of software (more on that in the next post!). And then I tried using the PC for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my main purpose was to avoid the crashing, the first test was running Magic Arena. Sure enough, no crashes since the reset, all the games finished smoothly etc. Pretty good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for the bad news: I was getting terribly slow read/write times on my secondary 2TB HDD. At first I thought there was some ridiculousness with Windows Explorer or other background processes gumming up the worst, so I booted into Ubuntu (using a USB boot drive) to see if copying from the disk would be better there. (Side note: I miss having an Ubuntu desktop, but discretion is the better part of valor, so maybe I won&amp;rsquo;t try to dual-boot it just yet). Sadly, Ubuntu told me there were some 40,000+ bad sectors on the 2TB drive (!) which meant it was almost certainly failing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily I had the foresight to do backups beforehand and got all the critical stuff. Or not. It turns out I forgot to archives a whole 20+ gigs of photos from my Mom&amp;rsquo;s old PC after that PC&amp;rsquo;s hard drive had died. And violating the backup rule, there was no other copy of those photos anywhere else!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secondary drive was still there, so my first instinct was to power through and try to copy them off that drive but this turned out to be impractical as it was taking forever. Then I remembered that before using the old PC (which she inherited from me after I bought this current one), my Mom had been using a small ASUS netbook whose display had died. I confirmed with her that all the photos from the PC had come from that netbook, and happily I was able to boot it up and connect it to an old VGA monitor so I could copy her files from there. It took the better part of a day, but I was able to save most of her files. Whew! I&amp;rsquo;m backing these up to her Google Photos account as soon as she remembers to give me her creds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the next problemw as what to do with my current desktop&amp;rsquo;s 2TB drive. A couple of consecutive chkdsk runs (both of which took more than a workday to finish) confirmed the worst: many bad sectors and many unreadable segments. It would certainly not be prudent to continue to use it, it had to be replaced. I considered just replacing with a 500GB SSD, but I needed the 2TB capacity. Not just for the critical stuff, but mostly for game installations as well and also I had been running a Plex media server off this desktop so there were a bunch of movies and TV series eps there. It was ok to lose them to a reformat, since most of them could be re-downloaded, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t go to a smaller capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really liked the idea of getting a second SSD though (to help with load times), so I considered getting both a 500GB SSD &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; a new 2TB HDD but this was a bit of an expensive option. Then I learned about the existence of so-called SSHDs or Solid State Hybrid Drives. Basically they&amp;rsquo;re normal HDDs except they come with a small SSD cache to boost read/write speeds for commonly-used files. Basically you&amp;rsquo;re getting something a bit faster than a normal HDD, but not with the capacity costs of a full-blown SSD. Not a bad idea, and I convinced myself to try it out. The 2TB Seagate Firecuda looked like a good SSHD to try out, and it was a quite a bit less expensive than my previous option of an SSD+an HD. I wanted to get one today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, all the shops I called didn&amp;rsquo;t have any in stock, so I went ahead and ordered one from Lazada (slightly pricier). I&amp;rsquo;m a bit wary about ordering electronics online, because of warranty issues and such. But what the heck, I should risk my money every so often. Purchased! Ordering online meant I&amp;rsquo;d have to wait a few days for the delivery, so until then I have to live only with my primary 250GB SSD. Luckily this is sufficent to play Magic Arena and SC2 and write on this blog and SSH to work servers etc. I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to install most Steam games or download videos and such until the new drive gets here though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hopeful that the failing hard drive was the cause of my recent gaming crashes and that replacing it solves the issue. All of the offending games were previously installed on the 2TB secondary so it&amp;rsquo;s a decent hypotheses. Both Arena and SC2 have been behaving since I moved them to the SSD, so signs are good. That being said, this HDD failure combined with the previous episode is pretty much an indication that my PC is getting on with age. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping it will last me a few more years still, but that is more the optimist in me than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;backups good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gonna try out an SSHD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pc might be dying. Well, we&amp;rsquo;re all dying I guess&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>MTG Arena: Thoughts on Historic
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/mtg-arena-thoughts-on-historic/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/mtg-arena-thoughts-on-historic/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Magic Arena&amp;rsquo;s community was in an uproar this past weekend over the latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://magic.wizards.com/en/articles/archive/magic-digital/mtg-arena-state-beta-august-29-2019&#34;&gt;state of the beta&lt;/a&gt;, mostly over the announced plans for Arena&amp;rsquo;s eternal Historic format that will become relevant with the coming rotation. It&amp;rsquo;s likely that Wizards will backpedal in some way in response to the community, but here are my thoughts for now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;historic-cards-to-cost-double-wildcards-to-craft&#34;&gt;Historic cards to cost double wildcards to craft&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the universally-reviled bit and has been the target of much outrage, accursing Wizards of being greedy etc. On this point I am in agreement with the community that yes, this sucks. On the other hand, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned not to be outraged by ridiculous DLC/microstransaction pricing. If something is too unaffordable, I simply won&amp;rsquo;t indulge it. If I can&amp;rsquo;t afford to craft a historic deck, I won&amp;rsquo;t play the format, until I can. More on this later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WotC&amp;rsquo;s plans for Historic looks to me like they are trying to replicate the &amp;ldquo;scarcity&amp;rdquo; inherent to paper eternal formats like Modern and Legacy. Arena is actually a bit more generous that either MTGO or HS, since both of those don&amp;rsquo;t sell boosters from older sets in their stores. WotC still plans to have Historic sets available, though only in 45-pack bundles (I don&amp;rsquo;t care about this either, as I rarely purchase packs anyway, but some people also dislike this change). The 2-for-1 crafting cost is still uniquely Arena and thus their own bad decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, digital games have to have slightly different business models than IRL counterparts. Arena is unique in this regard since it&amp;rsquo;s the only modern digital CCG that has a strong paper analogue. Trying to replicate the scarcity of paper Magic may have made sense for MTGO, since that platform allows trading and thus cashing out, but for Arena it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most likely the goal is to ensure that Standard is the main gameplay mode especially for newer players, as Standard generall drives sales. But increasing the crafting cost is unnecessary. The barrier to entry for Historic will already be pretty high for a new player anyway, even if the crafting cost was 1-to-1, since a new player will have more sets to catch up with. There is no sensible reason for doing this, as it is only setting Historic up for failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;curated-cards-to-be-periodically-added-to-historic&#34;&gt;Curated cards to be periodically added to Historic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this one, the community is more split. There are those like me who consider this a good idea, as long as they are conservative with the power level of the curated cards added to historic. My personal preference is that they release cards that were pretty good in standard during their time, but haven&amp;rsquo;t really found a good place in Modern, so that they have a chance to shine. Clouding the issue is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MTG_Arena/status/1167184191215165440&#34;&gt;recent tweet by the official twitter&lt;/a&gt; where they suggest that examples of curated cards could be Brainstorm, Firebolt, Wurmcoil Engine, and Dark Confidant, all of which are at least Modern power level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who dislike this change seem to be mainly because they don&amp;rsquo;t want Historic to be Modern or Legacy. I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest, I would love it if I could play Modern on Arena. But technically, it&amp;rsquo;s not likely that the historic format will ever be the same as Modern (or Legacy), unless WotC goes crazy. It&amp;rsquo;s highly unlikely that they would add the Tron lands or Storm cards or Dredge cards into Historic for example. It would take a lot of cards for historic to even come close to Modern. But I understand the concern &amp;ndash; there are a lot of broken cards in Modern and Legacy, and WotC is made up of humans, so there is a nontrivial risk that they will screw up and add something ridiculous into Historic, breaking the format. The Brainstorm inclusion in the tweet linked above certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand the appeal of having an eternal format that is Arena sets only, moving forward. Some also want the previous Arena-implemented sets (Shadows over Innistrad, Kaladesh, and Amonkhet) to be included as well. Some prefer that Arena start adding sets one by one working backwards and stopping at Magic Origins. In general, these are all in the same vein. The idea generally is that more recent sets are more &amp;ldquo;balanced&amp;rdquo; in terms of power level, especially since Play Design is now a thing, thus the format will probably be healthier in generally than Modern which is a turn 4 format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also a secondary concern that adding curated cards so often (the initial plan is quarterly) will shake up the metagame more often and make Historic even more expensive as a format to get into, as you need to be getting new cards every so often. The assumption is that the curated cards will be high power level staples which would be necessary to participate in the format. Again, such concern could be mitigated by careful curation. If the curation is done well, each batch of new cards could introduce new strategies and make small changes to the metagame without necessarily invalidating entire decks. And again, there is a nontrivial risk of screw-ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To assuage these concerns in general, what I would do if were WotC would be to introduce two eternal formats instead. One is just Arena eternal - all Arena sets (maybe including Amonkhet, but people don&amp;rsquo;t seem to like Kaladesh very much &lt;a href=&#34;https://gatherer.wizards.com/Pages/Card/Details.aspx?multiverseid=417766&#34;&gt;for some reason&lt;/a&gt;), and a second one which is basically just what they&amp;rsquo;re already planning for Historic. More options is always better (although it might &amp;ldquo;confuse the new players&amp;rdquo;, whatever that means).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;managing-your-own-expectations&#34;&gt;Managing your own expectations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circling back to my point earlier. If Historic is too cost prohibitive, I won&amp;rsquo;t play it, until I can. In many ways, it&amp;rsquo;s a case of managing your own expectations for an online game. I like playing Magic, and Arena lets me do that at a manageable cost (i.e. free and conveniently). The addition of the Historic format doesn&amp;rsquo;t change that. I can still play Standard regardless of whether I can afford Historic or not. Until this state of the beta, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even thinking about what happens to my cards that are rotating out, whether I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to use them again or not. For most of those cards, I drafted them, I played with them, I used them with standard decks and I generally enjoyed my time playing Arena (Nexus of Fate notwithstanding). It helps that I am a f2p player, as all I invested was my time, and since I enjoyed my time, it was not wasted time for me no matter what happens to those cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;rsquo;s a different matter if you&amp;rsquo;ve been paying for the cards? IDK, I have a friend who&amp;rsquo;s bought at least a bundle every time a new set comes in, I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard any complaints from him. If you&amp;rsquo;ve invested more into this game, I get that it&amp;rsquo;s a feel bad if you can&amp;rsquo;t make the most of the game by participating in all the available modes because of cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit like Wild in Hearthstone. I played Hearthstone for a while before rotation became a thing, so I had a lot of cards that are now only playable in Wild. I don&amp;rsquo;t really play HS anymore, but in the short time when I was active and Wild was available, I probably played only a handful of games. And I never disenchanted all those cards, even if I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to play them much. I don&amp;rsquo;t care that they&amp;rsquo;re just sitting there not doing anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-conclusion&#34;&gt;In conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to how WotC responds to the outrage.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Games: What Remains of Edith Finch
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/edith-finch/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/edith-finch/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I might be lending out my PS4 next month when the latest annual release of a sports franchise rolls around, so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d finish off a PS4 game before the console vanishes on me for a few months. &lt;em&gt;What Remains of Edith Finch&lt;/em&gt; came out on PS+ a couple of months ago and people are always raving about how good it is and how it&amp;rsquo;s relatively short, so I decided to give it a go. I went in blind, not knowing anything, since mysteriously no one on Reddit could explain what makes the game good. This is understandably so as any sort of information kind of spoils the story for you. As such, consider yourself warned that this review might be considered spoiler-y. Overall if you like story-based games, just go ahead and play this one, then come back here to read the review if you&amp;rsquo;d like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-narratives&#34;&gt;1 Narratives&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Remains of Edith Finch&lt;/em&gt; is a first-person exploration game. The gameplay is largely focused around the story and advancing the narrative. The story revolves around the Finch family and their so-called &amp;ldquo;curse&amp;rdquo; which causes many of the family members to die of unusual causes. You spend the game exploring the now-abandoned Finch family house where five generations of Finches have lived since coming to America. As you explore the house you come across shrines for each deceased Finch family member, and each one takes you into a different scenario narrating their individual stories. Each family member&amp;rsquo;s story is told in a different manner: there&amp;rsquo;s one told as if it were a comic book, one told from the point of view of a baby in a bathtub, several are seen through the lens of a child&amp;rsquo;s imagination, and so on. The presentation of the substories and the main story exploring the house is very clever, with the actual text of the narratives often appearing throughout the environment, guiding you where to go next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-gameplay&#34;&gt;2 Gameplay&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gameplay is primarily based on exploration and experimentation. In the main story you explore the house and unlock secret passages and crawl through tunnels and climb to the roof and so on. There are no failure states in the gameplay, you simply keep pushing forward. If you get stuck, you walk around until you figure out a way to advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The individual substories are the same way, although many of them adjust the control schemes and expect you to experiment accordingly. As an example, in one of the substories you get to fly around as an owl, then later crawl around a cruise ship as some kind of tentacle monster. In another, you&amp;rsquo;re a baby in a bathtub imagining your toys coming to life. In yet another, you&amp;rsquo;re an assembly-line worker in a cannery dreaming of a fantasy world, and you must explore your fantasy world and slice off fishheads at the cannery at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The substories take place in their own little sandboxes, so to speak, and many of them seem like tech demos of cool things a developer would want to try like &amp;ldquo;Ooh, let&amp;rsquo;s make the player a shark on land and he has to fall into the ocean!&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s make a scenario where the player is just flying a kite!&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s not a proble, and it does create some interesting ways of presenting the narratives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this happens from the first person view, which was a bit problematic at times. Since I&amp;rsquo;m getting along with age, I&amp;rsquo;m not as good with first person gaming as I used to be, and playing with this view for an extended period of time can give me some dizziness. Luckily, the game was quite short, and I managed to finish it in two sittings. (Maybe 1.5 hours total)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-achievements&#34;&gt;3 Achievements?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually try to go for achievement completion before posting a review, especially for story-based games like this. But this time I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother. Most of the achievements are silly things that you can do during the exploration gameplay, like knocking all of the balls off a pool table. Most can be acquired after completing the game the first time, since that unlocks the ability to replay individual substories. But there was one achievement that required looking through every peephole/telescope in the game, and that seemed like I couldn&amp;rsquo;t do it without replaying everything from the beginning. That didn&amp;rsquo;t appeal to me because (a) I might get dizzy again; and (b) this is the sort of game where it&amp;rsquo;s best experienced the first time around, and successive playthroughs won&amp;rsquo;t be of much value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-overall&#34;&gt;4 Overall&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;I liked it, though not as much as say, Life is Strange. The exploration of the house is great and the all of the scenes and sandboxes are well set up and very detailed, although the overarching Finch family story is a thinly-veiled framing device to bring together the individual substories. The game is well worth the 1-2 hours to go through it.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Great Memory Scare of 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/the-great-memory-scare-of-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/the-great-memory-scare-of-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My current desktop PC has been with me since late 2015, so going on 4 years now. I bought relatively high-end parts for it at the time, hoping to be a bit future-proof so that it would last me longer than previous desktops. So I was a bit worried when I started encountering issues during the recent weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the timeline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 2019, before my overseas trip. It happened a few times that the computer would completely shut down while I was playing &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/starcraft-2/&#34;&gt;Starcraft 2&lt;/a&gt; coop. The displays would go black, but they still had power, and for a little while the OS would keep going. I know this because I could still hear the game sounds for a bit. Eventually the PC would be inaccessible, even via network. Only choice would be to hard reset. It didn&amp;rsquo;t happen regularly enough for me to figure it out before we left for the 5 week trip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;July 2019. After getting back from the trip, I encountered the Starcraft 2 issue again. Some reading indicated early concerns that SC2 may be killing video cards, but that was from 4 years ago! Besides, after my quick hard reboot, the GPU temp would be quite normal so I didn&amp;rsquo;t think that was the issue. The problem began to happen regularly, until I could not play SC2 at all. Eventually, a friend suggested I tried lowering SC2 graphics settings and surprisingly that worked! Things looked terrible, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t mind, and I could play again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EVO weekend, Aug 3-4 2019. I started playing Dragonball Fighter Z because it had a free weekend promo. I enjoyed the game and eventually bought it before the free weekend finished. The loading times were a bit long on my system, but tolerable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After EVO weekend, I tried installing Microsoft Windows update 1903, as my current version was nearing end of life. Update went smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the update, I noticed the performance of DBFZ had drastically worsened. Incredibly long loading times, occasionaly framerate drops during battles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Aug 5, first BSOD encountered:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#85c44ca416915055df00fa0efaff0f78-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/the-great-memory-scare-of-2019/bluescreen_hu952dd7ed026f0f96b5127da3081ac276_1135197_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;85c44ca416915055df00fa0efaff0f78-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/the-great-memory-scare-of-2019/bluescreen.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;22 Aug 2019 12:00am&#34;&gt;22 Aug 2019 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;because of the recent Windows update, I assumed first that was the cause of the problems. So I rolled it back first and observed the behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;over the next two weeks, additional instances of BSODs were observed, along with occasional crashes where the PC just straight freezes in place (often with annoying beeping sound) and a hard reset is needed. The crashes would happen even during normal usage (browsing etc) and sometimes even while the PC was unattended!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;last week I got fed up and started doing serious diagnostics:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I re-installed the Windows 10 1903 update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I updated my graphics drivers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I uninstalled a bunch of unnecessary old stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ran &lt;code&gt;chkdsk&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;sfc&lt;/code&gt;. System File Checker found some issues and repaired them! Maybe that fixed things? Nope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I tried running the Windows Memory Diagnostic tool. Standard check froze up the first time, but was successful on the second try.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At this point I was still hoping it was a software issue (since hardware issues generally require cash to fix), but all signs pointed to either video card (due to SC2) or memory (due to memory diagnostic failure) problems. Time to test each component in turn!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#0467e22f95d101d351c8514706ce2ace-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/the-great-memory-scare-of-2019/20190819_080244_hub4ddedb5154cb122abe7c37065511f9d_1316978_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;0467e22f95d101d351c8514706ce2ace-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/the-great-memory-scare-of-2019/20190819_080244.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;22 Aug 2019 12:00am&#34;&gt;22 Aug 2019 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no stranger to digging through computer parts, but this is literally my least favorite part of being PC master race: having to figure out which of your hardware components is failing. At least my PC case is a lot more organized and spacious this time; my older PCs had super tight layouts that were hard to manipulate
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started with the easy one: I moved my monitors to the onboard graphics card and enabled it in the BIOS. If the issue is the video card, then I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t encounter it while using the onboard graphics. Nope, had a crash less than an hour in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next we try the memory. I had two 8gb DDR3 ram sticks installed. I removed one of the sticks (pretty sure I could live on 8gb RAM tbh) and then rebooted and ran the memory diagnostics. Pass! I used the PC for one whole day with this config, even playing some SC2 and DBFZ and no issues were encountered. Things were looking up, it was likely there was a faulty memory stick!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the next day I decided to confirm it by swapping the memory sticks. Oops, now PC wouldn&amp;rsquo;t boot. Displays don&amp;rsquo;t get any signal, USB devices (mouse and keyboard unpowered). Is it because of the faulty memory stick? I swap back the &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; RAM, but still the same issue. I try a few other combinations, different RAM slots, but no such luck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This was last Monday (Quezon City holiday!). I concede defeat and acknowledge that this is beyond my power. I call up a nearby EasyPC branch and ask if they can take a look at it for me. I take a quick Grab there and the guy starts taking a look. He starts by pulling out the mem sticks and the vid card and cleaning out the connectors with an eraser. He pops out the CMOS battery to reset the board. He plugs them back in but the PC doesn&amp;rsquo;t boot. He tells me the motherboard is dead. He tries some thing with a jumper, and the MB comes back to life!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have my full 16GB back. He tells me the memory problems were probably due to the dirty connectors and suggests I take the desktop back home to do an extended memory diagnostic. I agree, since I don&amp;rsquo;t want to leave it at the shop. I happily pay the repair fee plus a small tip and take another Grab back home. I was expecting that I would have to shell out for new memory sticks as the best case! The whole process took less than an hour. This is one of those examples where I was wasting too many man-hours trying to do something myself!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back home, I run the standard Memory Diagnostic first and it passes! Hooray. I use the PC for a while, no issues. Before going to sleep, I start the extended Memory Diagnostic and left it running overnight. In the morning, it was still going around 10 hours after it started, at less than 80% of the first pass! I reduce the passes from 2 to 1, because to be honest I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to wait another 10-12 hours for a second pass! Luckily, the test finished a couple of hours later without issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hooray! All is well! Generally, at least. It&amp;rsquo;s been 48 hours and no crashes or BSODs or such have been encountered. Gaming seems fine. There seems to be a minor problem of Windows Explorer randomly spiking in CPU usage every so often, but that&amp;rsquo;s probably some software issue I&amp;rsquo;ll have to figure out independently. In any case, the Great Memory Scare of 2019 was over, and I get to keep using this desktop, hopefully for a lot longer!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a bit amused at how sad I felt when I first realized there might be a hardware problem with the PC, especially since I was hoping it would last me for years down the line. I may be a bit too attached to it lol. Well, my desktop generally does give me joy, so I&amp;rsquo;m not Kondo-ing it anytime soon!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/the-great-memory-scare-of-2019/20190819_080244_hub4ddedb5154cb122abe7c37065511f9d_1316978_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/the-great-memory-scare-of-2019/bluescreen_hu952dd7ed026f0f96b5127da3081ac276_1135197_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;No one messes with the Nords.&#39; on /r/gaming at https://reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/cndi17/no_one_messes_with_the_nords/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/ewaqetp/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 07:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/ewaqetp/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;No one messes with the Nords.&amp;#39; on /r/gaming at https://reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/cndi17/no_one_messes_with_the_nords/:

            &lt;p&gt;I wonder if they&amp;rsquo;ll bother adding some logic to the next elder scrolls where npcs get offended if you place objects on them. Otherwise people are getting buckets on their heads again.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Fighting Games
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/fighting-games/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/fighting-games/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This past weekend was &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evo_2019&#34;&gt;EVO 2019&lt;/a&gt;, the world&amp;rsquo;s biggest celebrations of fighting games. If I had stayed in the US another month maybe I could have gone to Vegas to attend and lose badly. Instead, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write about fighting games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider fighting games one of my weaknesses, in the sense that (a) I easily succumb to the temptation to spend money on them; and (b) I&amp;rsquo;m not very good at them. Example of (a): I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased Street Fighter IV on at least 4 different platforms, including all DLC. Example of (b): I have yet to advance past bronze rank in online Street Fighter V, despite having purchased the game at launch back in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many in my generation, I got my introduction to fighting games with the arcade release of &lt;strong&gt;Street Fighter II&lt;/strong&gt; in the arcades in the early 90s. Prior to that, my arcade experience had been mostly side-scrolling beat-em ups like the old &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VgF_VMQ19aA&#34;&gt;X-Men arcade game&lt;/a&gt;. I remember my brother and I literally playing the SF2 arcade release like &amp;ldquo;scrubs&amp;rdquo;, i.e., often times scrubbing our palms over the buttons trying to get moves going. Back then arcade machines didn&amp;rsquo;t come with instructions and you had to figure out how the character moves worked by experimentation. I remember he preferred playing Ryu/Ken, while I liked Guile. We didn&amp;rsquo;t really do combos, most of the time we just did Flash Kicks (which we called the &amp;ldquo;Slice&amp;rdquo;), Sonic Booms, Fireballs, and Dragon Punches most of the time. We also found it hard to understand what the Japanese characters were saying; we called Ryu&amp;rsquo;s hurricane kick the &amp;ldquo;Kat-kat-nougat&amp;rdquo; because that&amp;rsquo;s what it sounded like he was shouting! The other characters were mysteries! We didn&amp;rsquo;t know how Zangief worked for example. And I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure we never finished the arcade mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Street Fighter II eventually got a home release, I remember playing it for the first time at a friend&amp;rsquo;s house when he got his copy first. We would be playing SF2 on the SNES a lot. I remember the annoyance when playing SF2 at another person&amp;rsquo;s house, I&amp;rsquo;d have to configure my controller because I didn&amp;rsquo;t use the default button layout. I used a layout called &amp;ldquo;YXLBAR&amp;rdquo; (with the heavy attacks on the SNES shoulder buttons) instead of the default &amp;ldquo;YLXBRA&amp;rdquo;. Rumor has it someone used an insane layout like &amp;ldquo;YBAXLR&amp;rdquo;. I also remember seeing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uY0KBMkvDyo&#34;&gt;arcade intro for the updated &lt;strong&gt;Super Street Fighter II&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and being so amazed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#9255053aacc428b06549560c2419f614-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/fighting-games/ssf2shinkuhadouken_huf0b9fa7f4cb0977fcabeeae76d376d02_338304_300x0_resize_box.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;9255053aacc428b06549560c2419f614-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/fighting-games/ssf2shinkuhadouken.gif&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;7 Aug 2019 12:00am&#34;&gt;7 Aug 2019 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried out some other fighting game franchises on SNES too, like the Japanese &lt;strong&gt;Dragonball Butoden&lt;/strong&gt; series, a TMNT fighting game, and the &lt;strong&gt;Justice League Task Force&lt;/strong&gt; fighting game. On the PC, we also had a copy of &lt;strong&gt;Mortal Kombat&lt;/strong&gt; 1. I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure our PC could handle color back then, we may have been playing Mortal Kombat in black and white! We also didn&amp;rsquo;t have controllers for the PC back then, so we had to play with two players to one keyboard, and if you held down four buttons or more on your side, the keyboard couldn&amp;rsquo;t register any more additional inputs so your opponent couldn&amp;rsquo;t move!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from playing with my brothers, me and some HS friends often got together at a friend&amp;rsquo;s house and would be playing fighting games &amp;lsquo;til the early morning hours. We got to try a lot more fighting games in the PS1 era, since games were cheaper in the PH then. A lot of it was still capcom stuff: &lt;strong&gt;Street Fighter Alpha 3&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;Street Fighter EX&lt;/strong&gt; series, &lt;strong&gt;Rival Schools&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Darkstalkers&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Xmen vs Street Fighter&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Marvel vs Capcom&lt;/strong&gt; 1. There were also the games that were similar in command style like the King of Fighters series and Guilty Gear. We would also sometimes try the 3d games like &lt;strong&gt;Tekken&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Soul Edge&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Virtua Fighter&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;Battle Arena&lt;/strong&gt; Toshinden but those played a lot differently than SF-style games and they never really caught on with our group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PS2 era brought with it one of our most played games of all time: the legendary &lt;strong&gt;Capcom vs SNK 2&lt;/strong&gt;. With a ridiculous 48 characters and six different &amp;ldquo;grooves&amp;rdquo; or playstyles to choose from, there was a lot of variety in the game and we rarely got tired of it. The &lt;strong&gt;Street Fighter III&lt;/strong&gt; series also came out at around the same time, but we never got too much into it because &lt;strong&gt;New Generation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Second Impact&lt;/strong&gt; only had home releases on Dreamcast; I remember we did play &lt;strong&gt;Third Strike&lt;/strong&gt; for a while, but that was quickly overshadowed when CvS2 came out. There were a lot of other Capcom/SNK/other fighting game releases we tried out at this time too, but CvS2 was the main one I remember from this era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the PS3 era came &lt;strong&gt;Street Fighter IV&lt;/strong&gt; and a new dimension: online play! This is where I got my first indication that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very good at fighting games, despite enjoying them so much. I was fine when playing on the couch casually with my friends, but online was another matter entirely. I remember being so frustrated at the &amp;ldquo;ten wins in a row&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;get C rank for all characters&amp;rdquo; achievements in SF4 because of how difficult they were. Around this time, my brother and I also tried attending a local tournament or two, but we did poorly. During this era, I also tried out games like &lt;strong&gt;Blazblue&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Injustice&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Persona 4 Arena&lt;/strong&gt;, and so on. (ArcSys really got it&amp;rsquo;s groove in this era as far as I&amp;rsquo;m concerned.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was during this era that I started preferring fight sticks as well. I bought my first fight stick for the PS3, and I found I liked it a lot more than playing with a controller. My play group still prefers controllers, so when I meet up with them I have to suck it up, but at home and for online play I&amp;rsquo;m usually on a fight stick. This generation also marked the first time for me to play the &lt;strong&gt;Smash Brothers&lt;/strong&gt; series via the Wii U installment, but I never could get the hang of that game either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally that brings us to the PS4 era and of course &lt;strong&gt;Street Fighter V&lt;/strong&gt;. SF5 isn&amp;rsquo;t too popular these days, mainly due to some balancing issues and lack of innovation,making the game feel stale, but it&amp;rsquo;s still very hype at EVO. My old play group doesn&amp;rsquo;t get to play much anymore, mostly because the one who usually brought the console has moved abroad, but we still manage to meet up at least once a year or so and put up our fighting dukes. I still play SF5 online, though not as often as I did with SF4. Matchmaking is a lot tougher, probably because I&amp;rsquo;ve been stuck at bronze level all this time. I still get hyped for fighting games when EVO rolls around, and I&amp;rsquo;m always tempted to buy these flashy new fighting games that come out. Just this weekend I purchased &lt;strong&gt;Dragonball Fighter Z&lt;/strong&gt; on Steam after trying it out for the free weekend and enjoying it. It helps that it has a lot of nice single-player content so I can justify the cost even if I don&amp;rsquo;t win/play online too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why am I so bad at fighting games? I&amp;rsquo;m sure part of it is old age - these days my reaction time isn&amp;rsquo;t as good as I&amp;rsquo;d want it to be (maybe it never was?!?). A large part of it is due to laziness - fighting games take a lot of practice, and you need a lot of experience to do well online. You also need to put in the time in training to be able to pull off execution of more complicated moves like &lt;a href=&#34;https://streetfighter.fandom.com/wiki/Focus_Attack#Dash_Cancelling&#34;&gt;SF4&amp;rsquo;s famous FADC&lt;/a&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to really play fighting games all the much anymore. I was doing slightly better online during the PS3 era because my play group and me and my brothers were still playing regularly, but with SF5, I don&amp;rsquo;t really have anyone to practice offline with on a regular basis, and just spending a lot of time in training bores me, so here we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I still enjoy playing fighting games so much even though I&amp;rsquo;m bad at them? I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about this a lot, and I think the main reason other than general competitiveness, is that I enjoy the spectacle (these days at least). It&amp;rsquo;s one of the few genres where I can truly appreciate the over-the-top graphics and cool moves and supers and so on. When I get a new fighting game and try out a new character one of the first things I do is try to get a super off to see how cool it is. I also enjoy the variance in game play - which is why I prefer fighting games with larger rosters like CvS2, and I especially like it when there is a random character select option. When my play group meets up, we always do random character selection where possible, it exposes us to all the characters and everything the game has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years it has become easier to enjoy fighting games even if you&amp;rsquo;re not good at them or you don&amp;rsquo;t have much time to play, since there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more tournaments these days and many of them are live-streamed and available to watch on demand online. I still want to play the games, but when I can&amp;rsquo;t find a match, watching tournament play is a good alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My reflexes can only get worse as the years pass, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll still be playing fighting games for years to come, and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably buy Street Fighter VI day one when it comes out for the PS5 or whatever. I may not have the skills to be the world champion in fighting games, but I&amp;rsquo;ll always be a street fighter at heart.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/fighting-games/ssf2shinkuhadouken_huf0b9fa7f4cb0977fcabeeae76d376d02_338304_300x0_resize_box.gif&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Civilization, Liberal Democracy, and Authoritarianism
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/civilization-liberal-democracy-and-authoritarianism/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/civilization-liberal-democracy-and-authoritarianism/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I remember when playing the original version of Civilization &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/ancient-pc-gaming/&#34;&gt;back in the day&lt;/a&gt;, the &amp;ldquo;most advanced&amp;rdquo; form of government was Democracy, with the only downside of it being you can&amp;rsquo;t declare war (because you had a senate that would stop you.) The other available forms of government were typically not very useful, but Democracy massively increased your trade output, so most often I would build the Pyramids (a wonder which allowed switching to any government immediately and without penalty), and spend the rest of the game toggling between Democracy and Despotism (for when I wanted to go to war).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This made the game heavily slanted in favor of Western-style democracies, which was understandable for that time period. Around that era, the Soviet Union had just fallen, and the liberal democracy practiced by the United States, the one remaining superpower, became the shining example of a successful government that brought propserity to its citizens. I think that having grown up in this era and having been exposed to a lot of American culture (via TV and games and so forth) has led to my general bias in favor of liberal democracy and the values associated with it - freedom, equality, civil liberties, human rights, due process, checks and balances, separation of powers, and so on. (I cannot say the same is true for other people in my generation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, the modern versions of Civilization have matured in terms of how they handle governments, recognizing that modern governments have different approaches that are not necessarily represented by &amp;ldquo;democracy&amp;rdquo;. Civ 6 presents three choices for modern governments: Democracy, Communism, and Fascism; Civ 5 lets you choose between ideologies: Freedom, Order, or Autocracy. Perhaps this is a reflection of modern geopolitics, where not only is the United States teetering on the brink of authoritarianism, despite being the lone superpower, but those daring to challenge its hegemony are leaning more towards authoritarian governments as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from America&amp;rsquo;s traditional enemies like Russia and Iran, the starkest challenge comes from China, the juggernaut of Asia. Perhaps the ultimate counterexample to the idea that liberal democracy is the key to prosperity, China has been able to bring an economic boom to its citizens, leveraging the weight of a billion-person size market, all while retaining the trappings of power centralized in the state instead of the people. Censorship, propaganda, and adherence to the party are the norm, and those who dare speak out against the party are punished viciously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about all of this after a recent discussion with some Duterte supporters over at &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/philippines&#34;&gt;r/PH on reddit&lt;/a&gt;. The arguments in favor of the Duterte administration seem to stem around seeing him as a leader that &amp;ldquo;gets things done&amp;rdquo; (in quotes because I&amp;rsquo;m not sure quantifiably that he is getting things done more than other presidents), without regard for the damage to liberal values such as human rights, due process, checks and balances, and so on. Indeed even during the 2016 elections you could see some internet commentary stating that the problem with the country was that we had &amp;ldquo;too much freedom&amp;rdquo;, as if freedom were not an ideal to be aspired to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this light, the tendency of this admin to capitulate to China has an ideological angle as well, because China is the epitome of getting things done despite the cost to civil liberties, and of the state accumulating all power onto itself. It is disturbingly a trend not only in the Philippines, but even in a number of Western nations, where far-right parties with tendencies towards extreme nationalism and authoritarianism are gaining steam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been of the opinion that the world mostly exists in a state of trying to find balance; most trends wax and wane, trying to find the optimal equilibrium in which to settle. I worry that perhaps liberal democracy&amp;rsquo;s peak days have come and gone, and we are now on the brink on an era where authoritarianism gains ground. I had always hoped that our future was somehow leading to something like a Star Trek-like utopia, but there are plenty of other potential sci-fi future scenarios, not all of them pleasant. We can only hope that things get better before they get worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m not a political science expert or anything, so probably I&amp;rsquo;m not exactly using some of these terms accurately, feel free to educate me in the comments if you like.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Street Fighter Background Wallpapers
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I often prefer having a randomly changing background wallpaper, even back in the day when Windows didn&amp;rsquo;t support it natively and I had to install various plugins to support it. I like the variance! The one I&amp;rsquo;ve been using recently was this set of wallpapers based on Street Fighter stage backgrounds, which I got from a reddit thread that I unfortunately can&amp;rsquo;t find anymore (I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post if I find it later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I also took this opportunity to install a Hugo gallery plugin for this sort of thing. Credits to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/liwenyip/hugo-easy-gallery/&#34;&gt;Hugo Easy Gallery&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: Found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/StreetFighter/comments/9i5y65/street_fighter_3_enhanced_stage_wallpapers/&#34;&gt;the link to the reddit thread&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit 2020-09-23: To reduce the number of shortcodes used on the site, I decided to just include the wallpapers as inline image resources.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/1%20-%20CWZzhn3_hu2682fef87b60c855c1cf330457a949fa_2836115_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/1%20-%20ustHrs6_hu5455b7fa699de8b613ceaa6ac54119f2_2227975_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/2%20-%2054jBfp6_huf2eeb635f9eaba3a92ff073aa6c11ee9_299957_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/2%20-%20qKkTjEn_huc37a6602e1dd2304b930d6941b321bd5_3132664_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/3%20-%20M0XzSDD_hu282c42a706faf12050bed979fa954f68_2098317_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/3%20-%20xEV5Qg1_hudebe3b4ae54ca38d44bd7e0f34cc93e5_2031057_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/4%20-%20Bxm6xPA_hu43b16bd826a7c92b3390ec3afe6f0759_2473219_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/4%20-%20ENNvoPS_hu51ede7303b9dc88c5eeac65ed7a75462_2483186_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/5%20-%20MVlPaKt_hu198a764508bd9d03933c0376a71d8f19_1687243_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/5%20-%20aZuy9Pt_hu4b46763c1355c21a32255a8fb47fe4e3_1856758_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/6%20-%20YOvQWgL_hu632f17887b30d67a10f66dbe8a8c69e1_2884677_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/7%20-%20kh6v3Jb_hu315638922c33ed36f7011b526f1778f8_2701508_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/8%20-%20e7evPvz_hu58ef431fbf92e00f549cb736d8b7f87a_2001557_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/9%20-%20TtZp0yn_huba32638f333893bee9cfc34ab2e5747f_2448919_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/street-fighter-background-wallpapers/akuma_huea4ae1a734875733ab1d618a4bfb717e_2012198_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Mobile games have a short shelf life
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/mobile-games-have-a-short-shelf-life/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/mobile-games-have-a-short-shelf-life/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Rami Ismail of Vlambeer &lt;a href=&#34;https://variety.com/2019/gaming/features/android-ios-apple-google-game-dev-problems-1203191551/&#34;&gt;points out some of the problems with the mobile app ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;: platform SDKs update so often, so older mobile games often break, such that the reasonable option is to make freemium games that you update continuously rather than single purchase games that won&amp;rsquo;t work a year later unless you burn capital on them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; Im just a little wary of the smartphone market right now. I dont currently feel at ease developing for those platforms because the SDKs change, their hardware specs change and when you dont update the game just breaks.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed this a while back when I was looking at what games I had previously purchase for my iPad on Apple&amp;rsquo;s App Store and found that many of the older purchases are either no longer available for download or simply don&amp;rsquo;t work anymore. (I imagine that Android has a similar issue, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never purchased anything from the Play Store, so I won&amp;rsquo;t bother to check.) For this reason, I have resolved never again to pay for any games on mobile. (Actually the last purchase was as far back as 2013).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike consoles where the platform SDK is locked in for an entire generation, mobile app SDKs are updated on a regular basis, which means mobile game devs need to support the equivalent of new console platforms more than once a year. Mobile gaming fares even worse than PC gaming, despite the wide variety of PC configurations, the software-level support for games is pretty much standardized at the OS-level and companies like Microsoft are careful to support backward compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my pipe dreams is of course to get into game development, and for a while I considered mobile as a possible option for that (if I ever get around to it), but with the state of the ecosystem these days that seems unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Starcraft 2
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/starcraft-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/starcraft-2/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been nine years since Starcraft 2: Wings of Liberty came out, and the last expansion Legacy of the Void came out four years ago in 2015. I bought all three releases as soon as they came out and recently found the boxes while spring cleaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#9516ab30707fbe7faa61047ebc0c6c7e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/starcraft-2/starcraft2_huc24b8781521256c3c224ea15a10b49d3_70781_300x0_resize_q75_box.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;9516ab30707fbe7faa61047ebc0c6c7e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/starcraft-2/starcraft2.JPG&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Apr 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;18 Apr 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the game&amp;rsquo;s age surprisingly people are still playing it, including me. Not for the ranked ladder - whenever I go into the competitive multiplayer mode I find myself stressing out and feel like my blood pressure is going up and I can&amp;rsquo;t manage more than one or two games at a time. I still am able to find ranked matches, but they always feels so intense, and you have to worry about being cheesed and yes I often do poorly. The mode I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying these days is Starcraft 2 Co-op, a mode which was released together with Legacy of the Void. Some friends of mine have been playing the coop mode recently and I got enticed to join in on the fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically there are mission maps similar to the campaign missions, except they require two players working together to accomplish objectives. You can choose between a few difficulty levels and play with friends, or queue up to be matched with anons. There are a number of different coop commanders available with different army compositions and special abilities. Completing missions gains you experience for the commander you chose, which lets you level them up to gain upgrades. A few come fully unlocked, some are unlocked because I had purchased all three campaigns. The ones that are locked you can still play up to level up, after that they need to be purchased for $4.99 per commander. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of content too even after you&amp;rsquo;ve maxed the levels, as there are mastery and ascencion levels to be climbed, and there are weekly &amp;ldquo;mutation&amp;rdquo; variants that are much more challenging than the normal missions. One thing I like about Starcraft 2 is that there are a lot of achievements, and that includes coop mode too so that adds a lot of replay value for me as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been enjoying the mode, and due to various freebies, I initially had nine commanders unlocked. I enjoy playing a variety of styles so I levelled them all to max, and the mode is fun enough that I am considering purchasing a few of the locked commanders as well. (Maybe all of them!) It&amp;rsquo;s a lot less stressful than ranked, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about being cheesed (and sometimes you get to do the cheesing yourself!), and a lot less toxic, people are generally friendly and don&amp;rsquo;t blame you too much for screwing up. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit old so my reflexes probably aren&amp;rsquo;t good enough for ranked anymore, but I&amp;rsquo;m happy I can still play in real-time well enough for the highest difficulties of coop mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was some discussion in in-game chat about how the game was &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo;, but these sentiments seemed to come mostly from people who preferred competitive multiplayer modes, so maybe not many people are playing ranked anymore? But coop seems to be going strong - I never have trouble matching up even with anons. Apparently Coop mode has been profitable enough for Blizzard that they&amp;rsquo;ve still been releasing new content for it fairly recently, last year saw the release of the latest coop commander Zeratul, and there are more commanders rumored to be in development. So I guess somehow the business model is working for them which is great since it gives the game legs to go on for a few more years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note: I really dig the packaging for all 3 SC2 games and am glad I got them physical copies. There are some nice artworks on the boxes and some inserts with a bit of lore, and Legacy of the Void even came with some free codes for WoW and Hearthstone (I wonder if I can still claim this free pack lol)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#ca94d5dee527178ec49432151619b7c0-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/starcraft-2/starcraft2_packaging_hua0a6cb034bb25cf60534af269223a5b8_298612_300x0_resize_q75_box.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;ca94d5dee527178ec49432151619b7c0-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/starcraft-2/starcraft2_packaging.JPG&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Apr 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;18 Apr 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/starcraft-2/starcraft2_huc24b8781521256c3c224ea15a10b49d3_70781_300x0_resize_q75_box.JPG&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/starcraft-2/starcraft2_packaging_hua0a6cb034bb25cf60534af269223a5b8_298612_300x0_resize_q75_box.JPG&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Google Stadia
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/google-stadia/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/google-stadia/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, Google officially announced their much-rumored streaming game platform, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ign.com/articles/2019/03/21/google-announces-its-video-game-platform-stadia&#34;&gt;Google Stadia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initial thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If this works out, it will greatly lower the barrier for access to AAA games, since people won&amp;rsquo;t have to buy desktops or consoles anymore, and you would be able to game on laptops without worrying about overheating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sadly like many online services, it will probably be a while before it even becomes available over here in the PH (I believe even Sony&amp;rsquo;s Playstation Now is not yet accessible here)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One would presumably worry about how well it would work with the limited bandwidth available to third-world countries like ours, but I had this worry too when Netflix first became available here, and that worked out fine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of Netflix, if Stadia manages to have a Netflix-like unlimited access service, that can only mean my gaming backlog is going to get a lot worse!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Zero Time Dilemma
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;With the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/rip-ps-vita/&#34;&gt;PS Vita recently being discontinued by Sony&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to work on reducing my Vita backlog a bit. One of the games I&amp;rsquo;d been meaning to play for a while now was Zero Time Dilemma, the third game in the Nonary Games trilogy. I&amp;rsquo;ve only previously played the 2nd game in the series, Virtue&amp;rsquo;s Last Reward, which is a bit appropriate given how the events in these games often unfold nonlinearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#eec3f3dcaf74c2aba71bfe2db6d3e39e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/ztd-phi_hu2d16a9ba67469bfb9806d424cff0a232_107631_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;eec3f3dcaf74c2aba71bfe2db6d3e39e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/ztd-phi.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;20 Mar 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;20 Mar 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ZTD is pretty good, but the story is understandably complex, given how it builds off a series of games that already involved espers and time travel and multiple timelines and cults and world pandemics and so on. It didn&amp;rsquo;t help that it&amp;rsquo;s been 4-5 years since I played VLR, and that game already had an overly complex plot so I can barely remember the details from that game as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s a story-based series, the gameplay largely consists of two parts: (a) escape rooms; and (b) decision-making. The escape rooms part are entertaining enough, nothing too difficult, but satisfying enough to solve everything. The decision-making part is used to unlock branching timelines, and the path to the &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; endings is determined by your ability to find the correct decisions to unlock the correct events. Not all decisions are binary or multiple-choice; some of the more important ones require text or numeric input, making it impossible to guess them. At multiple points, you will need to reference information learned from other branches of history (don&amp;rsquo;t worry, there is a story reason for why this happens).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Took me a couple of weeks of playing sporadically to finish the game. I enjoyed the game enough to spend a couple of late nights to finish it once I got really going. I will shamefully admit I did get stuck in one place and in my impatience I googled my way past it. Still, a platinum is a platinum:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#464ea2382226fa4e0d255676200af297-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/ztd-platinum_hud697a1a6556e2713bcac2e1fabb23b1f_93213_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;464ea2382226fa4e0d255676200af297-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/ztd-platinum.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;20 Mar 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;20 Mar 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, given how old the first game is, it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely I&amp;rsquo;m going to get to complete the trilogy. There&amp;rsquo;s still a couple of other Vita games I want to play as well (notably, I&amp;rsquo;m still in the middle of a 3-year old Tales of Hearts R run), so maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get around to those&amp;hellip; someday!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/ztd-phi_hu2d16a9ba67469bfb9806d424cff0a232_107631_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/ztd-platinum_hud697a1a6556e2713bcac2e1fabb23b1f_93213_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>RIP PS Vita
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/rip-ps-vita/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/rip-ps-vita/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.polygon.com/2019/3/2/18246372/playstation-vita-canceled-discontinued-production-ended-ps-vita-sony&#34;&gt;The PS Vita has officially ended production.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadness for the little handheld that could. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/02/i-have-a-psp/&#34;&gt;PSP&lt;/a&gt; that came before it was a juggernaut, and so was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/06/handheld-gaming-2013-playstation-vita-vs-nintendo-3ds/&#34;&gt;3DS it went into battle with&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately Sony never gave the Vita proper support, and third parties didn&amp;rsquo;t follow, so the handheld never lived up to its true potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t had much opportunity for handheld gaming the past few years, since I don&amp;rsquo;t travel as much anymore. But I still pick up my PS Vita every so often, much more so than my 3DS (which my niece has absconded with anyway). And I still have a few more games there I consider part of my backlog I want to someday finish. (Namely &lt;em&gt;Tales of Hearts R&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Zero Time Dilemma&lt;/em&gt;, at the very least) And my Vita is still doing pretty well, no obvious issues, so I&amp;rsquo;m hoping it can stick around for a long while.&lt;/p&gt;








    
    
        
    
    
    
        
            
            
            
            
              
            
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#64dda6d554d77f6a8f0b3b69064f7470-lightbox&#34;&gt;
                &lt;figure&gt;
                  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/bujac3rbrht/7d850d59c2b4f6da13f02cfe894469c8_hu8ccc3d6e6f50f5aa0069b29cd9cd0b4c_61991_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;RIP Ps Vita which was discontinued last week (mine is still going strong!)&#34; title=&#34;RIP Ps Vita which was discontinued last week (mine is still going strong!)&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
                  &lt;figcaption&gt;RIP Ps Vita which was discontinued last week (mine is still going strong!) (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
                &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;64dda6d554d77f6a8f0b3b69064f7470-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/bujac3rbrht/7d850d59c2b4f6da13f02cfe894469c8.jpg&#34; /&gt;
              &lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;RIP Ps Vita which was discontinued last week (mine is still going strong!)&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;5 Mar 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;5 Mar 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/bujac3rbrht/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;            
        
    




            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>