<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>jamesbond on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/jamesbond/</link>
      <description>Recent content in jamesbond on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 23:26:51 +0800</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/jamesbond/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Reviews: Skyfall, Jumanji: Welcome to the Jungle, Police Story
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/reviews-skyfall-jumanji-welcome-to-the-jungle-police-story/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 23:26:51 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/reviews-skyfall-jumanji-welcome-to-the-jungle-police-story/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;h3 id=&#34;skyfall-2012&#34;&gt;Skyfall (2012)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 23, Daniel Craig&amp;rsquo;s third. I watched this in the theaters back in 2012, so this is the last rewatch of my James Bond run. Back then my main complaint was that &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/11/264691037212131328/&#34;&gt;Bond&amp;rsquo;s plan in the last thirty minutes of the movie was terrible&lt;/a&gt;. The same complaint stands even now, especially given the eventual outcome of that plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole film is basically a swan song for Judi Dench&amp;rsquo;s M, exploring the extremes of her relationship with Bond and how fond they are of each other in spite of everything. Ben Whishaw appears as the new Q, who starts his run appropriately, by letting MI6 get hacked. The film still calls out the old Bond film tropes, with Q telling Bond they&amp;rsquo;re not really into exploding pens anymore. Bardem gives a good performance as the villain Silva, but the character felt a bit underdeveloped as we didn&amp;rsquo;t get his background until an info drop around two-thirds through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This film also brings cyberterrorism into the modern Bond era, and the usefulness of MI6&amp;rsquo;s focus on human intelligence during the modern era is called into question. It will be interesting to see how technology further changes the Bond films moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film ends with basically the Connery status quo - Bond answering to a male M, flirting with his assistant Moneypenny, and assisted by Q. It&amp;rsquo;s something I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have appreciated back when I first saw the film in 2012, given that this was only the 4th Bond film I&amp;rsquo;ve seen at that point, and none of them had that Connery setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is &lt;strong&gt;Spectre&lt;/strong&gt;, which I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen before and is the last one of the run before &lt;strong&gt;No Time To Die&lt;/strong&gt; comes out in September!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;jumanji-welcome-to-the-jungle-2017&#34;&gt;Jumanji: Welcome to the Jungle (2017)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched this even if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen the old first movie. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a high opinion of The Rock, er&amp;hellip; Dwayne Johnson&amp;rsquo;s acting skills, because I&amp;rsquo;ve previously seen him only in silly sports films like The Game Plan or The Tooth Fairy, but he does a good enough job here, portraying a nerdy high schooler trapped in a buff, macho, adventurer hero type. Same goes for Jack Black portraying a teenage girl in&amp;hellip; well, Jack Black&amp;rsquo;s body. I like how the Jumanji game evolved from a board game to a video game for more modern times. The movie overall is a pretty good popcorn movie and has a few funny bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;police-story-1985&#34;&gt;Police Story (1985)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was just something that I saw was on Netflix and was like &amp;ldquo;Why not?&amp;rdquo; Had to watch with Cantonese voice and English subs, the only alternative was Japanese voice. Pretty good, for its time. As you&amp;rsquo;d expect from Jacky Chan, all the action/fight sequences are great; I especially like the bus chase sequence and the ending fights in the mall were great. Apparently that sliding down the pole stunt is considered one of the best action film stunts of all time. The film glorifies police excesses though.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Quantum of Solace
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/quantum-of-solace/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 16:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/quantum-of-solace/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 22, Daniel Craig&amp;rsquo;s second outing. I actually &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/11/996918103/&#34;&gt;watched this back in 2008&lt;/a&gt;, but apparently I wasn&amp;rsquo;t super impressed (and I wish I wrote more back then lol). I suspect I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like it because this movie is actually a direct sequel to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-casino-gunpowder-halloween-masters/&#34;&gt;Casino Royale&lt;/a&gt; which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen until this year. It picks up on several hanging plot threads, and some of the characters appear again, and Bond in this film is primarily motivated by anger over the events of the previous film. Not to mention I had only seen two Brosnan movies prior to watching Quantum of Solace at that time, so I really didn&amp;rsquo;t have either the franchise foundation or the context from Casino Royale to appreciate this film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This film sets up more of the gritty tone for modern Bond. Unlike the black and white factions of the cold war, the geopolitical setup here is more complicated, with even Bond&amp;rsquo;s traditional allies the CIA mostly turning against him. The villain&amp;rsquo;s plot and motivations seem kind of thin and the plot itself is a bit forgettable; while I recall many of the scenes from my previous watching, I didn&amp;rsquo;t remember what the overall plot was until it just happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olga Kurylenko gave a great performance here. The film also has some great action sequences, and even hits the trifecta of land, sea, and air chases/vehicle fights. The theme song here is &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Another Way to Die&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; by Alicia Keys and Jack White (of the White Stripes), which was ok but I didn&amp;rsquo;t particularly enjoy. Stana Katic makes a bit appearance here towards the end, before her run on &lt;strong&gt;Castle&lt;/strong&gt;. Also I just chuckle to myself whenever Bond tries to use a 2008-era dumbphone like it was a modern smartphone, such as taking pictures good enough for facial recognition from like a hundred feet away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the movie is a decent watch. Overall I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying modern Bond, but I have to admit I kind of miss the campy tropes of classic Bond, but I can understand why they&amp;rsquo;d have no place in a modern action franchise. I mean, Craig still hasn&amp;rsquo;t even got a Q or any fancy devices! (Yes, I know he gets a new Q eventually). Anyway, next is Skyfall!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reviews: Casino Royale, Gunpowder Milkshake, The Long Halloween, Masters of the Universe Revelation
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-casino-royale-gunpowder-milkshake-the-long-halloween-masters-of-the-universe-revelation/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-casino-royale-gunpowder-milkshake-the-long-halloween-masters-of-the-universe-revelation/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve watched lately. Spoilers for Gunpowder Milkshake and MotU: Revelation are marked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;casino-royale-2006&#34;&gt;Casino Royale (2006)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 21, and the first for Daniel Craig. The final era in this James Bond run, looking forward to it. Casino Royale is new to me, but I&amp;rsquo;ve seen two of Craig&amp;rsquo;s Bond films, so I have an idea of what to expect: a more serious and much less campy James Bond, grim and determined. The tone here is much closer to Dalton&amp;rsquo;s two films than any of the other runs. Since it&amp;rsquo;s kind of a reboot, it takes place early in Bond&amp;rsquo;s career, in fact he earns his double-O status right in the cold open. Craig&amp;rsquo;s Bond is younger, brasher, more vulnerable, and a bit more prone to mistakes, like letting himself getting caught on camera assassinating a prisoner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme song here is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YnzgdBAKyJo&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You Know My Name&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by Chris Cornell of SoundGarden fame. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit more alternative than recent theme songs; I like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judi Dench is back as M, the only actor carried over from previous incarnations. We don&amp;rsquo;t get any of the usual support staff like Moneypenny or Q. Bond spends most of the first half of the film alone in the field, and the second half supported by treasury agent Vesper Lynd (played by Eva Green). Mads Mikkelsen plays the protagonist, terrorist financier Le Chiffre, who Bond challenges to a high-stakes poker game at the titular Casino Royale. Also making an appearance is an old Bond ally, CIA&amp;rsquo;s Felix Leiter, who we last saw mauled by a shark in Dalton&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/4e93006d466cb2f6a53325cba8e27b63/&#34;&gt;License to Kill&lt;/a&gt;. (He has been recast as a black man for the modern age of James Bond.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot is reasonable and action-packed. Daniel Craig probably feels the least &amp;ldquo;Bond-like&amp;rdquo; compared to what his predecessors have established for the role, but his Bond is pretty good and is portrayed as relentless and unstoppable, in spite of his mistakes. The on-foot chase scene in Madagascar near the start of the film is great, especially all the crane shots. Le Chiffre seems a bit incompetent for a villain. The final third of the movie (after the poker game) plays out a bit strangely, for a while I was like &amp;ldquo;What the heck is going on?&amp;rdquo; There is a betrayal in the end that I didn&amp;rsquo;t see coming, which erased any doubt in my mind whether I had actually watched this one in the theaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to the rest of Craig&amp;rsquo;s run!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gunpowder-milkshake-2021&#34;&gt;Gunpowder Milkshake (2021)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We watched this during our Saturday online gaming session watch-along. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have high expectations for the film, as I thought it was kind of an ultraviolent grim John-Wick style thing and I didn&amp;rsquo;t really think Karen Gillan and Lena Headey would be good to lead that kind of movie. It does turn out to be ultraviolent, but not super grim, and in fact maybe even a little goofy. There are some great action sequences and fight scenes here, but as soon as I saw that 
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    Karen Gillan was going to have a fight scene in the doctor&amp;rsquo;s office with her arms all floppy from anesthesia
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
, I was like, ok this movie is already worth watching. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a very deep, complicated plot or anything, but overall a decent popcorn watch. A fun, ultraviolent, very bloody, very much not for kids movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;batman-the-long-halloween-2021&#34;&gt;Batman: The Long Halloween (2021)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a 2-part entry to the DC Universe animated movie line, an adaptation of the famous comic of the same name by Jeph Loeb and Tim Sale. The story covers an early year of Batman&amp;rsquo;s career as he works with Captain Jim Gordon and then-district attorney Harvey Dent to face both the Gotham mob and a serial killer that kills once a month, on the holidays. The film mostly covers the same story beats as the comic (which I had to review because it&amp;rsquo;s been probably more than a decade since I read it!), with a bit of a twist towards the end of the first part that changes the eventual ending in the second part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t help but compare this storyline to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/07/movies-the-dark-knight/&#34;&gt;The Dark Knight (2008)&lt;/a&gt; as it covers some of the same elements: organized crime in Gotham and the origin of Two-Face among others. In fact I believe the comic book was one of the inspirations for Nolan&amp;rsquo;s eventual plot for TDK. I would guess that TDK changes were largely due to the need to focus on The Joker, who is more of a minor villain The Long Halloween, and I can&amp;rsquo;t help but imagine what if Nolan had chosen to stay more faithful to TLH storyline, what kind of movie could we have gotten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this particular animated version is pretty good, mostly faithful to the source material, and I like the animation style here. Jensen Ackles is a serviceable Batman voice, and Troy Baker is a pretty good Joker; for a moment I wondered if it was Mark Hamill in the role. Part one was released back in June, and part two just last week, so I only watched both parts today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the next DCU animated movie project is &lt;strong&gt;Injustice&lt;/strong&gt;, based on the game series of the same name, also looking forward to that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;masters-of-the-universe-revelation-season-1-part-1&#34;&gt;Masters of the Universe: Revelation (season 1 part 1)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also watched this during Saturday&amp;rsquo;s watch-along. This one is a bit controversial, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write about it even though technically the season is only halfway through. The controversy is because the show&amp;rsquo;s plot mostly focuses around Teela and a quest she undergoes after the events of the first episode: 
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    He-Man and Skeletor are presumed dead in a battle and Teela leaves the service of King Randor out of anger over having Adam&amp;rsquo;s secret withheld from her for so long.
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voice work is pretty good; we immediately recognized Lena Headey&amp;rsquo;s voice as Evil-Lyn, and Mark Hamill as Skeletor is unmistakeable. We didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize Sarah Michelle Gellar as Teela though! The storyline so far is okay, though not super original. It kind of felt like a typical JRPG party-gathering and going on a quest thing, really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of old fans didn&amp;rsquo;t like the focus being taken away from He-Man and focusing on a female character, which many imagined as purely a diversity play. I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s much too early to judge the season overall, since it&amp;rsquo;s only halfway through, but even then, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong about focusing on some other characters, as the show is explicitly titled &amp;ldquo;Masters of the Universe&amp;rdquo; without the &amp;ldquo;He-Man and the&amp;hellip; &amp;quot; prefix. It&amp;rsquo;s probably best to see where Kevin Smith takes us for the eventual second part (for which we have no release date yet).&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reviews: Die Another Day, Army of the Dead, Valerian, Superstore, Omelas
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-die-another-day-army-of-the-dead-valerian-superstore-omelas/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 02:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-die-another-day-army-of-the-dead-valerian-superstore-omelas/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I used to do these &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Watching Lately&amp;rdquo; posts&lt;/a&gt; to talk about movies/tv/books I&amp;rsquo;d recently consumed, but for a while I folded up the reviews into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/weeknotes&#34;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; and sometimes via short &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes&#34;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; but the reviews have been getting longer so I guess I&amp;rsquo;m bring the &amp;ldquo;Watching Lately&amp;rdquo; tag and series of posts back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;die-another-day-2002&#34;&gt;Die Another Day (2002)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 20 and Brosnan&amp;rsquo;s final appearance. The main question for me going in was: have I actually watched this before in the theatre? My memory says no, but this movie does have the ice palace scene I originally thought was in World is Not Enough. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember any of the other plot details though. I think I would have if I had seen it before, because I actually really liked the film and think it&amp;rsquo;s the best of the Brosnan run. I mean, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even remember the betrayal towards the end, and that took me by surprise this time. The likely explanation seems to be that I had caught the later parts of the film on cable tv which is why I remember the ice palace thing, so I will consider this NOT a rewatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I read up on it after watching, apparently this film had a mixed reception, but I liked it. It has the campiness of the earlier films, and some good throwbacks and references, as it&amp;rsquo;s the 40th anniversary of the film. I mean, I agree the invisible car was a bit silly, but maybe about as much as everyday use of a jetpack (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/c6152994fa5ddf4b9c3302bcddfdd699/&#34;&gt;Thunderball&lt;/a&gt;) or going into space (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/cbb6135fa20b48a488982eccc7df76ce/&#34;&gt;Moonraker&lt;/a&gt;). There&amp;rsquo;s also an actual honest-to-goodness sword fight here that goes on quite a bit, first with fencing swords and later with actual swords. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just that I really enjoy swordfights lol. I also liked the car vs car battle later on in the movie; Bond has not had to face anyone with the same level of fancy car gadgets before, so it was fun. Also, the villain plot was to use something akin to C&amp;amp;C&amp;rsquo;s ion cannon! A space laser! I really would have remembered that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked the opening theme performed by Madonna, but didn&amp;rsquo;t actually recognize her in the cameo. This is the first film without Desmond Llewelyn as Q, as he had passed away the year before release. John Cleese is an adequate replacement, but this is also his final appearance in the role. This movie was also apparently Rosamund Pike&amp;rsquo;s first film. Hally Berry is ok as a Bond girl, nothing too exceptional. Her character was quite competent at first but then got captured (twice) in the second half. I believe this film is also the first time Bond has faced a North Korean villain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I think a fitting end to the Brosnan run and as a 40th anniversary celebration of the series. The campiness is fine, especially since the upcoming Daniel Craig era would be much more serious and gritty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;army-of-the-dead-2021&#34;&gt;Army of the Dead (2021)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watched this yesterday, mostly as background while I did other things, so not paying 100% attention I guess. I remembered reading that Tig Notaro (who plays the helicopter pilot) was never on set with the other actors (due to covid or something I guess) so every time she would be in a scene I&amp;rsquo;d mentally note how she&amp;rsquo;s not shown together with the others or was possible just edited into the shot. I really led with that lol, it&amp;rsquo;s what was foremost on my mind while watching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a reasonable action movie and zombie/heist flick, if not a bit predictable. I liked that safecracker guy, he really had a passion for his work, too bad he died. I actually thought more of their team would survive, but maybe I just haven&amp;rsquo;t seen enough zombie flicks. There&amp;rsquo;s an obvious setup at the end for a possible sequel, but Batista won&amp;rsquo;t be coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;valerian-and-the-city-of-a-thousand-planets-2017&#34;&gt;Valerian and the City of a Thousand Planets (2017)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ended up watching a second movie later in the day. I had been meaning to watch this for a while as it looked good. It&amp;rsquo;s an ok sci-fi movie to watch, but not a must-see as the plot is kind of predictable / cookie clutter, and there&amp;rsquo;s this one sequence in the middle which felt unnecessary and was just an excuse to get Cara Delevingne in a dress. Visuals are super pretty though, all the space stuff and the special effects and the City of a Thousand Planets all look great. The main guy Valerian fights waaaay too well, so that needs a bit of suspension of disbelief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only learned after watching that this movie was actually a French production directed by Luc Besson (of &lt;em&gt;Fifth Element&lt;/em&gt; fame), and was based on a French comic called &lt;em&gt;Valerian and Laureline&lt;/em&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s right, the comic actually had Laureline on equal billing with Valerian but noooo, the movie had to be titled for Valerian only. Actually, the comic seems more interesting from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Val%C3%A9rian_and_Laureline&#34;&gt;the wikipedia description&lt;/a&gt; as it seems to be more time-travel focused (Laureline is actually supposed to be from 11th-century France), but the movie doesn&amp;rsquo;t really give us much background on either of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this movie got mixed reviews and was a flop, so a follow-up in the same universe seems unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;superstore-season-5&#34;&gt;Superstore season 5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I binged the first four seasons of Superstore on Prime Video &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-09-13/&#34;&gt;back in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, and over the weekend I saw the fifth season was already up, so I had it as my background watching for most of the weekend and actually finished it already by Monday. Season 5 is pretty much more of the same flavor, though there are a bit more Filipino references (which I always enjoy) since there&amp;rsquo;s a stronger focus on the character Matteo, who in the last season was arrested by ICE because he was an illegal immigrant from the Philippines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-ones-who-walk-away-from-omelas-by-ursula-k-le-guin&#34;&gt;The Ones Who Walk Away From Omelas by Ursula K. Le Guin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone gave me a copy of this because I mentioned I&amp;rsquo;d never read any Le Guin before. It&amp;rsquo;s super short but quite thought-provoking, making you think about what costs any possible utopia could have. But I also think the ending is projecting a bit of optimism, in that no matter what darkness you discover, there&amp;rsquo;s always the option of just walking away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure whether to log this in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/lists/media/books/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;books read list&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; category, given that it&amp;rsquo;s not really a book and the length is actually barely a short story, but hey it&amp;rsquo;s my list, I&amp;rsquo;ll do what I want. It did make me want to seek out other Le Guin works, I&amp;rsquo;ll see what I can find.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reviews: The World is Not Enough, Barry season 1, Loki
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-the-world-is-not-enough-barry-season-1-loki/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 10:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-the-world-is-not-enough-barry-season-1-loki/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Warning: Spoilers for the just-ended season of Loki at the end of this. I have &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2021/07/1415238174377340930/&#34;&gt;a spoiler-free review&lt;/a&gt; of that if you&amp;rsquo;d like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world-is-not-enough-1999&#34;&gt;The World Is Not Enough (1999)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 19 and Brosnan&amp;rsquo;s third. Pretty sure I saw this in the theaters when it came out, but for the life of me could not recall any of the plot details at all. Turns out it was because the plot was a bit unnecessarily convoluted. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to tell straight away that Sophie Marceau is on the bad guy side, given her henchmen, so that was no surprise. Renard was a bit boring, revenge yada yada, bullet in my head, etc. The master plan here, originally misdirected as terrorism, turns out to just be financial all along. What assured me that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t insane and that I did see it in theaters was that as soon as I saw Denise Richards name in the opening credits I remember she played a nuclear physicist in this one. Probably the weakest of the Brosnan ones so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have a scene of Brosnan in some kind of ice building (?) in my random access memory, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t here so I think that&amp;rsquo;s a sign that I may have actually seen his next and last Bond film &lt;strong&gt;Die Another Day&lt;/strong&gt; before and just blocked out any memory of it for some reason. We&amp;rsquo;ll find out next week I suppose!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;barry-season-1&#34;&gt;Barry (season 1)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this late last week, and the season is only eight episodes but I only finished last night because each episode is a bit stressful to watch. Stressful in the sense that you pretty much expect that bad things are going to keep happening and that things are just going to get tougher for the protagonist. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit like Breaking Bad, where the protag just keeps getting into deeper and deeper trouble, but where Walter White started to revel in his notoriety, Barry just wants out, but he can&amp;rsquo;t get a break, and keeps on finding himself forced to do bad things. It&amp;rsquo;s very good, but also very dark. The season ends in a surprisingly satisfactory manner while still setting up possible follow-up storylines. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit tempted to just stop there and be happy with the show as it is and not continue to the second season as the show might actually get worse, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how long I hold it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;loki-season-1&#34;&gt;Loki (season 1)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season finale ended earlier today. As noted above, there is a spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;On 
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/2021/07/1415238174377340930/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;time datetime=&amp;quot;2021-07-14 09:14:09&amp;quot;&amp;gt;14 Jul 2021 9:14am&amp;lt;/time&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
I wrote:
&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;#Loki spoiler-free review:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;overall plot was fine, if not predictable, given what we knew about mcu phase 4 going in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;weak pacing and writing in most episodes; could have easily been a two hour movie instead of six one hour episodes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;good watch for mcu fans because of the larger phase 4 implications, but much weaker as a standalone series&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think overall, the plot of Loki delving into the truth behind the TVA and eventually causing the return of the multiverse was entirely predictable given the series&amp;rsquo; premise and what we knew of the larger MCU even before the series aired. The whole thing is even telegraphed completely in the first episode: removing the TVA means multiversal war; we are told the stakes from the very beginning and nothing really changes in that regard even up to the final episode and the reveal of who was actually behind the TVA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of the whole &amp;ldquo;reveal a new character and info dump his background in the last episode&amp;rdquo; treatment that character got. I get that the reveal was necessary for the larger MCU set up, but there&amp;rsquo;s no reason it could have been done or hinted from earlier episodes so that he didn&amp;rsquo;t have to monologue his back story for like 60% of this episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pacing of the entire six-episode runs just seemed so off to me; basically nothing interesting happening during the first three episodes (other than the reveal of a female Loki variant, which should surprise us why?), then some interesting stuff in episodes 4 and 5 and finally this disappointing finale was like 90% dialogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ramifications for the entire MCU at large are huge of course, and as a setup vehicle for the greater cinematic multiverse the series does the job well. But on the smaller scale, as a series standing by itself we got an anticlimactic finale, Renslayer and Mobius don&amp;rsquo;t get any kind of resolution or advancement to their character arcs, and our protagonist ends up right back where he was from the start - lost and alone. So unsatisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will of course still watch the eventual season 2, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to What If in August, but this finale just left a sour taste in my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Tomorrow Never Dies
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/tomorrow-never-dies/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 10:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/tomorrow-never-dies/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Last night I watched Tomorrow Never Dies (1997). Bond film no. 18 and Brosnan&amp;rsquo;s second. Also the first one I actually saw in theaters when it came out so officially my first rewatch! That said, it was 24 years ago so while I remember the general overarching plot (Jonathan Pryce playing a multibillionaire media mogul inciting a war between China and the UK to profit off the news), I have forgotten many of the finer details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did remember Michelle Yeoh in her role as a Chinese agent who ends up working with Bond. (She looks so young here, especially compared to &lt;em&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/em&gt; where I last saw her! I guess Asian women do age somehow.) I forgot about Teri Hatcher being here though, apparently in the middle of her heyday on the &lt;em&gt;Lois and Clark&lt;/em&gt; TV series. She looked great too, but had little screen time, so maybe that&amp;rsquo;s why I forgot about her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also remembered the scene with the remote controlled car as I remember thinking that was pretty neat back when I first saw it. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve actually learned how driving a car works (not that I actually drive), it seems ridiculous that Bond could have such fine control using only a touchpad. It&amp;rsquo;s 2021 and the touchpad UX isn&amp;rsquo;t even that great for laptops, let alone a car!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time possible conflict with China came into play in the Bond series (though they have made appearances before as &amp;ldquo;Red China&amp;rdquo;), maybe a sign of China&amp;rsquo;s rising prominence at the time? This was also the same year that Hong Kong was ceded back to China by the British, so perhaps appropriate for Bond to be working with a Chinese agent this time, in the spirit of international friendship?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice of villain may have been a bit prescient, given our current woes with billionaires and their platforms endangering the world and/or democracy, although if this film were made today the company would be more tech/internet focused than mass media, as that age has passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the theme music here (performed by Sherly Crow) better than the one in Goldeneye, possibly because I kind of still remembered how it went (or the chorus part anyway).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trivia: There were no more unadapted Fleming stories remaining so this is an original film story, but the original title was meant to be &lt;em&gt;Tomorrow Never Lies&lt;/em&gt;, which would have made a lot more sense! But there was a typo when the potential title was sent over to MGM, and they liked the current version better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall Goldeneye seemed the stronger film, though this one appeals to me too because it&amp;rsquo;s my second watch; It&amp;rsquo;s aged rather well I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next film is the only other Brosnan film I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, &lt;em&gt;The World Is Not Enough&lt;/em&gt;, but I seem to remember even less about it than this film, can&amp;rsquo;t even call the plot to mind. I seem to remember some kind of&amp;hellip; ice building? I suppose I&amp;rsquo;ll find out when I get to it, probably next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s some commentary from the movie about software development.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/tomorrow-never-dies/tomorrow_never_dies1_hu414c89fc49b4fadf995b95c69f971058_2266509_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/tomorrow-never-dies/tomorrow_never_dies2_hub352fc13e2c19fe2461a015a3f4a31d7_1596320_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/tomorrow-never-dies/tomorrow_never_dies3_hub76b38891f327391e3f4b663fa8b8335_2404244_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Goldeneye (1995)
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/goldeneye-1995/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 01:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/goldeneye-1995/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The Bond film reviews were starting to get a bit long for Twitter/&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes&#34;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt;, so a full blog post it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldeneye (1995). Bond film no. 17 and first for Brosnan. The films are starting to look &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo;, but might just be because this is the first Bond film to come out after I graduated high school and that&amp;rsquo;s what I see as &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t see this in theaters when it first came out though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get that dry wit and humor back, and a bit more modern armaments. Not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen Bond use an automatic weapon before (usually it&amp;rsquo;s just the PPK). Sean Bean is here as 006, but I knew that already. I imagine him coming back was intended as a huge twist in theaters, but that&amp;rsquo;s kinda spoiled with him getting top billing in the opening credits sequence. Unremarkable opening theme by Tina Turner (not really a fan of that genre of music).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First appearance of Judi Dench as M, who gets a bit more characterization compared to her predecessors. The film tries to address some of the series&amp;rsquo; more problematic tropes, with M telling Bond he&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;sexist, misogynist dinosaur, a relic of the Cold War&amp;rdquo;. New Moneypenny (Samantha Bond) is less enamoured over Bond. His CIA ally even complains about the &amp;ldquo;stiff-assed Brits&amp;rdquo; and their &amp;ldquo;codes and passwords&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Famke Janssen gives a great and insane performance as the sadistic henchman Xenia Onatopp. Not sure why that Russian general was involved in 006&amp;rsquo;s plan, he was introduced as some kind of &amp;ldquo;iron man of Russia&amp;rdquo; so I initally thought he had some kind of political ambition. In the end it was all about money after all (and vengeance for 006).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Might proceed to the next film (Tomorrow Never Dies) later today!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/4e93006d466cb2f6a53325cba8e27b63/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 10:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/4e93006d466cb2f6a53325cba8e27b63/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;License to Kill (1989): Bond film no 16, Dalton&amp;rsquo;s second and last outing is much darker and yet weaker than the first one. The first one where Bond goes rogue, driven by vengeance instead of duty. Unremarkable theme song. Villain is a drug smuggler; &lt;!--sep--&gt;I guess with the collapse of the USSR they couldn&amp;rsquo;t have another Russia-centered plot. More actors look familiar as we near the 90s. Notable are a young Benicio del Toro playing a henchman and Cary-Hiroyuki Tagawa (known for playing Shang Tsung. &lt;!--sep--&gt;Dalton&amp;rsquo;s performance is mixed, and for some reason he reminds me of Sir Patrick Stewart in some scenes. Too bad he couldn&amp;rsquo;t have had a better sendoff as Bond.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/69d2374b0f0232065102954a54736506/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 13:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/69d2374b0f0232065102954a54736506/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;The Living Daylights (1987): Bond film no. 15 and first of only two Dalton entries. More 80s music theme song, this time by A-ha. Much more serious in tone compared to Connery / Moore. John Rhys-Davies is here, years before Sliders or LOTR. &lt;!--sep--&gt;No sci-fi mad scientist stuff this time, straight-up spy stuff (more or less). Assassinations, defections, Russia&amp;rsquo;s internal politics, Afghan rebels, weapons, smuggling, drug deals, faked deaths, etc. Might be a tiny bit too long. Surprisingly, I liked this one!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/7d38789afe70956e56d61914ed7d195a/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 09:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/7d38789afe70956e56d61914ed7d195a/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Watched A View To A Kill (1985), Bond film no. 14. Moore is showing his age, luckily this is his last entry. Very 80s theme song by Duran Duran. Christopher Walken is here, as a Bond villain with a plan straight out of Superman (1978).&lt;!--sep--&gt; Tanya Roberts plays a young Bond girl just 14 years before playing a middle-aged mom on That 70s Show. Random young Dolph Lundgren cameo! Kind of a ridiculous street chase scene through San Francisco. Overall not the best of Moore&amp;rsquo;s run.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/1639118365d91bdbd1a41eb9b170a9a0/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 03:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/1639118365d91bdbd1a41eb9b170a9a0/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Yesterday I saw Octopussy (1983), Bond film no. 13. Another grounded entry with no fantastical elements, with the plot centered around geopolitical concerns. Some interesting action sequences, but overall, but I found most of the movie unremarkable.&lt;!--sep--&gt;  India shown as an exotic place (w/c I suppose it was to Westerners at that time) with elephants and firebreathers and whatnot all over. There was one scene where the bad guy appears to have broken a genuine Faberge egg but no one said anything lol.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/2641c1868d6ccb70715302ea340cae74/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 16:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/2641c1868d6ccb70715302ea340cae74/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;For Your Eyes Only (1981): Bond film no. 12. After the sci-fi fantasy of Moonraker, this one is more grounded and down-to-Earth, a callback to early Connery adventures. No megamalomaniacs to defeat, just foreign agents and mercs.&lt;!--sep--&gt; The opening sequence pays homage to the earlier pre-Moore films, acknowledging the death of Tracy Bond and killing off a villain that looks suspiciously like arch-nemesis Blofeld. The opening song is pretty good.&lt;!--sep--&gt; The rest of the film was ok, if a bit forgettable. I liked the rock climbing scene, but the ski chase and car chases felt like things we&amp;rsquo;ve seen before. Also, Moore is starting to show his age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melina Havelock (portrayed by Carole Bouquet) reminded me a lot of DC’s Huntress - a crossbow-wielding woman out for revenge&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/cbb6135fa20b48a488982eccc7df76ce/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 08:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/cbb6135fa20b48a488982eccc7df76ce/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Watched Moonraker (1979). Spectacular opening sequence. Villain reminds me of Tyrion Lannister. California -&amp;gt; Venice -&amp;gt; Rio de Janeiro. Mandatory canal chase while in Venice, obviously. Lots of of product placement.&lt;!--sep--&gt; A bad guy tried to ambush 007 with a KENDO STICK. Have they heard of guns? Comically indestructible assassin Jaws appears again, and actually has a character arc this time.&lt;!--sep--&gt; First half of the movie was kind of meh, but the last third of the film with the space station and the laser battles and the ridiculous villain plan kind of won me over with how campy it all was.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/ea715fa4d23937c15e47022adf93e192/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 06:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/ea715fa4d23937c15e47022adf93e192/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 10: The Spy Who Loved Me (1977). The best Moore installment so far. Excellent opening sequence. Austria; Cairo, Egypt; Sardinia, Italy. 007 and Triple-X have great chemistry. &lt;!--sep--&gt;Jaws has to be the most unstoppable Bond villain / henchman. Stromberg&amp;rsquo;s Atlantis reminds me of the Legion of Doom&amp;rsquo;s base in the old Superfriends cartoon. Actually, I think his evil plan might be the best one so far as well.&lt;!--sep--&gt;I wonder if I can get through the rest of these before No Time to Die actually comes out lol.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/ba2999c2cc9d8803ad982d24e52035e6/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 09:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/ba2999c2cc9d8803ad982d24e52035e6/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 9: The Man With The Golden Gun (1974). Christopher Lee was a Bond villain! Beirut, Macau, Hong Kong, Bangkok. An Asian girl is introduced just for the pun in her name. Comic relief southern sheriff dude is back from the previous film. &lt;!--sep--&gt;Final fight scene with Nick Nack was ridiculous. As per usual, Bond gets captured and the bad guy explains everything. Still not used to Roger Moore in the role.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/ced0a77eea2857ad31bd014fac3ded9a/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 10:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/ced0a77eea2857ad31bd014fac3ded9a/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 8: Live and Let Die (1973).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moore feels a lot more &amp;ldquo;generic white guy&amp;rdquo; than Connery was. Maybe I just need to get used to him. Young Jane Seymour is here! There&amp;rsquo;s a bayou chase scene here that goes on just a bit too long and had superfluous cop characters. &lt;!--sep--&gt;All the voodoo stuff felt weirdly out of place. There&amp;rsquo;s a character named Tee Hee! Most ridiculous villain death so far.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/8fd56682f77942eb0badef9444d465a4/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 12:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/8fd56682f77942eb0badef9444d465a4/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 7: Diamonds are Forever (1971). Connery&amp;rsquo;s hair starting to go a bit gray in his last appearance. More Blofeld than I&amp;rsquo;d expected (harhar). Space laser! Plenty O&amp;rsquo;Toole seemed pointless, there just to die. A lot of cheesy lines from the assassin henchment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--sep--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These movies would be a lot shorter if they just shot Bond whenever they caught him. The action scenes in all these old Bond films always feel so jarring compared to modern ones. Limited by the technology of their time I guess.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1a1ab3ad610478ba3b672b0a89c26333/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 06:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1a1ab3ad610478ba3b672b0a89c26333/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 6: On Her Majesty&amp;rsquo;s Secret Service (1969). Only Lazenby appearance. He was fine, I suppose. Tracy probably best Bond girl so far. I liked the ski scenes more than Thunderball&amp;rsquo;s underwater scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--sep--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loose continuity. Was confused by Blofeld not recognizing Bond after they already met in the previous movie. Apparently, the novel order was reversed. Also, did Bond just leave him stuck in a tree assuming he was dead after hunting him relentlessly?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/fb71576d1974213ea471b5cda8a20948/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 08:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/fb71576d1974213ea471b5cda8a20948/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 5: You Only Live Twice (1967). Such Japan. Much wow. Cringe at trying to pass Bond off as Japanese. Introduction of secret volcano lair trope. Ninjas with guns! First screen appearance of the head of SPECTRE, inspiration for Dr Evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--sep--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That endgame scene of ninjas invading the secret volcano lair reminded me of the Simpsons episode &lt;em&gt;You Only Move Twice&lt;/em&gt;. Bond&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;wife&amp;rdquo; never named despite being only Bond girl to survive the movie.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/c6152994fa5ddf4b9c3302bcddfdd699/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 07:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/c6152994fa5ddf4b9c3302bcddfdd699/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 4: Thunderball (1965). This is the first one I didn&amp;rsquo;t like very much. Too many boring/confusing underwater parts. There&amp;rsquo;s a jetpack! Wasn&amp;rsquo;t there an atomic bomb aboard that boat when it exploded? And did they just leave the guy who helped Domino escape floating alone in the ocean?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/273eae12d668c24135d4db358511c9d4/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 09:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/273eae12d668c24135d4db358511c9d4/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 3: Goldfinger (1964). Lot of the classic Bond tropes introduced. Bad guy&amp;rsquo;s plan was actually pretty good, even had the escape contingency. Disappointed he did not have an actual gold finger. Great fight between Bond and Oddjob.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/096b7c67797c165b01283d0c7cd6c016/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 09:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/096b7c67797c165b01283d0c7cd6c016/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;James Bond movie no. 2: To Russia With Love (1963). This one actually had more bits that felt like actual espionage. And Bond didn&amp;rsquo;t need to get captured this time!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/2b14f8356f57460da0a4790b27b44b8a/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 07:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/2b14f8356f57460da0a4790b27b44b8a/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Haven&amp;rsquo;t seen any of the pre-Brosnan Bond films, so I started today with Dr No (1962). Pretty good, but if this were a modern film, I&amp;rsquo;d have expected some kind of plot twist with Honey Rider, like maybe she would have turned out to be the actual Dr No&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>