<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Learning Things on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/tags/learning-things/</link>
      <description>Recent content in Learning Things on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 01:00:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/tags/learning-things/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Let&#39;s Encrypt!
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2018/03/lets-encrypt/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 01:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2018/03/lets-encrypt/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;figure style=&#34;width: 559px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignnone&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.redd.it/hfd9ok7bstf01.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;559&#34; height=&#34;235&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;(Image credit: r/ProgrammerHumor)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to add SSL to this blog ever since I first heard of &lt;a href=&#34;https://letsencrypt.org/&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt; last year. Unfortunately, support on my otherwise awesome webhost was not yet first-class and seemed complicated at the time, so I kept putting it off. But recently I was testing something unrelated and found out that I &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/requests/requests-oauthlib/issues/287&#34;&gt;needed to have SSL on my server in order for OAuth2 to work&lt;/a&gt;, so I grudgingly got to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily I found out about a handy utility written in Ruby that does most of the stuff for me: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/will-in-wi/letsencrypt-webfaction&#34;&gt;letsencrypt-webfaction&lt;/a&gt;. It was surprisingly easy to setup, with only a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/will-in-wi/letsencrypt-webfaction/issues/116#issuecomment-368930373&#34;&gt;single false start because I had a silly typo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now this site has SSL! Hooray!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Trying out 3d Modelling with Blender
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2018/02/trying-out-3d-modelling-with-blender/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 01:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2018/02/trying-out-3d-modelling-with-blender/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I decided to try learning some 3d modeling. For the past couple of weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been following this beginner &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blender.org/&#34;&gt;Blender&lt;/a&gt; tutorial where I had to make donuts. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JYj6e-72RDs&amp;amp;index=2&amp;amp;list=PLjEaoINr3zgHs8uzT3yqe4iHGfkCmMJ0P&#34;&gt;Link to the tutorial series on Youtube&lt;/a&gt;.) Here&amp;rsquo;s my output!&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#e122ce97c5258e307e77a24c36181c12-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2018/02/trying-out-3d-modelling-with-blender/donut4_hu6e8b1665346fb560094f645dbbdad573_3005276_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;e122ce97c5258e307e77a24c36181c12-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2018/02/trying-out-3d-modelling-with-blender/donut4.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;1 Feb 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;1 Feb 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This image took around 40 minutes to render. I had to do 2000 samples per tile which is why it was so slow. I was getting too much noise/graininess at lower sampling rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t follow the tutorial exactly. My plate is square and made of glass for one thing. The chocobutternut donut wasn&amp;rsquo;t part of the tutorial, I just wanted to try it (obviously did not turn out too well and all those orange particles on the donut probably really slowed down the render lol). I also didn&amp;rsquo;t bother too much with the stuff in the last two videos of the series which involved adjusting the lighting and other stuff to make the image prettier (wasn&amp;rsquo;t really interested). I actually also tried to model a fork (not in the tutorial), but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the tines right and gave up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long time ago I read an interview in an old PC gaming mag about how they implemented Age of Empires and there was an image of a 3d mesh of a knight on horseback and I remember thinking &amp;ldquo;That looks really complicated, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably never be able to do something like that.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried this tutorial, I have to agree with that initial assessment &amp;ndash; any complex modelling would surely try my patience. But I was also pleasantly surprised with how advanced Blender is &amp;ndash; I sort of imagined that you had to position and adjust all the mesh nodes/vertices/faces by hand a lot, but actually there&amp;rsquo;s a ton of functions to make some common operations simpler (but it&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One complaint is that Blender&amp;rsquo;s user interface is very obtuse and daunting though &amp;ndash; I don&amp;rsquo;t usually do video tutorials but I doubt I could have figured this stuff out on my own. Though I suppose it can&amp;rsquo;t be helped given the sheer complexity of the task involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m probably not going into any sort of significant 3d modelling or 3d artwork soon (like I said, not enough patience), but it was good to give it a try so at least I have a passing knowledge of some of the concepts involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2018/02/trying-out-3d-modelling-with-blender/donut4_hu6e8b1665346fb560094f645dbbdad573_3005276_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>