<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>windows-7 on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/windows-7/</link>
      <description>Recent content in windows-7 on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 16:17:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/windows-7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2011/01/233276/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 16:17:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2011/01/233276/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;So I came home and stumbled upon a bit of a mystery. When I got home my brother was using my desktop PC that was running Windows 7 (I have accounts for my 2 brothers and my mom on the machine, but mine is the only admin account). After he finished his game he logged out and I logged in to my account, but found only strangeness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My windows account seems to have been somewhat &amp;ldquo;reset&amp;rdquo;, meaning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my quick launch shortcuts were gone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my dropbox account did not automatically login&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my pidgin accounts were no longer there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had to relogin Steam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iTunes could not launch (I had hooked up my iDevice before logging in)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Documents/Pictures/Music shortcuts in the start menu no longer work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, despite that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my desktop wallpaper was still correct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my documents folder was still there in c:\Users\my account name\My Documents as expected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Chrome settings seem to have been retained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;other accounts on the same machine seem to be fine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked my brother if he had installed anything strange during the day, he only installed Yahoo Messenger. I last used the machine around 24 hours ago and it was fine then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what else has been affected. I&amp;rsquo;m inclined to just create a new admin user for me to use, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to have some idea of what actually happened.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/10/63436/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 04:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/10/63436/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Can anyone make recommendations? I used to use Launchy back in the XP days, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know if there are better alternatives now.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>