<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>walking on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/walking/</link>
      <description>Recent content in walking on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/walking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Break of dawn
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/break-of-dawn/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/break-of-dawn/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I stepped out of the house a bit past five in the morning today. I haven&amp;rsquo;t done this in a while, taking my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/daily-walks/&#34;&gt;daily walk&lt;/a&gt; in the early morning. I used to do it pretty regularly, except back then I confined myself to the inner roads of our subdivision, or doing loops around the covered court in the nearby seminary. Walking the same routes every morning and doing repetitive routes got boring after a while, and combined with my erratic sleep schedule the habit soon fell off the wayside. I resumed my walking habit when I took a break from work in 2016, but this time mostly doing it late in the afternoons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoons have been getting more difficult lately, with some busyness in the schedule and the sudden yet inevitable onset of the summer heat, so I decided to try shifting back to mornings again. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how long it lasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walking during the early mornings, before the sun has even broken, has a completely different atmosphere than the afternoons or even the evenings. The streets glow a pale blue and are nearly empty, though traffic is already starting to build up at some of the busier intersections. There are few other people out on their feet (as opposed to in cars) this early, enough that I would involuntarily nod when I passed some other early morning walker. I&amp;rsquo;m surprised to find that a nearby Jollibee operated 24 hours, and that the nearby Starbucks didn&amp;rsquo;t. I assumed it was the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pass by a student on her way to school, with a companion accompanying her as she flags down a jeep. I commiserate with how early students need to get up to go to school in this country. I remember my own childhood when my mom would pick me up and drag me over to the sink to splash my face with water to get me going at five in the morning. Class usually started at seven, but the school bus would pick us up around six or even earlier. Somehow, we may be teaching kids to hate mornings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not one of those &amp;ldquo;not a morning person&amp;rdquo; people. I don&amp;rsquo;t need coffee to get started in the mornings either. I enjoy sleeping in when I can, but I&amp;rsquo;m always willing and able to get up early if I needed to. Combined with my tendency to sleep late into the night, this has led to my terribly erratic sleep schedule. Even as I&amp;rsquo;m walking out on the streets before the break of dawn, I expect myself to be taking a second sleep after getting home and having breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sun starts to break through the night as I near the end of my route, a couple of corners away from home. My walk this morning is a bit shorter than my usual target of steps. There are some areas I prefer not to traverse before the light of day, so my options are a bit limited. As I get used to walking in the early mornings again I&amp;rsquo;ll try a few different routes to see if I can increase my steps. In the meantime, I turn the corner and head back home, looking forward to the morning&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;pan de sal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Benefits of Walking
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/benefits-of-walking/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/benefits-of-walking/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The other day &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/daily-walks/&#34;&gt;I wrote about how I&amp;rsquo;ve been walking on a regular basis recently&lt;/a&gt;. While the regularity and the tracking are fairly recent, I&amp;rsquo;m actually not that much of a stranger to walking as an activity. Even back when I was in high school I would often walk all the way home instead of taking the bus-and-jeep commute route I was supposed to take. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take that much longer, and I often enjoyed the solace (and I got to save a bit of money, even as a child I was quite frugal~). In college, I would regularly walk the couple of kilometers between classes, or from the campus itself to Philcoa. Sometimes, when it was especially hard to commute, I would walk through UP/Teacher&amp;rsquo;s/Sikatuna Village all the way back to our old home in Kamias. I remember doing this once during the aftermath of a terrible storm when there were no jeeps around to take me home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even back then, walking for me was kinda therapeutic. Like I said, I enjoyed the solace. I would often stop at some places and just be at peace for a while. I wrote about this once in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10152788551883912&#34;&gt;old facebook post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a place at the corner of East Avenue and BIR Road in Quezon City. When I was young I would walk to that intersection and wait there to catch a jeepney ride that would take me home. It was often easy to get a ride, no more than a couple of minutes wait. But sometimes I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t flag down a jeep immediately. I would sit there at the base of the lamp post at the corner of East Avenue and BIR Road, and let the noise of the world wash over me for some time. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember contemplating anything specific while I was there or whether I had worries or was sad. I would just sit there and be peaceful and the world would move around me and I would watch the people and the cars pass by and wonder who they were or where they were going. After a while the trance would break, and I would fall back into the real world and tell myself I had to get home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, a side note, checking Google Maps now, that route&amp;rsquo;s distance was a measly 3.7km, a couple of km shorter than my average walking routes these days. Back then it felt like I was walking a lot!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started working in Ortigas, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much opportunity for regular walking. I almost always walked the short distance from the office to Megamall, unless it was raining or insanely hot. When traffic was really bad and it was difficult to get a bus ride or a taxi, I sometimes took the opportunity to walk from Ortigas to Cubao, or vice versa (Distance: somewhere around 5-6km). I often said to myself that someday I would walk the whole 13 or so km home, but I never did get that chance. Occasionally I would get deployed to another country for work, and when I did one of the things I would do during my nights there would be &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/03/sometimes-you-just-go-where-your-feet-take-you/&#34;&gt;to walk around a lot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, as I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned in the other post, I intentionally try to find the time to walk. I don&amp;rsquo;t always find it, but I do most of the time. It&amp;rsquo;s an additional way to burn off stress. When I&amp;rsquo;m feeling angry or frustrated or sad (usually about work-related things), I say to myself, it&amp;rsquo;s time for a walk. And it helps me think. My mind wanders as I walk, coming up with ideas or solutions to problems or unlocking new thoughts or awakening slumbering areas of my brain or just overall improving my creativity. Walking is also a way of being in the present, leaving behind your worries and anxieties and simply taking in the world. I intentionally don&amp;rsquo;t pace myself too quickly lest the walk end too soon, although I am often impatient to get back home. I find walking is quite good for developing patience as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The philosopher Henry David Thoreau said of walking:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think that I cannot preserve my health and spirits, unless I spend four hours a day at least—and it is commonly more than that—sauntering through the woods and over the hills and fields, absolutely free from all worldly engagements. You may safely say, A penny for your thoughts, or a thousand pounds. When sometimes I am reminded that the mechanics and shopkeepers stay in their shops not only all the forenoon, but all the afternoon too, sitting with crossed legs, so many of them—as if the legs were made to sit upon, and not to stand or walk upon—I think that they deserve some credit for not having all committed suicide long ago.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four hours a day seems excessive of course. I have other things to do. And unlike Thoreau, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the benefit of having nearby woods or hills or fields to saunter through. Mine is more of an urban jungle. But I&amp;rsquo;m not much of a naturalist anyway (biology was always my weakest science), and I find there is still much to see as I walk through Metro Manila&amp;rsquo;s uneven streets. People rushing by. Small businesses I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed before. A large franchise restaurant that&amp;rsquo;s often empty. A couple quietly holding hands in the dusk. Too many politicians&amp;rsquo; posters. The endless traffic. One time a biker almost got run over by a car. He managed to jump off the bike and landed right beside me on the sidewalk. Sometimes I feel I&amp;rsquo;m not observant enough, I should take more opportunity during these walks to observe more things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note: another extra benefit of all this walking is that my sense of distance has improved. I now generally have a sense of roughly how far a kilometer is. This is why I was able to recognize that Manhattan can&amp;rsquo;t be 4km from top to bottom in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/game-review-marvels-spider-man-for-ps4/&#34;&gt;my Spider-Man PS4 review&lt;/a&gt;. I walk more than that distance daily!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there are many benefits to walking. So, what are you waiting for? Go take a walk!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Fitbit Charge 2
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-fitbit-charge-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-fitbit-charge-2/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/daily-walks/&#34;&gt;yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post about my daily walks&lt;/a&gt; that my brother got me a Fitbit Charge 2 mid last year, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a quick review. (Actually, this is mainly an excuse to write down a story about how stupid I am.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, yeah my bro got me a Fitbit. Or maybe I paid for it. I don&amp;rsquo;t really recall. The point is, I had it and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it regularly for the past year and a half. It&amp;rsquo;s a great little gizmo, not only do I use it for step counts, but it also lets me track how much sleep I&amp;rsquo;m getting (which is why I know how rare a regular continuous 8-hour sleep is for me, even when I&amp;rsquo;m not working). I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of measuring my own data for self-improvement purposes so I like it. Conveniently, it also works with &lt;a href=&#34;http://ifttt.com/&#34;&gt;IFTTT&lt;/a&gt;, so I have an applet that exports my daily data to the a Google Sheets for easy reference. In theory I could also use the Fitbit to track stuff like my food intake and weight, but those don&amp;rsquo;t happen automatically so I don&amp;rsquo;t. Maybe someday. The fitbit itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t use too much battery and has an Android app that syncs with the device via bluetooth (so I have bluetooth on all the time now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One minor nitpick I have is that it my wrist doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to like the fitbit too much, after a while I realized it was growing darker where I wore it. My brother suggested maybe I was wearing the wrist strap too tightly. After this realization, I sometimes started wearing it on the other wrist when I felt like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, on to the stupid story! About 4 or 5 months after i started using the fitbit, this happened:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#7df3d189d76ff9003b27de0f3f2855f3-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-fitbit-charge-2/fitbit1_hua16e6a31c539de7e411e63f564ba5e77_70551_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;7df3d189d76ff9003b27de0f3f2855f3-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-fitbit-charge-2/fitbit1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;29 Nov 2018 2:06am&#34;&gt;29 Nov 2018 2:06am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh noes! Normally you can just snap the strap part back into place, but this time something had come off and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t stick back. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend money on a replacement strap, so in a brilliant move that I would surely never regret, I glued it back into place with Mighty Bond. This worked well! The strap held in place and I could now use the fitbit again without worry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast-forward another seven months or so later, and now the strap on the other side came off too! AND around the same time, my charger thingy fell apart as well, and I could not put it back together! Oh noes! Was this the end of my fitbit experiment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily it turns out a friend owned an online shop that could get me a replacement strap and charger for a good price (check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Activstylephl/&#34;&gt;FitbitManila on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re interested), and it would be delivered to my house. All I had to do was wait a few days. During that time I was unable to charge the fitbit so it died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the goods arrived, I attempted to replace the faulty half-strap only. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remove the other side since it was glued into place! What a surprising twist, I did regret that decision from just three paragraphs ago! And to make it worse, for some reason the replacement strap was not the same width as the older strap, so I can&amp;rsquo;t use the old half with the new half! I was forced to pry apart the glued half-strap, and I did eventually manage to do it, and now my fitbit was whole again, and I think I lost a couple of days data? Actually when I charged the fitbit again it was no longer sync&amp;rsquo;ed to my phone and I had to reinstall it. The replacement strap felt a bit off, but I got used to it soon enough, and here we are half a year later and I&amp;rsquo;m still using the Fitbit, hooray! Stupidity overcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I&amp;rsquo;m quite happy with my year and a half of fitbit usage. I&amp;rsquo;m told that the devices themselves last fairly long, even if the straps don&amp;rsquo;t, so I hope to be using it for at least a couple of years more, maybe? I&amp;rsquo;ll try never to glue the straps again.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-fitbit-charge-2/fitbit1_hua16e6a31c539de7e411e63f564ba5e77_70551_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Daily Walks
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/daily-walks/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/daily-walks/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;These days the only real exercise I get comes in the form of daily walks. When I took a work hiatus in 2016, it was one of the daily habits I promised myself I would pick up. During that time, I wanted to hit the often-recommended daily target of 10,000 steps per day. (Tangent: I found out while writing this post that this number &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2018/sep/03/watch-your-step-why-the-10000-daily-goal-is-built-on-bad-science&#34;&gt;may have no scientific basis after all&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back then, all I had to track my steps was the dinky Samsung health app that came with my Galaxy phone. It was good enough, at least at first. At some point I switched to the Google Fit app. Neither app was super accurate though. I started with a modest target, and slowly ramped up to 10,000 steps per day, which I hit sometime near the end of 2016. (Frustratingly, I can&amp;rsquo;t find my daily records of my step counts from that year. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I had them in a spread sheet of some kind somewhere&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I learned on these daily walks is that I don&amp;rsquo;t like repetition. I had been trying to get into the daily habit even before my work hiatus, but because of limited time, I only went a short distance from home and just did laps around a nearby basketball court or subdivision. This however was hard for me to keep up because I found it terribly boring. During 2016, since I had more time, what I did was I would walk as far away from home as possible until I hit half my target, then I&amp;rsquo;m also forced to walk all the way back and meet my target. And because I dislike repetition, I seldom took the same route on succeeding days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pleasant side effect of this method is that I got a better layout of the geography near our house. I&amp;rsquo;ve lived here for more than a decade, but haven&amp;rsquo;t really explored the nearby areas that much because when you&amp;rsquo;re a working joe you don&amp;rsquo;t really have that much time for exploratory walks. And I would walk pretty far too, something like 8-10 km a day. I went down roads I never travelled, visited small malls I never knew of, walked all the way to a friend&amp;rsquo;s house, sometimes even walked through some sketchy-looking neighborhoods and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s also happened more than once that a friend I don&amp;rsquo;t see too often but lives nearby will say to me &amp;ldquo;Hey, I saw someone who looks like you walking around [my neighborhood]!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around mid-2017, my brother got me a Fitbit Charge 2, so I switched to that for my step counting. By this time, I had been maintaining the 10,000 step target for a while after I hit it, but when I started working regularly again I started to slip and often found myself only hitting 2 or 3 thousand a day. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to ramp it up again the past few months, but I find that usually 10,000 steps takes way too much time, in the neighborhood of 1.5-2 hours of walking, depending on my pace. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll still ramp up to that step count but I&amp;rsquo;ll take it a lot slower this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, my daily target is now a more manageable 6,000 to 8,000 steps a day, and I have more regular routes I follow. It somehow feels a bit more challenging to do this regularly in 2018 as the weather now seems much hotter than it used to be (that, or I had gotten used to being in an air-conditioned office again). I find my walks now more often happen after dusk, which makes them a bit more dangerous (these are Metro Manila streets after all), despite what a certain former DFA secretary might say. I just try to avoid wandering through shady streets these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, according to the fitbit logs, I&amp;rsquo;ve clocked in around 2.8 million steps since I got the fitbit, over around 500 days, more or less 5,500 steps per day. While it&amp;rsquo;s not ideal, I think it&amp;rsquo;s a lot more than I used to get regularly, and I am able to burst to 10,000 every so often. Hopefully I can get back to 10,000 regularly soonish.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>