<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>neverforget on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/tags/neverforget/</link>
      <description>Recent content in neverforget on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 10:50:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/tags/neverforget/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Repost from AngeMaryClaire https://twitter.com/AngeMaryClaire/statuses/815145029308035073/:
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2016/12/815148200008921092/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 10:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2016/12/815148200008921092/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from AngeMaryClaire https://twitter.com/AngeMaryClaire/statuses/815145029308035073/:
            &lt;p&gt;2016 is the year we learned democracy is a farce and the people&amp;rsquo;s voices will be ignored by those in power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#BoatyMcBoatface. #Neverforget&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2016/11/10155102720598912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 07:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2016/11/10155102720598912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a number of people posting/sharing something promoting the idea that instead of blaming the Marcos or Duterte, we should be blaming the people who were in power for 30 years for not passing a law to prevent the dictator from being buried in an place of honor. This is a ridiculous, after-the-fact justification to attempt to shift blame and wash hands of a betrayal done to the people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about it, of those 3 parties:
a) one party has been negligent
b) one party has purposely and systematically abused power over this country for more than a decade
c) one party has purposely traded this country&amp;rsquo;s dignity for the sake of political patronage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these are things we should condemn, but the last two are betrayals while the other one is at worst stupidity. If you think (a) is worse than (b) or (c) and that we should just move on or something, you are contributing to the problem of our short-term political memory being akin to a goldfish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#MarcosNotAHero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Moving on&amp;rdquo; shouldnt mean setting aside these betrayals and letting their memory fade, otherwise we are condemned to history repeating itself. Instead we should #NeverForget and remain vigilant against abuses by current and future governments.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from Ninotchka Rosca https://www.facebook.com/ninotchka.rosca/posts/1198763870141266:
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2016/09/10154935173373912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 11:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2016/09/10154935173373912/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from Ninotchka Rosca https://www.facebook.com/ninotchka.rosca/posts/1198763870141266:
            &lt;p&gt;Ingat (careful out there) became the word of good-bye, replacing the old &amp;ldquo;sige,&amp;rdquo; during the martial law years. It was the last word uttered between and among those meeting to discuss what had to be done, in ways big and small, to end the Marcos Dictatorship. It was said with all the love and respect one was capable of. Because chances were one would meet again only in a prison cell, or a torture house (called a safe house by the military) or at a wake. #neverforget #cultureaswitness #languageofstruggle&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>