<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>anime on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/anime/</link>
      <description>Recent content in anime on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 15:26:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/anime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Rurouni Kenshin: The Final
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/rurouni-kenshin-the-final/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/rurouni-kenshin-the-final/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Earlier today I watched Rurouni Kenshin: The Final (2021), now out on Netflix (PH, not sure about elsewhere). I don&amp;rsquo;t normally do full blog posts for &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/reviews/movies&#34;&gt;movies&lt;/a&gt; anymore, but I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/archives/ancient/geocities/rk/&#34;&gt;a big Rurouni Kenshin fan&lt;/a&gt;, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much commentary on record for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/12/277092263371350017/&#34;&gt;first three live action films&lt;/a&gt;, so I figured I would write some words mostly about this new film, but maybe also a bit about the first three as well. The film is based on a manga story arc from more than 20 years ago, so I&amp;rsquo;m not really going to be avoiding spoilers here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this film covers the Revenge / Jinchuu arc, the third and final arc of the Rurouni Kenshin manga, most of which was never adapted to anime. This kind of works in the film&amp;rsquo;s favor, as I don&amp;rsquo;t have any anime to compare it to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/09/10153244419688912/&#34;&gt;a bit disappointed&lt;/a&gt; in the original trilogy&amp;rsquo;s handling of the fight scenes, since in my head I was comparing them to the epic anime battles, which is silly since an anime series and a live-action film are fundamentally different media, and some things simply wouldn&amp;rsquo;t translate well. Like, in the manga and anime, Kenshin&amp;rsquo;s learning the succession art of the Hiten Mitsurugi school and later using it to overcome Shishio was a big plot point, but was completely glossed over in the films. (And in the revenge arc, it&amp;rsquo;s also a plot point that Enishi is able to defeat that same succession art.) I guess I&amp;rsquo;m more forgiving these days of not strictly adhering to the source material (countless comic book movies will do that I guess), so I&amp;rsquo;m learning more to enjoy them as swashbuckling samurai adventures rather than only as anime adaptations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing about the Jinchuu arc is that it was quite long, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how they were going to fit it all in a single movie, even taking liberties with the plot points. I found out before that they had actually made two new films, with &lt;em&gt;The Final&lt;/em&gt; only being the first, so I kind of assumed this one would end with a cliffhanger, assuming they follow the general plot of the manga. Well, it turns out that while the first half of the film largely follows the plot of the manga arc and the first part of Enishi&amp;rsquo;s revenge plan, they scrapped the second half of the manga arc in favor of an all-out battle / assault for the film&amp;rsquo;s final act, pulling in appearances from characters that never appeared in the manga arc (some of them obviously appearing as fan service!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this divergence from the manga is fine and understandable given the limitations of the medium, it does significantly weaken the impact of Enishi&amp;rsquo;s revenge plan; early on in the film he states that death is insufficient for Kenshin to atone, but in the third arc he just ends up attempting to kill him or to get him to kill himself. The manga arc had a stronger punishment for Kenshin in the form of faking Kaoru&amp;rsquo;s death, sending Kenshin into a downward spiral that takes him a while to recover from, a character arc that speaks more strongly towards the series&amp;rsquo; general message of atonement and redemption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also disappointed because cutting out the second half of the revenge arc means we never get to see Yahiko in a one-on-one battle against one of Enishi&amp;rsquo;s minions. That was one of the most memorable parts of the manga arc for me because it represented a big growth in strength and capability for Yahiko to be able to hold his own using Kamiya Kasshin techniques. But again, I guess that&amp;rsquo;s not a thing that would have translated well to the big screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an English rock / R&amp;amp;B track that plays over the end credits, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4n5bpeh5NNg&#34;&gt;Renegades by One OK Rock&lt;/a&gt;. It felt slightly jarring and out of place since I watched the film with Japanese voices and English dubs, but I&amp;rsquo;m told even the first trilogy had English tracks over the end credits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing the movie, I wondered what the fifth film would actually be about, and it turns out it&amp;rsquo;s actually going to expand more on the Tomoe / Kenshin backstory that was only covered briefly in this film. While that would be a reasonable way to split up the revenge arc into two movies, it feels like it would have made more sense to release the prequel film first (and more appropriate since it&amp;rsquo;s titled &lt;em&gt;The Beginning&lt;/em&gt;), especially since this film already covers the major plot points that they would show in the prequel. Still as a big series fan (despite &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/11/932887665346670593/&#34;&gt;the author becoming controversial&lt;/a&gt; later on), I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the prequel&amp;rsquo;s eventual release on Netflix; we&amp;rsquo;ll see what surprises await us there.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/rurouni-kenshin-the-final/jinchu_hua12b81e072f157e1daee404141766e3e_1932695_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Anime Opening/Ending Themes
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/anime-op/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 05:07:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/anime-op/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Had a friendly discussion last night about our favorite anime theme music, figured I&amp;rsquo;d share some of my favorites. J-Pop in general and anime theme music in particular have a kind of energy that you just don&amp;rsquo;t get from Western music. I think that generally I tend to favor those that openings for series that I had a chance to watch on TV (instead of via streaming/online channels), since back in those days I had to sit through the openings! (So most of these are rather old!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kimi Ga Suki da to Sakebitai from Slam Dunk by Baad:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7qLwmho_240&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hohoemi no Bakudan from Yu Yu Hakusho by Matsuko Mawatari:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IEjRBJChZMA&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/3 no Junjou na Kanjou from Rurouni Kenshin by Siam Shade:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rzziisIJudY&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(RK in particular had a lot of tracks I liked, but let&amp;rsquo;s limit it to one per series)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chala Head Chala from Dragonball Z by Hironobu Kageyama:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pYnLO7MVKno&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We Are! from One Piece by Hiroshi Kitadani:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZwXKz2CeHwY&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for now! Here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/1aUsKTSASpG2jPSDSzVICw&#34;&gt;spotify playlist&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re into that sort of thing.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Naruto-kun
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/09/naruto-kun/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2005 12:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/09/naruto-kun/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via delicious:
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.naruto-kun.com/&#34;&gt;Naruto-kun&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Narutrix Re-ninja&#39;ed
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/04/narutrix-re-ninja-ed/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2005 16:08:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/04/narutrix-re-ninja-ed/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via delicious:
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boingboing.net/2005/04/13/matrix_reloaded_trai.html&#34;&gt;Narutrix Re-ninja&amp;#39;ed&lt;/a&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Matrix Reloaded trailer audio remixed with anime cartoon footage&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Anime-Planet - Anime Recommendations Database
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/01/anime-planet-anime-recommendations-database/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2005 07:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/01/anime-planet-anime-recommendations-database/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via delicious:
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.anime-planet.com/animerec/&#34;&gt;Anime-Planet - Anime Recommendations Database&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>