<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>PiliPinasDebates2016 on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/pilipinasdebates2016/</link>
      <description>Recent content in PiliPinasDebates2016 on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 19:17:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/pilipinasdebates2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>3rd Presidential Debate
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/04/3rd-presidential-debate/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 19:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/04/3rd-presidential-debate/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Commentary thread for 3rd presidential debate (consolidated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:17] Dapat magtaas kamay na lang si Miriam at humingi ng enerhiya sa taong bayan para sa genki dama&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:35] Bakit pa ba umaattend ng debate etong si Binay? Ni hindi sinasagot ang tinatanong sa kanya #PiliPinasDebates2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[19:44] Panalo, quinote si Batman!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[20:19] Babawasan mga tax, pero andaming mga planong transportation at libreng healthcare&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[20:31] Looking forward to the pro roxas crowd posting about davao philheath beneficiaries at 8am tomorrow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[20:49] May cinite na stats si duterte na 300,000 new vehicles per month. At that time I was reading a newspaper article which said there 280,000+ vehicles sold all of last year. Fact check?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[21:01] Duterte: puro 75 ang grade ko&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miriam: ang presidente dapat may academic excellence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[23:31] In my opinion, the performances at today&amp;rsquo;s debate (from best to worst) were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roxas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Santiago&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duterte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The debate wasn&amp;rsquo;t too exciting, although may konting immature fireworks between two certain candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BONUS: In my opinion, the debates (in terms of format and moderator performances) can be ranked (from best to worst) as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2nd debate (TV5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3rd debate (ABS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1st debate (GMA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: Swapped #3 and #4 because my someone reminded me of somethings Miriam said and I remembered that stupid Emilio Aguinaldo reply&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Apr 25 02:10] Some other things I noted in the debate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duterte no longer harping on &amp;ldquo;3-6 months&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roxas no longer mentioning &amp;ldquo;Daang Matuwid&amp;rdquo; (although he did use tuwid as an adjective a couple of times I think)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Isko Moreno has &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; of ads. He must have had like 3-4 different ads shown during the debate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ABS&amp;rsquo; silly drama scenes before each question were a waste of time better used for asking more questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We LOLed every time Binay took the opportunity to walk forward to answer. Baka kulang pa sya ng exercise for that day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from karlocatapang https://twitter.com/karlocatapang/statuses/724193943831875584/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/04/724194702107373568/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 11:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/04/724194702107373568/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from karlocatapang https://twitter.com/karlocatapang/statuses/724193943831875584/:
            &lt;p&gt;Ang daming pinapangako tapos tatanggalin  o babaan ang tax?? #PiliPinasDebates2016&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/711535710302396417/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 12:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/711535710302396417/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alvinjtang/&#34;&gt;@alvinjtang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/iamsuperbianca/status/711535418441748480&#39;&gt;iamsuperbianca&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    Near real-time fact-checking here &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rappler.com/nation/politics/elections/2016/presidential-debate-philippines-comelec-cebu&#34;&gt;http://www.rappler.com/nation/politics/elections/2016/presidential-debate-philippines-comelec-cebu&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/VoltaireTupaz/&#34;&gt;@VoltaireTupaz&lt;/a&gt; #PiliPinasDebates2016
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from GilbertCRemulla https://twitter.com/GilbertCRemulla/statuses/711522504620158977/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/711526770604843008/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 12:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/711526770604843008/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from GilbertCRemulla https://twitter.com/GilbertCRemulla/statuses/711522504620158977/:
            &lt;p&gt;Naaawa ako sa nag sa-sign language. #PiliPinasDebates2016&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from pau_araos https://twitter.com/pau_araos/statuses/711514613720817664/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/711515334621028352/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 11:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/711515334621028352/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from pau_araos https://twitter.com/pau_araos/statuses/711514613720817664/:
            &lt;p&gt;Si Binay tuwing korupsyon ang usapan. #PiliPinasDebates2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video width=&#39;320&#39; height=&#39;238&#39; controls&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#39;https://video.twimg.com/tweet_video/Cd_OvKnUkAE_xYU.mp4&#39; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
    &lt;/video&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/02/10154387631398912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/02/10154387631398912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;My reactions to the first #PiliPinasDebates2016:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, nothing too difficult was discussed, and we got mostly motherhood statements from the candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Format was a bit strange, what is the format for debates in other countries? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t all candidates be allowed to respond to each question?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not enough time to give meaty answers really, and did we really need so many ads?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poe well-prepared, ready with answers and statistics, not much implementation details though&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duterte having trouble articulating himself sometimes, keeps harping on fixing everything within 3-6 months, without elaborating how. IDK much about Davao, but my impression is he didn&amp;rsquo;t do that in 3-6 months. But I am happy that his &amp;ldquo;killing criminals&amp;rdquo; rhetoric now includes the rider that it must be within the scope of the law&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Binay&amp;rsquo;s preparation for this debate seems to have been to keep telling himself &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m a decisive leader!!! I&amp;rsquo;m a decisive leader!!! I&amp;rsquo;m a decisive leader!!!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miriam no longer has the fire she used to have, stumbled a few times. She could have a much stronger rebuttal as to why we the constitution has that ban on political dynasties if only her VP candidate&amp;rsquo;s family wasn&amp;rsquo;t the reason we needed to put that there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duterte agreeing with people and insisting that implementation is the problem - upvotes. But none of the candidates detailed implementation plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussion on policies and issues generally one-sided - everyone agrees with the stuff that has to be done, but no one really talks about details of how, etc. Reflection of the fact that we don&amp;rsquo;t really have parties with differing ideologies (aside from Duterte&amp;rsquo;s federalism. Oh and Binay&amp;rsquo;s insistence that political dynasties are cool LOL)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from Binay getting shot down a few times, nothing too fiery/exciting happened. Candidates didn&amp;rsquo;t really do rebuttals so much as elaborate on their own plans&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roxas&amp;rsquo; closing statement is a much better approach than all his political ads and strategies so far&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know all too well that you can&amp;rsquo;t really form an accurate assessment of a person from one interview so I don&amp;rsquo;t really expect that the candidates will have room to espouse all the details of their platforms, but I hope the succeeding debates can at least give more challenging questions and a bit more time for the candidates to elaborate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I missed round 1 (rewatched the archive), but on my way home I noticed the security guards in our subdivision listening to the debate on the radio. Say what you will about the debate&amp;rsquo;s format and lack of challenging questions, but the fact that we are having any sort of discussion at all that manages to capture the public&amp;rsquo;s attention is already an improvement. Hopefully the organizers of the next two debates manage to learn something and try to improve on the first one&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/02/10154385571378912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 17:52:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/02/10154385571378912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;#PiliPinasDebates2016 Tomorrow will be the first Presidential debate. If I were hosting the debate, here are some of the questions I would want each candidate to address:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you weren&amp;rsquo;t running, who would you vote/support for president?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how can we educate voters to make better decisions so that candidates are elected based on merit and not merely on name recall or popularity?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how can we reform campaign finance, so that it becomes transparent and candidates are not beholden to campaign donors?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how can we improve the slow pace of justice in the philippines?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;do you think there is currently too much power in the executive? what improvements can we make to have the legislature and the judiciary be more independent?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how can we make it easier and more attractive to start small/medium enterprises?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how can we minimize red tape in government transactions and make government agencies more efficient?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how can we make it more difficult for government employees from extorting citizens or otherwise abusing their authority? how can we make it easier to catch those who do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what safeguards can we place in the procurement process to avoid getting bad deals for the government?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what are your plans to use ICT to improve government services and transparency?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what are your plans for reducing the high cost of electricity in the country?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;do you think the people are getting what they deserve for the taxes they pay? what are your plans for reducing the tax burden on our people?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What plans do you have for improving our education system to increase literacy rates, reduce drop out rates and in general improve the quality of our schools?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Edit:) How can we get rid of the culture of patronage politics, or people expecting politicians to give them favors in exchange for support?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are your plans for making sure the economic growth experienced by the country improves the lives of more people?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suspect none of the above topics will be discussed tomorrow though. And if ever, most will reply with generic/motherhood statements. But maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll be pleasantly surprised.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>