<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>politics on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/politics/</link>
      <description>Recent content in politics on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Civilization, Liberal Democracy, and Authoritarianism
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/civilization-liberal-democracy-and-authoritarianism/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/civilization-liberal-democracy-and-authoritarianism/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I remember when playing the original version of Civilization &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/ancient-pc-gaming/&#34;&gt;back in the day&lt;/a&gt;, the &amp;ldquo;most advanced&amp;rdquo; form of government was Democracy, with the only downside of it being you can&amp;rsquo;t declare war (because you had a senate that would stop you.) The other available forms of government were typically not very useful, but Democracy massively increased your trade output, so most often I would build the Pyramids (a wonder which allowed switching to any government immediately and without penalty), and spend the rest of the game toggling between Democracy and Despotism (for when I wanted to go to war).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This made the game heavily slanted in favor of Western-style democracies, which was understandable for that time period. Around that era, the Soviet Union had just fallen, and the liberal democracy practiced by the United States, the one remaining superpower, became the shining example of a successful government that brought propserity to its citizens. I think that having grown up in this era and having been exposed to a lot of American culture (via TV and games and so forth) has led to my general bias in favor of liberal democracy and the values associated with it - freedom, equality, civil liberties, human rights, due process, checks and balances, separation of powers, and so on. (I cannot say the same is true for other people in my generation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, the modern versions of Civilization have matured in terms of how they handle governments, recognizing that modern governments have different approaches that are not necessarily represented by &amp;ldquo;democracy&amp;rdquo;. Civ 6 presents three choices for modern governments: Democracy, Communism, and Fascism; Civ 5 lets you choose between ideologies: Freedom, Order, or Autocracy. Perhaps this is a reflection of modern geopolitics, where not only is the United States teetering on the brink of authoritarianism, despite being the lone superpower, but those daring to challenge its hegemony are leaning more towards authoritarian governments as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from America&amp;rsquo;s traditional enemies like Russia and Iran, the starkest challenge comes from China, the juggernaut of Asia. Perhaps the ultimate counterexample to the idea that liberal democracy is the key to prosperity, China has been able to bring an economic boom to its citizens, leveraging the weight of a billion-person size market, all while retaining the trappings of power centralized in the state instead of the people. Censorship, propaganda, and adherence to the party are the norm, and those who dare speak out against the party are punished viciously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about all of this after a recent discussion with some Duterte supporters over at &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/philippines&#34;&gt;r/PH on reddit&lt;/a&gt;. The arguments in favor of the Duterte administration seem to stem around seeing him as a leader that &amp;ldquo;gets things done&amp;rdquo; (in quotes because I&amp;rsquo;m not sure quantifiably that he is getting things done more than other presidents), without regard for the damage to liberal values such as human rights, due process, checks and balances, and so on. Indeed even during the 2016 elections you could see some internet commentary stating that the problem with the country was that we had &amp;ldquo;too much freedom&amp;rdquo;, as if freedom were not an ideal to be aspired to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this light, the tendency of this admin to capitulate to China has an ideological angle as well, because China is the epitome of getting things done despite the cost to civil liberties, and of the state accumulating all power onto itself. It is disturbingly a trend not only in the Philippines, but even in a number of Western nations, where far-right parties with tendencies towards extreme nationalism and authoritarianism are gaining steam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been of the opinion that the world mostly exists in a state of trying to find balance; most trends wax and wane, trying to find the optimal equilibrium in which to settle. I worry that perhaps liberal democracy&amp;rsquo;s peak days have come and gone, and we are now on the brink on an era where authoritarianism gains ground. I had always hoped that our future was somehow leading to something like a Star Trek-like utopia, but there are plenty of other potential sci-fi future scenarios, not all of them pleasant. We can only hope that things get better before they get worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m not a political science expert or anything, so probably I&amp;rsquo;m not exactly using some of these terms accurately, feel free to educate me in the comments if you like.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Things were simpler before we were woke
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/things-were-simpler-before-we-were-woke/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/things-were-simpler-before-we-were-woke/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The results are disappointing, but that&amp;rsquo;s only because we expected better. Historically, those who have made it into the Senate did so mostly on name recognition. What does it matter if Diokno had the best resume of all the candidates, if many of the voters did not know who he was? How could he compete against someone who appeared on a hit primetime TV series right up until the start of the campaign period?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I think, things were simpler before we were woke. For me, at least. When I was younger I didn&amp;rsquo;t care much about politics. Oh of course like everybody, I got riled up about Estrada&amp;rsquo;s impeachment trial and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/07/gloriagate-now-is-not-the-time/&#34;&gt;Gloria&amp;rsquo;s election scandals&lt;/a&gt;, but back then I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much awareness on who the senators were, what party they were aligned with, who were the senate president or the speaker of the house, etc. Not in-depth as I&amp;rsquo;ve done during the more recent elections. Even back then there was a general sense of how dirty the elections and our politicians were, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much outrage in me then. Not yet at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I started &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/05/halalan-2004/&#34;&gt;casting my vote in 2004&lt;/a&gt;, I certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t legal for the prior elections in &amp;lsquo;98 and I don&amp;rsquo;t remember voting in the midterms in &amp;lsquo;01. At first I was like &amp;ldquo;Okay, I cast my vote, that&amp;rsquo;s my civic duty, yay&amp;rdquo; and was done with it, but as time went by awareness started to grow. As the PH internet has matured, information about the candidates became more easily available, and with that came the eventual and repeated disappointment with who our electorate actually gave the victories to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cut to today, and the vicious cycle repeats. Disheartening results that make no rational sense whatsoever. As if elections were ever decided rationally. And so it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many are being down on those who express an intention to migrate because of their disappointment. I can&amp;rsquo;t blame those who feel this way. It would be better to stay and fight the good fight of course, but it&amp;rsquo;s never that easy. People can get tired of politics, and I know that&amp;rsquo;s what certain parties would want - to beat us into submission by bludgeoning us with these terrible politicians and their dirty ways - but let people be tired and let people express their frustrations, it&amp;rsquo;s healthier that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m envious of those who chose to stay &amp;ldquo;unwoke&amp;rdquo;, that is, unconcerned with modern-day political issues, and just stick to living their daily lives. Like I said, times were simpler then. You only worried about your own problems. You shook your fist at the taxman and the shitty government service but at the end of the day did nothing about it. It&amp;rsquo;s selfish, but it can be understandable. Life is not always easy, and not all are accorded the privilege of worrying about things greater than themselves. All the more reason for us who have that privilege to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am tempted to just step back from it all, back to those simpler times. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent too much energy worrying about this country, let others take over now. I won&amp;rsquo;t be personally affected too much - I&amp;rsquo;m not likely to be killed in a drug bust, I&amp;rsquo;m not one of the poor that his cronies can bully around, I don&amp;rsquo;t lose anything if they let China take our islands, I can survive any economic fallout (probably), I have enough sources of real information even if they choke the press, I have the option of migrating if things get too bad, etc. There is a part of me that is just like &amp;ldquo;bahala na kayo diyan, just let me watch my movies and play my video games in peace!&amp;rdquo; But who am I kidding? The odds that I can stay out of it for long are low, but perhaps a short respite is in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things were simpler before we were woke. Unfortunately, that&amp;rsquo;s a genie we can&amp;rsquo;t put back in the bottle. Being woke is exhausting. Rest, regroup, recover, and hopefully have the energy to come back and fight again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These rants were brought to you by the letters disappointment and frustration.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>PH Elections 2019: Otso Diretso, Compromises, Lesser Evils
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/ph-elections-2019-otso-diretso-compromises-lesser-evils/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/ph-elections-2019-otso-diretso-compromises-lesser-evils/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The PH senatorial and local elections are on Monday. I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t want to write the usual election post, mostly because I was annoyed with and tired of the electorate and the politicians and the system and all that. But we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t give in to despair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often when choosing who to vote, it will be difficult to find candidates who align perfectly with your values. You make compromises to prioritize those issues you think are more important. You settle on lesser evils to try to stave off the worse ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be scary sometimes to make a judgment that &amp;ldquo;this candidate is great&amp;rdquo;, because you can&amp;rsquo;t really know a person right? And these candidates, you only see a sliver of their lives, what they project publicly, so it can be difficult to judge. But at least you should be openly rejecting those who are already projecting poor values: supporting murders, blind support for the administration, plunderers, criminals, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the most important issue facing the country right now is the need to provide a decent check and balance in the legislative branch, so for this reason, I will vote all of the Otso Diretso senatorial slate. Some of them aren&amp;rsquo;t the best choices, but the administration candidates are far worse. Even if you are not inclined to support the opposition, I strongly suggest you consider Chel Diokno. He&amp;rsquo;s the best candidate I&amp;rsquo;ve seen since the late Raul Roco. Gutoc, Alejano, and Aquino are the next best ones. Hilbay has had some flaky opinions, but he&amp;rsquo;s smart without a doubt, and a bar topnotcher. Roxas had a poor stint sa executive branch, but he was ok sa legislative. Macalintal and Tanada are the ones I have the least info about, but again, opposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am considering leaving the remaining 4 slots open, will probably decide on election day. The pickings are slim. If only we had an option for downvotes instead, I could vote down the really bad choices like Marcos, Go, Revilla, dela Rosa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local elections: The Quezon City mayoral choices aren&amp;rsquo;t very good. Belmonte has an air of incompetence. But her opponent Crisologo is as a friend described &amp;ldquo;an evil Ilocano warlord stuck in the 70s&amp;rdquo;, so in the choice between incompetent and evil, we have no choice but to choose incompetence. (There is a third candidate, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think he has a chance.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I will skip voting for the vice mayor and councilor slots. I have no info on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the QC sixth district, I&amp;rsquo;m lucky that our district has a liberal party incumbent who has made some house votes I agree with, so for me it&amp;rsquo;s still Kit Belmonte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Party list: Eh, IDK anymore. Maybe Akbayan or Magdalo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I don&amp;rsquo;t have very strong opinions this time around, especially on the local level. I am not super optimistic about this election, as I suspect the electorate may very well disappoint me yet again. But still, duty is duty. And so we hope for the best while fearing the worst.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Truth, Logic, and Elections
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/truth-logic-and-elections/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/truth-logic-and-elections/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;From a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=10157380641633991&amp;amp;id=827533990&#34;&gt;friend&amp;rsquo;s Facebook post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less than 2 weeks to the elections, I want to share a hard lesson I learned from the previous one. Especially given that I&amp;rsquo;ve had formal lessons in rhetoric and logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not believe that logical fallacies are fallacies. Or rather&amp;ndash;understand that they are logical fallacies, but that the world does not run on logic and so any classroom lessons on what arguments are fallacious have no relevance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only relevant matter is if people react positively to what you say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people who respond to facts &lt;em&gt;ARE ALREADY ANTI-DUTS&lt;/em&gt;. So forget about convincing more voters with facts. The numbers of the executed don&amp;rsquo;t matter to them. Duterte&amp;rsquo;s bank accounts that have been proven to exist don&amp;rsquo;t matter to them. The Duts&amp;rsquo; family businesses that have not been registered with the SEC or which have irregularities in their filings don&amp;rsquo;t matter to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That shit just don&amp;rsquo;t fly for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accept it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rely on appeals to emotion, on ad hominem attacks, on oversimplified memes, on dramatic pictures, short posts with punchy lines that are light on numbers. Get people to identify with you first, get them to agree with you on things that are completely nonpolitical so that they start to see that you aren&amp;rsquo;t so different from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resort to all the muck that works in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If people have to be tricked into believing the truth&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s better than them continuing to be tricked into believing lies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pictures of executed people are more effective than the names of the murdered. Pictures of Chinese businesses are more effective than long talks about interest rates. If you&amp;rsquo;ve worked in graphic design or in marketing or the ad business, YOU ALREADY KNOW what works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m afflicted by a certain form of foolish idealism that makes me want to believe that decisions should be made based on things like facts, logic, and reason. I want to believe that we can take the high road, and not have to resort to the same tactics I find distasteful. I realize that often this isn&amp;rsquo;t how the world works, and yes ever since the last elections, I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself more and more disillusioned and disenchanted about how the Filipino electorate makes their decisions. I don&amp;rsquo;t what happens with the elections in two weeks - I don&amp;rsquo;t even know how I&amp;rsquo;m going to be voting - but my expectaions are not high. Regardless of what happens or what compromises we end up making or supporting or whatever imperfect politicians we end up voting for or electing, I think we need to make sure not to lose sight of the ideals we hold and of what we believe the ideal world needs to be, and how we need to get there. Otherwise, what are we even fighting for?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Discerning motives
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/discerning-motives/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/discerning-motives/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Scenario: Someone I know, let&amp;rsquo;s call him/her Person A, appears to be supporting Party B, who in my opinion represents some of the worsts traits of Philippine politics (including but not limited to corruption, patronage, personality politics, etc). Now, I like to be optimistic about people and give them the benefit of the doubt, so in a bid to understand I tried to list down some possible motivations for Person A to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are I believe two axes to consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whether Person A believes Party B is good/bad for the country&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whether Person A personally has good/bad motives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quadrant 1: Person A believes Party B is good for the country, and Person A has good motives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Person A does not believe the negative things about Party B&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quadrant 2: Person A believes Party B is bad for the country, and Person A has good motives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lesser evil&amp;rdquo;: Person A believes that while Party B is bad for the country, other options are worse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Necessary evil&amp;rdquo;: Person A believes the support of Party B (as a party in power) is necessary to get good things done and is using them as a means to an end to achieve better things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cynicism&amp;rdquo;: Person A believes that Party B&amp;rsquo;s politics is inevitably how the country works and to try to change things for the better would be foolish or a waste of time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quadrant 3: Person A believes Party B is good for the country, and Person A has bad motives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Person A does not believe the negative things about Party B (or does not care), and merely wants to use them to further their ambitions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quadrant 4: Person A believes Party B is bad for the country, and Person A has bad motives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greed/Ambition: Person A believes that Party B&amp;rsquo;s politics is inevitably how the country works and is just looking out for theirselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to my own leanings, I do not believe quadrants 1 and 3 are likely (I have yet to see evidence indicating otherwise), so this does not paint a good picture of Person A. People of course have complex motivations, and most of the time even the villains may see themselves as being the heroes. I can only hope that at worst Person A is somewhere in quadrant 2 and not quadrant 4&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The sky is falling
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/the-sky-is-falling/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 05:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/the-sky-is-falling/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of doom and gloom and bad news in the world these days, giving us ordinary folk little reason to be optimistic. Examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we are almost certainly too late to prevent climate change at all and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.minnpost.com/earth-journal/2018/10/new-outlook-on-global-warming-best-prepare-for-social-collapse-and-soon/?fbclid=IwAR2OR1lTChzd3eAnEl9nnlCpgDr9GhvUKxNrCd5JNXShQK9Uj8EMCbKPvhM&#34;&gt;social collapse is now an actual possibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump has begun taking steps to walk back a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www3.nhk.or.jp/nhkworld/en/news/20181021_80/&#34;&gt;nuclear arms control treaty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;increasing trends of nationalism and populism threatening to walk back the gains of globalisation (i.e. Brexit) and diversity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elon Musk warns us of the existential threat of artificial intelligence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;locally, some friends of mine are largely pessimistic about the future of Philippine society as it seems that we are falling further into the trap of autocratic leanings and dynasty-driven patronage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if things are looking so bad because we are coming from a period of relative peace and expansion of liberal democracy the past few decades (not saying things are perfect, but at least we haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten into any world wars recently). Maybe some of the societal and cultural problems highlighted above may be nothing more than society trying to find a new equilibrium in an age of political correctness and social justice. Climate change is of course, a game changing problem that we as a society seem to be unable to face or control. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to think of myself as an optimist, but even I am increasingly wary of where our world and my country are heading. I am slightly comforted by the words of an American novelist, which I heard from the recent season of Daredevil:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &#34;Life is to be lived, not controlled; and humanity is won by continuing to play in face of certain defeat.&#34;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&amp;ndash; Ralph Ellison&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to hold out hope that humanity and society can adapt and survive these crises, that we have not come all this way simply to lose to our own hubris.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Change and Risk and Governments
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/change-and-risk-and-governments/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 05:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/change-and-risk-and-governments/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Systemic change is difficult. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about software projects/systems, but there are a lot of parallels with societal systems too, like governments or states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been in large projects with hundreds of thousands of LOC where a lot of the code was painful to read and full of code smells and so on. It happens over time as projects get maintained by different developers and teams or different enhancements or changes are made. It becomes more difficult/costly for new developers to work on the project as things are brittle and may easily fall apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also had the dubious pleasure of living under a system of government heavily burdened by corruption and inefficiency and patronage and nepotism and inequality and a bunch of other problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Will Be Tempted To Throw Everything Out And Start Over&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such situations, you will often find yourself fed up. You will be tempted to throw everything away and start over and rebuild everything from scratch. You wonder who made all of these past decisions that have resulted in such a terrible system and what the heck were they thinking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, you can&amp;rsquo;t just throw everything away. People still need to eat, and the system users still need to do their work. You can instead do some kind of system-wide one-time big-time change. But the problem with that is&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change Is Risk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More often than not, the existing system works. Or at least, it works well enough that the system isn&amp;rsquo;t totally unusable. The software system&amp;rsquo;s users can still perform the needed functions, albeit maybe with some number of bugs. The state&amp;rsquo;s citizens can still mostly survive and there aren&amp;rsquo;t riots on the streets or people dying of mass starvation or anything like that. Life is hard, but there is life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking to change things means some level of risk, and of course some level of cost. There are several possible outcomes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change happens and things become better. Hooray! The change was worth it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change happens but things remain the same. Uhh, why did we spend all that time and effort for the change then?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change happens but things actually get worse. This is the worst of all worlds. We wasted time and money and energy and things got worse! Why didn&amp;rsquo;t anyone warn us this could happen!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often we can&amp;rsquo;t predict with any certainty which outcome will happen. We can make educated guesses, by comparing to past experiences or other people&amp;rsquo;s experiences. **But each software project is unique. **This is kind of a blessing since it means it&amp;rsquo;s hard for programmers to run out of work. But it&amp;rsquo;s also more of a curse since it means we can only reuse small parts from other projects with no guarantee that the entire whole will work cohesively together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countries/states/governments are unique too. Each people has their own geography, culture and history and unique problems arising from such. And to make matters worse, countries are made up of people, and most people will have differing opinions on which things are better and which things are worse. This makes it much more difficult to form a consensus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;****Granted that change is risk. But sometimes we have to take those risks anyway. We have to decide whether the risk is worth the possible upside vs the potential downside.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Superhero shows being political
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/superhero-shows-being-political/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 05:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/superhero-shows-being-political/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Comic books and superheroes have always tended to skew towards liberal philosophies, given how writers and artists tend to support ideals like individualism and free expression. So it&amp;rsquo;s not surprising that the derivative shows tend to lean the same way. Not only do many of the shows promote diversity, but many are becoming overtly political as well. Some recent examples. (Spoilers for current seasons of Supergirl, Legends of Tomorrow and Daredevil follow)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The current season 4 of Supergirl seems to be focusing on anti-alien sentiment, a thinly-veiled allegory towards the anti-immigration movement propagated in far right &amp;ldquo;nationalist&amp;rdquo; circles. Similar to real-life, hatemongers are portrayed riling up crowds frustrated with losing jobs and threats to law and order due to the presence of &amp;ldquo;aliens&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pilot episode of Legends of Tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s season 4 includes a short segment where one of the characters visits her mother, a Muslim immigrant in the US, and wishes she could warn her to move to Canada before &amp;ldquo;this country turns against her.&amp;rdquo; Do the Legends know about things to come? (Of course, during the previous season, the showrunners &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2017/aug/4/dcs-legends-of-tomorrow-producer-admits-muslim-cha/&#34;&gt;admitted that the Muslim character in question was introduced precisely as a response to Trump&amp;rsquo;s election&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally, in the fantastic Daredevil season 3, Wilson&amp;rsquo;s Fisk&amp;rsquo;s being billeted in the &amp;ldquo;Presidential Hotel&amp;rdquo; and his calling out his supposed crimes as politically-motivated &amp;ldquo;fake news&amp;rdquo; reminds a lot of people of the current American president. If that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, &lt;a href=&#34;http://boundingintocomics.com/2018/10/18/daredevil-season-3-showrunner-compares-wilson-fisk-to-donald-trump/&#34;&gt;even the showrunner compares the Kingpin to Trump&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though it&amp;rsquo;s not a completely new thing I&amp;rsquo;m glad the showrunners are willing to make their political opinions known. This, despite the existence the so-called ComicsGate movement among a minority of superhero fans, which is a self-described revolt against &amp;ldquo;liberalism&amp;rdquo;. I wonder if these ComicsGate people also hate the TV shows?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The perils of hyperpartisanship
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/the-perils-of-hyperpartisanship/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 01:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/the-perils-of-hyperpartisanship/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A few days ago I read this great &lt;a href=&#34;https://np.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/9mcuy2/viral_manspreading_video_is_staged_kremlin/e7e10n2/&#34;&gt;Reddit comment about how increasing hyperpartisanship makes it easier to influence the entire population&lt;/a&gt;. Quoting the relevant part:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Once you&#39;ve done that, you have a population that&#39;s easier to manipulate. You have, say, 30% that&#39;s 100% sure on both ends, and probably another 15% on both ends that are 80% sure, and a remaining 10% that could go both ways. The more you do this, the more the 15% will be set in stone.&lt;br /&gt;Then, the fun begins with manipulating the 10%. You know where they live (through facebook), you know how they think (Cambridge Analytica), so you can target &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt;, and only &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt;. Not only can you target this particular group, but by knowing how the electoral system works, you can target only a few people, in a few swing states.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US is already in this hyperpartisan state, as evidenced by how the &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1049048025073512448.html&#34;&gt;GOP rhetoric often has them itching for civil war&lt;/a&gt;. This is kind of mirrored in the more extreme online views of some pro-admin people here in the PH, with admin propaganda minions demonizing anyone who opposes the president and some literally calling for opposition to be jailed or even killed. I don&amp;rsquo;t think the PH has gotten as bad as the US in terms of hyperpartisanship though, mainly because (a) political parties in the Philippines are a joke; (b) Majority of Filipinos distrust politicians in general (hence the popular term &amp;ldquo;trapo&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s just that they still vote for them even knowing how they are); and (c) Filipino politicians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a friend who has given up on being moderate or centrist, he says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;The past couple of years have taught me that politics really is like Game of Thrones. Moderation and compromise is weak. If you get complacent, if you let your foot off their throat, they&#39;ll destroy you, so you need to be willing to do all that dirty stuff right back.&lt;br /&gt;In the US the other side is racists, misogynists and rich old white ppl. In the Philippines the other side LITERALLY HAS DEATH SQUADS.&lt;br /&gt;Progressives can never let up on the gas. They can never stop and say &#34;this is enough,&#34; because if you do, the gains it took decades to work toward can be undone just like that.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure he knows I disagree with this position &amp;ndash; I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in fighting dirty (but I do believe in calling out those who do). I&amp;rsquo;m not advocating we adhere to the Spaceballs quote &amp;ldquo;Evil will always triumph because good is dumb,&amp;rdquo; but rather I would prefer people find a way to rise above this hyperpartisanship and find better ways to resolve differences. Somehow, there&amp;rsquo;s still part of a &amp;ldquo;Lawful Good&amp;rdquo; idealist in me, despite the best efforts of this terrible world. Maybe this will be the death of me when fascists start trampling over the rest of us.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Repost from JuliaSerano https://twitter.com/JuliaSerano/statuses/828760357451673601/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/828883407492886529/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 08:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/828883407492886529/</guid>
            <description>
            
Repost from JuliaSerano https://twitter.com/JuliaSerano/statuses/828760357451673601/:
            &lt;p&gt;this is what philosopher Karl Popper had to say about the &amp;ldquo;paradox of tolerance&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@juliaserano/free-speech-and-the-paradox-of-tolerance-e0547aefe538&#34;&gt;https://medium.com/@juliaserano/free-speech-and-the-paradox-of-tolerance-e0547aefe538&lt;/a&gt; #freespeech #politics #activism&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Marcos and Historical Revisionism
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/marcos-and-historical-revisionism/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 07:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/marcos-and-historical-revisionism/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to keep telling people that Ferdinand Marcos was a terrible president and that the Martial Law he imposed was terrible for the country. Imagine if a significant percentage of German citizens kept insisting that Hitler was a great man and the more sensible Germans had to keep trying to educate them on why that wasn&amp;rsquo;t true and why World War II was a terrible idea and that they wanted to elect Hitler&amp;rsquo;s descendant to a position of national prominence. That&amp;rsquo;s where we are right now with all these Filipinos supporting Marcos. (Why yes, I did open a blog post immediately with Godwin&amp;rsquo;s Law, thankyouverymuch)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have nothing personally against Bongbong Marcos, and I make no judgments on his personal track record and qualifications as a public servant. My main issue with him is that he is promoting historical revisionism of the sort that holocaust deniers are proud of. By insisting that his father was a great President and that Martial Law was actually good for the country is to demand that we unlearn the lessons of the past. Sure, the Aquinos and the succeeding administrations weren&amp;rsquo;t exactly the best either and had their faults too, but that&amp;rsquo;s beside the point. The crimes and excesses of the Marcos regime are well-documented and even international bodies have rendered verdicts against them. To deny these truths is to fool ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do believe that at some point we need to move on from this issue. But I believe that in order to move on, there is one thing needed most of all: the truth. A friend recently asked: if Bongbong apologizes for his father&amp;rsquo;s sins and for Martial Law, would I accept that apology and move on? My answer, verbatim: &amp;ldquo;For me it&amp;rsquo;s acknowledging the sins of the father, returning the money, and telling all about the crimes of the marcos regime, including what they know about the forced disappearances and torture, the staged ambush that started martial law, the crony deals, the assassination of Ninoy, the cheating during the snap elections, etc.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I write this, I believe the Vice Presidential election results are too close to call. But regardless of whether BBM wins or not, the very fact that at least 13 million voters chose to accept his brand of historical revisionism should be a source of national shame.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;TIL that Fox News won a Supreme Court Case defending its right to lie to the American people.&#39; on /r/politics at https://reddit.com/r/politics/comments/tw3gf/til_that_fox_news_won_a_supreme_court_case/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/05/c4q7uv7/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/05/c4q7uv7/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;TIL that Fox News won a Supreme Court Case defending its right to lie to the American people.&amp;#39; on /r/politics at https://reddit.com/r/politics/comments/tw3gf/til_that_fox_news_won_a_supreme_court_case/:

            &lt;p&gt;They shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to use the word &amp;ldquo;News&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Chiz Escudero Real Ultimate Facts!!!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/03/chiz-escudero-real-ultimate-facts/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2007 13:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/03/chiz-escudero-real-ultimate-facts/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via delicious:
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://chizescuderofacts.info/&#34;&gt;Chiz Escudero Real Ultimate Facts!!!&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Pinoy Vote - Philippine Election 2007
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/03/pinoy-vote-philippine-election-2007/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 17:28:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/03/pinoy-vote-philippine-election-2007/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via delicious:
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pinoyvote.info/&#34;&gt;Pinoy Vote - Philippine Election 2007&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Recording Industry vs The People
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/04/recording-industry-vs-the-people/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2006 15:20:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/04/recording-industry-vs-the-people/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via delicious:
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://recordingindustryvspeople.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Recording Industry vs The People&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Download recordings of alleged destabilization tape - INQ7.net
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/06/download-recordings-of-alleged-destabilization-tape-inq7-net/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2005 22:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/06/download-recordings-of-alleged-destabilization-tape-inq7-net/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via delicious:
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.inq7.net/breaking/index.php?index=1&amp;amp;story_id=39543&#34;&gt;Download recordings of alleged destabilization tape - INQ7.net&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Code v2.0
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/03/code-v2-0/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2005 09:07:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/03/code-v2-0/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via delicious:
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://codebook.jot.com/WikiHome&#34;&gt;Code v2.0&lt;/a&gt;

            &lt;p&gt;Lawrence Lessig - Code and Other Laws of Cyberspace v2.0&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>