<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>movies on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/movies/</link>
      <description>Recent content in movies on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 15:26:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/movies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Reviews: Skyfall, Jumanji: Welcome to the Jungle, Police Story
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/reviews-skyfall-jumanji-welcome-to-the-jungle-police-story/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 15:26:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/reviews-skyfall-jumanji-welcome-to-the-jungle-police-story/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;h3 id=&#34;skyfall-2012&#34;&gt;Skyfall (2012)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 23, Daniel Craig&amp;rsquo;s third. I watched this in the theaters back in 2012, so this is the last rewatch of my James Bond run. Back then my main complaint was that &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/11/264691037212131328/&#34;&gt;Bond&amp;rsquo;s plan in the last thirty minutes of the movie was terrible&lt;/a&gt;. The same complaint stands even now, especially given the eventual outcome of that plan. Make no mistake: the entire defending the house sequence is one of the best things about the movie from an action standpoint, but tactically it was terrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole film is basically a swan song for Judi Dench&amp;rsquo;s M, exploring the extremes of her relationship with Bond and how fond they are of each other in spite of everything. Ben Whishaw appears as the new Q, who starts his run appropriately, by letting MI6 get hacked. The film still calls out the old Bond film tropes, with Q telling Bond they&amp;rsquo;re not really into exploding pens anymore. Bardem gives a good performance as the villain Silva, but the character felt a bit underdeveloped as we didn&amp;rsquo;t get his background until an info drop around two-thirds through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This film also brings cyberterrorism into the modern Bond era, and the usefulness of MI6&amp;rsquo;s focus on human intelligence during the modern era is called into question. It will be interesting to see how technology further changes the Bond films moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film ends with basically the Connery status quo - Bond answering to a male M, flirting with his assistant Moneypenny, and assisted by Q. It&amp;rsquo;s something I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have appreciated back when I first saw the film in 2012, given that this was only the 4th Bond film I&amp;rsquo;ve seen at that point, and none of them had that Connery setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is &lt;strong&gt;Spectre&lt;/strong&gt;, which I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen before and is the last one of the run before &lt;strong&gt;No Time To Die&lt;/strong&gt; comes out in September!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;jumanji-welcome-to-the-jungle-2017&#34;&gt;Jumanji: Welcome to the Jungle (2017)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched this even if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen the old first movie. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a high opinion of The Rock, er&amp;hellip; Dwayne Johnson&amp;rsquo;s acting skills, because I&amp;rsquo;ve previously seen him only in silly sports films like The Game Plan or The Tooth Fairy, but he does a good enough job here, portraying a nerdy high schooler trapped in a buff, macho, adventurer hero type. Same goes for Jack Black portraying a teenage girl in&amp;hellip; well, Jack Black&amp;rsquo;s body. I like how the Jumanji game evolved from a board game to a video game for more modern times. The movie overall is a pretty good popcorn movie and has a few funny bits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;police-story-1985&#34;&gt;Police Story (1985)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one was just something that I saw was on Netflix and was like &amp;ldquo;Why not?&amp;rdquo; Had to watch with Cantonese voice and English subs, the only alternative was Japanese voice. Pretty good, for its time. As you&amp;rsquo;d expect from Jacky Chan, all the action/fight sequences are great; I especially like the bus chase sequence and the ending fights in the mall were great. Apparently that sliding down the pole stunt is considered one of the best action film stunts of all time. The film glorifies police excesses though.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Suicide Squad
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/the-suicide-squad/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 14:25:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/the-suicide-squad/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;First, the spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/12cbfc5fe2bf124a832da481095c364b/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2021-08-06 10:27:59&#34;&gt;6 Aug 2021 10:27am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;THE SUICIDE SQUAD spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;great, fun, violent, hilarious, possibly best of DCEU so far&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;trailers have spoiled waaaay too much of this movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first act was ok, second act felt a bit meh, third act was great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--sep--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hard to comment on actor performances without spoiling things, but Daniela Melchior was great and Idris Elba took the role seriously&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is a post-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full review on the blog later&lt;/p&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second: I have to say, titling it &amp;ldquo;The Suicide Squad&amp;rdquo; is super annoying especially for anyone who does data processing/indexing, since &amp;ldquo;The&amp;rdquo; is what differentiates it from the 2016 word, and that&amp;rsquo;s usually ignored in stuff like search engines and such. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, it turns out I don&amp;rsquo;t actually have very spoiler-y stuff to say though; the film is pretty straightforward. I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll try. It&amp;rsquo;s a marked improvement over the 2016 film in all aspects. It&amp;rsquo;s also visually a feast; James Gunn obviously had way too much fun with many of the shots. I am less a fan of the music/soundtrack choices here than in Guardians of the Galaxy though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the DC characters here are very strange choices, but most of them are used well. At least, the ones that survived most of the movie are pretty good. The rest were mostly cannon fodder who got killed off in like the first 5 minutes. King Shark was hilarious; Bloodshot and Peacemaker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;rivalry&amp;rdquo; was great; you find yourself strangely rooting for Polka Dot Man; and Ratcatcher 2 was indeed the heart of this film, as promised. Also, I like how they straight-up just played Starro true to his comic book roots, and he&amp;rsquo;s just a giant kaiju starfish. He even walks around like Patrick Starr lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am disappointed at how much the trailers have spoiled though. Specifically thinking of that scene where they&amp;rsquo;re about to go rescue Harley but she just shows up outside and are all &amp;ldquo;What are you guys doing?&amp;rdquo;, that would have been a great gag on first watch. Also I would&amp;rsquo;ve led with that scene first before cutting to &amp;ldquo;X minutes earlier&amp;rdquo; and THEN show Harley tearing her way through the building to escape. I actually didn&amp;rsquo;t like the &amp;ldquo;Harley getting captured&amp;rdquo; subplot too much though, as it felt like unnecessary filler that was added just because they needed to give one of the big stars more to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still overall pretty good, and a welcome entry to the DCEU.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/12cbfc5fe2bf124a832da481095c364b/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 10:27:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/12cbfc5fe2bf124a832da481095c364b/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;THE SUICIDE SQUAD spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;great, fun, violent, hilarious, possibly best of DCEU so far&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;trailers have spoiled waaaay too much of this movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first act was ok, second act felt a bit meh, third act was great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!--sep--&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hard to comment on actor performances without spoiling things, but Daniela Melchior was great and Idris Elba took the role seriously&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is a post-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full review on the blog later&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Quantum of Solace
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/quantum-of-solace/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 16:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/quantum-of-solace/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 22, Daniel Craig&amp;rsquo;s second outing. I actually &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/11/996918103/&#34;&gt;watched this back in 2008&lt;/a&gt;, but apparently I wasn&amp;rsquo;t super impressed (and I wish I wrote more back then lol). I suspect I didn&amp;rsquo;t really like it because this movie is actually a direct sequel to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-casino-gunpowder-halloween-masters/&#34;&gt;Casino Royale&lt;/a&gt; which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen until this year. It picks up on several hanging plot threads, and some of the characters appear again, and Bond in this film is primarily motivated by anger over the events of the previous film. Not to mention I had only seen two Brosnan movies prior to watching Quantum of Solace at that time, so I really didn&amp;rsquo;t have either the franchise foundation or the context from Casino Royale to appreciate this film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This film sets up more of the gritty tone for modern Bond. Unlike the black and white factions of the cold war, the geopolitical setup here is more complicated, with even Bond&amp;rsquo;s traditional allies the CIA mostly turning against him. The villain&amp;rsquo;s plot and motivations seem kind of thin and the plot itself is a bit forgettable; while I recall many of the scenes from my previous watching, I didn&amp;rsquo;t remember what the overall plot was until it just happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olga Kurylenko gave a great performance here. The film also has some great action sequences, and even hits the trifecta of land, sea, and air chases/vehicle fights. The theme song here is &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Another Way to Die&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; by Alicia Keys and Jack White (of the White Stripes), which was ok but I didn&amp;rsquo;t particularly enjoy. Stana Katic makes a bit appearance here towards the end, before her run on &lt;strong&gt;Castle&lt;/strong&gt;. Also I just chuckle to myself whenever Bond tries to use a 2008-era dumbphone like it was a modern smartphone, such as taking pictures good enough for facial recognition from like a hundred feet away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the movie is a decent watch. Overall I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying modern Bond, but I have to admit I kind of miss the campy tropes of classic Bond, but I can understand why they&amp;rsquo;d have no place in a modern action franchise. I mean, Craig still hasn&amp;rsquo;t even got a Q or any fancy devices! (Yes, I know he gets a new Q eventually). Anyway, next is Skyfall!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reviews: Casino Royale, Gunpowder Milkshake, The Long Halloween, Masters of the Universe Revelation
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-casino-royale-gunpowder-milkshake-the-long-halloween-masters-of-the-universe-revelation/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-casino-royale-gunpowder-milkshake-the-long-halloween-masters-of-the-universe-revelation/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve watched lately. Spoilers for Gunpowder Milkshake and MotU: Revelation are marked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;casino-royale-2006&#34;&gt;Casino Royale (2006)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 21, and the first for Daniel Craig. The final era in this James Bond run, looking forward to it. Casino Royale is new to me, but I&amp;rsquo;ve seen two of Craig&amp;rsquo;s Bond films, so I have an idea of what to expect: a more serious and much less campy James Bond, grim and determined. The tone here is much closer to Dalton&amp;rsquo;s two films than any of the other runs. Since it&amp;rsquo;s kind of a reboot, it takes place early in Bond&amp;rsquo;s career, in fact he earns his double-O status right in the cold open. Craig&amp;rsquo;s Bond is younger, brasher, more vulnerable, and a bit more prone to mistakes, like letting himself getting caught on camera assassinating a prisoner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme song here is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YnzgdBAKyJo&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You Know My Name&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by Chris Cornell of SoundGarden fame. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit more alternative than recent theme songs; I like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judi Dench is back as M, the only actor carried over from previous incarnations. We don&amp;rsquo;t get any of the usual support staff like Moneypenny or Q. Bond spends most of the first half of the film alone in the field, and the second half supported by treasury agent Vesper Lynd (played by Eva Green). Mads Mikkelsen plays the protagonist, terrorist financier Le Chiffre, who Bond challenges to a high-stakes poker game at the titular Casino Royale. Also making an appearance is an old Bond ally, CIA&amp;rsquo;s Felix Leiter, who we last saw mauled by a shark in Dalton&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/4e93006d466cb2f6a53325cba8e27b63/&#34;&gt;License to Kill&lt;/a&gt;. (He has been recast as a black man for the modern age of James Bond.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot is reasonable and action-packed. Daniel Craig probably feels the least &amp;ldquo;Bond-like&amp;rdquo; compared to what his predecessors have established for the role, but his Bond is pretty good and is portrayed as relentless and unstoppable, in spite of his mistakes. The on-foot chase scene in Madagascar near the start of the film is great, especially all the crane shots. Le Chiffre seems a bit incompetent for a villain. The final third of the movie (after the poker game) plays out a bit strangely, for a while I was like &amp;ldquo;What the heck is going on?&amp;rdquo; There is a betrayal in the end that I didn&amp;rsquo;t see coming, which erased any doubt in my mind whether I had actually watched this one in the theaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to the rest of Craig&amp;rsquo;s run!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gunpowder-milkshake-2021&#34;&gt;Gunpowder Milkshake (2021)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We watched this during our Saturday online gaming session watch-along. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have high expectations for the film, as I thought it was kind of an ultraviolent grim John-Wick style thing and I didn&amp;rsquo;t really think Karen Gillan and Lena Headey would be good to lead that kind of movie. It does turn out to be ultraviolent, but not super grim, and in fact maybe even a little goofy. There are some great action sequences and fight scenes here, but as soon as I saw that 
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    Karen Gillan was going to have a fight scene in the doctor&amp;rsquo;s office with her arms all floppy from anesthesia
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
, I was like, ok this movie is already worth watching. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a very deep, complicated plot or anything, but overall a decent popcorn watch. A fun, ultraviolent, very bloody, very much not for kids movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;batman-the-long-halloween-2021&#34;&gt;Batman: The Long Halloween (2021)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a 2-part entry to the DC Universe animated movie line, an adaptation of the famous comic of the same name by Jeph Loeb and Tim Sale. The story covers an early year of Batman&amp;rsquo;s career as he works with Captain Jim Gordon and then-district attorney Harvey Dent to face both the Gotham mob and a serial killer that kills once a month, on the holidays. The film mostly covers the same story beats as the comic (which I had to review because it&amp;rsquo;s been probably more than a decade since I read it!), with a bit of a twist towards the end of the first part that changes the eventual ending in the second part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t help but compare this storyline to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/07/movies-the-dark-knight/&#34;&gt;The Dark Knight (2008)&lt;/a&gt; as it covers some of the same elements: organized crime in Gotham and the origin of Two-Face among others. In fact I believe the comic book was one of the inspirations for Nolan&amp;rsquo;s eventual plot for TDK. I would guess that TDK changes were largely due to the need to focus on The Joker, who is more of a minor villain The Long Halloween, and I can&amp;rsquo;t help but imagine what if Nolan had chosen to stay more faithful to TLH storyline, what kind of movie could we have gotten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this particular animated version is pretty good, mostly faithful to the source material, and I like the animation style here. Jensen Ackles is a serviceable Batman voice, and Troy Baker is a pretty good Joker; for a moment I wondered if it was Mark Hamill in the role. Part one was released back in June, and part two just last week, so I only watched both parts today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the next DCU animated movie project is &lt;strong&gt;Injustice&lt;/strong&gt;, based on the game series of the same name, also looking forward to that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;masters-of-the-universe-revelation-season-1-part-1&#34;&gt;Masters of the Universe: Revelation (season 1 part 1)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also watched this during Saturday&amp;rsquo;s watch-along. This one is a bit controversial, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write about it even though technically the season is only halfway through. The controversy is because the show&amp;rsquo;s plot mostly focuses around Teela and a quest she undergoes after the events of the first episode: 
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    He-Man and Skeletor are presumed dead in a battle and Teela leaves the service of King Randor out of anger over having Adam&amp;rsquo;s secret withheld from her for so long.
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voice work is pretty good; we immediately recognized Lena Headey&amp;rsquo;s voice as Evil-Lyn, and Mark Hamill as Skeletor is unmistakeable. We didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize Sarah Michelle Gellar as Teela though! The storyline so far is okay, though not super original. It kind of felt like a typical JRPG party-gathering and going on a quest thing, really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of old fans didn&amp;rsquo;t like the focus being taken away from He-Man and focusing on a female character, which many imagined as purely a diversity play. I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s much too early to judge the season overall, since it&amp;rsquo;s only halfway through, but even then, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong about focusing on some other characters, as the show is explicitly titled &amp;ldquo;Masters of the Universe&amp;rdquo; without the &amp;ldquo;He-Man and the&amp;hellip; &amp;quot; prefix. It&amp;rsquo;s probably best to see where Kevin Smith takes us for the eventual second part (for which we have no release date yet).&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/1420073402728026115/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 17:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/1420073402728026115/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m here for the tiny Stay Pufts at 1:32&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghostbusters Afterlife Trailer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XKe5XTrThj8&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XKe5XTrThj8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#movies&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reviews: Die Another Day, Army of the Dead, Valerian, Superstore, Omelas
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-die-another-day-army-of-the-dead-valerian-superstore-omelas/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 02:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-die-another-day-army-of-the-dead-valerian-superstore-omelas/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I used to do these &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Watching Lately&amp;rdquo; posts&lt;/a&gt; to talk about movies/tv/books I&amp;rsquo;d recently consumed, but for a while I folded up the reviews into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/weeknotes&#34;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; and sometimes via short &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes&#34;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; but the reviews have been getting longer so I guess I&amp;rsquo;m bring the &amp;ldquo;Watching Lately&amp;rdquo; tag and series of posts back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;die-another-day-2002&#34;&gt;Die Another Day (2002)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 20 and Brosnan&amp;rsquo;s final appearance. The main question for me going in was: have I actually watched this before in the theatre? My memory says no, but this movie does have the ice palace scene I originally thought was in World is Not Enough. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember any of the other plot details though. I think I would have if I had seen it before, because I actually really liked the film and think it&amp;rsquo;s the best of the Brosnan run. I mean, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even remember the betrayal towards the end, and that took me by surprise this time. The likely explanation seems to be that I had caught the later parts of the film on cable tv which is why I remember the ice palace thing, so I will consider this NOT a rewatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I read up on it after watching, apparently this film had a mixed reception, but I liked it. It has the campiness of the earlier films, and some good throwbacks and references, as it&amp;rsquo;s the 40th anniversary of the film. I mean, I agree the invisible car was a bit silly, but maybe about as much as everyday use of a jetpack (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/c6152994fa5ddf4b9c3302bcddfdd699/&#34;&gt;Thunderball&lt;/a&gt;) or going into space (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/cbb6135fa20b48a488982eccc7df76ce/&#34;&gt;Moonraker&lt;/a&gt;). There&amp;rsquo;s also an actual honest-to-goodness sword fight here that goes on quite a bit, first with fencing swords and later with actual swords. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just that I really enjoy swordfights lol. I also liked the car vs car battle later on in the movie; Bond has not had to face anyone with the same level of fancy car gadgets before, so it was fun. Also, the villain plot was to use something akin to C&amp;amp;C&amp;rsquo;s ion cannon! A space laser! I really would have remembered that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked the opening theme performed by Madonna, but didn&amp;rsquo;t actually recognize her in the cameo. This is the first film without Desmond Llewelyn as Q, as he had passed away the year before release. John Cleese is an adequate replacement, but this is also his final appearance in the role. This movie was also apparently Rosamund Pike&amp;rsquo;s first film. Hally Berry is ok as a Bond girl, nothing too exceptional. Her character was quite competent at first but then got captured (twice) in the second half. I believe this film is also the first time Bond has faced a North Korean villain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I think a fitting end to the Brosnan run and as a 40th anniversary celebration of the series. The campiness is fine, especially since the upcoming Daniel Craig era would be much more serious and gritty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;army-of-the-dead-2021&#34;&gt;Army of the Dead (2021)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watched this yesterday, mostly as background while I did other things, so not paying 100% attention I guess. I remembered reading that Tig Notaro (who plays the helicopter pilot) was never on set with the other actors (due to covid or something I guess) so every time she would be in a scene I&amp;rsquo;d mentally note how she&amp;rsquo;s not shown together with the others or was possible just edited into the shot. I really led with that lol, it&amp;rsquo;s what was foremost on my mind while watching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a reasonable action movie and zombie/heist flick, if not a bit predictable. I liked that safecracker guy, he really had a passion for his work, too bad he died. I actually thought more of their team would survive, but maybe I just haven&amp;rsquo;t seen enough zombie flicks. There&amp;rsquo;s an obvious setup at the end for a possible sequel, but Batista won&amp;rsquo;t be coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;valerian-and-the-city-of-a-thousand-planets-2017&#34;&gt;Valerian and the City of a Thousand Planets (2017)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ended up watching a second movie later in the day. I had been meaning to watch this for a while as it looked good. It&amp;rsquo;s an ok sci-fi movie to watch, but not a must-see as the plot is kind of predictable / cookie clutter, and there&amp;rsquo;s this one sequence in the middle which felt unnecessary and was just an excuse to get Cara Delevingne in a dress. Visuals are super pretty though, all the space stuff and the special effects and the City of a Thousand Planets all look great. The main guy Valerian fights waaaay too well, so that needs a bit of suspension of disbelief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only learned after watching that this movie was actually a French production directed by Luc Besson (of &lt;em&gt;Fifth Element&lt;/em&gt; fame), and was based on a French comic called &lt;em&gt;Valerian and Laureline&lt;/em&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s right, the comic actually had Laureline on equal billing with Valerian but noooo, the movie had to be titled for Valerian only. Actually, the comic seems more interesting from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Val%C3%A9rian_and_Laureline&#34;&gt;the wikipedia description&lt;/a&gt; as it seems to be more time-travel focused (Laureline is actually supposed to be from 11th-century France), but the movie doesn&amp;rsquo;t really give us much background on either of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this movie got mixed reviews and was a flop, so a follow-up in the same universe seems unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;superstore-season-5&#34;&gt;Superstore season 5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I binged the first four seasons of Superstore on Prime Video &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-09-13/&#34;&gt;back in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, and over the weekend I saw the fifth season was already up, so I had it as my background watching for most of the weekend and actually finished it already by Monday. Season 5 is pretty much more of the same flavor, though there are a bit more Filipino references (which I always enjoy) since there&amp;rsquo;s a stronger focus on the character Matteo, who in the last season was arrested by ICE because he was an illegal immigrant from the Philippines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-ones-who-walk-away-from-omelas-by-ursula-k-le-guin&#34;&gt;The Ones Who Walk Away From Omelas by Ursula K. Le Guin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone gave me a copy of this because I mentioned I&amp;rsquo;d never read any Le Guin before. It&amp;rsquo;s super short but quite thought-provoking, making you think about what costs any possible utopia could have. But I also think the ending is projecting a bit of optimism, in that no matter what darkness you discover, there&amp;rsquo;s always the option of just walking away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure whether to log this in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/lists/media/books/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;books read list&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; category, given that it&amp;rsquo;s not really a book and the length is actually barely a short story, but hey it&amp;rsquo;s my list, I&amp;rsquo;ll do what I want. It did make me want to seek out other Le Guin works, I&amp;rsquo;ll see what I can find.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reviews: The World is Not Enough, Barry season 1, Loki
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-the-world-is-not-enough-barry-season-1-loki/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 10:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-the-world-is-not-enough-barry-season-1-loki/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Warning: Spoilers for the just-ended season of Loki at the end of this. I have &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2021/07/1415238174377340930/&#34;&gt;a spoiler-free review&lt;/a&gt; of that if you&amp;rsquo;d like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world-is-not-enough-1999&#34;&gt;The World Is Not Enough (1999)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 19 and Brosnan&amp;rsquo;s third. Pretty sure I saw this in the theaters when it came out, but for the life of me could not recall any of the plot details at all. Turns out it was because the plot was a bit unnecessarily convoluted. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to tell straight away that Sophie Marceau is on the bad guy side, given her henchmen, so that was no surprise. Renard was a bit boring, revenge yada yada, bullet in my head, etc. The master plan here, originally misdirected as terrorism, turns out to just be financial all along. What assured me that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t insane and that I did see it in theaters was that as soon as I saw Denise Richards name in the opening credits I remember she played a nuclear physicist in this one. Probably the weakest of the Brosnan ones so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have a scene of Brosnan in some kind of ice building (?) in my random access memory, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t here so I think that&amp;rsquo;s a sign that I may have actually seen his next and last Bond film &lt;strong&gt;Die Another Day&lt;/strong&gt; before and just blocked out any memory of it for some reason. We&amp;rsquo;ll find out next week I suppose!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;barry-season-1&#34;&gt;Barry (season 1)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this late last week, and the season is only eight episodes but I only finished last night because each episode is a bit stressful to watch. Stressful in the sense that you pretty much expect that bad things are going to keep happening and that things are just going to get tougher for the protagonist. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit like Breaking Bad, where the protag just keeps getting into deeper and deeper trouble, but where Walter White started to revel in his notoriety, Barry just wants out, but he can&amp;rsquo;t get a break, and keeps on finding himself forced to do bad things. It&amp;rsquo;s very good, but also very dark. The season ends in a surprisingly satisfactory manner while still setting up possible follow-up storylines. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit tempted to just stop there and be happy with the show as it is and not continue to the second season as the show might actually get worse, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how long I hold it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;loki-season-1&#34;&gt;Loki (season 1)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season finale ended earlier today. As noted above, there is a spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;On 
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/2021/07/1415238174377340930/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;time datetime=&amp;quot;2021-07-14 09:14:09&amp;quot;&amp;gt;14 Jul 2021 9:14am&amp;lt;/time&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
I wrote:
&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;#Loki spoiler-free review:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;overall plot was fine, if not predictable, given what we knew about mcu phase 4 going in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;weak pacing and writing in most episodes; could have easily been a two hour movie instead of six one hour episodes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;good watch for mcu fans because of the larger phase 4 implications, but much weaker as a standalone series&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think overall, the plot of Loki delving into the truth behind the TVA and eventually causing the return of the multiverse was entirely predictable given the series&amp;rsquo; premise and what we knew of the larger MCU even before the series aired. The whole thing is even telegraphed completely in the first episode: removing the TVA means multiversal war; we are told the stakes from the very beginning and nothing really changes in that regard even up to the final episode and the reveal of who was actually behind the TVA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of the whole &amp;ldquo;reveal a new character and info dump his background in the last episode&amp;rdquo; treatment that character got. I get that the reveal was necessary for the larger MCU set up, but there&amp;rsquo;s no reason it could have been done or hinted from earlier episodes so that he didn&amp;rsquo;t have to monologue his back story for like 60% of this episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pacing of the entire six-episode runs just seemed so off to me; basically nothing interesting happening during the first three episodes (other than the reveal of a female Loki variant, which should surprise us why?), then some interesting stuff in episodes 4 and 5 and finally this disappointing finale was like 90% dialogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ramifications for the entire MCU at large are huge of course, and as a setup vehicle for the greater cinematic multiverse the series does the job well. But on the smaller scale, as a series standing by itself we got an anticlimactic finale, Renslayer and Mobius don&amp;rsquo;t get any kind of resolution or advancement to their character arcs, and our protagonist ends up right back where he was from the start - lost and alone. So unsatisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will of course still watch the eventual season 2, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to What If in August, but this finale just left a sour taste in my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/saturday-10-movies/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/saturday-10-movies/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;A couple of movies we watched during our Saturday gaming session yesterday:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;America the Motion Picture (2021)&lt;/strong&gt;. Alternate history retelling of American revoluion, complete and utter nonsense. Good fun and we had a few laughs, but I really hope no American takes it seriously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ice Road (2021)&lt;/strong&gt;. Random Liam Neeson action flick that we actual started last Saturday. Somehow they managed to make a two hour movie about driving a truck across the ice. I thought it would be better than it was because it had Laurence Fishburn, but I guess that&amp;rsquo;s not really a good basis. One of those films where I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have minded sitting through it on cable, if I was busy doing something else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Black Widow
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/black-widow/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 14:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/black-widow/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;We finally return to the MCU films, a full two years after the &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/&#34;&gt;last film&lt;/a&gt; was released! Breaking a decade-long tradition, I am unable to watch it in theaters this time (and probably won&amp;rsquo;t get to watch any of the others this year in theaters either), but at least we are moving forward now, onto the next phase!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler-free review first, then spoilery bits follow afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;incredibly good as an action movie, great fight sequences and set pieces and chases etc. Felt like I was watching something from Mission Impossible or James Bond&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fairly stand-alone, though some knowledge of what happened in &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2016/04/10154562419893912/&#34;&gt;Captain America: Civil War&lt;/a&gt; would give context to where Nat is at the start of the film&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pacing is good, alternating between character moments and action sequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;terrific performances by Florence Pugh and David Harbour, hope to see both again in the MCU at some point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a bit of humor sprinkled in there, mostly via Florence and David&amp;rsquo;s characters, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not the funniest MCU movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;happy to see Natasha getting her own solo movie and get some development outside of the ensemble casts, though I wish it could have happened sooner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is one post-credits scene, at the very end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama? Possibly! She occasionally enjoys action movies. The themes are very family-focused, despite all the violence. She would probably ask a lot of questions though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solid 4/5 for me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall a decent start to phase four. Looking forward to the other films this year, maybe by some miracle I&amp;rsquo;ll get to watch them in the theaters!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;##########################&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;### Spoilery bits follow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;### Spoilery bits follow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;### Spoilery bits follow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;###&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;### Spoilery bits follow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;##########################&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nitpicks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is Nat a super soldier now? I mean, she survives a car exploding and tumbling in midair, and also a fall from several stories high where she bumps her head a couple of times along the way. She basically just gets up and shrugs it all off, it&amp;rsquo;s helluva plot armor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taskmaster fight sequences were great, but the character was severely underused, and the actress really got off easy I think?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the scene at the end with Nat not wanting to leave with the others &lt;strong&gt;on a plane&lt;/strong&gt; even while Ross and his men are still a ways away seems ridiculous, and the cut to &amp;ldquo;2 weeks later&amp;rdquo; leaves much to be desired; some people on Reddit claim there was probably a scene where she made a deal with Ross but the scene was cut; regardless, it&amp;rsquo;s an annoying discontinuity in the theatrical cut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wish they could have managed one or two more fanservice cameos, and not just Valentina in the post-credits scene. Like, I would have wanted to have Chris Evans&amp;rsquo; Cap meet up with Nat in the &amp;ldquo;2 weeks after&amp;rdquo; scene so they go break out their friends together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than the above, I don&amp;rsquo;t seem to have any complaints about the main plot itself. I watched very few trailers and didn&amp;rsquo;t have any real idea about the other characters like Red Guardian or Yelena, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any expectations to fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole &amp;ldquo;family&amp;rdquo; theme reminded me of the recent Fast and Furious memes about family lol.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Tomorrow Never Dies
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/tomorrow-never-dies/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 10:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/tomorrow-never-dies/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Last night I watched Tomorrow Never Dies (1997). Bond film no. 18 and Brosnan&amp;rsquo;s second. Also the first one I actually saw in theaters when it came out so officially my first rewatch! That said, it was 24 years ago so while I remember the general overarching plot (Jonathan Pryce playing a multibillionaire media mogul inciting a war between China and the UK to profit off the news), I have forgotten many of the finer details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did remember Michelle Yeoh in her role as a Chinese agent who ends up working with Bond. (She looks so young here, especially compared to &lt;em&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/em&gt; where I last saw her! I guess Asian women do age somehow.) I forgot about Teri Hatcher being here though, apparently in the middle of her heyday on the &lt;em&gt;Lois and Clark&lt;/em&gt; TV series. She looked great too, but had little screen time, so maybe that&amp;rsquo;s why I forgot about her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also remembered the scene with the remote controlled car as I remember thinking that was pretty neat back when I first saw it. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve actually learned how driving a car works (not that I actually drive), it seems ridiculous that Bond could have such fine control using only a touchpad. It&amp;rsquo;s 2021 and the touchpad UX isn&amp;rsquo;t even that great for laptops, let alone a car!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time possible conflict with China came into play in the Bond series (though they have made appearances before as &amp;ldquo;Red China&amp;rdquo;), maybe a sign of China&amp;rsquo;s rising prominence at the time? This was also the same year that Hong Kong was ceded back to China by the British, so perhaps appropriate for Bond to be working with a Chinese agent this time, in the spirit of international friendship?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice of villain may have been a bit prescient, given our current woes with billionaires and their platforms endangering the world and/or democracy, although if this film were made today the company would be more tech/internet focused than mass media, as that age has passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the theme music here (performed by Sherly Crow) better than the one in Goldeneye, possibly because I kind of still remembered how it went (or the chorus part anyway).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trivia: There were no more unadapted Fleming stories remaining so this is an original film story, but the original title was meant to be &lt;em&gt;Tomorrow Never Lies&lt;/em&gt;, which would have made a lot more sense! But there was a typo when the potential title was sent over to MGM, and they liked the current version better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall Goldeneye seemed the stronger film, though this one appeals to me too because it&amp;rsquo;s my second watch; It&amp;rsquo;s aged rather well I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next film is the only other Brosnan film I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, &lt;em&gt;The World Is Not Enough&lt;/em&gt;, but I seem to remember even less about it than this film, can&amp;rsquo;t even call the plot to mind. I seem to remember some kind of&amp;hellip; ice building? I suppose I&amp;rsquo;ll find out when I get to it, probably next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s some commentary from the movie about software development.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/tomorrow-never-dies/tomorrow_never_dies1_hu414c89fc49b4fadf995b95c69f971058_2266509_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/tomorrow-never-dies/tomorrow_never_dies2_hub352fc13e2c19fe2461a015a3f4a31d7_1596320_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/tomorrow-never-dies/tomorrow_never_dies3_hub76b38891f327391e3f4b663fa8b8335_2404244_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Goldeneye (1995)
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/goldeneye-1995/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 01:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/goldeneye-1995/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The Bond film reviews were starting to get a bit long for Twitter/&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes&#34;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt;, so a full blog post it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldeneye (1995). Bond film no. 17 and first for Brosnan. The films are starting to look &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo;, but might just be because this is the first Bond film to come out after I graduated high school and that&amp;rsquo;s what I see as &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t see this in theaters when it first came out though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get that dry wit and humor back, and a bit more modern armaments. Not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen Bond use an automatic weapon before (usually it&amp;rsquo;s just the PPK). Sean Bean is here as 006, but I knew that already. I imagine him coming back was intended as a huge twist in theaters, but that&amp;rsquo;s kinda spoiled with him getting top billing in the opening credits sequence. Unremarkable opening theme by Tina Turner (not really a fan of that genre of music).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First appearance of Judi Dench as M, who gets a bit more characterization compared to her predecessors. The film tries to address some of the series&amp;rsquo; more problematic tropes, with M telling Bond he&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;sexist, misogynist dinosaur, a relic of the Cold War&amp;rdquo;. New Moneypenny (Samantha Bond) is less enamoured over Bond. His CIA ally even complains about the &amp;ldquo;stiff-assed Brits&amp;rdquo; and their &amp;ldquo;codes and passwords&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Famke Janssen gives a great and insane performance as the sadistic henchman Xenia Onatopp. Not sure why that Russian general was involved in 006&amp;rsquo;s plan, he was introduced as some kind of &amp;ldquo;iron man of Russia&amp;rdquo; so I initally thought he had some kind of political ambition. In the end it was all about money after all (and vengeance for 006).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Might proceed to the next film (Tomorrow Never Dies) later today!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/cb5279cfdbc686e55eef33bd58e8aaeb/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 04:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/cb5279cfdbc686e55eef33bd58e8aaeb/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Saturday gaming group decided to do a movie watch-along while we played and randomly settled on Under Siege (1992) for some reason. I&amp;rsquo;d never seen it before and several times I said &amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t this just Die Hard on a boat?&amp;rdquo; and apparently that was a universal consensus. Very 90s. &lt;!--sep--&gt;Unsurprisingly this is already Seagal&amp;rsquo;s best-rated movie and has a surprising number of familiar and even good actors, including Tommy Lee Jones, Gary Busey, and Colm Meaney (Star Trek&amp;rsquo;s O&amp;rsquo;Brien)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/4e93006d466cb2f6a53325cba8e27b63/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 10:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/4e93006d466cb2f6a53325cba8e27b63/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;License to Kill (1989): Bond film no 16, Dalton&amp;rsquo;s second and last outing is much darker and yet weaker than the first one. The first one where Bond goes rogue, driven by vengeance instead of duty. Unremarkable theme song. Villain is a drug smuggler; &lt;!--sep--&gt;I guess with the collapse of the USSR they couldn&amp;rsquo;t have another Russia-centered plot. More actors look familiar as we near the 90s. Notable are a young Benicio del Toro playing a henchman and Cary-Hiroyuki Tagawa (known for playing Shang Tsung. &lt;!--sep--&gt;Dalton&amp;rsquo;s performance is mixed, and for some reason he reminds me of Sir Patrick Stewart in some scenes. Too bad he couldn&amp;rsquo;t have had a better sendoff as Bond.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/69d2374b0f0232065102954a54736506/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 13:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/69d2374b0f0232065102954a54736506/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;The Living Daylights (1987): Bond film no. 15 and first of only two Dalton entries. More 80s music theme song, this time by A-ha. Much more serious in tone compared to Connery / Moore. John Rhys-Davies is here, years before Sliders or LOTR. &lt;!--sep--&gt;No sci-fi mad scientist stuff this time, straight-up spy stuff (more or less). Assassinations, defections, Russia&amp;rsquo;s internal politics, Afghan rebels, weapons, smuggling, drug deals, faked deaths, etc. Might be a tiny bit too long. Surprisingly, I liked this one!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/c7033ad094d89afab1a8e1abcb2c3015/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 05:49:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/c7033ad094d89afab1a8e1abcb2c3015/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Was stuck in a waiting room long enough to watch Downsizing (2017) on cable. Interesting sci-fi concept (miniaturizing humans to reduce consumption and avoid climate change) serving as background for a mediocre Matt Damon story.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/2789a7cda3fd16feca84b58fae45811b/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 03:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/2789a7cda3fd16feca84b58fae45811b/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;In the wee hours earlier for some reason I decided to watch Transformers: The Last Knight (2017) while playing online boardgames with friends. It was the only one of the Bayverse films I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen yet, and now that I have that seemed like a good decision. Too long, ridiculous plot, and once again the Decepticons barely distinguishable from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story needs a lot of suspension of disbelief. Lots of spectacle as you&amp;rsquo;d expect from Michael Bay. Surprised they managed to get Anthony Hopkins for this. John Turturro is still around, but serving only as plot exposition. They decided to introduce a new female lead that looked as close to Megan Fox as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie ends with Cybertron crashed into Earth, so you kind of have to suspend your belief in physics as well. Also, apparently Earth is Unicron! WTH lol.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/7d38789afe70956e56d61914ed7d195a/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 09:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/7d38789afe70956e56d61914ed7d195a/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Watched A View To A Kill (1985), Bond film no. 14. Moore is showing his age, luckily this is his last entry. Very 80s theme song by Duran Duran. Christopher Walken is here, as a Bond villain with a plan straight out of Superman (1978).&lt;!--sep--&gt; Tanya Roberts plays a young Bond girl just 14 years before playing a middle-aged mom on That 70s Show. Random young Dolph Lundgren cameo! Kind of a ridiculous street chase scene through San Francisco. Overall not the best of Moore&amp;rsquo;s run.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Rurouni Kenshin: The Final
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/rurouni-kenshin-the-final/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 15:26:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/rurouni-kenshin-the-final/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Earlier today I watched Rurouni Kenshin: The Final (2021), now out on Netflix (PH, not sure about elsewhere). I don&amp;rsquo;t normally do full blog posts for &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/reviews/movies&#34;&gt;movies&lt;/a&gt; anymore, but I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/archives/ancient/geocities/rk/&#34;&gt;a big Rurouni Kenshin fan&lt;/a&gt;, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much commentary on record for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/12/277092263371350017/&#34;&gt;first three live action films&lt;/a&gt;, so I figured I would write some words mostly about this new film, but maybe also a bit about the first three as well. The film is based on a manga story arc from more than 20 years ago, so I&amp;rsquo;m not really going to be avoiding spoilers here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this film covers the Revenge / Jinchuu arc, the third and final arc of the Rurouni Kenshin manga, most of which was never adapted to anime. This kind of works in the film&amp;rsquo;s favor, as I don&amp;rsquo;t have any anime to compare it to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/09/10153244419688912/&#34;&gt;a bit disappointed&lt;/a&gt; in the original trilogy&amp;rsquo;s handling of the fight scenes, since in my head I was comparing them to the epic anime battles, which is silly since an anime series and a live-action film are fundamentally different media, and some things simply wouldn&amp;rsquo;t translate well. Like, in the manga and anime, Kenshin&amp;rsquo;s learning the succession art of the Hiten Mitsurugi school and later using it to overcome Shishio was a big plot point, but was completely glossed over in the films. (And in the revenge arc, it&amp;rsquo;s also a plot point that Enishi is able to defeat that same succession art.) I guess I&amp;rsquo;m more forgiving these days of not strictly adhering to the source material (countless comic book movies will do that I guess), so I&amp;rsquo;m learning more to enjoy them as swashbuckling samurai adventures rather than only as anime adaptations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing about the Jinchuu arc is that it was quite long, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how they were going to fit it all in a single movie, even taking liberties with the plot points. I found out before that they had actually made two new films, with &lt;em&gt;The Final&lt;/em&gt; only being the first, so I kind of assumed this one would end with a cliffhanger, assuming they follow the general plot of the manga. Well, it turns out that while the first half of the film largely follows the plot of the manga arc and the first part of Enishi&amp;rsquo;s revenge plan, they scrapped the second half of the manga arc in favor of an all-out battle / assault for the film&amp;rsquo;s final act, pulling in appearances from characters that never appeared in the manga arc (some of them obviously appearing as fan service!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this divergence from the manga is fine and understandable given the limitations of the medium, it does significantly weaken the impact of Enishi&amp;rsquo;s revenge plan; early on in the film he states that death is insufficient for Kenshin to atone, but in the third arc he just ends up attempting to kill him or to get him to kill himself. The manga arc had a stronger punishment for Kenshin in the form of faking Kaoru&amp;rsquo;s death, sending Kenshin into a downward spiral that takes him a while to recover from, a character arc that speaks more strongly towards the series&amp;rsquo; general message of atonement and redemption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also disappointed because cutting out the second half of the revenge arc means we never get to see Yahiko in a one-on-one battle against one of Enishi&amp;rsquo;s minions. That was one of the most memorable parts of the manga arc for me because it represented a big growth in strength and capability for Yahiko to be able to hold his own using Kamiya Kasshin techniques. But again, I guess that&amp;rsquo;s not a thing that would have translated well to the big screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an English rock / R&amp;amp;B track that plays over the end credits, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4n5bpeh5NNg&#34;&gt;Renegades by One OK Rock&lt;/a&gt;. It felt slightly jarring and out of place since I watched the film with Japanese voices and English dubs, but I&amp;rsquo;m told even the first trilogy had English tracks over the end credits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing the movie, I wondered what the fifth film would actually be about, and it turns out it&amp;rsquo;s actually going to expand more on the Tomoe / Kenshin backstory that was only covered briefly in this film. While that would be a reasonable way to split up the revenge arc into two movies, it feels like it would have made more sense to release the prequel film first (and more appropriate since it&amp;rsquo;s titled &lt;em&gt;The Beginning&lt;/em&gt;), especially since this film already covers the major plot points that they would show in the prequel. Still as a big series fan (despite &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/11/932887665346670593/&#34;&gt;the author becoming controversial&lt;/a&gt; later on), I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the prequel&amp;rsquo;s eventual release on Netflix; we&amp;rsquo;ll see what surprises await us there.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/rurouni-kenshin-the-final/jinchu_hua12b81e072f157e1daee404141766e3e_1932695_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/1639118365d91bdbd1a41eb9b170a9a0/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 03:03:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/1639118365d91bdbd1a41eb9b170a9a0/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Yesterday I saw Octopussy (1983), Bond film no. 13. Another grounded entry with no fantastical elements, with the plot centered around geopolitical concerns. Some interesting action sequences, but overall, but I found most of the movie unremarkable.&lt;!--sep--&gt;  India shown as an exotic place (w/c I suppose it was to Westerners at that time) with elephants and firebreathers and whatnot all over. There was one scene where the bad guy appears to have broken a genuine Faberge egg but no one said anything lol.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/2641c1868d6ccb70715302ea340cae74/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 16:50:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/2641c1868d6ccb70715302ea340cae74/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;For Your Eyes Only (1981): Bond film no. 12. After the sci-fi fantasy of Moonraker, this one is more grounded and down-to-Earth, a callback to early Connery adventures. No megamalomaniacs to defeat, just foreign agents and mercs.&lt;!--sep--&gt; The opening sequence pays homage to the earlier pre-Moore films, acknowledging the death of Tracy Bond and killing off a villain that looks suspiciously like arch-nemesis Blofeld. The opening song is pretty good.&lt;!--sep--&gt; The rest of the film was ok, if a bit forgettable. I liked the rock climbing scene, but the ski chase and car chases felt like things we&amp;rsquo;ve seen before. Also, Moore is starting to show his age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melina Havelock (portrayed by Carole Bouquet) reminded me a lot of DCs Huntress - a crossbow-wielding woman out for revenge&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/cbb6135fa20b48a488982eccc7df76ce/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 08:44:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/cbb6135fa20b48a488982eccc7df76ce/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Watched Moonraker (1979). Spectacular opening sequence. Villain reminds me of Tyrion Lannister. California -&amp;gt; Venice -&amp;gt; Rio de Janeiro. Mandatory canal chase while in Venice, obviously. Lots of of product placement.&lt;!--sep--&gt; A bad guy tried to ambush 007 with a KENDO STICK. Have they heard of guns? Comically indestructible assassin Jaws appears again, and actually has a character arc this time.&lt;!--sep--&gt; First half of the movie was kind of meh, but the last third of the film with the space station and the laser battles and the ridiculous villain plan kind of won me over with how campy it all was.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/09b5a24d69042602b9ac909e277987a6/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 08:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/09b5a24d69042602b9ac909e277987a6/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Watched Mortal Kombat (2021). Some friends tried to tell me not to waste my time, but joke&amp;rsquo;s on them I enjoyed it anyway! In hindsight, the plot was pretty flimsy, but I enjoyed the fights. It&amp;rsquo;s basically what you&amp;rsquo;d expect lol.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/ea715fa4d23937c15e47022adf93e192/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 06:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/ea715fa4d23937c15e47022adf93e192/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 10: The Spy Who Loved Me (1977). The best Moore installment so far. Excellent opening sequence. Austria; Cairo, Egypt; Sardinia, Italy. 007 and Triple-X have great chemistry. &lt;!--sep--&gt;Jaws has to be the most unstoppable Bond villain / henchman. Stromberg&amp;rsquo;s Atlantis reminds me of the Legion of Doom&amp;rsquo;s base in the old Superfriends cartoon. Actually, I think his evil plan might be the best one so far as well.&lt;!--sep--&gt;I wonder if I can get through the rest of these before No Time to Die actually comes out lol.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1392042759863689217/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 09:03:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1392042759863689217/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Earlier today I watched The Mitchells vs the Machines on Netflix. It&amp;rsquo;s a well-done, fantastic, ridiculous, fun, clever, family-friendly adventure, I really enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1392042759863689217/1_1392042759863689217_E1GHG0qVUAIGxkS_hu44fef533758c80259e3fac5e4a495191_68732_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1392042759863689217/2_1392042759863689217_E1GHG0qVoAQWE2A_hu518ca80b6a8fbbee4ccdbedbccb55a18_91383_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1392042759863689217/3_1392042759863689217_E1GHG0rUcAANxG6_hub927d57c64da4d6dd50bbd28032ac5eb_67308_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/1392042759863689217/4_1392042759863689217_E1GHG0sVEAIOr83_hu0d4ce4375e903823e79049ca3774ebfb_65284_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/ba2999c2cc9d8803ad982d24e52035e6/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 09:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/ba2999c2cc9d8803ad982d24e52035e6/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 9: The Man With The Golden Gun (1974). Christopher Lee was a Bond villain! Beirut, Macau, Hong Kong, Bangkok. An Asian girl is introduced just for the pun in her name. Comic relief southern sheriff dude is back from the previous film. &lt;!--sep--&gt;Final fight scene with Nick Nack was ridiculous. As per usual, Bond gets captured and the bad guy explains everything. Still not used to Roger Moore in the role.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/3bf3bc036db88610a1c7b3474555eb69/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 07:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/3bf3bc036db88610a1c7b3474555eb69/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Last night I accidentally watched most of the latter part of Green Hornet (2011) starring Seth Rogen. I never new he portrayed this character! Movie was reasonable popcorn action-comedy.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/b178a1efcfc005930f062c7be447d7c1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 10:56:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/b178a1efcfc005930f062c7be447d7c1/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Today I decided to watch Rocky (1976) for some reason. The quintessential sports film, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen it before. Stallone looks only a bit younger than I remember him from the 90s. Apollo Creed is that dude from the Mandalorian! Surprised at the ending.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/ced0a77eea2857ad31bd014fac3ded9a/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 10:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/ced0a77eea2857ad31bd014fac3ded9a/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 8: Live and Let Die (1973).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moore feels a lot more &amp;ldquo;generic white guy&amp;rdquo; than Connery was. Maybe I just need to get used to him. Young Jane Seymour is here! There&amp;rsquo;s a bayou chase scene here that goes on just a bit too long and had superfluous cop characters. &lt;!--sep--&gt;All the voodoo stuff felt weirdly out of place. There&amp;rsquo;s a character named Tee Hee! Most ridiculous villain death so far.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1381509474259673090/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 07:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1381509474259673090/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Needed something light to watch in the background, so I watched Airplane! (1980). It&amp;rsquo;s the kind of movie where they just stuff in as many gags as possible, every throwaway line and even stuff happening in the background is a gag.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/8fd56682f77942eb0badef9444d465a4/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 12:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/8fd56682f77942eb0badef9444d465a4/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 7: Diamonds are Forever (1971). Connery&amp;rsquo;s hair starting to go a bit gray in his last appearance. More Blofeld than I&amp;rsquo;d expected (harhar). Space laser! Plenty O&amp;rsquo;Toole seemed pointless, there just to die. A lot of cheesy lines from the assassin henchment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--sep--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These movies would be a lot shorter if they just shot Bond whenever they caught him. The action scenes in all these old Bond films always feel so jarring compared to modern ones. Limited by the technology of their time I guess.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1a1ab3ad610478ba3b672b0a89c26333/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 06:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1a1ab3ad610478ba3b672b0a89c26333/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 6: On Her Majesty&amp;rsquo;s Secret Service (1969). Only Lazenby appearance. He was fine, I suppose. Tracy probably best Bond girl so far. I liked the ski scenes more than Thunderball&amp;rsquo;s underwater scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--sep--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loose continuity. Was confused by Blofeld not recognizing Bond after they already met in the previous movie. Apparently, the novel order was reversed. Also, did Bond just leave him stuck in a tree assuming he was dead after hunting him relentlessly?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/fb71576d1974213ea471b5cda8a20948/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 08:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/fb71576d1974213ea471b5cda8a20948/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 5: You Only Live Twice (1967). Such Japan. Much wow. Cringe at trying to pass Bond off as Japanese. Introduction of secret volcano lair trope. Ninjas with guns! First screen appearance of the head of SPECTRE, inspiration for Dr Evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--sep--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That endgame scene of ninjas invading the secret volcano lair reminded me of the Simpsons episode &lt;em&gt;You Only Move Twice&lt;/em&gt;. Bond&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;wife&amp;rdquo; never named despite being only Bond girl to survive the movie.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Zack Snyder&#39;s Justice League (aka The Snyder Cut) review
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/zack-snyders-justice-league-aka-the-snyder-cut-review/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 06:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/zack-snyders-justice-league-aka-the-snyder-cut-review/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;See also: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/11/931540341919965184/&#34;&gt;Justice League spoiler-free review (2017)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is basically a movie that&amp;rsquo;s more than 3 years old, we&amp;rsquo;re not holding back on spoilers here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plot basically follows the same beats as the theatrical cut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;except this time we have a lot more team setup time (one of my criticisms from the previous version), giving the characters stronger backgrounds, especially Cyborg and Flash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ray Fisher was right to complain; in this version he&amp;rsquo;s one of the important characters of the ensemble while he was basically a minor guest character in the theatrical cut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more DC characters make appearances in this version, among them Ryan Choi, DeSaad, Granny Goodness, Martian Manhunter, the Joker and of course Darkseid himself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I accept this version as a better version of the original theatrical release and is my new DCEU headcanon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it never would have worked in theaters anyway, given the four hour runtime. Maybe if they split it into two movies&amp;hellip; (and I actually did take two sittings to watch this one!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anyway, this version does a much better job of setting up any succeeding movies, including the upcoming Flash movie (although I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if the changes cause any continuity issues with the 2019 Aquaman movie&amp;hellip; not that the DCEU cares too much about continuity anyway&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/c6152994fa5ddf4b9c3302bcddfdd699/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 07:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/c6152994fa5ddf4b9c3302bcddfdd699/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 4: Thunderball (1965). This is the first one I didn&amp;rsquo;t like very much. Too many boring/confusing underwater parts. There&amp;rsquo;s a jetpack! Wasn&amp;rsquo;t there an atomic bomb aboard that boat when it exploded? And did they just leave the guy who helped Domino escape floating alone in the ocean?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/273eae12d668c24135d4db358511c9d4/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 09:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/273eae12d668c24135d4db358511c9d4/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 3: Goldfinger (1964). Lot of the classic Bond tropes introduced. Bad guy&amp;rsquo;s plan was actually pretty good, even had the escape contingency. Disappointed he did not have an actual gold finger. Great fight between Bond and Oddjob.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/096b7c67797c165b01283d0c7cd6c016/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 09:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/096b7c67797c165b01283d0c7cd6c016/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;James Bond movie no. 2: To Russia With Love (1963). This one actually had more bits that felt like actual espionage. And Bond didn&amp;rsquo;t need to get captured this time!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/2b14f8356f57460da0a4790b27b44b8a/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 07:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/2b14f8356f57460da0a4790b27b44b8a/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Haven&amp;rsquo;t seen any of the pre-Brosnan Bond films, so I started today with Dr No (1962). Pretty good, but if this were a modern film, I&amp;rsquo;d have expected some kind of plot twist with Honey Rider, like maybe she would have turned out to be the actual Dr No&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2021-02-28
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/weeknotes-2021-02-28/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 02:01:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/weeknotes-2021-02-28/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Today is the last day of February. Tomorrow, we march on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world&#34;&gt;The world:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biden ordered his &lt;a href=&#34;https://thehill.com/policy/defense/540631-Biden-orders-US-strikes-on-iranian-backed-militia-facilities-in-syria&#34;&gt;first military strike last week&lt;/a&gt;. America is back, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This past week, embrassingly our local police and anti-drug agency got into a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rappler.com/nation/pnp-pdea-shootout-bungled-buy-bust-operation-ever-gotesco-quezon-city&#34;&gt;shootout&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;against each other&lt;/em&gt; near the Ever Gotesco mall in Quezon City. Both sides claim they were doing a buy-bust, which is impossible. As usual, there is little transparency about what actually happened, and many promises of &amp;ldquo;impartial&amp;rdquo; probes and investigations. People speculate that at least one of the parties involved really was dealing drugs, and they got into a shootout because they were afraid of being EJK&amp;rsquo;ed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-of-interest&#34;&gt;Links of interest:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have any of these today, sadly. This is why I don&amp;rsquo;t have a newsletter, I&amp;rsquo;m unable to promise regular content lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-stuff&#34;&gt;My stuff:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This week was busy with family and medical errands, so not much else was accomplished.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook/&#34;&gt;Still sketching&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WandaVision&lt;/strong&gt; penultimate ep, people still liked it, but it was a bit meh for me. Still looking forward to next week&amp;rsquo;s finale, as there are still so many things to wrap up!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started watching &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek: Enterprise&lt;/strong&gt;, the last of the non-animated Trek shows I have yet to watch. (I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen the TOS animated series). It&amp;rsquo;s Scott Bakula! Their uniforms here remind me of something like modern astronaut wear, so I assume they wanted something closer to &amp;ldquo;modern day&amp;rdquo; Earth to bridge to the Star Trek future. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting because at this point the relationship between the humans and Vulcans isn&amp;rsquo;t well established, there is no federation, no prime directive, etc, so we get to see the beginnings of those things later on I guess?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also watched a couple of movies this week. First was &lt;strong&gt;Space Sweepers&lt;/strong&gt;, a Korean space sci-fi adventure on Netflix. Entertaining enough, though the plot is easily predictable and the villain seemed like a moron. Great visuals and special effects, miles apart from anything local cinema has to offer. One-inch barrier of subtitles, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second movie was &lt;strong&gt;Once Upon A Time In Hollywood&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a very laid-back, relaxed movie, unfolding mostly as a series of slice-of-life vignettes of what life was like Hollywood in 1969, with no real plot urgency to speak of. The climax sort of just happens through no real actions by the main characters. Fairly long, took me four sittings to get through. Was surprised to find out later that it was based on a true story of a massacre that took place at that time, with Margot Robbie playing a real-life actress who was the victim in the actual massacre. The story unfolds a bit differently, probably due to the presence of fictional protagonists Rick Dalton and Cliff Booth (portrayed by Leonardo DiCaprio and Brad Pitt). Bruce Lee also makes an appearance!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last week was also the premiere of &lt;strong&gt;Superman and Lois&lt;/strong&gt; on CW. I still like these positive portrayals of Superman better than something like Snyder&amp;rsquo;s Man of Steel, although I&amp;rsquo;m a bit meh on the premiere overall. Everything about the teens gives me Smallville vibes. They had a really big missed opportunity to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/1364758520885772288/&#34;&gt;match a scene from the opening sequence with a classic comic cover&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played a bit of Civ6 now that the Barbarian Clans mode has dropped. Restarted a few times with Kublai Khan before I got a decent start. Not super impressed with the Barbarian Clans mode so far, seems like the main effect is that we get more city-states going into the endgame. Will probably still try it out for a few games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second Fire Emblem Three Houses run still in progress, finally got to the Edelgard decision point, and went as I planned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have been trying to figure out why I&amp;rsquo;m having &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/StreetFighter/comments/lquag0/sf5_is_it_expected_to_be_so_hard_to_find_a_match/&#34;&gt;so much trouble finding matches in Street Fighter V&lt;/a&gt;. Still no luck though. I want to indulge myself by getting the season 5 pass, but it&amp;rsquo;s not worth it if I can&amp;rsquo;t actually find matches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always annoying whenever this happens, but next month&amp;rsquo;s PS+ games include FF7 Remake, which I&amp;rsquo;ve already played and finished. Good for everyone else though! New content was also announced for the PS5 version of the game, which is also annoying since it&amp;rsquo;s probably goinna be a while before I bother with a PS5 (maybe waiting for a smaller version!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edit: One of my loyal readers pointed out I failed to mention that we played a few games of 4-player Free For All in Starcraft 2 last Saturday. I won one and some undeserving people won the other two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books:&lt;/strong&gt; Finished reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/ghost-of-my-father/&#34;&gt;Scott Berkun&amp;rsquo;s Ghost of my Father&lt;/a&gt;. Then started reading pioneering cyberpunk classic &lt;em&gt;Neurmancer&lt;/em&gt; by William Gibson. Kind of a challenging read, I&amp;rsquo;m inching through it slowly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz&lt;/strong&gt;: We managed to win the AboutQuiz league, just barely. Yay us!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed to sneak in a few minor upgrades to this here site, mostly CSS and rendering improvements on the frontend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-coming-week&#34;&gt;This coming week:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WandaVision finale!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Flash season premiere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New One Piece later tonight!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;supposedly vaccination in this country will finally kick off!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/1363747640391860225/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 07:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/1363747640391860225/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;For some reason, I watched Space Sweepers, a Korean sci-fi movie on Netflix. Fun ride, fairly entertaining, pretty good setpieces and special effects. (They are so far ahead of the local film industry.) Plot a bit predictable. Villain made no sense.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1352137686614564867/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 06:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1352137686614564867/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;2021 movie no. 3: World War Z (2013). Pretty typical action movie I think, entertaining enough. Should have watched at the start of the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350361902149324800/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 08:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350361902149324800/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;2021 #movies no 2: The Godfather part 2 (1974). This is two movies rolled into one. Still pretty good, but I think I liked the singular focus of the first one more.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350042544567029763/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 11:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350042544567029763/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;2021 movies no. 1: The Godfather (1972). Everyone is so young! Such a well-told gangster tale. Looking forward to the sequel&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1344191049963425795/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 23:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1344191049963425795/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Finally watched #WonderWoman1984. Maybe don&amp;rsquo;t think too much about what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the movie. My headcanon is that the only reason it takes place in 1984 is because it&amp;rsquo;s pre-crisis&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/girl-next-door/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/girl-next-door/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I watched Girl Next Door (2004) on Prime Video. Mostly for Elisha Cuthbert lol.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-09-27
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-27/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-27/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;October is imminent! There are two distractions I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to in the coming month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one is &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober/&#34;&gt;Inktober&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing since 2016. Basically it&amp;rsquo;s just to do 30 ink drawings in October, one per day. There are some &lt;a href=&#34;https://inktober.com/rules&#34;&gt;official prompts&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;ll probably follow. I haven&amp;rsquo;t really done any serious &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook&#34;&gt;sketching&lt;/a&gt; in a while, maybe this will help me get back into the groove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one is &lt;a href=&#34;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/&#34;&gt;Hacktoberfest&lt;/a&gt;! Basically it&amp;rsquo;s an event where you have to submitted some number of GitHub PRs in October, and there&amp;rsquo;s some swag for people who finished. I last &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/hacktoberfest/&#34;&gt;participated in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, skipped last year because I was a bit busy. I have a bit more free time this year, so hopefully I can get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these are welcome distractions, as the world continues to suck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on the Django-based rewrite for my personal site (this one!). It&amp;rsquo;s one of those projects where I find myself being productive not because of deadlines or anything like that, but because I genuinely enjoy working on it. When I find myself thinking of of new things that need to be done, or a new feature, or a way to solve an interesting problem, I am cursed (blessed?) with restlessness until I get it done. There are a number of challenges with the way I chose to approach this problem, most probably the subject of a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned this before, but I went ahead and paid for a year of the Micro plan on Migadu.com. The email in/out limits aren&amp;rsquo;t that high, but the price is decent, and I don&amp;rsquo;t really use my personal email that much anyway (I&amp;rsquo;m no spammer!). I&amp;rsquo;ll re-evaluate next year whether I want to migrate. (Sets a calendar event.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I went ahead and watched the second season of Umbrella Academy. It&amp;rsquo;s more or less structured like the first season: each member has their own problems; five discovers an upcoming apocalypse, so he tries to bring everyone together; also, there&amp;rsquo;s people who want to kill them. The ending of this is more satisfying than S1 though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enola Holmes on Netflix. It was ok, but it&amp;rsquo;s more of a young adult story, maybe a bit above the Nancy Drew/Hardy Boys level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming this past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;managed to get in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgznr/&#34;&gt;couple more Zendikar Rising drafts&lt;/a&gt;. Fun format, but I continue to have a terrible record, with only one draft actually going well. I did get a refund for that last one, so let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can&amp;rsquo;t do better this coming week!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;additional drop on the Civ6 New Frontier pass came out, giving us Gaul and Byzantium. A friend and I tried it in a multiplayer game. I played Byz and he went with Gaul; we only played for a couple of hours, but both new civs seem quite powerful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my SC2 group managed to finish the Wings of Liberty coop campaign! Pretty fun, and it was fun to relive the story too, as I had already forgotten a lot of it. We started the Heart of the Swarm version the next day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday gaming group have been playing Blood Rage over the past few months, and it even came out with a new DLC/expansion a couple of weeks ago. The game client is a bit buggy, but we tolerate it because it&amp;rsquo;s a fun/deep game anyway. We&amp;rsquo;re looking at maybe trying out a different game next week though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trivia was meh this week, the topics weren&amp;rsquo;t really to our liking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I purchased last month&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humblebundle.com/subscription&#34;&gt;Humble Choice&lt;/a&gt; (or rather, let it lapse into purchase). It&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable, there&amp;rsquo;s some games there I can try like Forager and Evoland, and given my recent streak of Mario playing, I was wanting a platformer for the PC, so Yooka Layle isn&amp;rsquo;t a bad idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Late-breaking Sunday news: I have kind of impulse bought a Nintendo Switch. Well, I was agonizing over it for a while, but stores were selling it just a bit overpriced. Today I found that there was a slight price drop (around $40 worth) of the Labo bundle at one of my local stores, so I impulsively went ahead and ordered it. Maybe should have waited a day or so? regardless, it&amp;rsquo;s on the way, along with Zelda: Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening and Super Mario 3D All Stars. No interest in the Labo personally, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll try to sell it off?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried using Messenger Rooms for a family conf call today, in lieu of Zoom which limits us to 40-minute calls. Might have been bad luck or poor internet, but the experience was substantially worse. Disconnections, lag, poor video quality, etc. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if they want to switch back to Zoom next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems weird that we are so close to the end of 2020 now. Still no idea what Christmas is going to look like. I&amp;rsquo;m sure many other people are also looking forward to closing out 2020 and going to 2021, even though that holds no logical promise of things being better than they are now. But we can always dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-08-30
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-30/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-30/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This last week was weird. I feel like I didn&amp;rsquo;t really get much done in terms of productivity, yet I don&amp;rsquo;t feel I was unproductive. A very relaxed and chill week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again a tiny bit of work done this past week, some fixes, including to side projects. I also spent some time preparing for some events next weekend. Although I wasn&amp;rsquo;t productive this week, I did outline a bit of a roadmap of new features for one of my side projects, hopefully I can get into that in the coming weeks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still in a pandemic! But I did have my first dine-in meal at a restaurant last Monday. It was because I went to get blood drawn for routine medical reasons, and I had needed to skip breakfast for the test (spoiler: my blood sugar levels were very, very normal). So after getting the blood drawn I was super hungry and decided to have breakfast at the nearby Pancake House. I was the only customer since it was super early (and you know, pandemic), although a second guy came in after I had given my order. I almost subconsciously picked up the glass of water to sip from it as soon as it was served, luckily I remembered I was wearing a face mask and a face shield. I decided to hold off on removing the gear until the actual pancakes were served, to minimize the exposure time. The next day I also decided to have a snack at a Starbucks after running some errands, mainly because I had a free coffee from Globe Rewards. It was afternoon so there were a few other customers there. The cashier said it was ok to dine in, but for a maximum of one hour only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a longish post I was writing, but it felt too raw to publish and might break it up into smaller posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We actually managed to win an online quiz night this week! It&amp;rsquo;s been a while, good job trivia team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels great to no longer be following the covid19 stats regularly, even though they are still fairly terrible. UP experts are projecting that we get the reproduction rate to below 1 in like a month though, so that&amp;rsquo;s some good news, though we may still be a ways away from getting this under control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching and playing the past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still playing a lot of SC2 Coop, trying to unlock the new prestiges. Levelling the commanders again can be a pain, but at least they managed to provide new goals/objectives for the players, breathing back a bunch of life into this game mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still drafting Amonkhet Remastered, although the last few drafts haven&amp;rsquo;t gone well. Need to save up gems, so I&amp;rsquo;ll do one last one draft once I get enough gold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huh, I guess I kind of paused Uncharted 4 for most of the week, not sure why. I should get back to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started re-playing Super Mario 3D Land (on the 3DS) lately, mostly to stave off my desire to get a Nintendo Switch (prices are still inflated here due to supply issues!). I had forgotten a lot about this game, so even when I finished the first 8 worlds and rescued Princess Peach, I was pleasantly surprised to find there were another 8 &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; worlds to play!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watched the video game history documentary &lt;strong&gt;High Score&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. Pretty good, although there&amp;rsquo;s some Dragon Quest erasure going on in the RPG episode!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watched &lt;strong&gt;Bill and Ted Face the Music&lt;/strong&gt;, this was a most excellent sequel. I found the start a bit clunky (I always find it awkward watching characters be awkward), but the rest of it was a fun and sweet adventure that echoed elements of both of the first two movies. A lot of the time travel stuff didn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense if you sat down and thought about it, but I was smiling through a lot of it. Little Billie and Theda are great!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also watched &lt;strong&gt;Superman: Man of Tomorrow&lt;/strong&gt;, the first entry in the new DC animated universe (following the reboot at the end of Justice League Dark: Apokolips). Yet another Superman origin story here. Not too happy with this one. Not fond of the animated style, and the writing and plot seemed weird at many points. I felt like there could have been a better way to resolve the whole situation with the big bad that felt more &amp;ldquo;Superman&amp;rdquo;-like, and the movie doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to earn the monicker &amp;ldquo;Man of Tomorrow&amp;rdquo; for the hero.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for one reason or another, I also ended up watching a few standup specials on Amazon Prime. A couple from Craig Ferguson, and one from Jimmy Yang.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cobra Kai is now on Netflix! Yet another thing to add to the ever-increasing backlog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tech stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have about three months left on my Webfaction hosting, which I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/rip-webfaction/&#34;&gt;been planning to migrate away from&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m currently leaning towards getting a cheap $5/mo VPS from Linode, although I&amp;rsquo;m still willing to accept any recommendations. Switching to a VPS means more effort (since it won&amp;rsquo;t be a managed service anymore), but that should provide some learning opportunities. It&amp;rsquo;s just as well anyway, my apps have been pushing the memory limits on the current hosting, and even the cheapest Linode VPS provides more RAM.  I&amp;rsquo;ll probably start looking into the migration in September.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wrote before about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/gmail-migration/&#34;&gt;migrating away from GMail&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Migadu.com&amp;rsquo;s free tier for about half a year now. This past week, they wrote that they are sunsetting the free tier. Totally understandable, given the economy. They are also introducing a new Micro tier at $20 a year, with slightly better limits than the old free tier, so I may migrate to that near the end of September (when the free tier runs out). In theory, I could just try to run a mail server on whatever VPS I set up (see above bullet), but that&amp;rsquo;s a big hassle. This cost + the $5/mo for the VPS is still less than what I was paying for at Webfaction, so I don&amp;rsquo;t mind paying for this for a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was notified by a local bank that their old web platform is being sunsetted and I needed to migrate to the new system, so I did that. But whenever I tried the migration steps, the process never completed, it just kept telling me it was processing. I finally had to message someone I knew on the dev team lol. Hopefully it can getr resolved next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1299644349643255808/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 09:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1299644349643255808/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Bill and Ted Face the Music is a most excellent sequel&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1299644349643255808/1_1299644349643255808_EglDnbZU8AMZ8z__hu07d1f098faf18c8ec2bc955f3d888baa_71943_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-07-19
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-19/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-19/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My country:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are days when I have to consciously temper my rage at the shenanigans of this government. I can&amp;rsquo;t write about them today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/covid19-07-19/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s pandemic notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had a busy work week again; at the same time I also picked up an older charity project where the client asked for UI updates. Had issues with running the old code, and it was small enough, so I decided to rewrite it in a new tech stack. Might write about it at some point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am like 98% through the FF7R hard mode run. I&amp;rsquo;m totally making these percentages up, but I do have only one trophy left, and it&amp;rsquo;s this annoying minigame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started trying out some of the new leaders/civs in the Civ6 New Frontier pack. Another drop should be coming this week, so looking forward to that!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG JumpStart is out this week! I tried it a couple of times on Arena. Some combinations are much better than others; the sad things is if you picked a miserable pair you have to stick with it longer before you can get your requisite two wins. Here&amp;rsquo;s an (ongoing) &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/1283901490206109698/&#34;&gt;thread of my JumpStart results&lt;/a&gt; will probably update it through the month it&amp;rsquo;s available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t win any online quiz this week, boo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After watching Atomic Blonde last week, I watched the Old Guard for back-to-back Charlize Theron action flicks. Pretty fun, although some plot points might make you go what?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of stuff coming out in July that I might watch: new season of Umbrella Academy, and there&amp;rsquo;s a Transformers anime coming out on NF, and well, there&amp;rsquo;s also a long backlog of things to watch&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing to note, too busy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/sections/coronavirus-live-updates/2020/07/09/889394605/please-scream-inside-your-heart-japanese-amusement-park-tells-thrill-seekers&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Please scream inside your heart&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; should be the motto for 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-07-12: Media Shutdown Edition
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-12/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-12/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My country:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday afternoon the House of Representatives voted to deny the franchise application of the nation&amp;rsquo;s biggest broadcaster ABS-CBN. This despite all agencies of the executive testifying that the company had no violations. Justifications cited were mostly personal reasons. The Palace claims they remained neutral on this issue, but no one really believes that. Probably not even then. What now, Philippines?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/covid19-07-12/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s pandemic notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had a busy week work-wise. Learning a lot about Vue and Laravel though, so that&amp;rsquo;s fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am like 95% through the FF7R hard mode run. Only a 5% difference from last week, progress is slow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I bought a few games off the Steam Sale: Civ 6&amp;rsquo;s New Frontiers Pass (not actually on sale), Disco Elysium, and Garou Mark of the Wolves. You can watch me struggling in Garou &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2yQ6B9IlwHU&amp;amp;t=70s&#34;&gt;on Youtube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We only played one online quiz this week, didn&amp;rsquo;t do too well D:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watched Atomic Blonde yesterday. I thought it was like a John Wick style action flick. That&amp;rsquo;s true, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a Cold-War era spy thriller with lots of double-crosses and whatnot. Fairly engaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing to note.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.dev/one-line-layouts/&#34;&gt;Ten modern layouts in one line of CSS&lt;/a&gt;. I could have used this two weeks ago!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really enjoyed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swiss-miss.com/2020/07/alike-an-animated-short-film.html&#34;&gt;Alike, an Animated Short Film&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an allegory for modern life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>