<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>movies on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/movies/</link>
      <description>Recent content in movies on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 07:26:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/movies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/3bf3bc036db88610a1c7b3474555eb69/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 07:26:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/3bf3bc036db88610a1c7b3474555eb69/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Last night I accidentally watched most of the latter part of Green Hornet (2011) starring Seth Rogen. I never new he portrayed this character! Movie was reasonable popcorn action-comedy.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/b178a1efcfc005930f062c7be447d7c1/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 10:56:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/b178a1efcfc005930f062c7be447d7c1/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Today I decided to watch Rocky (1976) for some reason. The quintessential sports film, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen it before. Stallone looks only a bit younger than I remember him from the 90s. Apollo Creed is that dude from the Mandalorian! Surprised at the ending.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/ced0a77eea2857ad31bd014fac3ded9a/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 10:05:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/ced0a77eea2857ad31bd014fac3ded9a/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 8: Live and Let Die (1973).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moore feels a lot more &amp;ldquo;generic white guy&amp;rdquo; than Connery was. Maybe I just need to get used to him. Young Jane Seymour is here! There&amp;rsquo;s a bayou chase scene here that goes on just a bit too long and had superfluous cop characters. &lt;!--sep--&gt;All the voodoo stuff felt weirdly out of place. There&amp;rsquo;s a character named Tee Hee! Most ridiculous villain death so far.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1381509474259673090/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 07:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1381509474259673090/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Needed something light to watch in the background, so I watched Airplane! (1980). It&amp;rsquo;s the kind of movie where they just stuff in as many gags as possible, every throwaway line and even stuff happening in the background is a gag.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/8fd56682f77942eb0badef9444d465a4/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 12:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/8fd56682f77942eb0badef9444d465a4/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 7: Diamonds are Forever (1971). Connery&amp;rsquo;s hair starting to go a bit gray in his last appearance. More Blofeld than I&amp;rsquo;d expected (harhar). Space laser! Plenty O&amp;rsquo;Toole seemed pointless, there just to die. A lot of cheesy lines from the assassin henchment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--sep--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These movies would be a lot shorter if they just shot Bond whenever they caught him. The action scenes in all these old Bond films always feel so jarring compared to modern ones. Limited by the technology of their time I guess.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1a1ab3ad610478ba3b672b0a89c26333/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 06:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1a1ab3ad610478ba3b672b0a89c26333/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 6: On Her Majesty&amp;rsquo;s Secret Service (1969). Only Lazenby appearance. He was fine, I suppose. Tracy probably best Bond girl so far. I liked the ski scenes more than Thunderball&amp;rsquo;s underwater scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--sep--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loose continuity. Was confused by Blofeld not recognizing Bond after they already met in the previous movie. Apparently, the novel order was reversed. Also, did Bond just leave him stuck in a tree assuming he was dead after hunting him relentlessly?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/fb71576d1974213ea471b5cda8a20948/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 08:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/fb71576d1974213ea471b5cda8a20948/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 5: You Only Live Twice (1967). Such Japan. Much wow. Cringe at trying to pass Bond off as Japanese. Introduction of secret volcano lair trope. Ninjas with guns! First screen appearance of the head of SPECTRE, inspiration for Dr Evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--sep--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That endgame scene of ninjas invading the secret volcano lair reminded me of the Simpsons episode &lt;em&gt;You Only Move Twice&lt;/em&gt;. Bond&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;wife&amp;rdquo; never named despite being only Bond girl to survive the movie.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Zack Snyder&#39;s Justice League (aka The Snyder Cut) review
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/zack-snyders-justice-league-aka-the-snyder-cut-review/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 06:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/zack-snyders-justice-league-aka-the-snyder-cut-review/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;See also: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/11/931540341919965184/&#34;&gt;Justice League spoiler-free review (2017)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is basically a movie that&amp;rsquo;s more than 3 years old, we&amp;rsquo;re not holding back on spoilers here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plot basically follows the same beats as the theatrical cut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;except this time we have a lot more team setup time (one of my criticisms from the previous version), giving the characters stronger backgrounds, especially Cyborg and Flash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ray Fisher was right to complain; in this version he&amp;rsquo;s one of the important characters of the ensemble while he was basically a minor guest character in the theatrical cut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more DC characters make appearances in this version, among them Ryan Choi, DeSaad, Granny Goodness, Martian Manhunter, the Joker and of course Darkseid himself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I accept this version as a better version of the original theatrical release and is my new DCEU headcanon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it never would have worked in theaters anyway, given the four hour runtime. Maybe if they split it into two movies&amp;hellip; (and I actually did take two sittings to watch this one!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anyway, this version does a much better job of setting up any succeeding movies, including the upcoming Flash movie (although I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if the changes cause any continuity issues with the 2019 Aquaman movie&amp;hellip; not that the DCEU cares too much about continuity anyway&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/c6152994fa5ddf4b9c3302bcddfdd699/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 07:13:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/c6152994fa5ddf4b9c3302bcddfdd699/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 4: Thunderball (1965). This is the first one I didn&amp;rsquo;t like very much. Too many boring/confusing underwater parts. There&amp;rsquo;s a jetpack! Wasn&amp;rsquo;t there an atomic bomb aboard that boat when it exploded? And did they just leave the guy who helped Domino escape floating alone in the ocean?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/273eae12d668c24135d4db358511c9d4/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 09:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/273eae12d668c24135d4db358511c9d4/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Bond movie no. 3: Goldfinger (1964). Lot of the classic Bond tropes introduced. Bad guy&amp;rsquo;s plan was actually pretty good, even had the escape contingency. Disappointed he did not have an actual gold finger. Great fight between Bond and Oddjob.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/096b7c67797c165b01283d0c7cd6c016/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 09:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/096b7c67797c165b01283d0c7cd6c016/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;James Bond movie no. 2: To Russia With Love (1963). This one actually had more bits that felt like actual espionage. And Bond didn&amp;rsquo;t need to get captured this time!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/2b14f8356f57460da0a4790b27b44b8a/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 07:40:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/2b14f8356f57460da0a4790b27b44b8a/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Haven&amp;rsquo;t seen any of the pre-Brosnan Bond films, so I started today with Dr No (1962). Pretty good, but if this were a modern film, I&amp;rsquo;d have expected some kind of plot twist with Honey Rider, like maybe she would have turned out to be the actual Dr No&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/1363747640391860225/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 07:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/1363747640391860225/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;For some reason, I watched Space Sweepers, a Korean sci-fi movie on Netflix. Fun ride, fairly entertaining, pretty good setpieces and special effects. (They are so far ahead of the local film industry.) Plot a bit predictable. Villain made no sense.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1352137686614564867/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 06:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1352137686614564867/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;2021 movie no. 3: World War Z (2013). Pretty typical action movie I think, entertaining enough. Should have watched at the start of the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350361902149324800/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 08:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350361902149324800/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;2021 #movies no 2: The Godfather part 2 (1974). This is two movies rolled into one. Still pretty good, but I think I liked the singular focus of the first one more.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350042544567029763/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 11:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350042544567029763/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;2021 movies no. 1: The Godfather (1972). Everyone is so young! Such a well-told gangster tale. Looking forward to the sequel&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1344191049963425795/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 23:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1344191049963425795/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Finally watched #WonderWoman1984. Maybe don&amp;rsquo;t think too much about what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the movie. My headcanon is that the only reason it takes place in 1984 is because it&amp;rsquo;s pre-crisis&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-09-27
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-27/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-27/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;October is imminent! There are two distractions I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to in the coming month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one is &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober/&#34;&gt;Inktober&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing since 2016. Basically it&amp;rsquo;s just to do 30 ink drawings in October, one per day. There are some &lt;a href=&#34;https://inktober.com/rules&#34;&gt;official prompts&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;ll probably follow. I haven&amp;rsquo;t really done any serious &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook&#34;&gt;sketching&lt;/a&gt; in a while, maybe this will help me get back into the groove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one is &lt;a href=&#34;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/&#34;&gt;Hacktoberfest&lt;/a&gt;! Basically it&amp;rsquo;s an event where you have to submitted some number of GitHub PRs in October, and there&amp;rsquo;s some swag for people who finished. I last &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/hacktoberfest/&#34;&gt;participated in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, skipped last year because I was a bit busy. I have a bit more free time this year, so hopefully I can get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these are welcome distractions, as the world continues to suck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on the Django-based rewrite for my personal site (this one!). It&amp;rsquo;s one of those projects where I find myself being productive not because of deadlines or anything like that, but because I genuinely enjoy working on it. When I find myself thinking of of new things that need to be done, or a new feature, or a way to solve an interesting problem, I am cursed (blessed?) with restlessness until I get it done. There are a number of challenges with the way I chose to approach this problem, most probably the subject of a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned this before, but I went ahead and paid for a year of the Micro plan on Migadu.com. The email in/out limits aren&amp;rsquo;t that high, but the price is decent, and I don&amp;rsquo;t really use my personal email that much anyway (I&amp;rsquo;m no spammer!). I&amp;rsquo;ll re-evaluate next year whether I want to migrate. (Sets a calendar event.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I went ahead and watched the second season of Umbrella Academy. It&amp;rsquo;s more or less structured like the first season: each member has their own problems; five discovers an upcoming apocalypse, so he tries to bring everyone together; also, there&amp;rsquo;s people who want to kill them. The ending of this is more satisfying than S1 though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enola Holmes on Netflix. It was ok, but it&amp;rsquo;s more of a young adult story, maybe a bit above the Nancy Drew/Hardy Boys level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming this past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;managed to get in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgznr/&#34;&gt;couple more Zendikar Rising drafts&lt;/a&gt;. Fun format, but I continue to have a terrible record, with only one draft actually going well. I did get a refund for that last one, so let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can&amp;rsquo;t do better this coming week!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;additional drop on the Civ6 New Frontier pass came out, giving us Gaul and Byzantium. A friend and I tried it in a multiplayer game. I played Byz and he went with Gaul; we only played for a couple of hours, but both new civs seem quite powerful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my SC2 group managed to finish the Wings of Liberty coop campaign! Pretty fun, and it was fun to relive the story too, as I had already forgotten a lot of it. We started the Heart of the Swarm version the next day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday gaming group have been playing Blood Rage over the past few months, and it even came out with a new DLC/expansion a couple of weeks ago. The game client is a bit buggy, but we tolerate it because it&amp;rsquo;s a fun/deep game anyway. We&amp;rsquo;re looking at maybe trying out a different game next week though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trivia was meh this week, the topics weren&amp;rsquo;t really to our liking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I purchased last month&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humblebundle.com/subscription&#34;&gt;Humble Choice&lt;/a&gt; (or rather, let it lapse into purchase). It&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable, there&amp;rsquo;s some games there I can try like Forager and Evoland, and given my recent streak of Mario playing, I was wanting a platformer for the PC, so Yooka Layle isn&amp;rsquo;t a bad idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Late-breaking Sunday news: I have kind of impulse bought a Nintendo Switch. Well, I was agonizing over it for a while, but stores were selling it just a bit overpriced. Today I found that there was a slight price drop (around $40 worth) of the Labo bundle at one of my local stores, so I impulsively went ahead and ordered it. Maybe should have waited a day or so? regardless, it&amp;rsquo;s on the way, along with Zelda: Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening and Super Mario 3D All Stars. No interest in the Labo personally, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll try to sell it off?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried using Messenger Rooms for a family conf call today, in lieu of Zoom which limits us to 40-minute calls. Might have been bad luck or poor internet, but the experience was substantially worse. Disconnections, lag, poor video quality, etc. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if they want to switch back to Zoom next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems weird that we are so close to the end of 2020 now. Still no idea what Christmas is going to look like. I&amp;rsquo;m sure many other people are also looking forward to closing out 2020 and going to 2021, even though that holds no logical promise of things being better than they are now. But we can always dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-08-30
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-30/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-30/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This last week was weird. I feel like I didn&amp;rsquo;t really get much done in terms of productivity, yet I don&amp;rsquo;t feel I was unproductive. A very relaxed and chill week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again a tiny bit of work done this past week, some fixes, including to side projects. I also spent some time preparing for some events next weekend. Although I wasn&amp;rsquo;t productive this week, I did outline a bit of a roadmap of new features for one of my side projects, hopefully I can get into that in the coming weeks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still in a pandemic! But I did have my first dine-in meal at a restaurant last Monday. It was because I went to get blood drawn for routine medical reasons, and I had needed to skip breakfast for the test (spoiler: my blood sugar levels were very, very normal). So after getting the blood drawn I was super hungry and decided to have breakfast at the nearby Pancake House. I was the only customer since it was super early (and you know, pandemic), although a second guy came in after I had given my order. I almost subconsciously picked up the glass of water to sip from it as soon as it was served, luckily I remembered I was wearing a face mask and a face shield. I decided to hold off on removing the gear until the actual pancakes were served, to minimize the exposure time. The next day I also decided to have a snack at a Starbucks after running some errands, mainly because I had a free coffee from Globe Rewards. It was afternoon so there were a few other customers there. The cashier said it was ok to dine in, but for a maximum of one hour only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a longish post I was writing, but it felt too raw to publish and might break it up into smaller posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We actually managed to win an online quiz night this week! It&amp;rsquo;s been a while, good job trivia team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels great to no longer be following the covid19 stats regularly, even though they are still fairly terrible. UP experts are projecting that we get the reproduction rate to below 1 in like a month though, so that&amp;rsquo;s some good news, though we may still be a ways away from getting this under control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching and playing the past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still playing a lot of SC2 Coop, trying to unlock the new prestiges. Levelling the commanders again can be a pain, but at least they managed to provide new goals/objectives for the players, breathing back a bunch of life into this game mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still drafting Amonkhet Remastered, although the last few drafts haven&amp;rsquo;t gone well. Need to save up gems, so I&amp;rsquo;ll do one last one draft once I get enough gold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huh, I guess I kind of paused Uncharted 4 for most of the week, not sure why. I should get back to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started re-playing Super Mario 3D Land (on the 3DS) lately, mostly to stave off my desire to get a Nintendo Switch (prices are still inflated here due to supply issues!). I had forgotten a lot about this game, so even when I finished the first 8 worlds and rescued Princess Peach, I was pleasantly surprised to find there were another 8 &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; worlds to play!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watched the video game history documentary &lt;strong&gt;High Score&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. Pretty good, although there&amp;rsquo;s some Dragon Quest erasure going on in the RPG episode!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watched &lt;strong&gt;Bill and Ted Face the Music&lt;/strong&gt;, this was a most excellent sequel. I found the start a bit clunky (I always find it awkward watching characters be awkward), but the rest of it was a fun and sweet adventure that echoed elements of both of the first two movies. A lot of the time travel stuff didn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense if you sat down and thought about it, but I was smiling through a lot of it. Little Billie and Theda are great!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also watched &lt;strong&gt;Superman: Man of Tomorrow&lt;/strong&gt;, the first entry in the new DC animated universe (following the reboot at the end of Justice League Dark: Apokolips). Yet another Superman origin story here. Not too happy with this one. Not fond of the animated style, and the writing and plot seemed weird at many points. I felt like there could have been a better way to resolve the whole situation with the big bad that felt more &amp;ldquo;Superman&amp;rdquo;-like, and the movie doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to earn the monicker &amp;ldquo;Man of Tomorrow&amp;rdquo; for the hero.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for one reason or another, I also ended up watching a few standup specials on Amazon Prime. A couple from Craig Ferguson, and one from Jimmy Yang.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cobra Kai is now on Netflix! Yet another thing to add to the ever-increasing backlog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tech stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have about three months left on my Webfaction hosting, which I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/rip-webfaction/&#34;&gt;been planning to migrate away from&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m currently leaning towards getting a cheap $5/mo VPS from Linode, although I&amp;rsquo;m still willing to accept any recommendations. Switching to a VPS means more effort (since it won&amp;rsquo;t be a managed service anymore), but that should provide some learning opportunities. It&amp;rsquo;s just as well anyway, my apps have been pushing the memory limits on the current hosting, and even the cheapest Linode VPS provides more RAM.  I&amp;rsquo;ll probably start looking into the migration in September.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wrote before about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/gmail-migration/&#34;&gt;migrating away from GMail&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Migadu.com&amp;rsquo;s free tier for about half a year now. This past week, they wrote that they are sunsetting the free tier. Totally understandable, given the economy. They are also introducing a new Micro tier at $20 a year, with slightly better limits than the old free tier, so I may migrate to that near the end of September (when the free tier runs out). In theory, I could just try to run a mail server on whatever VPS I set up (see above bullet), but that&amp;rsquo;s a big hassle. This cost + the $5/mo for the VPS is still less than what I was paying for at Webfaction, so I don&amp;rsquo;t mind paying for this for a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was notified by a local bank that their old web platform is being sunsetted and I needed to migrate to the new system, so I did that. But whenever I tried the migration steps, the process never completed, it just kept telling me it was processing. I finally had to message someone I knew on the dev team lol. Hopefully it can getr resolved next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1299644349643255808/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 09:45:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1299644349643255808/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Bill and Ted Face the Music is a most excellent sequel&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1299644349643255808/1_1299644349643255808_EglDnbZU8AMZ8z__hu07d1f098faf18c8ec2bc955f3d888baa_71943_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-07-19
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-19/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-19/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My country:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are days when I have to consciously temper my rage at the shenanigans of this government. I can&amp;rsquo;t write about them today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/covid19-07-19/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s pandemic notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had a busy work week again; at the same time I also picked up an older charity project where the client asked for UI updates. Had issues with running the old code, and it was small enough, so I decided to rewrite it in a new tech stack. Might write about it at some point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am like 98% through the FF7R hard mode run. I&amp;rsquo;m totally making these percentages up, but I do have only one trophy left, and it&amp;rsquo;s this annoying minigame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started trying out some of the new leaders/civs in the Civ6 New Frontier pack. Another drop should be coming this week, so looking forward to that!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG JumpStart is out this week! I tried it a couple of times on Arena. Some combinations are much better than others; the sad things is if you picked a miserable pair you have to stick with it longer before you can get your requisite two wins. Here&amp;rsquo;s an (ongoing) &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/1283901490206109698/&#34;&gt;thread of my JumpStart results&lt;/a&gt; will probably update it through the month it&amp;rsquo;s available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t win any online quiz this week, boo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After watching Atomic Blonde last week, I watched the Old Guard for back-to-back Charlize Theron action flicks. Pretty fun, although some plot points might make you go what?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of stuff coming out in July that I might watch: new season of Umbrella Academy, and there&amp;rsquo;s a Transformers anime coming out on NF, and well, there&amp;rsquo;s also a long backlog of things to watch&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing to note, too busy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/sections/coronavirus-live-updates/2020/07/09/889394605/please-scream-inside-your-heart-japanese-amusement-park-tells-thrill-seekers&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Please scream inside your heart&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; should be the motto for 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-07-12: Media Shutdown Edition
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-12/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-12/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My country:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday afternoon the House of Representatives voted to deny the franchise application of the nation&amp;rsquo;s biggest broadcaster ABS-CBN. This despite all agencies of the executive testifying that the company had no violations. Justifications cited were mostly personal reasons. The Palace claims they remained neutral on this issue, but no one really believes that. Probably not even then. What now, Philippines?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/covid19-07-12/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s pandemic notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had a busy week work-wise. Learning a lot about Vue and Laravel though, so that&amp;rsquo;s fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am like 95% through the FF7R hard mode run. Only a 5% difference from last week, progress is slow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I bought a few games off the Steam Sale: Civ 6&amp;rsquo;s New Frontiers Pass (not actually on sale), Disco Elysium, and Garou Mark of the Wolves. You can watch me struggling in Garou &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2yQ6B9IlwHU&amp;amp;t=70s&#34;&gt;on Youtube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We only played one online quiz this week, didn&amp;rsquo;t do too well D:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watched Atomic Blonde yesterday. I thought it was like a John Wick style action flick. That&amp;rsquo;s true, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a Cold-War era spy thriller with lots of double-crosses and whatnot. Fairly engaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing to note.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.dev/one-line-layouts/&#34;&gt;Ten modern layouts in one line of CSS&lt;/a&gt;. I could have used this two weeks ago!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really enjoyed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swiss-miss.com/2020/07/alike-an-animated-short-film.html&#34;&gt;Alike, an Animated Short Film&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an allegory for modern life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-07-05: Anti-Error Edition
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-05/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-05/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My country:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday afternoon the president sighed the controversial &amp;ldquo;Anti-terror law&amp;rdquo; that vastly expands police powers, allows people to be arrested without warrants on mere suspicion of terrorism etc. Interesting timing, right after China applies a new anti-terror low to Hong Kong (and rightly gets castigated for it by countries all over the world) and also right after the PNP (who &lt;em&gt;promise&lt;/em&gt; not to abuse their newfound powers) are under criticism for killing some soldiers in a &lt;em&gt;misencounter&lt;/em&gt; and tampering with the crime scene to cover it up. Many are afraid of the chilling impact on freedom of speech, but I like to think that I will be as complain-y as I used to be. I am privileged to be able to do that, so might as well keep going.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Congressmen &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/abscbn-bias-press-freedom/&#34;&gt;tightening the screws on ABS-CBN&lt;/a&gt; during the franchise hearings reminds me that: given how complicated the various laws and statutes are, anyone with an agenda who wants to harass you can always find some obscure laws or regulations that you allegedly violated. That is not to say we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t follow such regulations, but given when one randomly keeps digging up new issues, it becomes obvious that there is a vendetta at work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I often ruminate about what I can do to help the state of my country today. Or maybe even the state of the world? I used to think being a good citizen and making good voting choices was enough, but it&amp;rsquo;s not. The systems are rigged to perpetuate inequality, exploitation, and bad people in power. I read somewhere recently that one should imagine the path towards the future he wishes to claim and take the steps to make it happen, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think my imagination is up to the task at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/covid19-07-05/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s pandemic notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fair bit of consulting work for this coming week, might be busy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have already &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/quitting-facebook/&#34;&gt;deactivated Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. If I would be honest, I still find myself sometimes instinctively thinking about checking the Facebook feed. Hopefully, it&amp;rsquo;s an instinct that gets weaned away with time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am like 90% through the FF7R hard mode run, but I&amp;rsquo;m currently stuck at a certain point trying to beat the so-called &amp;ldquo;hardest fight in the game&amp;rdquo;. Hopefully I can finish it this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divinity OS2 inched along slightly as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday gaming group picked up a new board game on Steam, it&amp;rsquo;s Blood Rage, about vikings trying to earn glory for Ragnarok. A bit more violent than Scythe, lots more fighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG: I did six twitch streams/yt episodes of M21 drafting, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kXZO7Ukg5Xk&amp;amp;list=PLmU0vkKslGXiz0shcCJgV1YTP5emzWgr4&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Able to play a couple more online quiz nights this week, but still didn&amp;rsquo;t do well lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some new movies on Netflix lately. Decided to watch Mission Impossible Fallout. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I ever watched Rogue Nation though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need to plan out the next set of updates for the trivia thing, but I might be too busy in the coming weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I changed the fonts on this blog. Again. Someday I&amp;rsquo;ll probably try Comic Sans just for the heck of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Again: I should probably write more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This list of &lt;a href=&#34;https://whimsical.club/&#34;&gt;websites that spark joy&lt;/a&gt; is great, have some new sites to browse!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A walk back through the history of web trends and standards: &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavellaptev.github.io/web-dark-ages/&#34;&gt;dark ages of the web&lt;/a&gt;. As someone &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.technology/@schwartz/104450459330476402&#34;&gt;commented on Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; though: &amp;ldquo;dark ages for development, golden age for content.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-06-28: Internet Outage Edition
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/weeknotes-06-28/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/weeknotes-06-28/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/covid19-06-28/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s pandemic notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily the most annoying thing this week: our broadband modem conked out Wednesday night. Customer support isn&amp;rsquo;t super responsive for local telcos: I called their support line the next day (support line is not even available 24/7!), got put on hold for 45 minutes TWICE before they agreed to send a repair crew over the next day (Friday). Friday morning I got a text that the technician visit was actually scheduled for SATURDAY morning. They arrive Saturday AFTERNOON, due to traffic apparently. And unluckily, they are out of spare modems for the replacement. They promise to come back first thing in the morning SUNDAY. They come back Sunday LUNCHTIME. And I finally have internet back. An annoying experience, and I&amp;rsquo;m also worried that my mobile plan might be charged for the two one-hour calls I had to do to their support line (hopefully I can clear that up), and I&amp;rsquo;m told I can also call them up to ask for a rebate for their days we had no service, but eh, I&amp;rsquo;d have to sit through another long on-hold period!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One would think that being offline for half a week would lead to some kind of gigantic productivity boost, but no such luck. I still had my mobile internet for my doomscrolling after all. I did manage to read/write/watch a few more things than usual I guess?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finished Final Fantasy VII Remake (before the internet outage)! So I spent a lot of the outage (including my time on hold with tech support) playing through hard mode, already about half-way through. Still not sure I&amp;rsquo;m going to do achievement completion, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see. Hard mode is actually an enjoyable challenge, nothing too insane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divinity OS2 inched along slightly as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;won my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/1274581114628108289/&#34;&gt;first Trivia Royale&lt;/a&gt;, I can quit now lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the internet outage coincided with the start of this week&amp;rsquo;s Steam Summer Sale. There&amp;rsquo;s some games/DLC I&amp;rsquo;m considering buying, but realistically in terms of backlog I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t lol. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if willpower holds out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the new MTG core set also came out on Magic Arena during the outage. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get back into regular streaming for M21 limited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still tried to join the Zoom and voice chats for the online quizzes with only my tethered mobile internet, but that was kind of a miserable experience. Still, I was able to contribute a bit, though we didn&amp;rsquo;t actually do too well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching lately:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finished watching season 2 of Harley Quinn. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve written about the show before. The whole Harley/Poison Ivy dynamic isn&amp;rsquo;t really for me, but I like the show&amp;rsquo;s take on Gotham and the wider DC universe and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun characters like King Shark and Clayface. Also, Riddler was recognizably voiced by Dean Pelton from Community, and that was fun lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also did a rewatch of Spider-Man Far From Home on Netflix, before the internet problems and all. Still a pretty good movie, and watching it made me eager to get back to the MCU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also watched the Sonic the Hedgehog movie while things were offline. The best thing about this is Sonic being recognizably voiced by Ben Schwartz, who apparently &lt;a href=&#34;https://thesuperheroesnetwork.tumblr.com/post/622121477003739136/supernova-swirls-gothammite-he-really&#34;&gt;voices everyone blue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As soon as my internet came back, I started watching Ghost Fighter/Yu Yu Hakusho, which came out on Netflix (as you guessed it, during the outage)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also tried reading a book. It was a Discworld book. &amp;ldquo;Tried&amp;rdquo; being the operative word. I&amp;rsquo;ll write about it if I manage to get to the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uh, proceeding apace I guess?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Again: I should probably write more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://slatestarcodex.com/2020/06/22/nyt-is-threatening-my-safety-by-revealing-my-real-name-so-i-am-deleting-the-blog/&#34;&gt;NYT threatened to doxx Scott Alexander of Slate Star Codex&lt;/a&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t really follow SSC too strictly, but that seemed like a bad thing. I also read up some more on &lt;a href=&#34;https://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Scott_Alexander&#34;&gt;Scott Alexander / SSC&lt;/a&gt; because of this, and it looks like he had a lot of problematic views, so I don&amp;rsquo;t really think I want to support him lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great essay from Ankit Shah about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ankit.fyi/being-alone&#34;&gt;Being Alone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gomakethings.com/always-bet-on-html/&#34;&gt;Always Bet on HTML&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-05-31
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-05-31/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-05-31/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It seems difficult to write about stuff today, when the world seems like it is on fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For historical context, for the past few days the USA, presumably a first-world nation, has been in the grip of massive protests and riots and police brutality following the murder of a black man by four police officers was captured on video and went viral. Basically, many states are responding to protests against police brutality with&amp;hellip; police brutality. Bold move Cotton. I&amp;rsquo;m not an American, but this resonates with me a lot because to see this kind of thing happening in a country that purports to champion human rights, how much worse can it be in a country like ours or a dictatorship like China where they don&amp;rsquo;t even give lip service to the concept? (Spoiler: we already know police brutality and EJKs are a thing in my country.) I give my support to those protesting, and hope they achieve the reforms their country needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One would question why I (and maybe the world) focuses so much on what happens in the USA, given that violence and brutality happen in a lot of other countries too. The main difference is that the USA is presumably a superpower and provide some semblance of leadership to democratic countries. The USA needs to shape up, they&amp;rsquo;re making democracy look bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s weird watching a hegemony fall apart in real time to weight of its own excesses. It&amp;rsquo;s like they&amp;rsquo;re trying to hard to make &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Past_Tense_(Star_Trek:_Deep_Space_Nine)&#34;&gt;Deep Space Nine&amp;rsquo;s 2020s prediction&lt;/a&gt; come true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: I should also highlight in this space that this past week China rammed its National Security Law through Hong Kong, bypassing the HK legislature and essentially ending HK&amp;rsquo;s autonomy through one country, two systems. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to Hong Kong multiples times and know and have worked with people there, so this one hits a lot closer to home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/covid19-05-31/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s quarantine notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather slightly cooling off, with more thunderstorms happening in the afternoons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep schedule completely out of whack again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; Moved along my Divity OS2 game. A friend got me some Steam keys for the older Jackbox Party Packs, so I have more access to games to play. I tried streaming via Twitch, but seems difficult due to streaming delay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz:&lt;/strong&gt; We didn&amp;rsquo;t really do too well in the quiz nights this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have uploaded some gaming videos to our trivia team&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCptXvNbp4ETVttb_k-1oOww&#34;&gt;Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;, check it out!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching lately:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watched Zombieland: Double Tap. My friends and I really enjoyed the first movie when it came out ten years ago. This one was fun, but pretty much more of the same&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caught up with Legends of Tomorrow in anticipation of their season finale this coming week. I have to say I had low expectations but once again Legends may be the best of the Arrowverse shows this season. I really enjoyed the penultimate episode where they had parodies of other shows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site updates: Nothing to announce!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do have some social media related thing to announce, maybe tomorrow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent Links of Interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/&#34;&gt;Rediscovering the small web.&lt;/a&gt; Great post here, and I like the term &amp;ldquo;small web&amp;rdquo; to describe what I&amp;rsquo;ve been missing on the internet lately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slim pickings this week apparently. Been distracted by other things.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-05-17
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-2020-05-17/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-2020-05-17/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My Stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/covid19-05-17/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s quarantine notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt;: A bit of Laravel work, and a bit of server management and deployment. Nothing too ridiculous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching&lt;/strong&gt;: Haven&amp;rsquo;t watched much this week. There was the really great &lt;strong&gt;Justice League Dark: Apokolips War&lt;/strong&gt; which came out last week. Apparently it&amp;rsquo;s the last one for the DC AMU, or this particular timeline at least.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz&lt;/strong&gt;: We are now up to 3 locally produced online quiz nights per week, which seems like a lot because we only used to attend 2-3 live events per month. I managed to tie for first place in the Geekfight one this week, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t win either of the other two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I played a lot of Divinity Original Sin 2 this week, probably much more than a healthy amount. Really started to get into it, but I think I&amp;rsquo;m not even halfway into the game?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday group also played some Scythe from the Asmodee bundle. It&amp;rsquo;s a challenging worker placement-like boardgame with some combat, but the UI for the PC version is pretty terrible. I did not win during our first session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech&lt;/strong&gt;: Got tired of my terrible audio jack which has been emitting static to my speakers and earphones. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t clean it, instead I went ahead and ordered some fancy HyperX gaming headphones from Lazada, which has already started selling nonessentials again. Might take a couple of weeks to get here though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site Updates&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this site used to have a live backup available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.github.io/&#34;&gt;roytang.github.io&lt;/a&gt;, but starting this week the builds have been failing. I assume it&amp;rsquo;s because my repository has gotten too large. Most of it is images and videos. I may need to consider an alternative approach where only the text stuff is in the repos, to keep the repo size down, otherwise we are really gonna have scaling issues down the road. Need to think about this for a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent Links of Interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I always like it when a &lt;a href=&#34;http://tttthis.com/blog/if-i-could-bring-one-thing-back-to-the-internet-it-would-be-blogs&#34;&gt;post about blogs&lt;/a&gt; makes it to the front page of Hacker News. It means the &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23205588&#34;&gt;ensuing discussion&lt;/a&gt; has a lot of people talking about why blogs aren&amp;rsquo;t actually dead and many sharing their own blogs which I get to take a look at. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll write a post detailing how I think about this particular post. If I feel like it. After reading through all the blogs from these links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://macwright.org/2020/05/10/spa-fatigue.html&#34;&gt;This post by Tom MacWright&lt;/a&gt; encapsulates much of how I feel by the modern push toward React and other frameworks in web development. Old-school web dev forever!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2020/may/09/the-real-lord-of-the-flies-what-happened-when-six-boys-were-shipwrecked-for-15-months&#34;&gt;Fascinating story&lt;/a&gt; about a real-life Lord of the Flies situation that turned about much better than the very pessimistic book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for this week!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-05-10
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-2020-05-10/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-2020-05-10/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My Stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early this morning I took a walk outside for the first time since the lockdown started. Previously I had only gone out for groceries and meds. Only for less than 30 mins, and only in our subdivision, walking up and down the street. It&amp;rsquo;s good to be walking again, although this short and limited route is quite boring and full of neighbor&amp;rsquo;s dogs barking at me, so I&amp;rsquo;m not too fond of it, but it&amp;rsquo;s better to get the habit started again since I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling the fatness piling on due to the quarantine and the lack of exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt;: A few consultation meetings here and there, but starting next week I may need to do some actual coding work for other people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching&lt;/strong&gt;: Watched a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;few movies this week&lt;/a&gt;, The Siege (caught it on TV during my lunch break), Skull Island (because Brie Larson), Ready Player One (it&amp;rsquo;s Cyclops!), and also watched Ang Huling El Bimbo the Musical (Not really a movie, but ok). I also ended up watching the 2 episodes of the Battlestar Galactica miniseries; apparently I had not watched this before watching the 2004 series. I also watched the hilarious Middleditch and Schwartz improv comedy specials on Netflix, fun times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;: Played a bunch of Divinity Original Sin 2 this week, though I guess I&amp;rsquo;m still not that far along in the story? I also purchased the Humble Asmodee bundle, for more boardgames-converted-to-PC-games that my weekend playgroup can do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site Updates&lt;/strong&gt;: Been putting up some content elsewhere on this site. You can find it easily if you look around, but nothing to announce publicly yet. Need to think about how to present properly, good permalinks, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent Links of Interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of starting a separate regular type of post where I just post links to things I found on the internet. Kind of like the links page, except with more commentary? I know people like &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralistic.net/&#34;&gt;Doctorow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kottke.org/&#34;&gt;Kottke&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://waxy.org/&#34;&gt;Waxy&lt;/a&gt; have been doing this kind of thing for a while, thinking of something along the same lines I guess? Something I can maybe turn into some kind of newsletter later on? We&amp;rsquo;ll see if it pans out. For now, let&amp;rsquo;s keep it in the weeknotes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Somewhat related to the first bullet: Great post from &lt;a href=&#34;https://secondbreakfast.co&#34;&gt;secondbreakfast.co&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://secondbreakfast.co/its-too-late-to-collect-sand&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s too late to collect sand&lt;/a&gt;. Basically saying if there&amp;rsquo;s something you regret not being able to start earlier on, it would be a trap to think that you can&amp;rsquo;t just start it today. I say somewhat related to the first bullet because as I was reviewing some older blog entries during the past few weeks I was wondering if I could have made it as a &amp;ldquo;successful blogger&amp;rdquo; like the people mentioned above if I had only been more consistent with my content. Such regrets are ridiculous, as the post implies, because I could always just ramp up my linkblogging now if I wanted. Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ve also scanned a few of the other posts on secondbreakfast.co, and many of them are fairly good reads, so this one might end up being added to the regular follows and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/blogroll/&#34;&gt;blogroll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AirBNB is laying off one-fourth of its staff and refocusing its priorities. This is not exactly unexpected given the current situation and the bleak outlook for the travel industry in the near term, but what I found exceptional was &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.airbnb.com/a-message-from-co-founder-and-ceo-brian-chesky/&#34;&gt;CEO Brian Chesky&amp;rsquo;s message to their employees&lt;/a&gt;. Announcing layoffs is obviously a feel-bad, but this note was handled extremely well, walking through the rationales and the painful decision and giving their staff clear expectations on what will happen moving forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One tech company that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been treating their employees too well however, has been Amazon. Last week, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/202x/2020/04/29/Leaving-Amazon&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; from Amazon VP, Senior Engineer, and XML spec-writer Tim Bray made the rounds as he publicly declared he was resigning from his position (costing him around a million dollars) because of how the company has fired whistleblowers who were complaining about Covid-19 safety concerns at their warehouses. Good for Bray, and boo for Amazon. One may also find the links he posted in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/202x/2020/05/06/Answers&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Responses&amp;rdquo; post&lt;/a&gt; of interest as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/23/magazine/closing-prune-restaurant-covid.html&#34;&gt;Great article in the NY times&lt;/a&gt; (Annoying paywall warning!) about what it&amp;rsquo;s like owning and having to shutdown a restaurant in these times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kk.org/thetechnium/68-bits-of-unsolicited-advice/&#34;&gt;68 bits of unsolicited advise&lt;/a&gt; from Kevin Kelly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying Tom Scott&amp;rsquo;s Youtube channel recently (unsurprisingly, he&amp;rsquo;s a very popular Youtuber). I recently found out his background is actually in linguistics! Anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l4bmZ1gRqCc&#34;&gt;a video from him about confusing differences in numbers across languages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Singapore, they have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/8/21251788/spot-boston-dynamics-robot-singapore-park-social-distancing&#34;&gt;a robot dog making sure people are social distancing in public&lt;/a&gt;. This is why &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yahoo.com/entertainment/no-black-mirror-episodes-creator-162238548.html&#34;&gt;the creator of Black Mirror isn&amp;rsquo;t even bothering right now&lt;/a&gt;, reality is just too much already.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hoping we have a good week incoming, despite the current situation!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;I created a Netflix (34 countries) search site with lists, filters and sort.&#39; on /r/movies at https://reddit.com/r/movies/comments/g760e3/i_created_a_netflix_34_countries_search_site_with/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/fog070h/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/fog070h/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;I created a Netflix (34 countries) search site with lists, filters and sort.&amp;#39; on /r/movies at https://reddit.com/r/movies/comments/g760e3/i_created_a_netflix_34_countries_search_site_with/:

            &lt;p&gt;Does Netflix have an open API? I remember looking around for it before but couldnt find any details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also any chance you could also serve rss feeds for new netflix shows/movies added per country?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-04-19
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/weeknotes-2020-04-19/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/weeknotes-2020-04-19/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This week went by quickly, for some reason. And despite the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s summer, the rains have started coming in early, although only sporadically. inb4 &amp;ldquo;the world is healing&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;COVID19 Diary&lt;/a&gt; is still being updated every few days. Actually went out 3 times this week, once for groceries, and twice for meds for the parental units (one would assume they would coordinate so I can just buy everything in one go, but nooooo.) Maybe that contributed to why the week went by so fast for me. Going out these days saps your energy a lot more than it used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiny bit of consulting work this week. Wrapped up something I was checking for a client, and helped another one optimize their Wordpress install. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, but it&amp;rsquo;s honest work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were two online quiz nights again this week. I didn&amp;rsquo;t play in the Geekfight one, only watched, as the theme (musicals) was out of my wheelhouse. We actually attended the original one for this back in 2016, and correspondingly did quite poorly lol. The second one was team based and was literature-themed, with four rounds based on specific authors each: Stephen King, Agatha Christie, Michael Crichton and Neil Gaiman. I actually rewatched the Agatha Christie Doctor Who ep for this, but the relevant question was super easy anyway, doh! We did reasonably well, but only managed to finish second. Facebook Live continues to be a horrible experience for this given the lag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;watching-lately&#34;&gt;Watching lately&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed that Psych was on Prime Video and have now accidentally binged the entire first season. I recommended this series to a friend, but upon watching the first season (I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve seen any of these eps before) I can&amp;rsquo;t explain why I&amp;rsquo;m so entertained by it. Shawn&amp;rsquo;s antics are over-the-top, and the cases he solves are often ridiculous, but I enjoy it anyway. (Edit: After reading some old convos with people, I suspect it might because I also on occasion attempt to pretend to be a psychic lol.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only movie I watched last week was Spirited Away. Check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;2020 movies page&lt;/a&gt; for my commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things of interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cory Doctorow is blogging again outside of BoingBoing via a new blog called &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralistic.net/&#34;&gt;Pluralistic&lt;/a&gt;. Each daily entry contains some number of links, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of like a newsletter really.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bibliogram.art/&#34;&gt;Bibliogram&lt;/a&gt; is a privacy-focused write-only web frontend for Instagram, that also provides RSS feeds. This kind of site can be fragile to maintain since I doubt they are using the closed official Instagram API. I fully expect whatever integration they are using to break sometimes and at some point in the future, permanently. Nonetheless, I used it to move some of my follows from Instagram to my feed reader (mostly less important ones like comic book artists). There is also an equivalent web front end for Twitter called &lt;a href=&#34;https://nitter.net/&#34;&gt;Nitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is also a web extension called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SimonBrazell/privacy-redirect&#34;&gt;Privacy Redirect&lt;/a&gt; that automatically redirects twitter and instagram requests (among others) to the privacy-focused equivalents (as described above). I tried this for a bit, and it&amp;rsquo;s ok if you only use these sites in a read-only manner. But you can&amp;rsquo;t reply or repost, etc. And if I want to share something via tweet, it attempts to redirect the twitter dialog to nitter, which has no equivalent URL. I also logged an issue &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zedeus/nitter/issues/146&#34;&gt;re:trailing slashes on Nitter&lt;/a&gt;. Since I&amp;rsquo;m still using these sites on a read-write basis, I can&amp;rsquo;t use this extension myself, but maybe some of you may find it useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gaming&#34;&gt;Gaming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ikoria is out on Magic Arena! I&amp;rsquo;ve done a few drafts already, you can check them out at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgiko&#34;&gt;MTGIKO tag&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Saturday gaming group recently switched our multiplayer game from Sentinels of the Multiverse to Armello. Quick review: It&amp;rsquo;s a fun, four player competitive board-game like where you try to beat each other to become king of a land of anthromorphized animals. I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s a real-world board game equivalent for it though, some of the mechanics don&amp;rsquo;t seem feasible IRL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also thought about buying one of the Jackbox party packs so I could play online trivia with the quiz team, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten much positive feedback. And they&amp;rsquo;d all need Steam accounts so I could stream the screen to them, that&amp;rsquo;s a barrier. I&amp;rsquo;ll think about it some more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Divinity: Original Sin 2 is still my current ongoing RPG. Haven&amp;rsquo;t been playing it too often, but making some progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site updates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I added a link to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ko-fi.com/roytang&#34;&gt;support me via Ko-fi&lt;/a&gt;, if you&amp;rsquo;d like. I don&amp;rsquo;t really expect anybody to use it, but maybe someone finds one of my posts useful and is generous? My expectations are low, so anything that comes through this channel will be a pleasant surprise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve disabled the comment form from blog posts. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of spam that gets submitted, despite the Google Captcha. They don&amp;rsquo;t show up on the site since I have to review them, but it&amp;rsquo;s a mild annoyance. And for some reason, the spam comments tend to focus on specific posts, an example is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2020/01/new-years-checklist/&#34;&gt;2020 New Year Checklist&lt;/a&gt; post. They used to focus on some older posts, but a while back I disabled comments on posts older than a year. I wonder if spammers share these links and are like &amp;ldquo;hey, this would be a good post to spam comments on!&amp;rdquo; Anyway: on a rare occasion some of my friends will comment via the form, but the majority of interaction with my posts these days is via bridgy webmention, so it probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t worth keeping around. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what to expect in the weeks to come. The future is so uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-04-12 Easter Sunday Edition
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/weeknotes-2020-04-12/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/weeknotes-2020-04-12/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I stopped updating the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;COVID19 Diary&lt;/a&gt; for a few days (last update was on Maunday Thursday), and I feel like that was a healthier choice overall. It helped that nothing significantly newsworthy happened over the long weekend. (Well, there&amp;rsquo;s still thousands of deaths worldwide, but somehow our bar for &amp;ldquo;significant&amp;rdquo; has shifted quite a bit.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lockdown has of course been extended to the end of April. I expect it will go beyond that though, likely the earliest chance for things to start going back to normal might be by June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got some consulting work done in the first half of the week, mostly setting up some automation for a client. Looks like they&amp;rsquo;ll have more to do for me next week so at least I&amp;rsquo;m keeping busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also managed to do two online quiz nights again, doing more poorly this time, but still pretty fun. The second one was held last night (Black Saturday), and it was a team effort, so it involved our trivia team on an FB Messenger call while watching the quiz via FB live. FB Live sucks for this kind of thing due to lag, but we had fun (but still did not do well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it&amp;rsquo;s Easter Sunday and the folks haven&amp;rsquo;t seen their grandkids for a while, me and the bros set up a Zoom call so all the grandkids could see the grandparents, everyone all together at once. As could be expected, it was kind of chaotic, but also all kinds of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;watching-lately&#34;&gt;Watching lately&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the weekend to watch a few movies, notably completing the Hobbit trilogy. This trilogy wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good as the LotR one (talk about high bar to meet right?), but pretty watchable in its own right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also watched The Departed, pretty intense movie. Gradually building up to watching the Irishman on Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I watched this fantastic collaborative fan-made shot-by-shot remake of Back to the Future II put together during quarantine, featuring all kinds of ridiculousness: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GcUUjWbVc4I&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GcUUjWbVc4I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;2020 movies page&lt;/a&gt; for my commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I also rewatched the last two seasons of Community (now surprisingly available on both Netflix and Prime Video at the same time!), mostly to prep for a trivia round, but also because it&amp;rsquo;s a fun underrated show and more people should watch it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things of interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ai-art.tokyo/en#/&#34;&gt;Al Gahaku&lt;/a&gt;, an AI &amp;ldquo;artist&amp;rdquo; that takes an existing photograph and modifies it to look like a renaissance-style painting. Pretty fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this &lt;a href=&#34;https://ncase.me/contact-tracing/&#34;&gt;great comic&lt;/a&gt; summarizing a privacy-respecting bluetooth-based contact tracing protocol. Nice way to present information for easier consumption by the general public.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gaming&#34;&gt;Gaming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Been playing mostly Magic Arena (wasting my gold on &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/1248178769275256832/&#34;&gt;cube sealed&lt;/a&gt;, really fun), Divinity: Original Sin 2 (kind of a slow burn) and a bit of Megaman Legacy Collection (currently about halfway through Megaman 3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake is out this week. I had a Deluxe edition preorder with our local game store, but given they&amp;rsquo;re all closed IDK how that&amp;rsquo;s going to work now. The store collected information from everyone who preordered so that they can give out info, but no updates yet. I suspect they&amp;rsquo;re going to try to set up some kind of delivery service, but don&amp;rsquo;t want to promise too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas even if I could get my FF7R copy, I don&amp;rsquo;t even have my PS4 at home as it was borrowed by my brother in February. I was planning to get it back right before the FF7R release, but eh, life in quarantine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dug up some old draft blog posts that I never published, so I polished them up and we should have some new content for the coming week (other than these weeknotes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, I&amp;rsquo;ve been considering re-organizing how this blog/site is organized. I was recently reading Kev Quirk&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://kevq.uk/why-i-dont-use-a-static-site-generator/&#34;&gt;post about why he doesn&amp;rsquo;t use a static site generator&lt;/a&gt;, it kind of tempted me to consider switching back to Wordpress. The main problem with Hugo running this site at the moment is that the build time is quite long, so feedback can take a while. (Still the same issue I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/one-year-with-hugo/&#34;&gt;reported in November&lt;/a&gt;.) Anyway, I considered going back to Wordpress, and while that&amp;rsquo;s certainly a viable solution, there are some things that I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of doing that would be complicated to do in Wordpress&amp;rsquo;s data structure. Also, my gut doesn&amp;rsquo;t like the idea, although there are certainly some pros. I&amp;rsquo;ll need to think about this a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someday, we&amp;rsquo;ll find our way back to the world we once knew, but it will have moved beyond us.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-03-29 Time Is Meaningless
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-29/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-29/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;COVID19 Diary&lt;/a&gt; is still ongoing, although that TOC is starting to get unwieldy. Need to think of a better UX solution for that.&lt;/p&gt;








    
    
        
    
    
    
        
            
            
            
            
              
            
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#ebaca044327af45cfc02b507f864565e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
                &lt;figure&gt;
                  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1242953238497751040/ET_bYDoUMAA8vty_hu61559ea2fb5b54ac6f28ab0474d68098_8100_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;ldquo;Time is meaningless under extreme enhanced community quarantine&amp;rdquo;&#34; title=&#34;&amp;ldquo;Time is meaningless under extreme enhanced community quarantine&amp;rdquo;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
                  &lt;figcaption&gt;Time is meaningless under extreme enhanced community quarantine (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
                &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;ebaca044327af45cfc02b507f864565e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1242953238497751040/ET_bYDoUMAA8vty.png&#34; /&gt;
              &lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Time is meaningless under extreme enhanced community quarantine&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;29 Mar 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;29 Mar 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1242953238497751040/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;            
        
    

&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;rsquo;s probably unrealistic, but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the lockdown somehow gets lifted sooner rather than later. It&amp;rsquo;s not that I crave social interaction (I don&amp;rsquo;t), but I miss going out for food. I miss pizza. And japanese curry. And fancy sandwiches with sesame seeds and such. The food at the house is fine and all, but tends to get repetitive. And during the last grocery run, the only mayonnaise they had was Best Foods Mayo Magic. Bleah. I&amp;rsquo;m so gonna eat at so many places after all of this is over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the upside, I did get to do much more stuff this work compared to last week, among other things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/blog/&#34;&gt;few posts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;participated in 2 online quiz nights!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a bit more consulting work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some room cleanup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some cleanup/sorting of old files and stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;did the groceries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;paid my dad&amp;rsquo;s credit card bills online (he was actually planning to go to the bank to pay them!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;watching-lately&#34;&gt;Watching lately&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ll retire the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately/&#34;&gt;watching lately tag&lt;/a&gt; and just include my media notes here in the weeknotes. More convenient, and more fine-tuned. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it works out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;4 new movies&lt;/a&gt;. Rate has slowed down a lot, but I figure I could get to a 100 for the year still. Princess Mononoke and Logan Lucky were particularly good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also started watching Picard (via Amazon Prime Video), since all the episodes have aired. I&amp;rsquo;m only a couple of episodes in, but I can already tell it has a completely different feel than TNG (or any of the TV series pre-Discovery for that matter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;greatly enjoyed Brooklyn Nine-Nine this week with JK Simmons!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gaming&#34;&gt;Gaming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since everyone&amp;rsquo;s at home, I&amp;rsquo;m getting a lot of multiplayer gaming done. This week our gaming group got into team Starcraft 2 vs AI battles. (We find ladder too stressful!). Since we have discord these days for voice, there is much more coordination in the team battles. And we even have some post-match analysis going on in our discord channel!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the singleplayer side, I managed to finished Megaman 1 in the Legacy Collection! Easily the toughest of the early Megaman games. Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MiWhBlrGiK8&#34;&gt;a video of me struggling to beat the yellow devil/cyclops&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to be able to beat all 6 of the games in the collection. I&amp;rsquo;m old and rusty and don&amp;rsquo;t have the reflexes of 1990s Roy, but at least I have savescumming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I passed on this month&amp;rsquo;s Humble Choice. I kind of wanted Fell Seal, but not that badly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal projects: Minor bug fixes mostly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent site changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I added the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums&#34;&gt;albums&lt;/a&gt; section under photos (similar to how FB has albums I guess?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mass formatting cleanup of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/quora&#34;&gt;old posts imported from quora&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minor CSS changes in various places&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything specific to look forward to in the coming week. Time under the lockdown moves at a different scale, we just take everything one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Birds of Prey and the Fantabulous Emancipation of One Harley Quinn spoiler-free review!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/birds-of-prey/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 21:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/birds-of-prey/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;(Too late for the theatrical release, but it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;tradition&lt;/a&gt; for comic book movies, so here we are.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall: Totally watchable, maybe slightly better than Suicide Squad for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Somehow still fits into some kind of DCEU continuity (after &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/10154796013953912/&#34;&gt;Suicide Squad&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie is really centered around Harley, to the detriment of the other characters. I can understand why they titled it the way they did, and I can appreciate the effort to have Harley carry a Birds of Prey introduction to the masses. But I think it could have worked a lot better titled and marketed strictly as a Harley-centric movie that happens to set up an eventual Birds of Prey follow-up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this one has a lot more Harley flavor than SS though: bright colors, gratuitous violence and so on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Margot Robbie performs well, and she kind of has to as she&amp;rsquo;s carrying the movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ewan McGregor&amp;rsquo;s Roman Sionis/Black Mask is a great performance as well, although he is characterized as little more than psychopathic gang boss rather than anything specifically related to the comic book character&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dinah Lance/Black Canary probably second-best characterization and plot beats out of the main cast (that&amp;rsquo;s not saying much), and has some great fights. Jurnee Smollett-Bell gives a decent performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rosie Perez&amp;rsquo;s Renee Montoya is described as someone out of an 80s cop movie, and she very much reminds me of Roger Murtaugh (of Lethal Weapon fame), which I suppose is what they were going for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huntress origins are comic book accurate, but Mary Elizabeth Winstead has very little to work with beyond that, and her character is kind of given a slapstick treatment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cassandra Cain is one of my favorite comic book characters. Unfortunately in this movie she is little more than a plot device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is no mid/post credits scene, although there is a little bit of a gag to taunt people who wait til the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni mama? No!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately, Feb 2020 - Not Much Apparently
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/watching-lately/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/watching-lately/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;2020 Movies&lt;/a&gt; update: 7 movies watched in Feb. Probably the best movie I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this month was &lt;strong&gt;Knives Out&lt;/strong&gt;. (&lt;strong&gt;Jojo Rabbit&lt;/strong&gt; close second.) The goal of 200 movies for the year is getting farther!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for TV, I think most of my watching time was spent rewatching &lt;strong&gt;Rick and Morty&lt;/strong&gt; for quiz purposes lol. Well, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/criminal-minds/&#34;&gt;Criminal Minds&lt;/a&gt; ended, so there&amp;rsquo;s that. Arrowverse has been meh, though I did enjoy &lt;strong&gt;Supergirl&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;s 100th episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hm, I guess I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually watched a lot of stuff in the past month. There&amp;rsquo;s a ton of stuff that I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to watch but haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to: The Expanse, Star Trek Picard, new season of Jack Ryan, Birds of Prey/Harley Quinn, and so on. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if things get better next month maybe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus, since this entry was kinda short: Here&amp;rsquo;s three movies I started watching but didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to finish:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/strong&gt;. It started off with like 20 minutes of some monkeys shouting at each other and a mysterious black box and I kind of lost interest. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that kind of thing was fine in 1968 when the movie came out and the people whose butts were already in the theatre were like &amp;ldquo;this is strange, but we&amp;rsquo;re already here, so we might as well sit through it&amp;rdquo;, but it&amp;rsquo;s 2020, I kind of need something to hold my internet-broken attention span more easily. It&amp;rsquo;s also one of the most renowned and highly-praised movies of all time, so I&amp;rsquo;m probably losing something here. Will try to resume it sometime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Conjuring&lt;/strong&gt;. We have a horror-movie themed quiz category coming up so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d watch a horror movie. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve voluntarily done so since having been mentally scarred by &lt;strong&gt;The Gate (1987)&lt;/strong&gt; as a kid. I picked The Conjuring, it was first on Netflix&amp;rsquo;s list of horror movies. I sat through the appropriately-creepy intro, then one of my quiz teammates told me he&amp;rsquo;d already unwillingly seen it before and couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep for a week after, and I was like &amp;ldquo;You just gave me an excuse not to watch it.&amp;rdquo; so I stopped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carrie (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to give up on horror movies just yet, so I picked another title from Netflix. I chose this one because it had Hit-Girl. It started out with typical teenage bullying stuff before she manifested her mutant powers and after that I kept thinking they needed to contact Professor Xavier, and couldn&amp;rsquo;t take it seriously after that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1226403645308035073/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 07:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1226403645308035073/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;2020 movies no. 18: Knives Out. &amp;ldquo;A fantastic murder mystery, maybe the best Ive ever seen, great performances all around.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;https://roytang.net/lists/2020/movies/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1225826359177465861/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 16:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1225826359177465861/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;2020 #movies 17: Uncut Gems. &amp;ldquo;Sandler gave a good performance, but I struggled to get through the early parts of the movies because his character and situation are so unrelatable to me personally.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;https://roytang.net/lists/2020/movies/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately, Jan 2020: Arrow, The Good Place, The Witcher, Kim&#39;s Convenience, The Expanse
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/watching-lately/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/watching-lately/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if I should continue this &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately&#34;&gt;watching-lately&lt;/a&gt; series since I already set up a separate page for &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/lists/2020/movies&#34;&gt;listing my 2020 movies watched&lt;/a&gt;. It might have been more consistent to have a list for the 2020 TV shows also? But then again, TV shows are a much different beast, since each show/season is broken into an episode and sometimes you watch them all in one go or sometimes over the span of a few months. So maybe let&amp;rsquo;s keep this going for the while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, movies. From the list for January, I think the best one was Parasite. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any expectations on what this movie was about yet somehow I still feel like it subverted those expectations anyway. I only saw 15 movies in January, which is below rate if I&amp;rsquo;m targetting 200 for the year. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s one of those NYR things that peters out after a month or so. Too early to tell, and besides, that&amp;rsquo;s not an insurmountable deficit. And 200 isn&amp;rsquo;t a hard target either so let&amp;rsquo;s just see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the realm of TV, this kind of explains why my movie-watching trailed off in the second half of the month, since the regular TV series started coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/arrowverse-crisis-on-infinite-earths/&#34;&gt;wrote about the Arrowverse crossover&lt;/a&gt; when the back half aired. This month the last two episodes of Arrow aired. The first one was a backdoor pilot for a new spinoff series, Green Arrow and the Canaries, starring Mia Queen. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what to think about the spinoff or whether I&amp;rsquo;ll even try it out. The whole time travel thing seems so convoluted as a way to bring Mia, E2 Laurel and Dinah together. The second episode was the series finale, basically a retrospective on the entire series. They pulled out all the stops, bringing back supporting characters from all 8 seasons of the show (Except for Malcolm Merlyn, apparently John Barrowman was busy reappearing in a different series), and even surrendering to some long-time fan wishes such as Digg picking up a mysterious green object dropped from space. In spite of all my complaints about the poor writing on this show (and the related ones) through the years, I will admit the finale was pretty good and they stuck the landing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the rest of the Arrowverse, some comments that I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where else I can post, mostly on the post-crisis set up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently in the rebooted universe, there was still a multiverse (since E2 Laurel exists, and doppelgangers showed up in Supergirl), but then the other universes were destroyed in a crisis (probably similar but different than the one we actually watched.) This is totally different from the &amp;ldquo;it became one universe from the very start&amp;rdquo; ending of the original CoIE and took away from the crossover a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was mildly annoyed when Jonn turned out to be able to restore pre-crisis memories. This only makes sense if what he&amp;rsquo;s restoring are part of his own memories, but not events he never knew about, otherwise, where did those pre-crisis memories come from? This annoyance was exacerbated by the GAatC backdoor pilot introducing a &amp;ldquo;device made by Cisco that replicates&amp;rdquo; Jonn&amp;rsquo;s powers so now anyone can restore pre-crisis memories, even from people Jonn has never met like future JJ. And in the Arrow finale, it seemed like everyone at the funeral was aware of the previous universe, did Jonn reset them too?? Seemed wholly unnecessary, but I suppose then we get difficult to explain things like Tommy wondering why E2 Laurel seems different&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fun fact: at Oliver&amp;rsquo;s funeral, Dinah is from before the GAatC episode (since in that episode she says she vanished after the funeral), Mia is from after that episode, and presumably so is E2 Laurel, although this isn&amp;rsquo;t explicitly specified. Timey-wimey!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Good Place&lt;/strong&gt; is also ending this week. As the time this post goes live, I will not have yet watched the season finale, but I did binge the rest of the seasons leading up to it, so maybe I can share some thoughts anyway. The Good Place was a weird series. It&amp;rsquo;s highly acclaimed and covers a lot of interesting topics philosophically, and puts its cast through a lot of interesting situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main issue with TGP is that I don&amp;rsquo;t find it particularly funny. Not like other Schur-influenced shows such as Brooklyn Nine Nine and Parks and Recreation. The characters can be charming sure and ridiculous sure. But their situations are rarely sitcom funny. I think part of it is that the situations they face are always so dire. I mean, their consequences somehow ramped up from eternal torture and damnation to the erasure of earth and all of humanity during the course of the series. Not very light-hearted topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another part of it might be the severe &lt;a href=&#34;https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/Flanderization&#34;&gt;Flanderization&lt;/a&gt; of the most of the characters. Typically this is a process that happens over the lifetime of a show, but with TGP, the characters&amp;rsquo; most annoying traits are highly focused on from the start: Eleanor is an asshole, Jason is an idiot, Tahani is a name-dropping socialite and Chidi is an anxious, undecisive philosopher. Eleanor and Chidi get a bit of character growth through the series (more Eleanor than Chidi), but Jason and Tahani are kind of still the same people by the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I like the show, but more for the questions it raises about how the afterlife could possibly work, rather than for pure comedic value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some friends somehow convinced me to watch &lt;strong&gt;Kim&amp;rsquo;s Convenience&lt;/strong&gt; (it was on NF). I have no regrets. It&amp;rsquo;s a smart, funny show about a Korean immigrant family in Canada. There were 3 seasons to binge on NF and it was very easy to side-watch since it&amp;rsquo;s a sitcom. The best character is the father of the family, a first-generation Korean immigrant who owns a convenience store (hence the show title). My only complaint is that it&amp;rsquo;s challenging my suspension of disbelief that the first generation immigrants still speak in English when among themselves, but as a friend said, it was probably for the sake of avoiding subtitles. Also, I wanted to see what the future Shang-chi actor looked like. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it kind of weird that he&amp;rsquo;s Chinese but he&amp;rsquo;s playing a Korean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A shorter series I saw on Netflix was &lt;strong&gt;The Witcher&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty good, and I much prefer Henry Cavill as Geralt in this show rather than as Superman. (Although he looks nothing like W3 Geralt). I wish I had seen this series before playing the games, as it sets up a lot of the character back stories that I kind of just accepted in the games. Looking forward to future seasons!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I managed to watch the first half of The Expanse season 3. It takes me a whole to catch up with this show because each episode is heavy and a lot of things are always happening, so it always needs my full attention. It&amp;rsquo;s so good, and it&amp;rsquo;s not like those shows where you never get any answers, things actually get resolved at a reasonable pace. One and a half more seasons to catch up on!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>My Top Tens of the 2010s
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/my-top-tens-of-the-2010s/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/my-top-tens-of-the-2010s/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Apparently I&amp;rsquo;m not done looking back at the 2010s yet. I had some &amp;ldquo;top tens of 2010s&amp;rdquo; discussions with some friends recently, here are my personal lists, each in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-top-ten-movies-of-the-2010s&#34;&gt;My Top Ten Movies of the 2010s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers Endgame (2019).&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m keeping only one slot per franchise, so I had to choose an MCU movies for this. Runner-ups for this slot were &lt;strong&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Captain America Winter Soldier&lt;/strong&gt;, and individually either one of those movies might be around the same or better than Endgame, but Endgame is the culmination of a decade&amp;rsquo;s worth of movies and gave me the most enjoyment as a comic book fan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue One (2016)&lt;/strong&gt;. I really liked &lt;strong&gt;The Force Awakens&lt;/strong&gt; too, but Rogue One is easily the best of the Disney Star Wars era.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interstellar (2014)&lt;/strong&gt;. The top ten discussions led to an extended debate about some of the science in this movie, all in good fun. It requires some suspension of disbelief is needed, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a pretty good sci-fi movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Martian (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;. This one was my favorite sci-fi movie of the decade though, I&amp;rsquo;ll read the book someday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inception (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;. The fact that this movie spawned so many memes and so many debates and discussions was an indication of how good it was.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: Into The Spider-Verse (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;. The MCU was a series of great movies based on comic books, but Spider-Verse was the best movie that really feels like a comic book. (I suppose the comparison is slightly unfair since Spider-Verse has the advantage of being animated!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One Cut of the Dead (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a Japanese film I saw at Eiga-sai. If you can overcome the one-inch barrier of subtitles it&amp;rsquo;s easily one of the funniest movies I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in the past decade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logan (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;. Easily the best of Fox&amp;rsquo;s X-Men films, and among the top echelon of comic book films overall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mad Max Fury Road (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;. This was my first Mad Max film, I really enjoyed the performances and the stunts and the ridiculous vehicle scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Baby Driver (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;. Makes me want to imagine what Edgar Wright&amp;rsquo;s Ant-Man would have been like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-top-ten-tv-shows-of-the-2010s&#34;&gt;My Top Ten TV Shows of the 2010s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parks and Recreation (2009-2015)&lt;/strong&gt;. I know it started before the 2010s, but this might be appropriate anyway since the show didn&amp;rsquo;t really pick up until the third season. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of other notable comedies of its class that I really enjoyed during the last decade, such as &lt;strong&gt;30 Rock&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;, but I tip the hat to PnR because I really like the characters of Ben Wyatt and Ron Swanson and Andy Dwyer. (Apparently I really like all the male main characters except for Tom lol)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brooklyn Nine Nine (2013-)&lt;/strong&gt;. B99 is just my kind of ridiculous, similar to PnR, super quotable, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Young Justice (2010-)&lt;/strong&gt;. Young Justice is the true successor to the excellent JL/JLU of the 00s, with a deep plot full of conspiracy and betrayal, a large cast of characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daredevil (2015-2018)&lt;/strong&gt;. The Netflix shows had great promise, and Daredevil seasons 1 and 3 were among the best of them. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad that they fell to the IP disputes of their time, but who knows maybe we get to revisit them again some time in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Who (2005-)&lt;/strong&gt;. The DW revival started in the 00s, but I only started watching it in 2012, when Matt Smith was already the Eleventh. There have been some weaker seasons and episodes, but overall I enjoyed the general campiness and sci-ifi silliness of the series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black Mirror (2011-)&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m actually still not caught up with the latest season, but I have greatly enjoyed the near-future what-ifs posed by this popular show. (It&amp;rsquo;s too bad we are unlikely to heed its warnings!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breaking Bad (2008-2013)&lt;/strong&gt;. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s generally regarded as one of the best series of all time right? I haven&amp;rsquo;t even bothered watching El Camino because for me the ending of BB was already prefect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Orville (2017-)&lt;/strong&gt;. 2017 was a great year for Star Trek (-like) content, with the more serious &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; and more lighthearted The Orville both debuting. I enjoyed both shows, but the Orville&amp;rsquo;s sci-fi sitcom brought us something a lot more unique.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game of Thrones (2011-2019)&lt;/strong&gt;. Say what you will about the quality of writing (or lack thereof) for the last couple of seasons, but this was a TV series that got people obsessed and following every episode and arguing about spoilers and forming fan theories, book readers or otherwise. It pretty much defined the decade of TV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-top-ten-games-of-the-2010s&#34;&gt;My Top Ten Games of the 2010s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starcraft 2 (2010-2015)(PC)&lt;/strong&gt;. Got all 3 parts on release, and still playing it to this day (mostly coop missions - I don&amp;rsquo;t really have the heart for the stress of ladder matches anymore!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Last of Us (2013)(PS3)&lt;/strong&gt;. There are games where you&amp;rsquo;re saddened that you can&amp;rsquo;t play them again for the first time, and the Last of Us was one of the best of those.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild (2017)(WiiU)&lt;/strong&gt;. The defining Zelda of modern times. I loved the exploratory nature similar to the original NES LoZ and the cel-shaded graphics were fantastic. The sequel may yet convince me to get a Switch!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persona 5 (2017)(PS4)&lt;/strong&gt;. Easily the best JRPG of its era (sorry, Final Fantasy XV!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fallout: New Vegas (2010)(PC)&lt;/strong&gt;. Obsidian&amp;rsquo;s part of the Fallout franchise had much improved writing and questlines over it&amp;rsquo;s predecessor Fallout 3, good enough for multiple run throughs, and I even managed to finish all the DLCs as well!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Elder Scrolls: Skyrim (2011)(PC)&lt;/strong&gt;. I came late to this series with Oblivion in 2008, but it&amp;rsquo;s one of the few RPGs in this decade that I&amp;rsquo;ve replayed and finished multiple times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Witcher 3: The Wild Hunt (2015)(PS4)&lt;/strong&gt;. Easily the best PC RPG of the past decade, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t even played the expansions yet! Runner-up: Divinity Original Sin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultra Street Fighter IV (2014)(PS3)&lt;/strong&gt;. Technically, the base game came out in the 00s, but all the later revisions came out in the 2010s. This game started a fighting game resurgence that&amp;rsquo;s going on to this today. I was never super good at it, but I sure played a lot of hours and bought multiple copies of each version that came out even. The next version, SFV, hasn&amp;rsquo;t been as well received, but the franchise and the fighting game resurgence is still going strong up to now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eternal Card Game (2016)(Multiplat)&lt;/strong&gt;. This one is actually my most played Steam game of all time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sid Meier&amp;rsquo;s Civilization V (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;. Been playing this series since &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/ancient-pc-gaming/&#34;&gt;the olden days&lt;/a&gt;! Civ5 brought a pretty big change to the series with one unit per tile, and at 395 hours it&amp;rsquo;s still currently among my most played games on Steam. (Civ6 is about a hundred hours behind)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>2020 Movies List
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;List of new (to me) movies watched in 2020. Ongoing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ratings scale:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5: I regret that I can never again watch it for the first time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4: I would enjoy watching it again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3: I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind watching it again, maybe running in the background while I do other things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2: I would not want to watch it again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1: If you suggest watching it, it might be time to end the friendship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;#&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Release Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Date Watched&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Rating (out of 5)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sicario&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2015&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 05&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Great thriller movie, but the lesson here is so bleak&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paprika&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2006&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Colorful, vivid and great animation but so so bizaare&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Birdman or (The Unexpected Virtue of Ignorance)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Insanely good, I can see why it won best picture&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Looper&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2012&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Entertaining enough, but raises so many time travel questions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;John Wick 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Better than I expected&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ad Astra&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kinda draggy&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Klaus&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Surprisingly good. Fantastic animation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Marriage Story&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Great performances. Ma didn&amp;rsquo;t like the ending.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fist of Fury&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1972&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Great fight scenes. Actually a bit more plot than I expected&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Coming to America&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1988&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I had low expectations, but it was better than I thought it would be. Ma would like it!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MIB International&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kind of predictable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Batman vs TMNT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ridiculous, but fun. Good for kids.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6 Underground&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The editing and scene transitions were all over the place. A very Michael Bay film.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Wolf of Wall Street&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This movie does nothing to improve my opinion of modern capitalism.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4.5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Parasite&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 19&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Really good, but IDK how to begin to describe it. Worth overcoming the 1 inch subtitle barrier for.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kiki&amp;rsquo;s Delivery Service&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1989&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 04&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Very light-hearted and idyllic. At first it felt a bit boring, but it had me smiling by the end.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Uncut Gems&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 07&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sandler gave a good performance, but I struggled to get through the early parts of the movies because his character and situation are so unrelatable to me personally.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Knives Out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A fantastic murder mystery, maybe the best I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, great performances all around.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Master and Commander: The Far Side of the World&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2003&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Watched this because a redditor said ROTK robbed it of best picture in 2003. This is a great war movie, but he was wrong&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jojo Rabbit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Best movie about a Nazi ever. Most colorful depiction of Nazi Germany. Fantastic movie.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;21&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Superman: Red Son&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;An acceptable adaptation of one of my favorite Superman stories. Minus points for not including the &amp;ldquo;House of L&amp;rdquo; epilogue.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Coach Carter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2005&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I watched this because I saw it in a &amp;ldquo;top inspirational speeches&amp;rdquo; YT video. Pretty good sports movie.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Billy Madison&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1995&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Watched this so I know the context of the &amp;ldquo;I award you no points and may god have mercy on your soul&amp;rdquo; clip. Typical early Sandler movie.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Princess Mononoke&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1997&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Much more action-packed than the last Ghibli movie I watched. Beautifully animated.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Birds of Prey and the Fantabulous Emancipation of One Harley Quinn&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/birds-of-prey/&#34;&gt;Spoiler-free review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Logan Lucky&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fun heist movie, but I find it hard to take the characters seriously. Might be some anti-redneck bias.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2012&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See below&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;28&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Hobbit: The Desolation of Smaug&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2013&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 07&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;See below&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bttftoo.com/&#34;&gt;Project 88: Back to the Future Too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fantastic fan-made shot-by-shot recreation of Back to the Future II, put together during quarantine, w/ stop motion, kids, sock puppets, bananas, potatoes and much more! &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GcUUjWbVc4I&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GcUUjWbVc4I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Hobbit: Battle of the Five Armies&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This trilogy had far too many extra things that weren&amp;rsquo;t in the books, but it was pretty good. I rank them Desolation &amp;gt; Five Armies &amp;gt; Journey.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;31&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Departed&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2006&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This was intense. I liked it more than Goodfellas.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Spirited Away&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2001&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shades of Alice in Wonderland and The Wizard of Oz. Easily the best Ghibli film I&amp;rsquo;ve watched so far.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;33&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Psych the Movie&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 03&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like an extended episode of Psych!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;34&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ready Player One&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 05&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A predictable yet fun romp.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;35&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Siege&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1998&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 05&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Caught this on Cinemax when I went down for lunch. Much too idealistic in hindsight, given what happened in New York 3 years after this film released.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;36&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kong: Skull Island&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 07&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exciting popcorn movie.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;37&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ang Huling El Bimbo: The Musical&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ok, so this one isn&amp;rsquo;t really a movie. The appeal for me is mostly the music and the nostalgia. The plot was serviceable, though some may find it problematic.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;38&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Justice League Dark: Apokolips War&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;This was great, and appropriatly dark. Good send-off for the DCAMU.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;39&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Zombieland Double Tap&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A fun romp, but pretty much more of the same.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;40&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sonic the Hedgehog&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2019&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jun 27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fun with Ben Schwartz, but James Marsden&amp;rsquo;s character is kinda dumb. Needs a lot of suspension of disbelief.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;41&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mission Impossible Fallout&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jun 29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Good watch, it&amp;rsquo;s MI, you know how it goes. Maybe 40% of it is Tom Cruise running.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;42&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Atomic Blonde&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jul 11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;I came in thinking it was a John Wick style action movie. True, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a Cold War spy thriller. Nice twists, but might be a bit hard to follow near the end.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;43&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Old Guard&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jul 12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to expect, never read the Greg Rucka graphic novel on which it was based. Action-packed, fun watch.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;44&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Superman Man of Tomorrow&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aug 28&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Not too good. Weird animation. Writing all over the place.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;45&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bill and Ted Face the Music&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aug 29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A most excellent sequel, echoing the earlier two movies. A midlife crisis journey full of heart and time travel nonsense. Little Billie and Theda are great!&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;46&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Enola Holmes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sep 27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay. Basically young adult/Nancy Drew Sherlock Holmes, with a bit of feminism thrown in. Mycroft annoying as usual.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;47&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wonder Woman 1984&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dec 30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of things that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense (even accounting for myths etc), but it helps to think this movie takes place pre-crisis.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: December 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/watching-lately-december-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/watching-lately-december-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Been watching a lot of things this December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally got back on &lt;strong&gt;The Expanse&lt;/strong&gt; after finishing S1 more than a year ago. I only finished S2, but it was already a vast improvement over S1. S1 felt like a lot of meandering around until the characters actually ran into the plot. S2 was stronger, faster-paced, and there&amp;rsquo;s always a lot of things going on in each episode. I really like this series now, looking forward to S3 and S4 when I have the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix-wise, I enjoyed their recently-added &lt;strong&gt;Jeopardy&lt;/strong&gt; series (always a great show to have playing in the background), the new documentary &lt;strong&gt;The Movies That Made Us&lt;/strong&gt; (loved their selection of movies to feature), and the second season of &lt;strong&gt;Final Space&lt;/strong&gt; (a fun sci-fi space romp if ever there was one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of crazy sci-fi, &lt;strong&gt;Rick and Morty&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve caught up with the recently released S4 as well. This series seems a lot more self-aware now, and a lot more unafraid to make fun of tropes and genre conventions. I liked the heist episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broadcast-wise, I enjoyed the front half of the Arrowverse&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Crisis of Infinite Earths&lt;/strong&gt; crossover. It had that same feeling as Avengers Endgame where I knew what was likely to happen based on comic book knowledge, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t think they could do it, but they did it! Whenever discussion of this crossover leaked over to the mainstream TV subreddits/forums, there was a lot of criticism of how it looked so low-budget, but I think any expecations of them being able to provide Avengers-quality costumes and effects on a broadcast TV show budget are unrealistic. The Arrowverse shows certainly have a lot of flaws, but this type of multiversal crossover isn&amp;rsquo;t something that could have been achieved without all the setup of the past eight years (and even beyond, considering older shows like Smallville and 90&amp;rsquo;s Flash), and that&amp;rsquo;s something comparable to what the MCU has built, even at a fraction of the budget. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll have more words for this series and the Arrowverse in general when the back half airs in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend also somehow tricked me into watching &lt;strong&gt;Sky High&lt;/strong&gt;, a rather old and campy and totally predictable superhero-type movie. I did finish it so I guess I enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nieces were over this weekend so I finally got to watch &lt;strong&gt;Toy Story 4&lt;/strong&gt;. I was a bit skeptical that they decided to add another installment when I felt the trilogy was already pretty tight. I have to admit I was surprised with the direction this movie took and the ending it gave, which leaves an opening for future movies in the franchise, though they might already be quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;Star Wars: Rise of Skywalker&lt;/strong&gt; before Christmas, here are &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/star-wars-rise-of-skywalker-spoilers/&#34;&gt;my thoughts on the film and the trilogy&lt;/a&gt;. WHile I wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely happy with it, I did enjoy watching the film and I recognize that it was a good retelling of Star Wars for new/modern fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also rewatched &lt;strong&gt;The Last Jedi&lt;/strong&gt; for the first time about a week later, it was still pretty good, especially that third act. (Casino subquest still felt superfluous). I did come out a bit more disappointed that ROS didn&amp;rsquo;t follow through with some of the themes of TLJ. I can only assume there are a couple of alternate universes out there where both Rian Johnson&amp;rsquo;s direction and JJ Abrams direction came true for the Skywalker saga ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Star Wars, I enjoyed the ending of &lt;strong&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/strong&gt;, although it did have a couple of weaker episodes in the middle that felt like filler (or maybe just there to seed characters for the eventual second season). The final two episodes are pretty good, and we get the payoffs of actualy learning the Mandalorian&amp;rsquo;s history and all. I do find it ridiculous that the Jedi and the Force are still unknown enough that the Mandalorian has never heard of them considering it probably hasn&amp;rsquo;t even been more than 30 years since Palpatine took down the Republic, which had literally an entire council of Jedi as an advisory body to the Senate and featuring prominently in the Clone Wars. Do they not have recorded history? Lol. In any case, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to season 2 whenever it lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THat&amp;rsquo;s it for the decade!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/rise-of-skywalker/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/rise-of-skywalker/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;RISE OF SKYWALKER Spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie is fine and entertaining to watch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a Star Wars movie, so you pretty much know what to expect, space wizards and space battles and such&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pacing is frantic in the first act, and a bit in the second. Abrams has a lot of things he wants to do and limited time to do it, so things happen in rapid succession&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the third act is basically an ode to &lt;em&gt;Return of the Jedi&lt;/em&gt;, as a parallel to The Force Awakens&amp;rsquo; ode to &lt;em&gt;A New Hope&lt;/em&gt;. In fact, there is a lot of fanservice for original trilogy fans sprinkled throughout the movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is not the best ending I could have imagined for the sequel trilogy, but it is an ending&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are a few twists and turns in the movie, but because it&amp;rsquo;s Star Wars, you largely know what to expect from the overall plot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;magugustuhan ba ni Mama: The movie is generally family-friendly (outside of the violence), but my mom doesn&amp;rsquo;t like space battles and she would probably be confused by the rapid pace of events and all these characters she&amp;rsquo;s not familiar with, so no.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watched in IMAX 3D, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think there was much noticeable 3D, the movie is probably perfectly fine without IMAX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is no post-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think I liked &lt;em&gt;The Last Jedi&lt;/em&gt; more than this one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a bit more &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/star-wars-rise-of-skywalker-spoilers/&#34;&gt;spoilery comments posted here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/rise-of-skywalker/howtowatchastarwar_hu5bb634bfc9261ec532ae3490534430ee_1213904_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Comic does not reflect my viewing experience&lt;/p&gt;
    



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Star Wars: Rise of Skywalker (spoilers!)
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/star-wars-rise-of-skywalker-spoilers/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/star-wars-rise-of-skywalker-spoilers/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I watched the most recent Star Wars last night. Spoiler-free review posted &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/rise-of-skywalker/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this ended the sequel trilogy and the entire &amp;ldquo;Skywalker Saga&amp;rdquo;, I thought it deserved a bit more spoilery discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure we needed to introduce some brand new characters in the third movie that don&amp;rsquo;t even get that much buildup because there were so many other things happening, unless they were seeded here for purposes of future Star Wars movie, which is just silly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much fondness for the guy, but Hux deserved better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some great appearances here that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lando showing up in the desert planet wearing the same outfit he used as a disguise in the first act of &lt;em&gt;Return of the Jedi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Han appearing as a hallucination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wedge Antilles is still alive! And comes back with Lando and Chewie to help out during the final space battle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the parallels with &lt;em&gt;Return of the Jedi&lt;/em&gt; are glaringly obvious, especially for the third act: Rey going alone to face off against the evil emperor while the rebellion pursues a last-chance and hopeless space battle outdoors? Check. Series protagonist face turn at the last minute? Check. Lando piloting the Falcon as a general in the final space battle? Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the sequel trilogy really suffered from not having a single creative vision for all three movies. J.J. Abrams and Rian Johnson obviously wanted to take the franchise in two different directions, with Abrams wanting to make an homage to the original trilogy with new characters, and Johnson wanting to explore what there is outside of the original trilogy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead, Abrams has to do a strong pull back from the second film, which meant he had a whole lot more setup to do, leading to ridiculous things like a huge plot point like Palpatine&amp;rsquo;s return being introduced in the opening crawl and that messy frantic pace of a first act&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine now where else the franchise could have gone, but I would have liked to see something like:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 7 as homage to original trilogy and passing of the torch to new characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 8 as subverting expectations and striking in a different direction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 9 as defining a new kind of future for Star Wars, perhaps with more Force users, not necessarily Jedi or Sith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;instead what we get with &lt;em&gt;Rise of Skywalker&lt;/em&gt; is basically the same ending as &lt;em&gt;Return of the Jedi&lt;/em&gt;: The evil emperor is defeated (the same evil emperor at that!) and the rebellion is victorious and celebrating and now only one Jedi remains and balance exists in the force. I can understand wanting to do a modern re-telling for a new generation of fans, but we lived with that ending since 1983, it would have been nice to see something different this time. Such was not to be. (And I&amp;rsquo;m sure the mixed reaction to &lt;em&gt;Last Jedi&lt;/em&gt; had a hand in Disney deciding to be more conservative with this one)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s really weird for me that the &amp;ldquo;Skywalker Saga&amp;rdquo; ends with a new Skywalker emerging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final Skywalker saga rankings: 5-ESB &amp;gt; 4-ANH &amp;gt; 6-ROJ &amp;gt; 3.5-RO &amp;gt; 7-TFA &amp;gt; 8-TLJ == 3-RTS &amp;gt; 9-ROS &amp;gt; SOLO &amp;gt; 2-AOC &amp;gt; 1-TPM&lt;/p&gt;


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: November 2019: Broly, Justice League, Arrowverse, Mandalorian
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-nov-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-nov-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Nothing in the cinema this month (going to the cinema is expensive!). I did watch a couple of animated movies this month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dragonball Super: Broly. I have some vague recollection of watching the original Broly movie, and I believe this one is much better. DBS Broly is a slightly more nuanced character than just &amp;ldquo;random raging monster&amp;rdquo; from the previous non-canon movie. The animation was okay, you could tell the animators were having fun with some of the battle parts. Also, I watched the English dub, and I just realized Goku&amp;rsquo;s voice is super annoying, so I pity the Americans who had to grow up with that voice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Justice League vs the Fatal Five. I&amp;rsquo;m still a bit behind on the DC animated stuff. I liked this one because I think it handled Jessica Cruz fairly well, and it got me backreading Justice League Odyssey for more Cruz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, since I got a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/new-video-card/&#34;&gt;new video card&lt;/a&gt; and have a second monitor again, side-watching is back on the menu, so I was able to catch up with some of the ongoing series: Modern Family (meh), Simpsons (meh), Rick and Morty (ok so far, only 3 eps in).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caught Season 3 of The Toys That Made Us on Netflix. Not as fun as S2 for me since that one had Transformers, and I only have secondary interest at best in the toylines for S4, but some of the stories here were pretty interesting, like they say that the giant robot from Japanese Spider-Man was the one that inspired sentai robots! What! The TMNT ep was also pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrowverse is still going on (somehow), with their upcoming big-deal Crisis crossover kicking off in mid December. Surprisingly, Arrow itself has been pretty good this season (perhaps because no Felicity? lol), followed by Flash, with Supergirl dead last. I am not fond of Lena&amp;rsquo;s heel turn in Supergirl, I felt like it was a disservice to the character who when introduced was desperate to get out of her brother&amp;rsquo;s shadow. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been watching Batwoman, even though it&amp;rsquo;s part of the crossover, we&amp;rsquo;ll see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to watch the first ep of Mandalorian, but haven&amp;rsquo;t had time yet for the most recent eps. It&amp;rsquo;s not the sort of thing I&amp;rsquo;d side-watch, so I have to dedicate time for it. I better do that before the spoilers catch up with me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next month I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crisis on Infinite Earths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Wars: Rise of the Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-nov-2019/broly_hu4d06564a23f2e71ac7d3766ad33b0777_2995425_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: October 2019: Joker, Scorsese, Stuber, Bloodlines, Brotherhood
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-oct-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-oct-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Actually watched something in the cinema this month: &lt;strong&gt;Joker&lt;/strong&gt;. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t originally sure if I wanted to see it, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t hyped for it at all in the months prior. But as the showing date came nearer, there was a lot of buzz around it so I decided to go anyway. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like it lived up to the hype and the warnings about promoting incel stuff, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s one of the higher-grossing DC movies, so maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll have more to come in that vein. MCU movies all have kind of same-y tone and feel, so probably DC can differentiate itself by doing these heavier movies with a different kind of style. My spoiler-free review of this movie is &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/10/1180086308963618816/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching Joker and also reading Scorsese recent comments about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/film/2019/oct/04/martin-scorsese-says-marvel-movies-are-not-cinema&#34;&gt;MCU movies not really being cinema&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to watch one of his movies and decided on &lt;strong&gt;Goodfellas&lt;/strong&gt;. (The only other one I had seen prior to this was &lt;em&gt;Shutter Island&lt;/em&gt;, which for a long while I thought was a Nolan flick.) Goodfellas was pretty good, definitely nothing like an MCU movie. They are obviously different kinds of &amp;ldquo;cinema&amp;rdquo; altogether, with the MCU movies leaning more towards the &amp;ldquo;popcorn&amp;rdquo; side of the spectrum. I did find it a bit hard to take Joe Pesci seriously here since I only really knew him from &lt;em&gt;Home Alone&lt;/em&gt;. I believe this is also the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen Ray Liotta in a film, so now I know who he is. I definitely enjoyed the &amp;ldquo;slice-of-life&amp;rdquo; look into the old-school gangster lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also watched &lt;strong&gt;Stuber&lt;/strong&gt;, mostly because this movie kept being advertised when I was in the US and it reminded me of Deadpool and that taxi driver friend of his. I was only expecting Batista, but Karen Gillan is also here (briefly!), so there&amp;rsquo;s a tiny GotG reunion there. Indian taxi driver dude was cool, the movie was ok, moderately funny, nothing too genre-busting. More popcorn movies for scorsese to snub his nose at, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catching up on my backlog of DC animated films, I decided to watch &lt;strong&gt;Wonder Woman: Bloodlines&lt;/strong&gt;. Plot spoilers, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a gaggle of WW villains (Silver Swan, Doctor Poison, Doctor Cyber, Cheetah, Giganta) plotting to invade Themyscira, I suspect to make them more well-known among the DC animated viewers. Coincidentally, I had also recently read the WW Rebirth story arc where a gaggle of WW villains tried to trick her into revealing the location of Themyscira, so I had a fresh point of comparison. In the comic book arc, everything was masterminded by Veronica Cale, a pharmaceutical CEO who had been created in the early 2000s with the intent of being the Lex Luthor to WW&amp;rsquo;s Superman. In the movie Cale works with WW for a while, and along I was waiting for the reveal that she was behind everything, but that never came. I would guess they have some bigger plans for Veronica Cale down the line in the DC animared film-universe. Otherwise, the movie was ok. Nothing too spectacular, missable, but also good enough to watch. EDIT: I found out after I wrote this that Bloodlines had a mid-credits scene where WW figures out Cale was behind everything all along!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, not much to say right now. The fall shows are back, that means the Arrowverse is in full swing again (except for Legends, they&amp;rsquo;ll be back in January). The &amp;ldquo;science&amp;rdquo; on &lt;strong&gt;Flash&lt;/strong&gt; is still ridiculous. The flash forwards on &lt;strong&gt;Arrow&lt;/strong&gt; are still boring (I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why they want to make a spinoff for Mia Smoak!), &lt;strong&gt;Supergirl&lt;/strong&gt; is also a bit meh. I&amp;rsquo;m really only looking forward to the Crisis crossover this season (and of course, &lt;em&gt;Legends of Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;.) Haven&amp;rsquo;t watched Batwoman yet, maybe I should since she has one of the five Crisis episodes. Also been following some of the regular stuff: The Good Place, Modern Family, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s also a lot of superhero shows still on the backlog, some of which I may never get to watch: Runaways, Cloak and Dagger (cancelled!), Krypton (cancelled!), Legion (finished!), Doom Patrol, Titans S2, etc. Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a point where there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;too much&lt;/em&gt; content for comic book fans? Lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix: I saw that Jenny Slate has a standup special out and I tried watching it, but eh, not for me, found it very boring and stopped about a third of the way through. I also found myself re-watching the end of &lt;strong&gt;Full Metal Alchemist: Brotherhood&lt;/strong&gt;, mostly because I was envious of a friend who was watching it for the first time. Was surprised to learn the anime is 10 years old as of this year! Still held up well, possibly my favorite anime of all time. The final confrontation and fight scenes were great, although the epilogue episode was a bit anticlimactic and awkward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for this month. Maybe next month we manage to dent the ever-growing backlog? Maybe?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/1180086308963618816/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 11:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/1180086308963618816/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;JOKER spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;very dark movie, not like any previous superhero movies at all; don&amp;rsquo;t bring your kids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is violent and potentially disturbing, but strangely not as much as the hype made it out to be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joaquin Phoenix definitely gives a pretty good performance, but IDK about the supposed &amp;ldquo;Oscar-worthy&amp;rdquo; hype&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some of the shots feels like the director definitely had a lot of fun bringing this story to life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would have liked less connection to the Batman mythos so that this movie is more stand-alone. I mean, it is pretty much stand-alone, but it does remind you where it&amp;rsquo;s set and direct connections to the Mythos exist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think a lot of the story and plot elements are handled well, any concerns I have would largely be nitpicking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No post credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i didnt watch in imax and don&amp;rsquo;t think it would be relevant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;magugustuhan ba ni mama: sure NO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ultimately, I still prefer that Joker&amp;rsquo;s origin story remain undetermined, as it makes him more akin to a natural force of chaos, but I accept this movie as a version that even canon Joker could have told and that might have been believable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s definitely a better movie overall than Suicide Squad, Man of Steel or Dawn of Justice or Justice League, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a different completely type of movie, so the comparison is difficult&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still like Ledger&amp;rsquo;s Joker the best, the character is best opposite Batman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: September 2019: Dark Phoenix, The Ranch
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/watching-lately-sep-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/watching-lately-sep-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I finally got around to watching &lt;strong&gt;X-Men Dark Phoenix&lt;/strong&gt; which I skipped when it came out mainly because (a) poor reviews, and while normally I&amp;rsquo;d have watched it anyway since I have not missed any of the X-Men movies in the cinema, not even the horrendous Wolverine Origins, there was also to consider that (b) I was in the US at the time and was only willing to spend my precious dollars on one expensive American cinema and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/&#34;&gt;Spider-man Far From Home&lt;/a&gt; won out. The movie wasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; bad really, at least I felt better about it than the aforementioned Wolverine Origins. Here are &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes/2019/09/1171737237135867906/&#34;&gt;some of my nitpicks&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not what would&amp;rsquo;ve been the best ending for the X-Men series which was really one of the pioneers of the superhero movie revolution (alongside Raimi&amp;rsquo;s Spider-Man), but that&amp;rsquo;s what we got. At least it ended with a big fiery bird explosion in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also watched Part 7 of &lt;strong&gt;The Ranch&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. The Ranch is one of those weird family comedy/drama shows that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally seem to be in my spheres of interest, especially since the show is probably a lot more appealing to conservative/right-wing viewers. (It&amp;rsquo;s often punctuated by country music and the characters regularly criticize Hillary Clinton and mock the idea of climate change.) I will not admit that I got into it mostly because of Elisha Cuthbert. It is a moderately enjoyable show, the kind you don&amp;rsquo;t mind having run in the background while you&amp;rsquo;re doing something else, although it did lose a bit of its comedy punch with the firing/writing off of Danny Masterson (&amp;ldquo;Hyde&amp;rdquo; from the 70s show) last season due to #MeToo issues, and the guy they replaced him with hasn&amp;rsquo;t been super impressive thus far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow month again this time. The lull should pick up in October once the fall US shows start off. And there&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of movies I want to watch too but some combination of laziness and lack of time always puts them off.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/1171737237135867906/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 10:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/1171737237135867906/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I finally watched Dark Phoenix today. It was not as bad as I thought it would be, but the #xmen jet did have a port where Cyclops could put his head so they can use him as a cannon, and apparently Nightcrawler can teleport 4 people across an entire city so there&amp;rsquo;s that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;some weird character choices too. I mean, Erik&amp;rsquo;s lackeys were basically random unknown mutants (I didn&amp;rsquo;t even realize who Selene was supposed to be until she fell off the train). Not to mention the obscure Marvel alien race in the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least we got our space firebird thingy so there&amp;rsquo;s that&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/1171737237135867906/EEMwEYZVAAAc81x_hub5b8857347b04f05593780a0fae36800_58178_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: August 2019: Young Justice, The Boys, Fleabag, One Cut of the Dead
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/watching-lately-aug-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/watching-lately-aug-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Hmm, surprisingly I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched too much stuff this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eigasai&#34;&gt;Eigasai&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched a Japanese film at Eigasai in UP Diliman for the first time ever, upon the invite of some friends. We saw &lt;strong&gt;One Cut of the Dead&lt;/strong&gt; a comedy zombie film. It was great and it was hilarious, although you must make sure not to lose patience with the first thirty minutes. I went in blind not knowing anything about it other than &amp;ldquo;Japanese comedy zombie movie&amp;rdquo;, so you should too! Easily one of the funniest movies I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;young-justice&#34;&gt;Young Justice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back half of Young Justice Outsiders finished this week. I&amp;rsquo;ve honestly been a bit whelmed for this half of the season as I feel like they&amp;rsquo;re all over the place and there&amp;rsquo;s too many plot threads going on at once. Still an enjoyable watch especially for DC fans of course. The thing about having such a large cast is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to focus on any one of them too long, but this season was all about Halo, Geoforce and Cyborg so the arc endings pretty much revolved around those three. It feels like so many status quo changes happened in the last episode though, felt a bit crammed. Also, some spoilers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like the Light declaring at the end that their gains were sufficient vs Luthor&amp;rsquo;s original plans seemed ridiculous (i.e. controlling Markovia vs controlling and registering all superhumans). They already had one puppet nation under their control (Queen Bee is right there!) and they&amp;rsquo;re literally planning to go against Darkseid, how does controlling Markovia help? Feels like a very post-facto justification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did like that they chose not to complete their Judas Contract re-telling in a similar manner and we get a &amp;ldquo;redeemed&amp;rdquo; Tara to contrast with the &amp;ldquo;fallen&amp;rdquo; Geoforce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fleabag&#34;&gt;Fleabag&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about this Amazon Prime series going in either, only that it was a comedy and it was well-reviewed. I did enjoy watching it, although it&amp;rsquo;s more of a tragic comedy than anything else. Basically about how people deal with absurdly difficult situations in their daily life. The story is well-told, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I get all the hype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-boys&#34;&gt;The Boys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Amazon Prime series. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read the source material, and I was a bit turned off by the first episode, but I powered through. I knew it would be dark going in, and possibly gratuitous in terms of the sex and violence at some points, so not many surprises there. The plot seems in my head to be &amp;ldquo;What if superheroes were driven by a greedy corporation&amp;rdquo;, which certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t help address my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/capitalism/&#34;&gt;misgivings about capitalism&lt;/a&gt;. The plot also reminds me of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s book Reckoners, which was also a story about a resistance trying to oppose a superhuman regime led by a Superman-like figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking over the Wikipedia entry for the comic book series, it seems the TV show had some significant divergences, which is understandable, so I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll be seeking out the comic books. The series was enjoyable enough to binge over a few days, although some parts are a bit predictable. I did like the treatment given to Hugh and Annie/Starlight. The cast is pretty good too, I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize Simon Pegg (because it was such a serious role) and Elisabeth Shue (because&amp;hellip;I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen her in anything in a while?). Oh and Gus Fring is also here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I ended up enjoying the season overall, as it tackles a lot of issues I relate with. I will probably be watching Season 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rockos-modern-life-static-cling&#34;&gt;Rocko&amp;rsquo;s Modern Life: Static Cling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix tried to bring Rocko into the modern era, although strangely none of the characters have aged at all. Although they are cartoon characters so I guess that makes sense? The special is about as ridiculous as the old cartoon was, unsurprisingly, although it does try to convey a message about how change is an inevitable part of life. I did like that they had a reference to my favorite episode, R-E-C-Y-C-L-E Recycle~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More next month! Maybe!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: June and July 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/watching-lately-june-and-july-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/watching-lately-june-and-july-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I was travelling for most of the past two months, so this covers both June and July, and I guess I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to watch too much. Maybe? IDK, we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was in the US, I took the opportunity to finish watching &lt;strong&gt;Voltron: Legendary Defender&lt;/strong&gt; which only had two seasons available on PH Netflix. Pretty good adaptation, lots of fun callbacks to the old series. Some annoying filler eps, especially in the middle seasons onwards. I like how they spent the entire series going through the main Voltron villains one by one: first Zarkon, then Lotor, then a little bit of Sendak, then finally Hagar. It got a bit too hocus pocus magicky BS near the finale for me, but overall a pretty good watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were staying with relatives in the US, it turns out they&amp;rsquo;re really fond of watching Filipino movies. I&amp;rsquo;m not big on Filipino movies, most of them seem either uninspired, formulaic or outright ridiculous. I did enjoy a couple of the ones that I sat through, at least enough to comment on them, coincidentally both starring Eddie Garcia (RIP). The first one was &lt;strong&gt;Rainbow&amp;rsquo;s Sunset&lt;/strong&gt;, which has Eddie Garcia playing a senior citizen ex-politician who comes out as gay and explores the repurcussions to his children and grandchildren. This movie had a strange ending that came out of nowhere though. The second movie was &lt;strong&gt;Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Waiting&lt;/strong&gt; where Garcia portrays an old man who has died and finds himself in a waiting area before he can be sent to heaven, basically purgatory. In this place he finds an old flame of his from his youth, who has secretly been waiting for him all this time, refusing to advance to heaven. The movie explores themes of life and death and love and regret and commitment, but in a context outside of the typical Filipino love team movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a bunch of other Netflix movies watched - these folks didn&amp;rsquo;t have that much to do at home - but the only other one I remember sitting through was &lt;strong&gt;Murder Mystery&lt;/strong&gt; starring Adam Sandler and Jennifer Aniston. Basically a comedic whodunnit, it was entertaining enough to sit through, but nothing too special. I did like the car chase scene at the end though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from watching on Netflix, I also tried out an American cinema and watched &lt;strong&gt;Spider-man Far From Home&lt;/strong&gt; with a friend. I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/&#34;&gt;separate blog post&lt;/a&gt; for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murder Mystery might not have been too special, but it did inspire me to watch the copy I had of &lt;strong&gt;Murder on the Orient Express&lt;/strong&gt; when I got back home. It was my first exposure to Hercule Poirot, and I was pleasantly surprised by the star-studded cast. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of movie where you can&amp;rsquo;t watch it twice though; I suppose all whodunits are like that, but now I can&amp;rsquo;t watch the older movie based on this book. There&amp;rsquo;s supposedly a sequel coming out next year, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll watch that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the trip, there was a whole lot of shows to catch up on. The only one I managed to complete was &lt;strong&gt;Jessica Jones S3&lt;/strong&gt;, the final season among the erstwhile Netflix-Marvel shows. I liked this season, mostly because it went way more dark than I expected and had a very &amp;ldquo;Criminal Minds&amp;rdquo;/procedural kind of vibe since her main antagonist here was a serial killer, and one of the themes is how a hero has to play by the rules and can&amp;rsquo;t just do whatever he wants like killing criminals. (This kind of message always resonates with me now because of where the country is.) While I feel like it might have been better to cap the Netflix-Marvel venture with Daredevil&amp;rsquo;s fantastic season 3, this one isn&amp;rsquo;t a bad ending either. I suspect I will do a more detailed look back on these shows soonish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I have a ton of shows to catch up on. Good Omens, Stranger Things, Doom Patrol, Legion, etc to name a few. And I missed out on a few movies though, like Dark Phoenix, which I was tempted to watch in the cinema despite the bad reviews, because I&amp;rsquo;ve never missed any of the prior X-Men movies, not even Wolverine Origins. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have time to catch up on all of this stuff before the Fall TV season comes in!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>A Look Back at the Marvel Cinematic Universe
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/a-look-back-at-the-marvel-cinematic-universe/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/a-look-back-at-the-marvel-cinematic-universe/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I know I already made a &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/04/more-thoughts-on-avengers-endgame-and-the-mcu/&#34;&gt;whole post about the MCU after Endgame came out&lt;/a&gt;, but after the MCU Phase 4 announcements this past weekend at SDCC I was a bit hyped. I thought it would be fun to look back at the past 10 years of MCU Phase 1-3 and see what I wrote about the movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iron Man (2008)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, I had written nothing about watching this film at all, and I don&amp;rsquo;t remember going to the cinema to watch it. The movie came out between Batman Begins and The Dark Knight, so my hype was undeniably towards the Batman movies back then. Before the MCU, Iron Man was a B-list hero at best, and back then no one could ever have imagined how far the MCU would go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Incredible Hulk (2008)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/06/movies-june-2008/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Movies &amp;ndash; June 2008&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edward Norton is cast brilliantly here, a choice on the same level as Robert Downey Jr as Iron Man. And they addressed the issue of Hulks stretchy pants!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iron Man 2 (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took them 2 years to get to a 2nd movie. They probably weren&amp;rsquo;t prepared for how well received Iron Man was!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I have for this movie is &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/13253318934&#34;&gt;from a tweet&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iron Man 2 was okay, but it was pretty much more of the same. Therefore it does not wow as much as the first movie did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thor (2011)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any notes about this movie either. Well, except that I thought it &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/82967835080527872&#34;&gt;was better than Green Lantern&lt;/a&gt; (an understatement). I do remember being impressed visually by the Asgard set-pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain America the First Avenger (2011)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/96637161473966080&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain America was fine. Definitely better than Thor/Green Lantern&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I started ranking them around this time, although maintaing an overall ranking was pretty much impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers (2012)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/195064455208501248&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avengers was very enjoyable, funny and action-packed. Re-reading Ultimates v1 now lol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I had more to say, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in the habit yet of more detailed reviews back then. On to phase two!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iron Man 3 (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/328877325867446273&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#IronMan3 It was ok. Not as great as some people have said, but probably better than 2. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alvinjtang&#34;&gt;@alvinjtang&lt;/a&gt; says it&amp;rsquo;ll look worse in a few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thor The Dark World (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/396176381819621376&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thor2 was okay, I like it more than Iron Man 3, mostly because I like the Star Wars x High Fantasy style&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thor2 is generally considered one of the lowest-ranked movies of the MCU, but as a comic book fan I&amp;rsquo;m very forgiving and I guess this means I generally liked all of them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain America Winter Solider (2014)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/449064262581768192&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cap America 2 snap judgment: fun movie, better than Iron Man 3/Thor 2. Great for comic fans!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, an understatement, as I would later go on to consider Winter Soldier possibly my favorite MCU movie of all time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also said in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10152883332768912&#34;&gt;a Facebook post&lt;/a&gt; that the movie would have been perfect if he had only done Final Justice lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy (2014)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10153122948543912&#34;&gt;Facebook post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guardians was a very funny and fun movie, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to say best Marvel movie so far, since I really liked Winter Soldier. And as a comic fan, I&amp;rsquo;m not that fond of how the Nova Corps was portrayed; I guess it&amp;rsquo;s understandable since they&amp;rsquo;re not the heroes here. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of stuff for comic fans to enjoy though&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014 was a great year for the MCU, as both of these movies are among my MCU favorites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Age of Ultron (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10153724990238912&#34;&gt;Facebook post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler-free Age of Ultron review: It&amp;rsquo;s great, go watch it. I loved it. I wish there had been less content made available ahead of time through trailers and casting announcements, but such are the times we live in. It is a good time to be a comic book fan. There is a short mid-credits scene. There is no post-credits scene&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was around this time that I started doing &amp;ldquo;spoiler-free reviews&amp;rdquo;. I also posted &lt;a href=&#34;http://nedstarkdies.com/avengers-age-of-ultron-by-hunter/&#34;&gt;a more detailed AoU review over on Nedstarkdies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ant Man (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10153946370273912&#34;&gt;Facebook post&lt;/a&gt; again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ant Man spoiler-free review: The first half felt a bit off, with some exposition coming off as forced and the pacing a bit awkward. Things picked up later on and while the plot was not entirely unpredictable there were a number of fun and surprising tangents. Overall a fun and entertaining movie with enough stuff for comic book Marvel fans to enjoy, probably close in quality to the first Iron Man movie, if not better&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized just now that both Ant Man movies have been used as a palate cleanser after an Avengers film. This first one also marked the end of phase two. On to phase three!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain America Civil War (2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10154562419893912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain America Civil War spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;great fight sequences, start to finish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the newcomers were great, airport big fight sequence had a great surprise (and not the one you already saw in the trailer - although you might have already been spoiled if you pay attention to certain toy lines), although I feel like a couple of the characters were pulled in to the conflict in a way that was a bit weak, but it&amp;rsquo;s still pretty good overall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the plot was ok. Justification for the civil war was ok. Some surprises. The villain motivation was slightly mediocre, but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t really the focus of the movie anyway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martin Freeman&amp;rsquo;s role felt totally superfluous - it did not seem necessary to cast Martin Freeman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie kind of ends with the MCU and the Avengers in a weird place, some people might not like it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better than: Winter Soldier. The plot kind of develops in the same way but everything is on a much bigger scale now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are two post-credit scenes, one in the middle and one at the very end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imax worth it? Probably. Not very ostentatious use of 3d, but most of the fight sequences have it. You might get dizzy if you&amp;rsquo;re not used to it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama? Maybe, but I&amp;rsquo;d have to keep explaining who these characters are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started doing this format of &amp;ldquo;Spoiler-free reviews&amp;rdquo; around this time, with what would turn out to be the well-loved &amp;ldquo;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama?&amp;rdquo; (Translation: Will Mama like it?) section. When I tried removing this section at some point, people complained lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Strange (2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10155041890913912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wow. Great visuals and fight-scenes, very trippy. Possibly the best fight scenes in all the MCU movies so far. You might get dizzy with all the things spinning around though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plot is typical of a MCU origin story. Hero&amp;rsquo;s journey, some light comedy bits, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was expecting them to go a different way with Mordo (if you&amp;rsquo;ve read the comics you know what I mean), but I&amp;rsquo;m happy with how things went down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stakes are high, but failure is not final&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The actors were great; I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen a lead this good for a role since RDJ&amp;rsquo;s Tony Stark. Swinton&amp;rsquo;s Ancient One, Eijofor&amp;rsquo;s Mordo, and even Wong&amp;rsquo;s Wong were great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doctor friends: Tell me if the medical parts were BS hohoho&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Probably not. She doesn&amp;rsquo;t like this kind of thing, and the dizziness thing is bad too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMAX or not? I think the 3d parts weren&amp;rsquo;t too exaggerated or critical, but the visuals might feel a bit flat and not as impressive if you don&amp;rsquo;t go IMAX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Midcredits scene? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postcredits scene? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy vol 2 (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10155588909688912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;overall a very entertaining movie to sit down and watch popcorn and to enjoy the jokes and the space battles and the different colored lights and the tiny adorable tree creature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GOTG&amp;rsquo;s humor was one of its strong points and for the 2nd movie, they push the comedy up a notch, perhaps a little too much in some places. Lots of funny gags and one-liners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt like some of the character/background development stuff was pushed a bit too hard as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie&amp;rsquo;s plot also felt a bit thin and straightforward. I mean, you could see some of the major plot points coming a mile away. Maybe from the trailers even&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Lord was ok. Gamora/Nebula felt poorly written. Rocket was a bit annoying. Drax and Mantis were ok, although the space they have for Mantis&amp;rsquo; character overlaps with Drax a bit.. I&amp;rsquo;m still not super happy with how Drax and Gamora are characterized in the MCU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m less happy with this movie&amp;rsquo;s soundtrack compared to the first one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Certainly not. In fact, she chose to derp around the mall instead of coming with me and my cousin to watch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMAX or not: Some visuals used the 3d effect, but nothing too exaggerated or critical. I&amp;rsquo;d say IMAX optional, but it definitely adds something to some scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are five extra scenes near the credits (one of them is right before the credits roll, so I can&amp;rsquo;t really say &amp;ldquo;post-credit&amp;rdquo; screens). Most of them are just setting the tone for the inevitable GOTG3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, just pay attention to the background of the credits roll as well, it&amp;rsquo;s great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I felt the movie was ok, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of just more of the same of what we got with the first movie, which felt a lot stronger overall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spider-man Homecoming (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10155834066513912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This movie is amazing. Possibly best in all MCU so far. It&amp;rsquo;s fun, it&amp;rsquo;s exciting, unexpected things happened. Maybe not watching the trailers helped lol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Covers a lot of ground the previous Spider-man movies didn&amp;rsquo;t. Helped along by not needing to rehash the origin story for the Nth time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of great call outs for the comic book fans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was worried about the Vulture, but it was handled very well. Keaton is great here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This movie is tightly coupled to the MCU yo. IDK how they&amp;rsquo;re going to handle it if Sony breaks it off after the two-movie deal. By they I mean Sony. Obviously MCU can just ignore him forever afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TBH I was also really worried about the MCU coupling and having too much Iron Man in the movie, but it turned out okay. Maybe could have had a little bit less Tony Stark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMAX? Probably not worth it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s a mid-credits scene and a post-credits scene.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama? Possibly! There&amp;rsquo;s some shaky cam footage near the start that can be a bit nauseating though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That first line is high praise lol. Around this time I started avoiding watching more than the first trailer for the MCU movies, as I always felt like they gave too many jokes and plot points away. I will certainly watch them anyway, so there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much point building up more hype than I needed to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thor Ragnarok (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10156133009878912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a fun, action-packed romp that shakes up the Thor status quo significantly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easily the best of the three Thor movies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a number plot points are fairly predictable, yet still fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Marvel formula is generally action mixed with witty banter here and there, and it&amp;rsquo;s what we get here, although some of the jokes feel like they&amp;rsquo;re stretched a bit too much&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some great-looking cinematic scenes here and there. One particular flashback scene looked really great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I kind of like how the older franchises need to be some sort of team effort nowadays. Like Civil War, this felt a bit like some kind of mini-Avengers crossover &amp;ndash; in space!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;speaking of space, one of the positive things about this installment is that they didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the need to tie Thor&amp;rsquo;s adventures to Earth anymore (not that the movie is 100% Earth-free), and they get to go a bit wild with space and aliens and all that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand the need to highlight Hulk&amp;rsquo;s involvement as part of the film&amp;rsquo;s marketing, but man, it would have been so awesome to just find out right then and there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This movie had that Star Wars: Last Jedi trailer I was trying to avoid D:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 mid-credits scene and 1 post-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think Imax was good for this movie. The 3d wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much and it definitely made some scenes pop. The film is a visual delight so I think the larger screen is important too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Probably not. Maybe I should stop including this section kasi parang same na parati ang answer. Unless for some reason I decide to watch some Tagalog romcom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damn Thor 3 was great. Looking forward to Love and Thunder!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black Panther (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10156423012653912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s a fun, action-filled romp and Wakanda is amazing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tchalla was ok, killmonger and nakia were great, shuri was badass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some of the actions scenes didnt seem too well-shot/edited, making them hard to follow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I realize I&amp;rsquo;m saying this about a universe where there are talking raccoons and magic hammers, but some of the Wakandan tech push the boundaries of my suspension of disbelief&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my expectations were probably set a bit too high what with some people saying it&amp;rsquo;s the best MCU movie since Iron Man or calling it revolutionary or eye-opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;off the top of my head I&amp;rsquo;d say I consider Civil War, Spider-Man Homecoming and Thor Ragnarok better than this one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand that it&amp;rsquo;s revolutionary in the sense that it&amp;rsquo;s a major hollowood motion picture filled with a cast of mostly african descent and that some of the characters are motivated by real world racial issues. But the plot itself was typical for an MCU first movie (maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve seen too many MCU movies? lol). I dont think it presents the issues it covers under any new or revolutionary context. I guess I kind of went in hoping to be impressed on the level of The Dark Knight or such, but I was disappointed in that regard. It&amp;rsquo;s a very straightforward movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t watch in Imax, which I kind of regret, as I can imagine some of the scenes being pretty good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Possibly, pero baka mahirapan sya intindihin accent ni Chadwick Boseman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a mid-credits scene and a post-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers Infinity War (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10156599221698912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m amazed that so little of this movie has been widely spoiled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movie was fantastic. the movie somehow managed to do everything it needed to do while not doing disservice to any of the bazillion characters involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the plot moves quickly. there is no good time to pee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is one post-credits scene.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;very happy to have watched in imax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ant Man and the Wasp (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10156749941023912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this movie is great; it&amp;rsquo;s fun and and action-packed and there&amp;rsquo;s even more Luis than you thought you wanted; go watch it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s like the first movie, except better and more fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;best new character: FBI Agent Jimmy Woo played by Randall Park (sorry Michelle Pfeifer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are two mid/post-credit scenes. One of them is better than the other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watched in Imax. Some scenes were nice, but it&amp;rsquo;s probably more of a nice-to-have&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Pwede, but kelangan ng kasama to explain things. Baka ok lang pag tagalized na sa tv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain Marvel (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around this time, I started &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/183266384975/captain-marvel-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;posting the reviews to Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movie was pretty good, no major issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doesnt follow the typical MCU origin story formula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some weird pacing issues in a few places, but that just might be because of the chosen story direction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lots of little call-outs and tie-ins to the other MCU movies (although I feel like they could have done a bit more in some spots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am not a cat person. But if you are a cat person, you might like this: there is a cat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theres some parts that made it obvious they were aiming for that Wonder Woman audience, so the movie may be better for you if youre in that demo (but I think WW was a better movie overall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imax was pretty good, nothing too excessive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Midcredits scene, and postcredits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni mama? Possibly! Also, its a good idea to bring little girls to watch this movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers Endgame (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read my review &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/more-thoughts-on-avengers-endgame-and-the-mcu/&#34;&gt;right here on this blog&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spider-man Far From Home (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read my review &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/&#34;&gt;right here on this blog&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was a fun walk through a decade of films, and it gave me an opportunity to fold some of my off-blog content back into this blog. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to be doing more movie reviews directly here on this blog instead of just on Facebook or Tumblr. Looking forward to more MCU in the years (decades?) to come!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Spider-Man Far From Home
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;First, the spoiler-free review, then more spoilery stuff afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watched Far From Home while I was&amp;hellip; far from home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;great movie, lots of fun, and the stakes are a lot higher than the Vulture just stealing some tech off Tony Stark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basically a story of Peter Parker the high school student trying to juggle his Spider-Man problems with his high school life, which was one of the best eras of comic book Spider-Man&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie gives us a look at what the world looks like post-Endgame and how weird it is for everyone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you&amp;rsquo;ve seen the trailers, you know who the &amp;ldquo;villain&amp;rdquo; is and you have certain expectations coming in. I was worried this would be a problem but it worked out fine, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a problem and was handled well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a mid-credits scene, possibly one of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, in terms of how it changes the entire tone of the movie. There is also a post-credits scene, the implications of which are still unclear and will leave the fanbase speculating for a while&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Possibly! There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of &amp;ldquo;cute&amp;rdquo; Peter Parker high school moments she&amp;rsquo;d probably like, and the plot and action aren&amp;rsquo;t too hard to follow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoilery stuff follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how could Midtown High afford to send their trivia team on a trip through Europe? Is this typical of American high schools?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As mentioned above, anyone even remotely familiar with Spider-Man lore wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised at the reveal that Mysterio is actually a villain. This is one of those times where there would have been some advantage to not knowing stuff ahead of time, as you get to enjoy the reveal. That being said, Mysterio&amp;rsquo;s villain monologue after getting the EDITH glasses may be one of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. Since I already knew Mysterio was a bad guy, the only realy mystery was HOW he was doing these destructive elementals since they obviously weren&amp;rsquo;t the simple light-and-sound shows that comics Mysterio was known for. Tying the illusions to the BARF holograms and even re-using side characters from previous movies was an inspired choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the rest of the movie&amp;rsquo;s plot was fairly predictable, but the MCU continues to subvert the expectations of Spider-Man fans since both Peter Parker and the supporting cast are completely different from the comicbook incarnations, powers notwithstanding. I assume they planned as far back as Homecoming that Tony would be dying in Endgame and Peter would be pressured to take the mantle, setting Tony up as his father figure instead of the mythical Uncle Ben. Zendaya&amp;rsquo;s MJ is completely different from the comics&amp;rsquo; Mary Jane &amp;ldquo;Hey tiger&amp;rdquo; Watson; Flash is a nerd like Peter instead of a footballer; Ned isn&amp;rsquo;t even based on a Peter supporting character but on a Miles supporting character, and so on. This is basically a completely different version of Peter&amp;rsquo;s HS life and it&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that first Mysterio vs Spider-Man scene was great, evocative of the comic book version and even Arkham Asylum&amp;rsquo;s Scarecrow sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the whole Peter/MJ/Brad Davis subplot gives the movie a bit of a &amp;ldquo;John Hughes&amp;rdquo; vibe and there are some cute moments and MJ really holds her own; I think this movie handles the whole &amp;ldquo;dual identity problems&amp;rdquo; aspect of Spider-man better than Homecoming did&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that webswinging sequence at the end of the movie was great, has the same feel as the PS4 game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the midcredits scene completely changes the tone of the ending of course. But first, we must acknowledge the awesome return of the one true J. Jonah Jameson, JK Simmons! The unmasking is a problem, and how will they handle it? Will Peter and May have to go into hiding at an Avengers facility? Will the bad guys come after them? WIll Peter have to make a deal with Mephisto to protect his secret in exchange for getting the worst prom ever with MJ? Or will they go some other route like have one of the Skrulls pose as Peter and appear together with Spider-man? The great thing about MCU Spider-Man is that because the setup is completely different, they&amp;rsquo;re not beholden to the comic book plots (neither Homecoming nor Far From Home are based on actual comic stories AFAIK). This ending also mirrors Homecoming&amp;rsquo;s unmasking in front of Aunt May, so my guess is that they&amp;rsquo;ll handle this cliffhanger the same way - completely off screen and we just see the repurcussions in the next movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the final postcredits scene will have fans speculating for a while, but it looks like Fury is busy setting up SWORD? Or could it be something else?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great movie, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to Marvel hopefully announcing their Phase 4 plans at SDCC later this month!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>