<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>movies on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/movies/</link>
      <description>Recent content in movies on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 07:28:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/movies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1381509474259673090/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 07:28:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/1381509474259673090/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Needed something light to watch in the background, so I watched Airplane! (1980). It&amp;rsquo;s the kind of movie where they just stuff in as many gags as possible, every throwaway line and even stuff happening in the background is a gag.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Zack Snyder&#39;s Justice League (aka The Snyder Cut) review
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/zack-snyders-justice-league-aka-the-snyder-cut-review/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 06:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/zack-snyders-justice-league-aka-the-snyder-cut-review/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;See also: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/11/931540341919965184/&#34;&gt;Justice League spoiler-free review (2017)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is basically a movie that&amp;rsquo;s more than 3 years old, we&amp;rsquo;re not holding back on spoilers here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;plot basically follows the same beats as the theatrical cut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;except this time we have a lot more team setup time (one of my criticisms from the previous version), giving the characters stronger backgrounds, especially Cyborg and Flash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ray Fisher was right to complain; in this version he&amp;rsquo;s one of the important characters of the ensemble while he was basically a minor guest character in the theatrical cut&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more DC characters make appearances in this version, among them Ryan Choi, DeSaad, Granny Goodness, Martian Manhunter, the Joker and of course Darkseid himself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I accept this version as a better version of the original theatrical release and is my new DCEU headcanon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it never would have worked in theaters anyway, given the four hour runtime. Maybe if they split it into two movies&amp;hellip; (and I actually did take two sittings to watch this one!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anyway, this version does a much better job of setting up any succeeding movies, including the upcoming Flash movie (although I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if the changes cause any continuity issues with the 2019 Aquaman movie&amp;hellip; not that the DCEU cares too much about continuity anyway&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350361902149324800/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 08:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350361902149324800/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;2021 #movies no 2: The Godfather part 2 (1974). This is two movies rolled into one. Still pretty good, but I think I liked the singular focus of the first one more.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;I created a Netflix (34 countries) search site with lists, filters and sort.&#39; on /r/movies at https://reddit.com/r/movies/comments/g760e3/i_created_a_netflix_34_countries_search_site_with/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/fog070h/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 16:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/fog070h/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;I created a Netflix (34 countries) search site with lists, filters and sort.&amp;#39; on /r/movies at https://reddit.com/r/movies/comments/g760e3/i_created_a_netflix_34_countries_search_site_with/:

            &lt;p&gt;Does Netflix have an open API? I remember looking around for it before but couldnt find any details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also any chance you could also serve rss feeds for new netflix shows/movies added per country?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Birds of Prey and the Fantabulous Emancipation of One Harley Quinn spoiler-free review!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/birds-of-prey/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 21:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/birds-of-prey/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;(Too late for the theatrical release, but it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;tradition&lt;/a&gt; for comic book movies, so here we are.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall: Totally watchable, maybe slightly better than Suicide Squad for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Somehow still fits into some kind of DCEU continuity (after &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/10154796013953912/&#34;&gt;Suicide Squad&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie is really centered around Harley, to the detriment of the other characters. I can understand why they titled it the way they did, and I can appreciate the effort to have Harley carry a Birds of Prey introduction to the masses. But I think it could have worked a lot better titled and marketed strictly as a Harley-centric movie that happens to set up an eventual Birds of Prey follow-up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this one has a lot more Harley flavor than SS though: bright colors, gratuitous violence and so on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Margot Robbie performs well, and she kind of has to as she&amp;rsquo;s carrying the movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ewan McGregor&amp;rsquo;s Roman Sionis/Black Mask is a great performance as well, although he is characterized as little more than psychopathic gang boss rather than anything specifically related to the comic book character&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dinah Lance/Black Canary probably second-best characterization and plot beats out of the main cast (that&amp;rsquo;s not saying much), and has some great fights. Jurnee Smollett-Bell gives a decent performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rosie Perez&amp;rsquo;s Renee Montoya is described as someone out of an 80s cop movie, and she very much reminds me of Roger Murtaugh (of Lethal Weapon fame), which I suppose is what they were going for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huntress origins are comic book accurate, but Mary Elizabeth Winstead has very little to work with beyond that, and her character is kind of given a slapstick treatment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cassandra Cain is one of my favorite comic book characters. Unfortunately in this movie she is little more than a plot device&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is no mid/post credits scene, although there is a little bit of a gag to taunt people who wait til the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni mama? No!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately, Feb 2020 - Not Much Apparently
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/watching-lately/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/watching-lately/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;2020 Movies&lt;/a&gt; update: 7 movies watched in Feb. Probably the best movie I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this month was &lt;strong&gt;Knives Out&lt;/strong&gt;. (&lt;strong&gt;Jojo Rabbit&lt;/strong&gt; close second.) The goal of 200 movies for the year is getting farther!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for TV, I think most of my watching time was spent rewatching &lt;strong&gt;Rick and Morty&lt;/strong&gt; for quiz purposes lol. Well, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/criminal-minds/&#34;&gt;Criminal Minds&lt;/a&gt; ended, so there&amp;rsquo;s that. Arrowverse has been meh, though I did enjoy &lt;strong&gt;Supergirl&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;s 100th episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hm, I guess I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually watched a lot of stuff in the past month. There&amp;rsquo;s a ton of stuff that I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to watch but haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to: The Expanse, Star Trek Picard, new season of Jack Ryan, Birds of Prey/Harley Quinn, and so on. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if things get better next month maybe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus, since this entry was kinda short: Here&amp;rsquo;s three movies I started watching but didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to finish:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/strong&gt;. It started off with like 20 minutes of some monkeys shouting at each other and a mysterious black box and I kind of lost interest. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that kind of thing was fine in 1968 when the movie came out and the people whose butts were already in the theatre were like &amp;ldquo;this is strange, but we&amp;rsquo;re already here, so we might as well sit through it&amp;rdquo;, but it&amp;rsquo;s 2020, I kind of need something to hold my internet-broken attention span more easily. It&amp;rsquo;s also one of the most renowned and highly-praised movies of all time, so I&amp;rsquo;m probably losing something here. Will try to resume it sometime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Conjuring&lt;/strong&gt;. We have a horror-movie themed quiz category coming up so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d watch a horror movie. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve voluntarily done so since having been mentally scarred by &lt;strong&gt;The Gate (1987)&lt;/strong&gt; as a kid. I picked The Conjuring, it was first on Netflix&amp;rsquo;s list of horror movies. I sat through the appropriately-creepy intro, then one of my quiz teammates told me he&amp;rsquo;d already unwillingly seen it before and couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep for a week after, and I was like &amp;ldquo;You just gave me an excuse not to watch it.&amp;rdquo; so I stopped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carrie (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to give up on horror movies just yet, so I picked another title from Netflix. I chose this one because it had Hit-Girl. It started out with typical teenage bullying stuff before she manifested her mutant powers and after that I kept thinking they needed to contact Professor Xavier, and couldn&amp;rsquo;t take it seriously after that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1225826359177465861/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 16:59:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1225826359177465861/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;2020 #movies 17: Uncut Gems. &amp;ldquo;Sandler gave a good performance, but I struggled to get through the early parts of the movies because his character and situation are so unrelatable to me personally.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;https://roytang.net/lists/2020/movies/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately, Jan 2020: Arrow, The Good Place, The Witcher, Kim&#39;s Convenience, The Expanse
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/watching-lately/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/watching-lately/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if I should continue this &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately&#34;&gt;watching-lately&lt;/a&gt; series since I already set up a separate page for &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/lists/2020/movies&#34;&gt;listing my 2020 movies watched&lt;/a&gt;. It might have been more consistent to have a list for the 2020 TV shows also? But then again, TV shows are a much different beast, since each show/season is broken into an episode and sometimes you watch them all in one go or sometimes over the span of a few months. So maybe let&amp;rsquo;s keep this going for the while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, movies. From the list for January, I think the best one was Parasite. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any expectations on what this movie was about yet somehow I still feel like it subverted those expectations anyway. I only saw 15 movies in January, which is below rate if I&amp;rsquo;m targetting 200 for the year. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s one of those NYR things that peters out after a month or so. Too early to tell, and besides, that&amp;rsquo;s not an insurmountable deficit. And 200 isn&amp;rsquo;t a hard target either so let&amp;rsquo;s just see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the realm of TV, this kind of explains why my movie-watching trailed off in the second half of the month, since the regular TV series started coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/arrowverse-crisis-on-infinite-earths/&#34;&gt;wrote about the Arrowverse crossover&lt;/a&gt; when the back half aired. This month the last two episodes of Arrow aired. The first one was a backdoor pilot for a new spinoff series, Green Arrow and the Canaries, starring Mia Queen. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what to think about the spinoff or whether I&amp;rsquo;ll even try it out. The whole time travel thing seems so convoluted as a way to bring Mia, E2 Laurel and Dinah together. The second episode was the series finale, basically a retrospective on the entire series. They pulled out all the stops, bringing back supporting characters from all 8 seasons of the show (Except for Malcolm Merlyn, apparently John Barrowman was busy reappearing in a different series), and even surrendering to some long-time fan wishes such as Digg picking up a mysterious green object dropped from space. In spite of all my complaints about the poor writing on this show (and the related ones) through the years, I will admit the finale was pretty good and they stuck the landing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the rest of the Arrowverse, some comments that I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where else I can post, mostly on the post-crisis set up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently in the rebooted universe, there was still a multiverse (since E2 Laurel exists, and doppelgangers showed up in Supergirl), but then the other universes were destroyed in a crisis (probably similar but different than the one we actually watched.) This is totally different from the &amp;ldquo;it became one universe from the very start&amp;rdquo; ending of the original CoIE and took away from the crossover a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was mildly annoyed when Jonn turned out to be able to restore pre-crisis memories. This only makes sense if what he&amp;rsquo;s restoring are part of his own memories, but not events he never knew about, otherwise, where did those pre-crisis memories come from? This annoyance was exacerbated by the GAatC backdoor pilot introducing a &amp;ldquo;device made by Cisco that replicates&amp;rdquo; Jonn&amp;rsquo;s powers so now anyone can restore pre-crisis memories, even from people Jonn has never met like future JJ. And in the Arrow finale, it seemed like everyone at the funeral was aware of the previous universe, did Jonn reset them too?? Seemed wholly unnecessary, but I suppose then we get difficult to explain things like Tommy wondering why E2 Laurel seems different&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fun fact: at Oliver&amp;rsquo;s funeral, Dinah is from before the GAatC episode (since in that episode she says she vanished after the funeral), Mia is from after that episode, and presumably so is E2 Laurel, although this isn&amp;rsquo;t explicitly specified. Timey-wimey!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Good Place&lt;/strong&gt; is also ending this week. As the time this post goes live, I will not have yet watched the season finale, but I did binge the rest of the seasons leading up to it, so maybe I can share some thoughts anyway. The Good Place was a weird series. It&amp;rsquo;s highly acclaimed and covers a lot of interesting topics philosophically, and puts its cast through a lot of interesting situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main issue with TGP is that I don&amp;rsquo;t find it particularly funny. Not like other Schur-influenced shows such as Brooklyn Nine Nine and Parks and Recreation. The characters can be charming sure and ridiculous sure. But their situations are rarely sitcom funny. I think part of it is that the situations they face are always so dire. I mean, their consequences somehow ramped up from eternal torture and damnation to the erasure of earth and all of humanity during the course of the series. Not very light-hearted topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another part of it might be the severe &lt;a href=&#34;https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/Flanderization&#34;&gt;Flanderization&lt;/a&gt; of the most of the characters. Typically this is a process that happens over the lifetime of a show, but with TGP, the characters&amp;rsquo; most annoying traits are highly focused on from the start: Eleanor is an asshole, Jason is an idiot, Tahani is a name-dropping socialite and Chidi is an anxious, undecisive philosopher. Eleanor and Chidi get a bit of character growth through the series (more Eleanor than Chidi), but Jason and Tahani are kind of still the same people by the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I like the show, but more for the questions it raises about how the afterlife could possibly work, rather than for pure comedic value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some friends somehow convinced me to watch &lt;strong&gt;Kim&amp;rsquo;s Convenience&lt;/strong&gt; (it was on NF). I have no regrets. It&amp;rsquo;s a smart, funny show about a Korean immigrant family in Canada. There were 3 seasons to binge on NF and it was very easy to side-watch since it&amp;rsquo;s a sitcom. The best character is the father of the family, a first-generation Korean immigrant who owns a convenience store (hence the show title). My only complaint is that it&amp;rsquo;s challenging my suspension of disbelief that the first generation immigrants still speak in English when among themselves, but as a friend said, it was probably for the sake of avoiding subtitles. Also, I wanted to see what the future Shang-chi actor looked like. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it kind of weird that he&amp;rsquo;s Chinese but he&amp;rsquo;s playing a Korean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A shorter series I saw on Netflix was &lt;strong&gt;The Witcher&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty good, and I much prefer Henry Cavill as Geralt in this show rather than as Superman. (Although he looks nothing like W3 Geralt). I wish I had seen this series before playing the games, as it sets up a lot of the character back stories that I kind of just accepted in the games. Looking forward to future seasons!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I managed to watch the first half of The Expanse season 3. It takes me a whole to catch up with this show because each episode is heavy and a lot of things are always happening, so it always needs my full attention. It&amp;rsquo;s so good, and it&amp;rsquo;s not like those shows where you never get any answers, things actually get resolved at a reasonable pace. One and a half more seasons to catch up on!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>My Top Tens of the 2010s
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/my-top-tens-of-the-2010s/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/my-top-tens-of-the-2010s/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Apparently I&amp;rsquo;m not done looking back at the 2010s yet. I had some &amp;ldquo;top tens of 2010s&amp;rdquo; discussions with some friends recently, here are my personal lists, each in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-top-ten-movies-of-the-2010s&#34;&gt;My Top Ten Movies of the 2010s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers Endgame (2019).&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m keeping only one slot per franchise, so I had to choose an MCU movies for this. Runner-ups for this slot were &lt;strong&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Captain America Winter Soldier&lt;/strong&gt;, and individually either one of those movies might be around the same or better than Endgame, but Endgame is the culmination of a decade&amp;rsquo;s worth of movies and gave me the most enjoyment as a comic book fan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rogue One (2016)&lt;/strong&gt;. I really liked &lt;strong&gt;The Force Awakens&lt;/strong&gt; too, but Rogue One is easily the best of the Disney Star Wars era.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interstellar (2014)&lt;/strong&gt;. The top ten discussions led to an extended debate about some of the science in this movie, all in good fun. It requires some suspension of disbelief is needed, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a pretty good sci-fi movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Martian (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;. This one was my favorite sci-fi movie of the decade though, I&amp;rsquo;ll read the book someday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inception (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;. The fact that this movie spawned so many memes and so many debates and discussions was an indication of how good it was.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man: Into The Spider-Verse (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;. The MCU was a series of great movies based on comic books, but Spider-Verse was the best movie that really feels like a comic book. (I suppose the comparison is slightly unfair since Spider-Verse has the advantage of being animated!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One Cut of the Dead (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a Japanese film I saw at Eiga-sai. If you can overcome the one-inch barrier of subtitles it&amp;rsquo;s easily one of the funniest movies I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in the past decade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logan (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;. Easily the best of Fox&amp;rsquo;s X-Men films, and among the top echelon of comic book films overall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mad Max Fury Road (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;. This was my first Mad Max film, I really enjoyed the performances and the stunts and the ridiculous vehicle scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Baby Driver (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;. Makes me want to imagine what Edgar Wright&amp;rsquo;s Ant-Man would have been like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-top-ten-tv-shows-of-the-2010s&#34;&gt;My Top Ten TV Shows of the 2010s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parks and Recreation (2009-2015)&lt;/strong&gt;. I know it started before the 2010s, but this might be appropriate anyway since the show didn&amp;rsquo;t really pick up until the third season. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of other notable comedies of its class that I really enjoyed during the last decade, such as &lt;strong&gt;30 Rock&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt;, but I tip the hat to PnR because I really like the characters of Ben Wyatt and Ron Swanson and Andy Dwyer. (Apparently I really like all the male main characters except for Tom lol)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brooklyn Nine Nine (2013-)&lt;/strong&gt;. B99 is just my kind of ridiculous, similar to PnR, super quotable, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Young Justice (2010-)&lt;/strong&gt;. Young Justice is the true successor to the excellent JL/JLU of the 00s, with a deep plot full of conspiracy and betrayal, a large cast of characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daredevil (2015-2018)&lt;/strong&gt;. The Netflix shows had great promise, and Daredevil seasons 1 and 3 were among the best of them. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad that they fell to the IP disputes of their time, but who knows maybe we get to revisit them again some time in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Who (2005-)&lt;/strong&gt;. The DW revival started in the 00s, but I only started watching it in 2012, when Matt Smith was already the Eleventh. There have been some weaker seasons and episodes, but overall I enjoyed the general campiness and sci-ifi silliness of the series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black Mirror (2011-)&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m actually still not caught up with the latest season, but I have greatly enjoyed the near-future what-ifs posed by this popular show. (It&amp;rsquo;s too bad we are unlikely to heed its warnings!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breaking Bad (2008-2013)&lt;/strong&gt;. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s generally regarded as one of the best series of all time right? I haven&amp;rsquo;t even bothered watching El Camino because for me the ending of BB was already prefect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Orville (2017-)&lt;/strong&gt;. 2017 was a great year for Star Trek (-like) content, with the more serious &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; and more lighthearted The Orville both debuting. I enjoyed both shows, but the Orville&amp;rsquo;s sci-fi sitcom brought us something a lot more unique.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game of Thrones (2011-2019)&lt;/strong&gt;. Say what you will about the quality of writing (or lack thereof) for the last couple of seasons, but this was a TV series that got people obsessed and following every episode and arguing about spoilers and forming fan theories, book readers or otherwise. It pretty much defined the decade of TV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-top-ten-games-of-the-2010s&#34;&gt;My Top Ten Games of the 2010s&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starcraft 2 (2010-2015)(PC)&lt;/strong&gt;. Got all 3 parts on release, and still playing it to this day (mostly coop missions - I don&amp;rsquo;t really have the heart for the stress of ladder matches anymore!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Last of Us (2013)(PS3)&lt;/strong&gt;. There are games where you&amp;rsquo;re saddened that you can&amp;rsquo;t play them again for the first time, and the Last of Us was one of the best of those.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild (2017)(WiiU)&lt;/strong&gt;. The defining Zelda of modern times. I loved the exploratory nature similar to the original NES LoZ and the cel-shaded graphics were fantastic. The sequel may yet convince me to get a Switch!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persona 5 (2017)(PS4)&lt;/strong&gt;. Easily the best JRPG of its era (sorry, Final Fantasy XV!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fallout: New Vegas (2010)(PC)&lt;/strong&gt;. Obsidian&amp;rsquo;s part of the Fallout franchise had much improved writing and questlines over it&amp;rsquo;s predecessor Fallout 3, good enough for multiple run throughs, and I even managed to finish all the DLCs as well!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Elder Scrolls: Skyrim (2011)(PC)&lt;/strong&gt;. I came late to this series with Oblivion in 2008, but it&amp;rsquo;s one of the few RPGs in this decade that I&amp;rsquo;ve replayed and finished multiple times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Witcher 3: The Wild Hunt (2015)(PS4)&lt;/strong&gt;. Easily the best PC RPG of the past decade, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t even played the expansions yet! Runner-up: Divinity Original Sin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultra Street Fighter IV (2014)(PS3)&lt;/strong&gt;. Technically, the base game came out in the 00s, but all the later revisions came out in the 2010s. This game started a fighting game resurgence that&amp;rsquo;s going on to this today. I was never super good at it, but I sure played a lot of hours and bought multiple copies of each version that came out even. The next version, SFV, hasn&amp;rsquo;t been as well received, but the franchise and the fighting game resurgence is still going strong up to now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eternal Card Game (2016)(Multiplat)&lt;/strong&gt;. This one is actually my most played Steam game of all time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sid Meier&amp;rsquo;s Civilization V (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;. Been playing this series since &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/ancient-pc-gaming/&#34;&gt;the olden days&lt;/a&gt;! Civ5 brought a pretty big change to the series with one unit per tile, and at 395 hours it&amp;rsquo;s still currently among my most played games on Steam. (Civ6 is about a hundred hours behind)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: December 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/watching-lately-december-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/watching-lately-december-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Been watching a lot of things this December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally got back on &lt;strong&gt;The Expanse&lt;/strong&gt; after finishing S1 more than a year ago. I only finished S2, but it was already a vast improvement over S1. S1 felt like a lot of meandering around until the characters actually ran into the plot. S2 was stronger, faster-paced, and there&amp;rsquo;s always a lot of things going on in each episode. I really like this series now, looking forward to S3 and S4 when I have the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix-wise, I enjoyed their recently-added &lt;strong&gt;Jeopardy&lt;/strong&gt; series (always a great show to have playing in the background), the new documentary &lt;strong&gt;The Movies That Made Us&lt;/strong&gt; (loved their selection of movies to feature), and the second season of &lt;strong&gt;Final Space&lt;/strong&gt; (a fun sci-fi space romp if ever there was one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of crazy sci-fi, &lt;strong&gt;Rick and Morty&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve caught up with the recently released S4 as well. This series seems a lot more self-aware now, and a lot more unafraid to make fun of tropes and genre conventions. I liked the heist episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broadcast-wise, I enjoyed the front half of the Arrowverse&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Crisis of Infinite Earths&lt;/strong&gt; crossover. It had that same feeling as Avengers Endgame where I knew what was likely to happen based on comic book knowledge, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t think they could do it, but they did it! Whenever discussion of this crossover leaked over to the mainstream TV subreddits/forums, there was a lot of criticism of how it looked so low-budget, but I think any expecations of them being able to provide Avengers-quality costumes and effects on a broadcast TV show budget are unrealistic. The Arrowverse shows certainly have a lot of flaws, but this type of multiversal crossover isn&amp;rsquo;t something that could have been achieved without all the setup of the past eight years (and even beyond, considering older shows like Smallville and 90&amp;rsquo;s Flash), and that&amp;rsquo;s something comparable to what the MCU has built, even at a fraction of the budget. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll have more words for this series and the Arrowverse in general when the back half airs in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend also somehow tricked me into watching &lt;strong&gt;Sky High&lt;/strong&gt;, a rather old and campy and totally predictable superhero-type movie. I did finish it so I guess I enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nieces were over this weekend so I finally got to watch &lt;strong&gt;Toy Story 4&lt;/strong&gt;. I was a bit skeptical that they decided to add another installment when I felt the trilogy was already pretty tight. I have to admit I was surprised with the direction this movie took and the ending it gave, which leaves an opening for future movies in the franchise, though they might already be quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;Star Wars: Rise of Skywalker&lt;/strong&gt; before Christmas, here are &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/star-wars-rise-of-skywalker-spoilers/&#34;&gt;my thoughts on the film and the trilogy&lt;/a&gt;. WHile I wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely happy with it, I did enjoy watching the film and I recognize that it was a good retelling of Star Wars for new/modern fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also rewatched &lt;strong&gt;The Last Jedi&lt;/strong&gt; for the first time about a week later, it was still pretty good, especially that third act. (Casino subquest still felt superfluous). I did come out a bit more disappointed that ROS didn&amp;rsquo;t follow through with some of the themes of TLJ. I can only assume there are a couple of alternate universes out there where both Rian Johnson&amp;rsquo;s direction and JJ Abrams direction came true for the Skywalker saga ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Star Wars, I enjoyed the ending of &lt;strong&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/strong&gt;, although it did have a couple of weaker episodes in the middle that felt like filler (or maybe just there to seed characters for the eventual second season). The final two episodes are pretty good, and we get the payoffs of actualy learning the Mandalorian&amp;rsquo;s history and all. I do find it ridiculous that the Jedi and the Force are still unknown enough that the Mandalorian has never heard of them considering it probably hasn&amp;rsquo;t even been more than 30 years since Palpatine took down the Republic, which had literally an entire council of Jedi as an advisory body to the Senate and featuring prominently in the Clone Wars. Do they not have recorded history? Lol. In any case, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to season 2 whenever it lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THat&amp;rsquo;s it for the decade!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/rise-of-skywalker/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/rise-of-skywalker/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;RISE OF SKYWALKER Spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie is fine and entertaining to watch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a Star Wars movie, so you pretty much know what to expect, space wizards and space battles and such&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pacing is frantic in the first act, and a bit in the second. Abrams has a lot of things he wants to do and limited time to do it, so things happen in rapid succession&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the third act is basically an ode to &lt;em&gt;Return of the Jedi&lt;/em&gt;, as a parallel to The Force Awakens&amp;rsquo; ode to &lt;em&gt;A New Hope&lt;/em&gt;. In fact, there is a lot of fanservice for original trilogy fans sprinkled throughout the movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is not the best ending I could have imagined for the sequel trilogy, but it is an ending&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are a few twists and turns in the movie, but because it&amp;rsquo;s Star Wars, you largely know what to expect from the overall plot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;magugustuhan ba ni Mama: The movie is generally family-friendly (outside of the violence), but my mom doesn&amp;rsquo;t like space battles and she would probably be confused by the rapid pace of events and all these characters she&amp;rsquo;s not familiar with, so no.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watched in IMAX 3D, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think there was much noticeable 3D, the movie is probably perfectly fine without IMAX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is no post-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think I liked &lt;em&gt;The Last Jedi&lt;/em&gt; more than this one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a bit more &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/star-wars-rise-of-skywalker-spoilers/&#34;&gt;spoilery comments posted here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/rise-of-skywalker/howtowatchastarwar_hu5bb634bfc9261ec532ae3490534430ee_1213904_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Comic does not reflect my viewing experience&lt;/p&gt;
    



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Star Wars: Rise of Skywalker (spoilers!)
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/star-wars-rise-of-skywalker-spoilers/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/star-wars-rise-of-skywalker-spoilers/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I watched the most recent Star Wars last night. Spoiler-free review posted &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/rise-of-skywalker/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this ended the sequel trilogy and the entire &amp;ldquo;Skywalker Saga&amp;rdquo;, I thought it deserved a bit more spoilery discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure we needed to introduce some brand new characters in the third movie that don&amp;rsquo;t even get that much buildup because there were so many other things happening, unless they were seeded here for purposes of future Star Wars movie, which is just silly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much fondness for the guy, but Hux deserved better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some great appearances here that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lando showing up in the desert planet wearing the same outfit he used as a disguise in the first act of &lt;em&gt;Return of the Jedi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Han appearing as a hallucination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wedge Antilles is still alive! And comes back with Lando and Chewie to help out during the final space battle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the parallels with &lt;em&gt;Return of the Jedi&lt;/em&gt; are glaringly obvious, especially for the third act: Rey going alone to face off against the evil emperor while the rebellion pursues a last-chance and hopeless space battle outdoors? Check. Series protagonist face turn at the last minute? Check. Lando piloting the Falcon as a general in the final space battle? Check.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the sequel trilogy really suffered from not having a single creative vision for all three movies. J.J. Abrams and Rian Johnson obviously wanted to take the franchise in two different directions, with Abrams wanting to make an homage to the original trilogy with new characters, and Johnson wanting to explore what there is outside of the original trilogy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead, Abrams has to do a strong pull back from the second film, which meant he had a whole lot more setup to do, leading to ridiculous things like a huge plot point like Palpatine&amp;rsquo;s return being introduced in the opening crawl and that messy frantic pace of a first act&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine now where else the franchise could have gone, but I would have liked to see something like:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 7 as homage to original trilogy and passing of the torch to new characters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 8 as subverting expectations and striking in a different direction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Episode 9 as defining a new kind of future for Star Wars, perhaps with more Force users, not necessarily Jedi or Sith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;instead what we get with &lt;em&gt;Rise of Skywalker&lt;/em&gt; is basically the same ending as &lt;em&gt;Return of the Jedi&lt;/em&gt;: The evil emperor is defeated (the same evil emperor at that!) and the rebellion is victorious and celebrating and now only one Jedi remains and balance exists in the force. I can understand wanting to do a modern re-telling for a new generation of fans, but we lived with that ending since 1983, it would have been nice to see something different this time. Such was not to be. (And I&amp;rsquo;m sure the mixed reaction to &lt;em&gt;Last Jedi&lt;/em&gt; had a hand in Disney deciding to be more conservative with this one)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s really weird for me that the &amp;ldquo;Skywalker Saga&amp;rdquo; ends with a new Skywalker emerging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final Skywalker saga rankings: 5-ESB &amp;gt; 4-ANH &amp;gt; 6-ROJ &amp;gt; 3.5-RO &amp;gt; 7-TFA &amp;gt; 8-TLJ == 3-RTS &amp;gt; 9-ROS &amp;gt; SOLO &amp;gt; 2-AOC &amp;gt; 1-TPM&lt;/p&gt;


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: November 2019: Broly, Justice League, Arrowverse, Mandalorian
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-nov-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-nov-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Nothing in the cinema this month (going to the cinema is expensive!). I did watch a couple of animated movies this month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dragonball Super: Broly. I have some vague recollection of watching the original Broly movie, and I believe this one is much better. DBS Broly is a slightly more nuanced character than just &amp;ldquo;random raging monster&amp;rdquo; from the previous non-canon movie. The animation was okay, you could tell the animators were having fun with some of the battle parts. Also, I watched the English dub, and I just realized Goku&amp;rsquo;s voice is super annoying, so I pity the Americans who had to grow up with that voice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Justice League vs the Fatal Five. I&amp;rsquo;m still a bit behind on the DC animated stuff. I liked this one because I think it handled Jessica Cruz fairly well, and it got me backreading Justice League Odyssey for more Cruz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, since I got a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/new-video-card/&#34;&gt;new video card&lt;/a&gt; and have a second monitor again, side-watching is back on the menu, so I was able to catch up with some of the ongoing series: Modern Family (meh), Simpsons (meh), Rick and Morty (ok so far, only 3 eps in).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caught Season 3 of The Toys That Made Us on Netflix. Not as fun as S2 for me since that one had Transformers, and I only have secondary interest at best in the toylines for S4, but some of the stories here were pretty interesting, like they say that the giant robot from Japanese Spider-Man was the one that inspired sentai robots! What! The TMNT ep was also pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrowverse is still going on (somehow), with their upcoming big-deal Crisis crossover kicking off in mid December. Surprisingly, Arrow itself has been pretty good this season (perhaps because no Felicity? lol), followed by Flash, with Supergirl dead last. I am not fond of Lena&amp;rsquo;s heel turn in Supergirl, I felt like it was a disservice to the character who when introduced was desperate to get out of her brother&amp;rsquo;s shadow. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been watching Batwoman, even though it&amp;rsquo;s part of the crossover, we&amp;rsquo;ll see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to watch the first ep of Mandalorian, but haven&amp;rsquo;t had time yet for the most recent eps. It&amp;rsquo;s not the sort of thing I&amp;rsquo;d side-watch, so I have to dedicate time for it. I better do that before the spoilers catch up with me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next month I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crisis on Infinite Earths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Wars: Rise of the Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-nov-2019/broly_hu4d06564a23f2e71ac7d3766ad33b0777_2995425_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: October 2019: Joker, Scorsese, Stuber, Bloodlines, Brotherhood
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-oct-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-oct-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Actually watched something in the cinema this month: &lt;strong&gt;Joker&lt;/strong&gt;. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t originally sure if I wanted to see it, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t hyped for it at all in the months prior. But as the showing date came nearer, there was a lot of buzz around it so I decided to go anyway. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like it lived up to the hype and the warnings about promoting incel stuff, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s one of the higher-grossing DC movies, so maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll have more to come in that vein. MCU movies all have kind of same-y tone and feel, so probably DC can differentiate itself by doing these heavier movies with a different kind of style. My spoiler-free review of this movie is &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/10/1180086308963618816/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching Joker and also reading Scorsese recent comments about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/film/2019/oct/04/martin-scorsese-says-marvel-movies-are-not-cinema&#34;&gt;MCU movies not really being cinema&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to watch one of his movies and decided on &lt;strong&gt;Goodfellas&lt;/strong&gt;. (The only other one I had seen prior to this was &lt;em&gt;Shutter Island&lt;/em&gt;, which for a long while I thought was a Nolan flick.) Goodfellas was pretty good, definitely nothing like an MCU movie. They are obviously different kinds of &amp;ldquo;cinema&amp;rdquo; altogether, with the MCU movies leaning more towards the &amp;ldquo;popcorn&amp;rdquo; side of the spectrum. I did find it a bit hard to take Joe Pesci seriously here since I only really knew him from &lt;em&gt;Home Alone&lt;/em&gt;. I believe this is also the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen Ray Liotta in a film, so now I know who he is. I definitely enjoyed the &amp;ldquo;slice-of-life&amp;rdquo; look into the old-school gangster lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also watched &lt;strong&gt;Stuber&lt;/strong&gt;, mostly because this movie kept being advertised when I was in the US and it reminded me of Deadpool and that taxi driver friend of his. I was only expecting Batista, but Karen Gillan is also here (briefly!), so there&amp;rsquo;s a tiny GotG reunion there. Indian taxi driver dude was cool, the movie was ok, moderately funny, nothing too genre-busting. More popcorn movies for scorsese to snub his nose at, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catching up on my backlog of DC animated films, I decided to watch &lt;strong&gt;Wonder Woman: Bloodlines&lt;/strong&gt;. Plot spoilers, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a gaggle of WW villains (Silver Swan, Doctor Poison, Doctor Cyber, Cheetah, Giganta) plotting to invade Themyscira, I suspect to make them more well-known among the DC animated viewers. Coincidentally, I had also recently read the WW Rebirth story arc where a gaggle of WW villains tried to trick her into revealing the location of Themyscira, so I had a fresh point of comparison. In the comic book arc, everything was masterminded by Veronica Cale, a pharmaceutical CEO who had been created in the early 2000s with the intent of being the Lex Luthor to WW&amp;rsquo;s Superman. In the movie Cale works with WW for a while, and along I was waiting for the reveal that she was behind everything, but that never came. I would guess they have some bigger plans for Veronica Cale down the line in the DC animared film-universe. Otherwise, the movie was ok. Nothing too spectacular, missable, but also good enough to watch. EDIT: I found out after I wrote this that Bloodlines had a mid-credits scene where WW figures out Cale was behind everything all along!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, not much to say right now. The fall shows are back, that means the Arrowverse is in full swing again (except for Legends, they&amp;rsquo;ll be back in January). The &amp;ldquo;science&amp;rdquo; on &lt;strong&gt;Flash&lt;/strong&gt; is still ridiculous. The flash forwards on &lt;strong&gt;Arrow&lt;/strong&gt; are still boring (I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why they want to make a spinoff for Mia Smoak!), &lt;strong&gt;Supergirl&lt;/strong&gt; is also a bit meh. I&amp;rsquo;m really only looking forward to the Crisis crossover this season (and of course, &lt;em&gt;Legends of Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;.) Haven&amp;rsquo;t watched Batwoman yet, maybe I should since she has one of the five Crisis episodes. Also been following some of the regular stuff: The Good Place, Modern Family, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s also a lot of superhero shows still on the backlog, some of which I may never get to watch: Runaways, Cloak and Dagger (cancelled!), Krypton (cancelled!), Legion (finished!), Doom Patrol, Titans S2, etc. Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a point where there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;too much&lt;/em&gt; content for comic book fans? Lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix: I saw that Jenny Slate has a standup special out and I tried watching it, but eh, not for me, found it very boring and stopped about a third of the way through. I also found myself re-watching the end of &lt;strong&gt;Full Metal Alchemist: Brotherhood&lt;/strong&gt;, mostly because I was envious of a friend who was watching it for the first time. Was surprised to learn the anime is 10 years old as of this year! Still held up well, possibly my favorite anime of all time. The final confrontation and fight scenes were great, although the epilogue episode was a bit anticlimactic and awkward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for this month. Maybe next month we manage to dent the ever-growing backlog? Maybe?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/1180086308963618816/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 11:44:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/1180086308963618816/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;JOKER spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;very dark movie, not like any previous superhero movies at all; don&amp;rsquo;t bring your kids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is violent and potentially disturbing, but strangely not as much as the hype made it out to be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joaquin Phoenix definitely gives a pretty good performance, but IDK about the supposed &amp;ldquo;Oscar-worthy&amp;rdquo; hype&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some of the shots feels like the director definitely had a lot of fun bringing this story to life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would have liked less connection to the Batman mythos so that this movie is more stand-alone. I mean, it is pretty much stand-alone, but it does remind you where it&amp;rsquo;s set and direct connections to the Mythos exist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think a lot of the story and plot elements are handled well, any concerns I have would largely be nitpicking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No post credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i didnt watch in imax and don&amp;rsquo;t think it would be relevant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;magugustuhan ba ni mama: sure NO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ultimately, I still prefer that Joker&amp;rsquo;s origin story remain undetermined, as it makes him more akin to a natural force of chaos, but I accept this movie as a version that even canon Joker could have told and that might have been believable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s definitely a better movie overall than Suicide Squad, Man of Steel or Dawn of Justice or Justice League, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a different completely type of movie, so the comparison is difficult&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still like Ledger&amp;rsquo;s Joker the best, the character is best opposite Batman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: September 2019: Dark Phoenix, The Ranch
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/watching-lately-sep-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/watching-lately-sep-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I finally got around to watching &lt;strong&gt;X-Men Dark Phoenix&lt;/strong&gt; which I skipped when it came out mainly because (a) poor reviews, and while normally I&amp;rsquo;d have watched it anyway since I have not missed any of the X-Men movies in the cinema, not even the horrendous Wolverine Origins, there was also to consider that (b) I was in the US at the time and was only willing to spend my precious dollars on one expensive American cinema and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/&#34;&gt;Spider-man Far From Home&lt;/a&gt; won out. The movie wasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; bad really, at least I felt better about it than the aforementioned Wolverine Origins. Here are &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes/2019/09/1171737237135867906/&#34;&gt;some of my nitpicks&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not what would&amp;rsquo;ve been the best ending for the X-Men series which was really one of the pioneers of the superhero movie revolution (alongside Raimi&amp;rsquo;s Spider-Man), but that&amp;rsquo;s what we got. At least it ended with a big fiery bird explosion in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also watched Part 7 of &lt;strong&gt;The Ranch&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. The Ranch is one of those weird family comedy/drama shows that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally seem to be in my spheres of interest, especially since the show is probably a lot more appealing to conservative/right-wing viewers. (It&amp;rsquo;s often punctuated by country music and the characters regularly criticize Hillary Clinton and mock the idea of climate change.) I will not admit that I got into it mostly because of Elisha Cuthbert. It is a moderately enjoyable show, the kind you don&amp;rsquo;t mind having run in the background while you&amp;rsquo;re doing something else, although it did lose a bit of its comedy punch with the firing/writing off of Danny Masterson (&amp;ldquo;Hyde&amp;rdquo; from the 70s show) last season due to #MeToo issues, and the guy they replaced him with hasn&amp;rsquo;t been super impressive thus far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow month again this time. The lull should pick up in October once the fall US shows start off. And there&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of movies I want to watch too but some combination of laziness and lack of time always puts them off.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: August 2019: Young Justice, The Boys, Fleabag, One Cut of the Dead
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/watching-lately-aug-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/watching-lately-aug-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Hmm, surprisingly I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched too much stuff this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eigasai&#34;&gt;Eigasai&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched a Japanese film at Eigasai in UP Diliman for the first time ever, upon the invite of some friends. We saw &lt;strong&gt;One Cut of the Dead&lt;/strong&gt; a comedy zombie film. It was great and it was hilarious, although you must make sure not to lose patience with the first thirty minutes. I went in blind not knowing anything about it other than &amp;ldquo;Japanese comedy zombie movie&amp;rdquo;, so you should too! Easily one of the funniest movies I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;young-justice&#34;&gt;Young Justice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back half of Young Justice Outsiders finished this week. I&amp;rsquo;ve honestly been a bit whelmed for this half of the season as I feel like they&amp;rsquo;re all over the place and there&amp;rsquo;s too many plot threads going on at once. Still an enjoyable watch especially for DC fans of course. The thing about having such a large cast is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to focus on any one of them too long, but this season was all about Halo, Geoforce and Cyborg so the arc endings pretty much revolved around those three. It feels like so many status quo changes happened in the last episode though, felt a bit crammed. Also, some spoilers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like the Light declaring at the end that their gains were sufficient vs Luthor&amp;rsquo;s original plans seemed ridiculous (i.e. controlling Markovia vs controlling and registering all superhumans). They already had one puppet nation under their control (Queen Bee is right there!) and they&amp;rsquo;re literally planning to go against Darkseid, how does controlling Markovia help? Feels like a very post-facto justification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did like that they chose not to complete their Judas Contract re-telling in a similar manner and we get a &amp;ldquo;redeemed&amp;rdquo; Tara to contrast with the &amp;ldquo;fallen&amp;rdquo; Geoforce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fleabag&#34;&gt;Fleabag&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about this Amazon Prime series going in either, only that it was a comedy and it was well-reviewed. I did enjoy watching it, although it&amp;rsquo;s more of a tragic comedy than anything else. Basically about how people deal with absurdly difficult situations in their daily life. The story is well-told, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I get all the hype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-boys&#34;&gt;The Boys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Amazon Prime series. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read the source material, and I was a bit turned off by the first episode, but I powered through. I knew it would be dark going in, and possibly gratuitous in terms of the sex and violence at some points, so not many surprises there. The plot seems in my head to be &amp;ldquo;What if superheroes were driven by a greedy corporation&amp;rdquo;, which certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t help address my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/capitalism/&#34;&gt;misgivings about capitalism&lt;/a&gt;. The plot also reminds me of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s book Reckoners, which was also a story about a resistance trying to oppose a superhuman regime led by a Superman-like figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking over the Wikipedia entry for the comic book series, it seems the TV show had some significant divergences, which is understandable, so I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll be seeking out the comic books. The series was enjoyable enough to binge over a few days, although some parts are a bit predictable. I did like the treatment given to Hugh and Annie/Starlight. The cast is pretty good too, I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize Simon Pegg (because it was such a serious role) and Elisabeth Shue (because&amp;hellip;I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen her in anything in a while?). Oh and Gus Fring is also here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I ended up enjoying the season overall, as it tackles a lot of issues I relate with. I will probably be watching Season 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rockos-modern-life-static-cling&#34;&gt;Rocko&amp;rsquo;s Modern Life: Static Cling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix tried to bring Rocko into the modern era, although strangely none of the characters have aged at all. Although they are cartoon characters so I guess that makes sense? The special is about as ridiculous as the old cartoon was, unsurprisingly, although it does try to convey a message about how change is an inevitable part of life. I did like that they had a reference to my favorite episode, R-E-C-Y-C-L-E Recycle~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More next month! Maybe!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: June and July 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/watching-lately-june-and-july-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/watching-lately-june-and-july-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I was travelling for most of the past two months, so this covers both June and July, and I guess I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to watch too much. Maybe? IDK, we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was in the US, I took the opportunity to finish watching &lt;strong&gt;Voltron: Legendary Defender&lt;/strong&gt; which only had two seasons available on PH Netflix. Pretty good adaptation, lots of fun callbacks to the old series. Some annoying filler eps, especially in the middle seasons onwards. I like how they spent the entire series going through the main Voltron villains one by one: first Zarkon, then Lotor, then a little bit of Sendak, then finally Hagar. It got a bit too hocus pocus magicky BS near the finale for me, but overall a pretty good watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were staying with relatives in the US, it turns out they&amp;rsquo;re really fond of watching Filipino movies. I&amp;rsquo;m not big on Filipino movies, most of them seem either uninspired, formulaic or outright ridiculous. I did enjoy a couple of the ones that I sat through, at least enough to comment on them, coincidentally both starring Eddie Garcia (RIP). The first one was &lt;strong&gt;Rainbow&amp;rsquo;s Sunset&lt;/strong&gt;, which has Eddie Garcia playing a senior citizen ex-politician who comes out as gay and explores the repurcussions to his children and grandchildren. This movie had a strange ending that came out of nowhere though. The second movie was &lt;strong&gt;Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Waiting&lt;/strong&gt; where Garcia portrays an old man who has died and finds himself in a waiting area before he can be sent to heaven, basically purgatory. In this place he finds an old flame of his from his youth, who has secretly been waiting for him all this time, refusing to advance to heaven. The movie explores themes of life and death and love and regret and commitment, but in a context outside of the typical Filipino love team movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a bunch of other Netflix movies watched - these folks didn&amp;rsquo;t have that much to do at home - but the only other one I remember sitting through was &lt;strong&gt;Murder Mystery&lt;/strong&gt; starring Adam Sandler and Jennifer Aniston. Basically a comedic whodunnit, it was entertaining enough to sit through, but nothing too special. I did like the car chase scene at the end though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from watching on Netflix, I also tried out an American cinema and watched &lt;strong&gt;Spider-man Far From Home&lt;/strong&gt; with a friend. I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/&#34;&gt;separate blog post&lt;/a&gt; for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murder Mystery might not have been too special, but it did inspire me to watch the copy I had of &lt;strong&gt;Murder on the Orient Express&lt;/strong&gt; when I got back home. It was my first exposure to Hercule Poirot, and I was pleasantly surprised by the star-studded cast. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of movie where you can&amp;rsquo;t watch it twice though; I suppose all whodunits are like that, but now I can&amp;rsquo;t watch the older movie based on this book. There&amp;rsquo;s supposedly a sequel coming out next year, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll watch that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the trip, there was a whole lot of shows to catch up on. The only one I managed to complete was &lt;strong&gt;Jessica Jones S3&lt;/strong&gt;, the final season among the erstwhile Netflix-Marvel shows. I liked this season, mostly because it went way more dark than I expected and had a very &amp;ldquo;Criminal Minds&amp;rdquo;/procedural kind of vibe since her main antagonist here was a serial killer, and one of the themes is how a hero has to play by the rules and can&amp;rsquo;t just do whatever he wants like killing criminals. (This kind of message always resonates with me now because of where the country is.) While I feel like it might have been better to cap the Netflix-Marvel venture with Daredevil&amp;rsquo;s fantastic season 3, this one isn&amp;rsquo;t a bad ending either. I suspect I will do a more detailed look back on these shows soonish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I have a ton of shows to catch up on. Good Omens, Stranger Things, Doom Patrol, Legion, etc to name a few. And I missed out on a few movies though, like Dark Phoenix, which I was tempted to watch in the cinema despite the bad reviews, because I&amp;rsquo;ve never missed any of the prior X-Men movies, not even Wolverine Origins. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have time to catch up on all of this stuff before the Fall TV season comes in!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>A Look Back at the Marvel Cinematic Universe
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/a-look-back-at-the-marvel-cinematic-universe/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/a-look-back-at-the-marvel-cinematic-universe/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I know I already made a &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/04/more-thoughts-on-avengers-endgame-and-the-mcu/&#34;&gt;whole post about the MCU after Endgame came out&lt;/a&gt;, but after the MCU Phase 4 announcements this past weekend at SDCC I was a bit hyped. I thought it would be fun to look back at the past 10 years of MCU Phase 1-3 and see what I wrote about the movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iron Man (2008)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, I had written nothing about watching this film at all, and I don&amp;rsquo;t remember going to the cinema to watch it. The movie came out between Batman Begins and The Dark Knight, so my hype was undeniably towards the Batman movies back then. Before the MCU, Iron Man was a B-list hero at best, and back then no one could ever have imagined how far the MCU would go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Incredible Hulk (2008)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/06/movies-june-2008/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Movies &amp;ndash; June 2008&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edward Norton is cast brilliantly here, a choice on the same level as Robert Downey Jr as Iron Man. And they addressed the issue of Hulks stretchy pants!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iron Man 2 (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took them 2 years to get to a 2nd movie. They probably weren&amp;rsquo;t prepared for how well received Iron Man was!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I have for this movie is &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/13253318934&#34;&gt;from a tweet&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iron Man 2 was okay, but it was pretty much more of the same. Therefore it does not wow as much as the first movie did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thor (2011)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any notes about this movie either. Well, except that I thought it &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/82967835080527872&#34;&gt;was better than Green Lantern&lt;/a&gt; (an understatement). I do remember being impressed visually by the Asgard set-pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain America the First Avenger (2011)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/96637161473966080&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain America was fine. Definitely better than Thor/Green Lantern&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I started ranking them around this time, although maintaing an overall ranking was pretty much impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers (2012)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/195064455208501248&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avengers was very enjoyable, funny and action-packed. Re-reading Ultimates v1 now lol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I had more to say, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in the habit yet of more detailed reviews back then. On to phase two!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iron Man 3 (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/328877325867446273&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#IronMan3 It was ok. Not as great as some people have said, but probably better than 2. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alvinjtang&#34;&gt;@alvinjtang&lt;/a&gt; says it&amp;rsquo;ll look worse in a few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thor The Dark World (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/396176381819621376&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thor2 was okay, I like it more than Iron Man 3, mostly because I like the Star Wars x High Fantasy style&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thor2 is generally considered one of the lowest-ranked movies of the MCU, but as a comic book fan I&amp;rsquo;m very forgiving and I guess this means I generally liked all of them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain America Winter Solider (2014)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/449064262581768192&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cap America 2 snap judgment: fun movie, better than Iron Man 3/Thor 2. Great for comic fans!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, an understatement, as I would later go on to consider Winter Soldier possibly my favorite MCU movie of all time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also said in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10152883332768912&#34;&gt;a Facebook post&lt;/a&gt; that the movie would have been perfect if he had only done Final Justice lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy (2014)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10153122948543912&#34;&gt;Facebook post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guardians was a very funny and fun movie, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to say best Marvel movie so far, since I really liked Winter Soldier. And as a comic fan, I&amp;rsquo;m not that fond of how the Nova Corps was portrayed; I guess it&amp;rsquo;s understandable since they&amp;rsquo;re not the heroes here. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of stuff for comic fans to enjoy though&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014 was a great year for the MCU, as both of these movies are among my MCU favorites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Age of Ultron (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10153724990238912&#34;&gt;Facebook post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler-free Age of Ultron review: It&amp;rsquo;s great, go watch it. I loved it. I wish there had been less content made available ahead of time through trailers and casting announcements, but such are the times we live in. It is a good time to be a comic book fan. There is a short mid-credits scene. There is no post-credits scene&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was around this time that I started doing &amp;ldquo;spoiler-free reviews&amp;rdquo;. I also posted &lt;a href=&#34;http://nedstarkdies.com/avengers-age-of-ultron-by-hunter/&#34;&gt;a more detailed AoU review over on Nedstarkdies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ant Man (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10153946370273912&#34;&gt;Facebook post&lt;/a&gt; again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ant Man spoiler-free review: The first half felt a bit off, with some exposition coming off as forced and the pacing a bit awkward. Things picked up later on and while the plot was not entirely unpredictable there were a number of fun and surprising tangents. Overall a fun and entertaining movie with enough stuff for comic book Marvel fans to enjoy, probably close in quality to the first Iron Man movie, if not better&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized just now that both Ant Man movies have been used as a palate cleanser after an Avengers film. This first one also marked the end of phase two. On to phase three!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain America Civil War (2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10154562419893912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain America Civil War spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;great fight sequences, start to finish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the newcomers were great, airport big fight sequence had a great surprise (and not the one you already saw in the trailer - although you might have already been spoiled if you pay attention to certain toy lines), although I feel like a couple of the characters were pulled in to the conflict in a way that was a bit weak, but it&amp;rsquo;s still pretty good overall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the plot was ok. Justification for the civil war was ok. Some surprises. The villain motivation was slightly mediocre, but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t really the focus of the movie anyway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martin Freeman&amp;rsquo;s role felt totally superfluous - it did not seem necessary to cast Martin Freeman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie kind of ends with the MCU and the Avengers in a weird place, some people might not like it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better than: Winter Soldier. The plot kind of develops in the same way but everything is on a much bigger scale now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are two post-credit scenes, one in the middle and one at the very end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imax worth it? Probably. Not very ostentatious use of 3d, but most of the fight sequences have it. You might get dizzy if you&amp;rsquo;re not used to it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama? Maybe, but I&amp;rsquo;d have to keep explaining who these characters are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started doing this format of &amp;ldquo;Spoiler-free reviews&amp;rdquo; around this time, with what would turn out to be the well-loved &amp;ldquo;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama?&amp;rdquo; (Translation: Will Mama like it?) section. When I tried removing this section at some point, people complained lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Strange (2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10155041890913912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wow. Great visuals and fight-scenes, very trippy. Possibly the best fight scenes in all the MCU movies so far. You might get dizzy with all the things spinning around though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plot is typical of a MCU origin story. Hero&amp;rsquo;s journey, some light comedy bits, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was expecting them to go a different way with Mordo (if you&amp;rsquo;ve read the comics you know what I mean), but I&amp;rsquo;m happy with how things went down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stakes are high, but failure is not final&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The actors were great; I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen a lead this good for a role since RDJ&amp;rsquo;s Tony Stark. Swinton&amp;rsquo;s Ancient One, Eijofor&amp;rsquo;s Mordo, and even Wong&amp;rsquo;s Wong were great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doctor friends: Tell me if the medical parts were BS hohoho&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Probably not. She doesn&amp;rsquo;t like this kind of thing, and the dizziness thing is bad too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMAX or not? I think the 3d parts weren&amp;rsquo;t too exaggerated or critical, but the visuals might feel a bit flat and not as impressive if you don&amp;rsquo;t go IMAX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Midcredits scene? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postcredits scene? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy vol 2 (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10155588909688912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;overall a very entertaining movie to sit down and watch popcorn and to enjoy the jokes and the space battles and the different colored lights and the tiny adorable tree creature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GOTG&amp;rsquo;s humor was one of its strong points and for the 2nd movie, they push the comedy up a notch, perhaps a little too much in some places. Lots of funny gags and one-liners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt like some of the character/background development stuff was pushed a bit too hard as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie&amp;rsquo;s plot also felt a bit thin and straightforward. I mean, you could see some of the major plot points coming a mile away. Maybe from the trailers even&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Lord was ok. Gamora/Nebula felt poorly written. Rocket was a bit annoying. Drax and Mantis were ok, although the space they have for Mantis&amp;rsquo; character overlaps with Drax a bit.. I&amp;rsquo;m still not super happy with how Drax and Gamora are characterized in the MCU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m less happy with this movie&amp;rsquo;s soundtrack compared to the first one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Certainly not. In fact, she chose to derp around the mall instead of coming with me and my cousin to watch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMAX or not: Some visuals used the 3d effect, but nothing too exaggerated or critical. I&amp;rsquo;d say IMAX optional, but it definitely adds something to some scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are five extra scenes near the credits (one of them is right before the credits roll, so I can&amp;rsquo;t really say &amp;ldquo;post-credit&amp;rdquo; screens). Most of them are just setting the tone for the inevitable GOTG3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, just pay attention to the background of the credits roll as well, it&amp;rsquo;s great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I felt the movie was ok, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of just more of the same of what we got with the first movie, which felt a lot stronger overall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spider-man Homecoming (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10155834066513912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This movie is amazing. Possibly best in all MCU so far. It&amp;rsquo;s fun, it&amp;rsquo;s exciting, unexpected things happened. Maybe not watching the trailers helped lol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Covers a lot of ground the previous Spider-man movies didn&amp;rsquo;t. Helped along by not needing to rehash the origin story for the Nth time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of great call outs for the comic book fans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was worried about the Vulture, but it was handled very well. Keaton is great here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This movie is tightly coupled to the MCU yo. IDK how they&amp;rsquo;re going to handle it if Sony breaks it off after the two-movie deal. By they I mean Sony. Obviously MCU can just ignore him forever afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TBH I was also really worried about the MCU coupling and having too much Iron Man in the movie, but it turned out okay. Maybe could have had a little bit less Tony Stark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMAX? Probably not worth it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s a mid-credits scene and a post-credits scene.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama? Possibly! There&amp;rsquo;s some shaky cam footage near the start that can be a bit nauseating though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That first line is high praise lol. Around this time I started avoiding watching more than the first trailer for the MCU movies, as I always felt like they gave too many jokes and plot points away. I will certainly watch them anyway, so there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much point building up more hype than I needed to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thor Ragnarok (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10156133009878912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a fun, action-packed romp that shakes up the Thor status quo significantly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easily the best of the three Thor movies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a number plot points are fairly predictable, yet still fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Marvel formula is generally action mixed with witty banter here and there, and it&amp;rsquo;s what we get here, although some of the jokes feel like they&amp;rsquo;re stretched a bit too much&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some great-looking cinematic scenes here and there. One particular flashback scene looked really great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I kind of like how the older franchises need to be some sort of team effort nowadays. Like Civil War, this felt a bit like some kind of mini-Avengers crossover &amp;ndash; in space!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;speaking of space, one of the positive things about this installment is that they didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the need to tie Thor&amp;rsquo;s adventures to Earth anymore (not that the movie is 100% Earth-free), and they get to go a bit wild with space and aliens and all that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand the need to highlight Hulk&amp;rsquo;s involvement as part of the film&amp;rsquo;s marketing, but man, it would have been so awesome to just find out right then and there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This movie had that Star Wars: Last Jedi trailer I was trying to avoid D:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 mid-credits scene and 1 post-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think Imax was good for this movie. The 3d wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much and it definitely made some scenes pop. The film is a visual delight so I think the larger screen is important too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Probably not. Maybe I should stop including this section kasi parang same na parati ang answer. Unless for some reason I decide to watch some Tagalog romcom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damn Thor 3 was great. Looking forward to Love and Thunder!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black Panther (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10156423012653912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s a fun, action-filled romp and Wakanda is amazing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tchalla was ok, killmonger and nakia were great, shuri was badass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some of the actions scenes didnt seem too well-shot/edited, making them hard to follow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I realize I&amp;rsquo;m saying this about a universe where there are talking raccoons and magic hammers, but some of the Wakandan tech push the boundaries of my suspension of disbelief&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my expectations were probably set a bit too high what with some people saying it&amp;rsquo;s the best MCU movie since Iron Man or calling it revolutionary or eye-opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;off the top of my head I&amp;rsquo;d say I consider Civil War, Spider-Man Homecoming and Thor Ragnarok better than this one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand that it&amp;rsquo;s revolutionary in the sense that it&amp;rsquo;s a major hollowood motion picture filled with a cast of mostly african descent and that some of the characters are motivated by real world racial issues. But the plot itself was typical for an MCU first movie (maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve seen too many MCU movies? lol). I dont think it presents the issues it covers under any new or revolutionary context. I guess I kind of went in hoping to be impressed on the level of The Dark Knight or such, but I was disappointed in that regard. It&amp;rsquo;s a very straightforward movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t watch in Imax, which I kind of regret, as I can imagine some of the scenes being pretty good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Possibly, pero baka mahirapan sya intindihin accent ni Chadwick Boseman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a mid-credits scene and a post-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers Infinity War (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10156599221698912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m amazed that so little of this movie has been widely spoiled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movie was fantastic. the movie somehow managed to do everything it needed to do while not doing disservice to any of the bazillion characters involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the plot moves quickly. there is no good time to pee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is one post-credits scene.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;very happy to have watched in imax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ant Man and the Wasp (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10156749941023912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this movie is great; it&amp;rsquo;s fun and and action-packed and there&amp;rsquo;s even more Luis than you thought you wanted; go watch it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s like the first movie, except better and more fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;best new character: FBI Agent Jimmy Woo played by Randall Park (sorry Michelle Pfeifer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are two mid/post-credit scenes. One of them is better than the other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watched in Imax. Some scenes were nice, but it&amp;rsquo;s probably more of a nice-to-have&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Pwede, but kelangan ng kasama to explain things. Baka ok lang pag tagalized na sa tv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain Marvel (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around this time, I started &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/183266384975/captain-marvel-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;posting the reviews to Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movie was pretty good, no major issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doesnt follow the typical MCU origin story formula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some weird pacing issues in a few places, but that just might be because of the chosen story direction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lots of little call-outs and tie-ins to the other MCU movies (although I feel like they could have done a bit more in some spots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am not a cat person. But if you are a cat person, you might like this: there is a cat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theres some parts that made it obvious they were aiming for that Wonder Woman audience, so the movie may be better for you if youre in that demo (but I think WW was a better movie overall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imax was pretty good, nothing too excessive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Midcredits scene, and postcredits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni mama? Possibly! Also, its a good idea to bring little girls to watch this movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers Endgame (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read my review &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/more-thoughts-on-avengers-endgame-and-the-mcu/&#34;&gt;right here on this blog&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spider-man Far From Home (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read my review &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/&#34;&gt;right here on this blog&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was a fun walk through a decade of films, and it gave me an opportunity to fold some of my off-blog content back into this blog. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to be doing more movie reviews directly here on this blog instead of just on Facebook or Tumblr. Looking forward to more MCU in the years (decades?) to come!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Spider-Man Far From Home
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;First, the spoiler-free review, then more spoilery stuff afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watched Far From Home while I was&amp;hellip; far from home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;great movie, lots of fun, and the stakes are a lot higher than the Vulture just stealing some tech off Tony Stark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basically a story of Peter Parker the high school student trying to juggle his Spider-Man problems with his high school life, which was one of the best eras of comic book Spider-Man&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie gives us a look at what the world looks like post-Endgame and how weird it is for everyone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you&amp;rsquo;ve seen the trailers, you know who the &amp;ldquo;villain&amp;rdquo; is and you have certain expectations coming in. I was worried this would be a problem but it worked out fine, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a problem and was handled well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a mid-credits scene, possibly one of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen, in terms of how it changes the entire tone of the movie. There is also a post-credits scene, the implications of which are still unclear and will leave the fanbase speculating for a while&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Possibly! There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of &amp;ldquo;cute&amp;rdquo; Peter Parker high school moments she&amp;rsquo;d probably like, and the plot and action aren&amp;rsquo;t too hard to follow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoilery stuff follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how could Midtown High afford to send their trivia team on a trip through Europe? Is this typical of American high schools?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As mentioned above, anyone even remotely familiar with Spider-Man lore wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised at the reveal that Mysterio is actually a villain. This is one of those times where there would have been some advantage to not knowing stuff ahead of time, as you get to enjoy the reveal. That being said, Mysterio&amp;rsquo;s villain monologue after getting the EDITH glasses may be one of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. Since I already knew Mysterio was a bad guy, the only realy mystery was HOW he was doing these destructive elementals since they obviously weren&amp;rsquo;t the simple light-and-sound shows that comics Mysterio was known for. Tying the illusions to the BARF holograms and even re-using side characters from previous movies was an inspired choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the rest of the movie&amp;rsquo;s plot was fairly predictable, but the MCU continues to subvert the expectations of Spider-Man fans since both Peter Parker and the supporting cast are completely different from the comicbook incarnations, powers notwithstanding. I assume they planned as far back as Homecoming that Tony would be dying in Endgame and Peter would be pressured to take the mantle, setting Tony up as his father figure instead of the mythical Uncle Ben. Zendaya&amp;rsquo;s MJ is completely different from the comics&amp;rsquo; Mary Jane &amp;ldquo;Hey tiger&amp;rdquo; Watson; Flash is a nerd like Peter instead of a footballer; Ned isn&amp;rsquo;t even based on a Peter supporting character but on a Miles supporting character, and so on. This is basically a completely different version of Peter&amp;rsquo;s HS life and it&amp;rsquo;s great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that first Mysterio vs Spider-Man scene was great, evocative of the comic book version and even Arkham Asylum&amp;rsquo;s Scarecrow sequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the whole Peter/MJ/Brad Davis subplot gives the movie a bit of a &amp;ldquo;John Hughes&amp;rdquo; vibe and there are some cute moments and MJ really holds her own; I think this movie handles the whole &amp;ldquo;dual identity problems&amp;rdquo; aspect of Spider-man better than Homecoming did&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that webswinging sequence at the end of the movie was great, has the same feel as the PS4 game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the midcredits scene completely changes the tone of the ending of course. But first, we must acknowledge the awesome return of the one true J. Jonah Jameson, JK Simmons! The unmasking is a problem, and how will they handle it? Will Peter and May have to go into hiding at an Avengers facility? Will the bad guys come after them? WIll Peter have to make a deal with Mephisto to protect his secret in exchange for getting the worst prom ever with MJ? Or will they go some other route like have one of the Skrulls pose as Peter and appear together with Spider-man? The great thing about MCU Spider-Man is that because the setup is completely different, they&amp;rsquo;re not beholden to the comic book plots (neither Homecoming nor Far From Home are based on actual comic stories AFAIK). This ending also mirrors Homecoming&amp;rsquo;s unmasking in front of Aunt May, so my guess is that they&amp;rsquo;ll handle this cliffhanger the same way - completely off screen and we just see the repurcussions in the next movie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the final postcredits scene will have fans speculating for a while, but it looks like Fury is busy setting up SWORD? Or could it be something else?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great movie, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to Marvel hopefully announcing their Phase 4 plans at SDCC later this month!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: May 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/watching-lately-may-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/watching-lately-may-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The big TV thing of May 2019 was of course, the much maligned finale for &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve written about that separately &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/game-of-thrones/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the US TV series also ended their runs in May. Arrowverse show seasons were littered with poor writing as usual. I rank the seasons in this order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;best is &lt;em&gt;Legends of Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt; season 4. The reason Legends is the best is that they&amp;rsquo;re not afraid to be outrageous. My favorite moment was from before the midseason break, Puppets of Tomorrow!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;second best is &lt;em&gt;Supergirl&lt;/em&gt; season 4. I don&amp;rsquo;t like that Supergirl always felt very preachy about modern-day issues like feminism and diversity and immigration, and this season amped that up a lot, but I still enjoyed it because (a) Lex Luthor was great; and (b) they adapted a couple of my favorite DC Superman storylines, namely Manchester Black and the Elite and Red Son (Red Daughter in this case).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;third best is &lt;em&gt;Flash&lt;/em&gt; season 5. Cicada was a terrible villain and the rules of when and how the dagger works were just screwy, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad Eobard gets to come back in the ending (though I still don&amp;rsquo;t know why he has Wells&amp;rsquo; face)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;last is &lt;em&gt;Arrow&lt;/em&gt; season 7, just poor all-around writing, including an episode where Roy Harper flat out murders two innocents and everyone else on Team Arrow is like &amp;ldquo;Huh, okay, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover this up so the police don&amp;rsquo;t find out&amp;rdquo;, and a poorly explained road to Star City&amp;rsquo;s future. The season finale tellss us that Oliver dies during the upcoming Crisis of Infinite Earths. Arrow had a good run, but a few of the seasons were really week. It didn&amp;rsquo;t get as many seasons as Smallville did, but it has a legacy of its own (and arguably Smallville lasted a couple of seasons too long as well). More on this when Arrow&amp;rsquo;s abbreviated eighth and final season finishes later this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all my complaints, I&amp;rsquo;m still looking forward to this year&amp;rsquo;s Crisis crossover!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of DC TV series, &lt;em&gt;Gotham&lt;/em&gt; also ended its 5-season run, and although the show diverges significantly from the traditional Batman mythos, I still liked it. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t spectacular or anything, but there were some nice portrayals of many Batman characters and events. We never get to see Bruce don the cape and cowl, although it is heavily foreshadowed in the last episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Bang Theory also had its series finale, and I liked it. Overall as a series it had its flaws, and at many times promoted smart-shaming and nerd stereotypes, but its a sitcom, so I don&amp;rsquo;t take it too seriously. I think the ending of Sheldon getting his nobel prize (with Amy) and finally acknowledging how difficult he has been as a friend is an appropriate ending for the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my attempt to watch/read more &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/manga/&#34;&gt;manga&lt;/a&gt;/anime again, I started watching &lt;em&gt;Boku no Hero Academia&lt;/em&gt; on Netflix a few months ago, but only got two episodes in. This month I finally binged the rest of the anime and for good measure caught up with the manga as well. This series feels like some cross of One Punch Man (for the superpowers and the modern society) and Naruto (for the kids being supervised by adults), except I&amp;rsquo;d say the depth of the lore so far is not that much, more OPM than Naruto. Still a fairly enjoyable read/watch, since I usually enjoy shonen manga/anime, and it got me thinking that Marvel should make a shonen version of an X-Men comic someday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much movies-wise this month, though I did do a rewatch of &lt;em&gt;Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt; the other day, mostly because I had watched some videos ranking the MCU movies now that Endgame is done. Winter Soldier was always in my #1 slot, and the rewatch basically affirmed that. I had only meant to watch a little bit before going off to do something else, but the pacing of the movie was so great I just ended up watching it to the end. I think the themes of freedom vs security also really resonate with the liberal in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for this month! Next month I&amp;rsquo;ll be travelling, so who knows what I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to watch! I&amp;rsquo;ll have access to US Netflix!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: April 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/watching-lately-april-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/watching-lately-april-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve already written extensively about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/more-thoughts-on-avengers-endgame-and-the-mcu/&#34;&gt;Avengers Endgame&lt;/a&gt;, but there are other things I watched this month too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shazam&lt;/strong&gt; came out early this month, and while it was unfortunately sandwiched between MCU blockbusters, it was a fun adventure romp and surprised me in a few ways. I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/183916511215/shazam-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;short spoiler-free review&lt;/a&gt; over on Tumblr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a rewatch binge of &lt;strong&gt;30 Rock&lt;/strong&gt; that unfortunately started with season 4 due to Amazon Prime&amp;rsquo;s weird way of presenting things. I&amp;rsquo;ve already blown past the series finale and wrapped around to the start and currently at season 2, so close to completion. The series is as great and insane as I remember. It&amp;rsquo;s like a more outrageous version of ensemble comedies like Parks and Recreation, and though I am fonder of PNR, I can see why 30 Rock is the more award-winning show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;The Orville&lt;/strong&gt; finished their second seasons this month. Discovery closed off their time loops neatly and sent the Discovery into an unknown future, meaning they get to start season 3 now no longer bound by Star Trek history and free to forge their own path. The season was ok, I enjoyed the classic Trek references and all the timey-wimey stuff. The Orville had a great season, with the introduction of a new enemy empire and possibly one of the best TV space battles of all time. They ended their season with a timey-wimey episode as well, looks like that&amp;rsquo;s a trend for April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/strong&gt; final season started up in April of course, and its only halfway through. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have a lot more to say about it when the season ends in May.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>More thoughts on Avengers Endgame and the MCU
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/more-thoughts-on-avengers-endgame-and-the-mcu/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/more-thoughts-on-avengers-endgame-and-the-mcu/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I already wrote about Avengers Endgame a bit in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/were-in-the-endgames-now/&#34;&gt;yesterday&amp;rsquo;s post&lt;/a&gt;, but that was a bit rushed and I had more thoughts, so here we are. I figured I might as well get everything out. There will be unmarked spoilers for Avengers Endgame and Agents of SHIELD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before even going into the movie that was seemingly sold out everywhere despite being on almost every cinema screen in the Metro, I was thinking to myself what a phenomenon. Endgame is the culmination of a decade&amp;rsquo;s worth of movies, 22 in total, and even some number of shows, something unrivalled in all of movie history. It&amp;rsquo;s a new form of serialized event entertainment - even though there have been movie franchises with continuity before, most have been limited to trilogies, and the MCU blows them all out of the water. In my head it&amp;rsquo;s more akin to an extended HBO or Netflix series, one that only gets three episodes a year, and each episode is an event in that you can go to the cinema and watch it with your friends. And Endgame was here, trying to put a bookend on all of that, an entire decade worth of stories, with dozens of characters and the stakes no less than half the universe. The scale of it is mind-boggling and very ambitious, and if they dropped the ball on this one it would be so terrible and a huge waste and it would take another decade to even attempt to conclude another story in this manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The movie starts with the cold open of Clint and his family getting dusted. This could have easily been done as a post-credits scene in Infinity War, but having this here allows them to remind the audience of the stakes involved at the very start. (And saves them having to credit Jeremy Renner in both movies.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next we get the trailer scene of Tony in space recording his message to Potts. The trailer makes this out to be kind of a hopeless-we&amp;rsquo;re-about-to-die situation for Tony (and Nebula), but the movies resolves it quickly by having Carol come in to save them at the last minute. At first I was confused a bit about whether we were going to see the Captain Marvel post-credits scene in this movie, but they save some time by having all of that (including introducing Carol to everybody and explaining Thanos and all) happen off-screen. Tony gets back to Earth but he&amp;rsquo;s still pissed at cap and they part ways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With Nebula now on Earth, they know where Thanos is and the plan is to go beat him up, get the stones and use that to resotre all the dusted people. But Thanos has destroyed the stones, making the snap apparently irreversible. Thor is frustrated and goes for the head this time, and we timeskip five years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both the timeskip and the length of it caught me a bit off-guard, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting it. I can imagine that Infinity War could&amp;rsquo;ve ended here too (if not for the pesky detail of Carol not yet being introduced.) Aparently five years was not enough for the people of the world to move on. That&amp;rsquo;s understandable, but I would have assumed they would clean up the mess a little bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next we have the rat that saves the world. Pure blind luck gets Scott out of the Quantum Realm; the only reason it took five years to get to this point is that rat was lazy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuing the MCU tradition of trying to complete the Community cast, we get a 2-second cameo by Ken Jeong/Senor Chang. Later on we also get a slightly longer cameo from Yvette Nicole-Brown/Shirley!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scott gets to meet grown-up Cassie, setting up the stage for her Phase 4 adventures as Stature, and perhaps, the Young Avengers? Who else would be there?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After some meandering, Scott makes his way to the Avengers compound, and finally explains his ludicrous timey-wimey plan of using the quantum realm to do a time heist. They need someone smart to figure this out so they go to Tony, and we get to meet his daughter Morgan (I would guess at 4 years old). Tony dismisses their plan as some fantasy Back to the Future-type nonsense. Apparently (as would be explained further on), Back to the Future rules do not apply in the MCU - changing the past does not affect the future. I initially thought they would try to use time travel to go back and redo the battle of Wakanda, this time with more foreknowledge and Carol on their side and thus stop the snap from even happening, but this throws that out the window. There&amp;rsquo;s no getting around it now - the snap is irrevocably part of MCU history and future films will have to work around that or otherwise deal with the consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They need another smart guy, so they go see Bruce, who is now Smart Hulk. Not what I was expecting, though not unprecedented from the comics. Banner has had a weird character arc since Age of Ultron, going from permanently Hulk to unable to Hulk and now both Banner and Hulk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tony figures it out and comes around, so they try to get the gang back together to do the Time Heist. Rocket and Bruce go to pick up Thor, who is now a depressed fat drunk idiot apparently. Far Thor is a bit of a disservice to the character - but given that during the last few movies he&amp;rsquo;s lost his mother and his father and his girlfriend and his home and his posse and half the remaining Asgardians and he feel responsible for the snap because he didn&amp;rsquo;t go for the head, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a little justified. Hey, at least Valkyrie and Korg survived, so that&amp;rsquo;s something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natasha tracks Clint swordfighting some Yakuza in Tokyo and gives him hope.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So the Time Heist crew are: Steve, Tony, Bruce, and Scott going for the three infinity stones in New York 2012, Rocket and Thor going for the Ether in Asgard 2013, Nebula, Rhodey going for the power stone on Morag in 2014, and Clint and Natasha going for the Soul Stone in 2014 as well. They only get one round trip each, so no one is allowed to fail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was pleasantly surprised all the appearances of characters from previous movies: the Ancient One, Rumlow, Agent Sitwell, Loki, Alexander Pierce, Frigga, even Natalie Portman&amp;rsquo;s Jane Foster! Did they actually get Portman to shoot a scene gain, or just reused footage from Dark World? (I assume the latter). Tt&amp;rsquo;s amazing that they were able to shoot new scenes with actors like Tilda Swinton and Robert Redford and not have that info leak&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some great throwback moments include:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I can do this all day&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Yeah, yeah&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Ancient One punching Bruce out of the Hulk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the elevator scene from Winter Soldier turned on its head by Cap whispering &amp;ldquo;Hail Hydra&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cap, Iron Man and Hulk going back to the battle of New York made sense, since they could blend in during the fight somehow and Tony has access to Stark tower&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thor does his blubbering idiot thing but gets a bit of his mojo back after talking to his mother and finding out he was still worthy to summon Mjolnir&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once you know that Clint and Natasha are going for the Soul Stone, you already know one of them has to die; the only question was which one. Natasha unfortunately, did not have a spouse and children to go back to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rhodey and Nebula successfully conk out idiot Peter Quill and grab the Power Stone from him. It&amp;rsquo;s weird that they chose to go back to this time instead of say, after Gotg1 when the power stone was safely in the hands of the Nova Corps. I guess they figured it was easier to get it from Quill rather than try to infiltrate Xandar, but coming back to this time creates an opportunity for Nebula to get her wifi network crossed with 2014 Nebula and so 2014 Thanos finds out about the entire Time Heist and sends 2014 Nebula back to 2023 as a sleeper agent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steve and Tony hop to 1970 as their back up plan for getting the tesseract. Steve catches a glimpse of Peggy, but she looks a bit too young considering she should be 50ish at this time. Tony meets up with Howard and I am momentarily confused because I am more familiar with Dominic Cooper than John Slattery but here we are. Howard saying Tony is about to be born tells us Tony is more than 50 in 2023, quite old already as well. Oh, and Jarvis is here too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Time Heist is successful! Everyone but Nat makes it back home, and they mourn her for all of ten seconds before going to build their own Infinity Gauntlet. She probably deserved more than that, but she is still slated for an upcoming movie, however that works, and this movie is all about a sendoff for Cap and Tony, so she gets less focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(As the third act is beginning, I suddenly get the urge to pee, but I can&amp;rsquo;t go now! And I&amp;rsquo;m in the middle of the row so going would bother a lot of people and I end up uncomfortably holding it in for an hour. This is my excuse in case I screw up some facts below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014 Nebula brings 2014 Thanos and his warship through the time machine into the present day. One would wonder how they got enough Pym particles to shrink the entire warship, but presumably they had enough time to study and clone the tech before 2014 Nebula called to them. The ship did not pop out full size in Avengers compound as I expected, instead appearing in the sky above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bruce prepares to use the gauntlet, and without explanation everyone suits up, as if expecting they&amp;rsquo;re about to be attacked by the Mad Titan they thought they killed a while back. Bruce snaps, and a phone call confirms the undusting worked, but then they get space bombarded by Thanos&amp;rsquo; warship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clint is left alone to run away with the gauntlet to protect it from beasties. The original three (Steve, Tony and Thor) go face to face with Thanos directly. Thor, probably bursting with a chance to redeem himself, dual wields Stormbreaker and Mjolnir and uses the lightning to get out his sweatpants and fashion himself new armor and braid his beard. They go at it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2014 Gamora frees 2023 Nebula and they go save Clint just when 2014 Nebula was about to take the gauntlet from him. Bruce is trying to keep the rubble from collapsing on Rhodey, Rocket and himself as Scott heads their way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanos vs the original three is a close fight, but the Mad Titan has them on the ropes when suddenly Steve wields Mjolnir! Completely predictable, but it&amp;rsquo;s something the fans have been clamoring for since Age of Ultron. Thor cheers &amp;ldquo;I knew it!!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In spite of everything, Thanos beats them back, shattering Steve&amp;rsquo;s shield. Steve struggles to get up, barely breathing, and all seems lost when he gets some radio comms from somewhere. It&amp;rsquo;s Sam! Right, all the dusted people are back! Took them long enough! &amp;ldquo;On your six&amp;rdquo; is a throwback to their jogging days back during Winter Soldier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magic portals from Doctor Strange&amp;rsquo;s peeps pop up all over, and the reinforcements are here: T&amp;rsquo;Challa, Shuri, Okoye and the armies of Wakanda! Sam, Bucky, Wanda, Quill, Drax and Mantis! Peter Parker, Spider-man! Pepper in the Rescue Armor! Hope van Dyne! Valkyrie and the Asgardians! Wong and his magic friends! 2014 Gamora and 2023 Nebula! Scott goes Giant-Man and busts Bruce, Rhodey and Rocket out of the rubble! Thanos calls down his armies, the Black Order and the Leviathans from the battle of New York. Everyone is geared up for a rematch of Wakanda, and Steve finally utters those magic words: Avengers Assemble! (We&amp;rsquo;re already assembled, Steve!). Hands down the best moment of the movie!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not much to say about the battle itself, its great and everyone has their moments. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a problem with the whole girl power moment after Carol comes in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tony&amp;rsquo;s response of &amp;ldquo;I am Iron Man&amp;rdquo; as he snaps his gauntlet is weird but I understand why it&amp;rsquo;s there. His journey begins and ends with that line. His body can&amp;rsquo;t take the power of infinity and he dies. Pepper tells him its time to rest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tony gets a long funeral scene, and some characters notably appear for the first time in the movie: Janet van Dyne, Maria Hill, Nick Fury and some teenager I don&amp;rsquo;t recognize but later find out is supposed to be the kid from Iron Man 3. Some posts are also naming him as &amp;ldquo;Iron Lad&amp;rdquo;, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t jive with the Young Avengers Iron Lad origin, but I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s a possible future something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And now, the weakest part of the movie&amp;rsquo;s plot: Steve going back to the past to return the infinity stones (and Mjolnir) to where they got them, to minimize timestream damage. So many questions:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is Steve the only one to go? Hank Pym is back, they can make more Pym Particles again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is his shield whole again? Did Shuri repair it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did he go back to Asgard and inject the ether back into Jane Foster?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did he make the tesseract a cube again? How did he put the mind stone back into the sceptre which he didn&amp;rsquo;t bring?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did the reunion with Red Skull on Vormir go? Did he get a refund on the price paid for the Soul stone?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are a bunch of timey-wimey problems but probably there are multiple ways to justify things and you shouldnt think about them too hard and just accept them. For the record, here is what I believe. Presumably, returning the infinity stones to where they got them removes the branch timeline that was created when they originally got them. This means:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Returning the time stone to the Ancient One means the events of Doctor Strange still happen in the prime timeline, and that time stone was the same one Thanos used in Infinity War&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Returning the sceptre to Agent Sitwell means it still has the same mind stone used in Age of Ultron etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Returning the space stone (now Tesseract) to the SHIELD vaults means it does all of its stuff in the prime timeline as expected, and is still the same space stone used in Infinity War&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Returning the ether to Jane Foster means the events of Dark World still unfold as they did&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of these are merged back into the prime timeline via &lt;a href=&#34;https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/YouAlreadyChangedThePast&#34;&gt;TV Tropes: You Already Changed The Past&lt;/a&gt;, so they all already happened in the prime universe. This means four of the stones used in Infinity War and later destroyed were also the same ones used in Endgame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, there are at least two changes Steve would have been unable to repair:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loki escaping with the Tesseract in 2012&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The removal of 2014 Thanos, Gamora, Nebula and all of Thanos&amp;rsquo; crew from their time. This means it was also unnecessary to return the power stone and soul stone to this branch timeline, but I guess they did it anyway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another mystery is in what timeline did Steve get his last dance with Peggy and hence grow old etc. The fact that he was able to appear on the bench as an old man shortly after being sent back implies to me that he grew old in the prime timeline (in yet another instance of You Already Changed The Past), and that Peggy simply kept the real identity of her husband a secret to her dying day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The real problem with this whole affair character-wise is that it means Steve became selfish and chose to live out his life given the chance, instead of going back to his friends as expected. I like to think that seeing Peggy again in 1970 made him realize he was always meant to be with her and thus made him decide to do what he did&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handing off the shield to Sam: I expected it to be Bucky, given that in the comics he got to be Cap before Sam, but this is okay too. Though I think Steve could&amp;rsquo;ve given Bucky a few parting words as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quill pretty much got the short end of the stick in IW/EG: Fans hate him now for screwing up the battle on Titan, his girlfriend is dead, and now his leadership of the Guardians is in question&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notable deaths/absences:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2018 Gamora truly dead and gone. No explanation given for what happened to 2014 Gamora, as she wasn&amp;rsquo;t shown being dusted. Presumably we&amp;rsquo;ll see her and Thor again in Guardians 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No Vision this time, but presumably Shuri would be able to restore him sans mind stone, especially since he and Wanda are slated for a Disney+ show&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Natasha dying was sad, but she is slated for a solo movie, and EG leaves at least two outs for her coming back: one is via a Soul Stone refund as mentioned above, and another is Bruce saying he tried to bring her back when he did the snap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Agent Coulson appearance would have been nice, although he presumably died after the end of the last season of Agents of SHIELD. This movie also leaves Agents of SHIELD in a weird place: in the last season they had Infinity War happening concurrently with the season finale, and they delayed the start of season 6 until after Endgame, but given that they now have to live with a 5-year time gap where half the people are dead, IDK if they&amp;rsquo;ll have to adapt their scripts to that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In future movies, they now have access to a time machine! They can&amp;rsquo;t change the past, but they can do silly things like bring back dead characters to help lol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Future movies also have to deal with the fact that half the population skipped ahead 5 years and also that the world is a mess. Things certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t look like a mess in the Far From Home trailer though. Presumably Peter Parker&amp;rsquo;s friends Ned, MJ and Flash all got dusted in IW so that they are all still the same age in Far From Home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whew, I wrote a lot! I guess it&amp;rsquo;s justified given how much I liked the movie and the scale of it and everything. As I mentioned in the spoiler-free review, they could end the MCU here and it would be fine. A fitting end and tribute to the past decade of movies. I am even tempted to watch it in the cinemas a second time, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll have even more insights then!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>We&#39;re in the Endgames now
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/were-in-the-endgames-now/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/were-in-the-endgames-now/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Two endgames to discuss in one post! MTG War of the Spark and Avengers Endgame spoilers ahoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endgame #1: War of the Spark&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#cdb655624b3cf2a4e1e4d7428d798e2a-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/were-in-the-endgames-now/endgame_huf808040a75b6fb5c1e9efb3608d00058_168404_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;cdb655624b3cf2a4e1e4d7428d798e2a-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/were-in-the-endgames-now/endgame.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;27 Apr 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;27 Apr 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latest Magic set has been a home run in terms of lore and flavor and storytelling, bringing the last three years worth of MTG lore to its conclusion as the villainous dragon planeswalker Nicol Bolas aims to complete his plan to achieve omnipotence over the multiverse. The set is packed with planeswalkers summoned to Ravnica by Bolas&amp;rsquo;s schemes, which means mechanically that a lot of new planeswalker design space is being explored. The spoiler season was well-executed (despite some leaks during the last week), allowing us to see the story unfolding through the cards in a clearer way than ever before: from the dreadhorde invasion of Ravnica, the counterattack by the guilds, the arrival of the Amonkhet God-Eternals, and the death and betrayal that soon followed. It remains to be seen what impact the set will have on the gameplay and the meta, but from lore and flavor alone it&amp;rsquo;s already a win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endgame #2: Avengers Endgame&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the spoiler-free review (mirrored from &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/184473737480/avengers-endgame-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, I figured there&amp;rsquo;s no reason to publish there exclusively):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avengers: Endgame spoiler-free review!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watched Endgame exactly 365 days after watching Infinity War! (And also 3 years to the day after watching Civil War)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I approve of this movie as a fitting end to the last decade of Marvel films. This is a slam dunk ending. They could end it here, with no additional MCU movies/shows coming out and that would be completely fine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I approve of how little information about the movie managed to leak, I approve of the trailers and the marketing campaign: just enough to get hyped but nothing too spoilery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a lot to unpack, but its impossible to cover anything without getting into spoilers, but I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with the movie and the fan service, especially as a comic book fan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the plot starts out slow and moves quickly at the end. If you have to pee, better to do it sometime during the first hour; I found myself holding my pee for the last hour of the movie and not wanting to miss anything, it was not pleasant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imax was fine, but without probably also would have been fine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is supposedly no post-credits, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know as I couldn&amp;rsquo;t hold it much longer and left mid-credits. The first half of the credits was nice though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: No, same issue as Infinity War, too many characters to follow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re going to earn a bajillion dollars with this one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoilers follow:

&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    There are some timey-wimey concerns, but nothing a bunch of nerds wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to rationalize quickly. So much to unpack here, so many easter eggs and fan service: Widow&amp;rsquo;s death, Fat Thor, Smart Hulk, revisiting several previous movies, Steve wielding Mjolnir, Steve and Peggy&amp;rsquo;s last dance, Pepper rocking the Rescue armor, the Tony Stark final sacrifice and sendoff, all the cameos from previously lost characters and villains (did they actually get Natalie Portman to shoot new footage?!?), and finally that scene where when all hope was lost, I was wondering what deus ex machine they would use to get out of the situation, and when Sam made contact I was like, that&amp;rsquo;s right, everyone&amp;rsquo;s back, then we get all the Avengers, Wakandans, Asgardians, Sanctorum dudes, etc and Cap going &amp;ldquo;Avengers Assemble!&amp;rdquo; (Hey, wheren&amp;rsquo;t they already assembled?!?)
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worth the wait, very happy with the movie, and even tempted to watch it one more time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is of course a third endgame that kicked off in April, and that&amp;rsquo;s Game of Thrones, but it&amp;rsquo;s not yet done, so I&amp;rsquo;ll cover that another time.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/were-in-the-endgames-now/endgame_huf808040a75b6fb5c1e9efb3608d00058_168404_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Shazam! spoiler-free review!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/shazam-spoiler-free-review/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 16:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/shazam-spoiler-free-review/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I liked this movie, it had good heart, fun kid-friendly humor, and a strong message about family&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basically the story of a kid with a messed up life being stupid and trying to be better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;john glover is here! does he now hold the record for portraying the most number of parents of bald supervillains? thats not a spoiler right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this movie is kid-friendly, aside from the violence and the occasional swear word&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is a mid credits scene and the post credits scene. one is sillier than the other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: March 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/watching-lately-march-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/watching-lately-march-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The big one this month was &lt;strong&gt;Captain Marvel&lt;/strong&gt;. I posted &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/183266384975/captain-marvel-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;the usual spoiler-free review over on Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, but I have some more spoiler-y thoughts over here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I thought the movie was ok, I was underwhelmed by the third act and specifically the lack of any serious threat for Carol to defeat towards the end of the movie. As this &lt;a href=&#34;https://mabeloni-sandwich.tumblr.com/post/183645870983/the-biggest-problem-with-every-single-bad-review&#34;&gt;tumblr post explains&lt;/a&gt; more clearly than I ever could, perhaps the issue is that the narrative is not something targetted towards me as a man, who has not experienced the emotional gaslighting IRL that many women are exposed to. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting way to frame the narrative, and probably explains why some movies (i.e. chick flicks) really don&amp;rsquo;t appeal to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did enjoy most everything else about the movie, especially most of the comic book tie-ins and links to other MCU movies. I appreciated how they re-told the &amp;ldquo;Carol getting her powers from an explosion&amp;rdquo; and Mar-vell still being there. I appreciate the surprise that Annette Benning was Mar-Vell all along. I appreciate their reimagination of the Kree Supreme Intelligence. I appreciate that by the time Avengers Endgame or any potential Captain Marvel 2 rolls around, Monica Rambeau will be old enough to be her own superhero as well. I appreciate all the little things connecting this movie to the first Iron Man, the first Avengers, and even to Infinity War itself. I also appreciated that their depiction of the Kree did not rule out the Agents of SHIELD versions existing! (That being said, I would have appreciated an explanation for why some Kree are blue and some are not!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much else to report. The Arrowverse is limping along. Recent episodes of &lt;strong&gt;Supergirl&lt;/strong&gt; have been great, I loved Jon Cryer as Lex Luthor, and I love how they&amp;rsquo;ve been able to adapt multiple comic book storylines this season such as &lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s So Funny About Truth, Justice, &amp;amp; the American Way?&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;American Alien&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Red Son&lt;/em&gt;. (Excuse me, red daughter.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In more sci-fi land, &lt;strong&gt;The Orville&lt;/strong&gt; has been fantastic, with their surprise twist to the Isaac storyline culminating in one of the best space battles portrayed on TV. &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; is not as good, but I still like it, as it feels a lot more classic Trek than S1 and the overarching S2 plot is more interesting to me too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next month is looking packed. The big headliners to look forward to are of course &lt;strong&gt;Avengers Endgame&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Shazam&lt;/strong&gt;, and the final season of &lt;strong&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Captain Marvel spoiler-free review!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/captain-marvel-spoiler-free-review/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 15:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/captain-marvel-spoiler-free-review/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movie was pretty good, no major issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doesnt follow the typical MCU origin story formula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some weird pacing issues in a few places, but that just might be because of the chosen story direction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lots of little call-outs and tie-ins to the other MCU movies (although I feel like they could have done a bit more in some spots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am not a cat person. But if you are a cat person, you might like this: there is a cat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theres some parts that made it obvious they were aiming for that Wonder Woman audience, so the movie may be better for you if youre in that demo (but I think WW was a better movie overall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imax was pretty good, nothing too excessive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Midcredits scene, and postcredits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni mama? Possibly! Also, its a good idea to bring little girls to watch this movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Netflix and Amazon Prime: An abundance of content
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/netflix-and-amazon-prime-an-abundance-of-content/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/netflix-and-amazon-prime-an-abundance-of-content/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t figured it out yet, I watch a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately/&#34;&gt;lot of TV shows&lt;/a&gt;, rarely on TV itself though. I outgrew scheduled television maybe more than a decade ago. I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of this because I was going through some old disks and found burned episodes of stuff like &lt;em&gt;Smallville&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Heroes&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;The Simpsons&lt;/em&gt;, various anime, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those were from the days before streaming though. These days an abundance of content is available online via the streaming services, no need to store all those episodes yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first tried out Netflix during my three-month London stint back in 2015 (which I now realized I never wrote about). Netflix wasn&amp;rsquo;t available in the PH yet, so I took the opportunity to take a free month trial which led to binge watching of shows like &lt;em&gt;House&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt; when I had the opportunity to work from home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months after I got back from the trip, Netflix became available in the PH, January 2016! I initially figured it might not be feasible at all given how terrible the internet here was, but it performed well enough even with our old 4Mbps BayanDSL. The content library was as expected, a lot smaller than the US one was, but it was a pretty good start. It meant a lot of the Netflix original content, including the Marvel shows, were available to me on demand so it was great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people like to use a VPN so they get access to a larger library, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried that. Honestly, there is already so much content in Netflix PH anyway, and if there&amp;rsquo;s any non Netflix content I wanted to watch, there are other ways rather than a VPN. (The old ways still worked of course.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Netflix is a staple in our household, even my nontechie dad uses it a lot, thanks to the LG smart tv we bought a while back. And the kids section helps entertain the nieces and nephews whenever they&amp;rsquo;re over. For me personally, aside from the old movies and shows I&amp;rsquo;m happy with a lot of the standup content and original shows. I think even with the limited content library, Netflix PH is still pretty good value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not content with Netflix though, I also subbed to Amazon Prime around six months back. Well, back then my primary goal was to get Twitch Prime in order to get some &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal-or-eternal-primer-for-mtg-players/&#34;&gt;Eternal&lt;/a&gt; loot (LOL), Amazon Prime was a nice bonus. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used it too much though. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the new Jack Ryan series, it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/october-2018-watching-lately/&#34;&gt;pretty good&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve also watched a few old movies there, and they have a bunch of comedy series I like such as Community, The Office, Parks, etc. I&amp;rsquo;m coming up on six months for my sub though, which means I&amp;rsquo;m about to lose the discounted new subscriber rate. I don&amp;rsquo;t use Amazon Prime nearly as often as I do Netflix, so I&amp;rsquo;m not yet sure whether I should keep it around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s definitely still a lot of holes in the streaming content available locally though - we don&amp;rsquo;t have Hulu for one thing. And the new services like DC Universe and Disney+ probably won&amp;rsquo;t be available here for a while. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping those companies choose to have Netflix distribute internationally in the meantime. For the regular network shows like the Arrowverse shows, I still have to use traditional less legal methods to keep up weekly. Hopefully we&amp;rsquo;re moving towards a future where international viewers have the same legal streaming options available as the Western world does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I really should cut down on my TV shows though&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: February 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/watching-lately-february-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/watching-lately-february-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;Alita: Battle Angel&lt;/strong&gt;, with the friend who introduced me to the series in the first place. The movie looked fantastic and the fight scenes were great. Plot was supercondensed, several books&amp;rsquo; worth of story combined into one. Ended in a weird place, kinda? Easily the best western live action anime adaptation by far.&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2019-02-07 14:06:10&#34;&gt;7 Feb 2019 2:06pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&lt;/p&gt;

        









  



&lt;a href=&#34;#18a9e28c111c6e73a78bad7b0dd717a5-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/1093511652643762176-DyzvBZ9W0AAC1JS_hu8c01b3250c12dfdca724a95257de8ea7_116708_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up
After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&#34; title=&#34;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up
After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;18a9e28c111c6e73a78bad7b0dd717a5-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/1093511652643762176-DyzvBZ9W0AAC1JS.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up
After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;7 Feb 2019 2:06pm&#34;&gt;7 Feb 2019 2:06pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;







    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another volume of &amp;ldquo;catching up with older films to improve my geek cred&amp;rdquo;, I watched &lt;strong&gt;The Usual Suspects&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. The movie was still really good, despite the internet having spoiled the Keyser Soze twist for me (and countless others) many years ago. I can see why Spacey won an Oscar for his performance here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;strong&gt;Ralph Breaks The Internet&lt;/strong&gt; with the nieces last weekend. The younger one really enjoyed the scenes with the Disney princesses. Movie was pretty good, despite losing the novelty of the first film. Many tropes were visited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over on the Netflix side, I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying &lt;strong&gt;The Patriot Act with Hasan Minaj&lt;/strong&gt;. Highly informative about a wide range of topics, I thought it would be solely about politics, but there were some surprising discussions on things like, uh, shoes? Conservatives may be annoyed by the liberal bias, but otherwise the show does a good job of breaking down complicated topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also had a few seasons of &lt;strong&gt;Family Guy&lt;/strong&gt; up recently, and it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good series to have running in the background while I&amp;rsquo;m working on other stuff so I managed to watch all of it fairly easily. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s good for my mental health though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Seth MacFarlane shows, I&amp;rsquo;ve caught up with &lt;strong&gt;The Orville&lt;/strong&gt; recently, and this show has been great. It&amp;rsquo;s basically &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; for a newer generation, but with a different (and sometimes more interesting) mythos and history and so on. The show is much more willing to tackle complex ideas relevant to the modern world as well. I hope it does well and goes on for many seasons to come.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Be excellent to each other, and party on, dudes
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/be-excellent-to-each-other-and-party-on-dudes/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/be-excellent-to-each-other-and-party-on-dudes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#ece114fafc526b73c9b858e6e11a3e95-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/be-excellent-to-each-other-and-party-on-dudes/be-excellent_hu7e3233b1eb981efa89f666137af55032_58005_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;ece114fafc526b73c9b858e6e11a3e95-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/be-excellent-to-each-other-and-party-on-dudes/be-excellent.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Feb 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;18 Feb 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quote is from the 1980s cult classic &lt;em&gt;Bill and Ted&amp;rsquo;s Excellent Adventure&lt;/em&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t include this movie in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/&#34;&gt;my top 10 movies post&lt;/a&gt;, but it and the sequel &lt;em&gt;Bill and Ted&amp;rsquo;s Bogus Journey&lt;/em&gt; are still among my childhood faves. These wise words are give by the Wyld Stallyns band composed of the epnoymous Bill and Ted, and form the philosophical basis of the future utopian civilization inspired by their music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this quote because it&amp;rsquo;s simple and comprises two principles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be good to other people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enjoy life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, what more is there? And maybe I&amp;rsquo;m reading too much into it, but it has a profound kind of balance too: each principle holds the other in check: you should enjoy life, but not by hurting other people; and you should help other people, but not to your own detriment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(A third movie, &lt;em&gt;Bill and Ted Face the Music&lt;/em&gt; has been greenlighted and might come as soon as end of 2019!)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/be-excellent-to-each-other-and-party-on-dudes/be-excellent_hu7e3233b1eb981efa89f666137af55032_58005_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 14:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/1093511652643762176-DyzvBZ9W0AAC1JS_hu8c01b3250c12dfdca724a95257de8ea7_116708_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: January 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/watching-lately-january-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/watching-lately-january-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bumblebee&lt;/strong&gt; only came out over here in January (thanks to the usual MMFF shenanigans), and I decided to watch it on a whim. Pretty decent soft reboot, read my &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/181926569205/bumblebee-spoiler-free-review-attached-image&#34;&gt;spoiler-free review over on the Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first half of &lt;strong&gt;Young Justice Outsiders&lt;/strong&gt; is out, and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. Focus is back on a smaller group after the larger team in YJ season 2. A few new characters are introduced and I learned about a couple of DC heroes I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with before. Probably still the best animated superhero show to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Netflix side, season 2 of &lt;strong&gt;Punisher&lt;/strong&gt; is out as well. I finished watching it but didn&amp;rsquo;t bother posting a spoiler-free review this time. It was okay, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have much commentary. Not as strikingly good as the first one was, but pretty decent. It feels weird now watching these shows knowing they are likely to end soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 2 of &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; has also started! Only two episodes in so far, but still very good. Feels a lot more classic Trek than the previous season, and a much lighter tone, not just because their captain isn&amp;rsquo;t afraid of the light anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Netflix history also says I watched Bird Box, which became a bit viral early this month for some reason, but that was just my niece making my mom watch it with her, even after I warned her she would get scared (she did).&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Trailers and Spoilers
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/trailers-and-spoilers/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/trailers-and-spoilers/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The first trailer for &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man Far From Home&lt;/em&gt; dropped last week. I used to pretty hyped for superhero movie trailers, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t bother watching this one yet. MCU still has two more movies coming out before this one, and I&amp;rsquo;m already hyped enough for those, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have hype to spare for a third one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My brother was complaining to me about the trailer, saying he was spoiled about some elements. Specifically, he wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware that [actor] was in the movie playing [villain]. I keep up with comic book news, so that wasn&amp;rsquo;t news for me, but I can see how disappointing it might be. Also, this seems to be typical - I check the first trailer for &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man Homecoming&lt;/em&gt; and it did show Michael Keaton&amp;rsquo;s Vulture. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to avoid the villain info, few people consider it a spoiler, it&amp;rsquo;s usually right there in the IMDB page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do think that trailers these days show too much though. During the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been avoiding watching any trailer beyond the first one that comes out. Although given that I follow comic book news, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to avoid spoilers from succeeding trailer. Starting with the new Spider-Man I&amp;rsquo;m considering not watching any trailers at all (at least until I&amp;rsquo;m forced to watch one before an actual movie).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might also be a problem with these comic book movies that they come from an established IP - so someone familiar with the source material like me basically already has an idea of what stuff might happen. The title alone of &lt;em&gt;Avengers Infinity War&lt;/em&gt; gave me an idea of what happens in the movie after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the perfect trailer for a completely new franchise gives you a taste of what&amp;rsquo;s to come without giving you details of the major conflict and so on. The &lt;em&gt;Captain Marvel&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Shazam&lt;/em&gt; trailers have been pretty good in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a sequel, the perfect trailer for me would be the first trailer for &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/em&gt;, which basically acted as a &amp;ldquo;story so far&amp;rdquo;, giving no new info that we didn&amp;rsquo;t know from &lt;em&gt;Infinity War&lt;/em&gt;. Other than the actual movie&amp;rsquo;s title at least, which I had been anticipating for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181926569205/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 16:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181926569205/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;BUMBLEBEE Spoiler-Free review!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- attached image summarizes the plot. loljk (credit: Transformers (1985 - Marvel) #2)&lt;br/&gt;- I&amp;rsquo;m a big Transformers fan, more G1 than Bayverse (I didn&amp;rsquo;t even watch the last Michael Bay one). If you are like me, you will probably enjoy the film&lt;br/&gt;- if you grew up in the 80s like me, you will enjoy the film a bit more. Props to the 80s soundtrack&lt;br/&gt;- the plot is simple, straightforward and unambitious, unencumbered by any of Bayverse Megatron&amp;rsquo;s super-complicated plans that he has been plotting for million of years in case he gets stranded on earth&lt;br/&gt;- not having a plethora of autobot and decepticon characters to develop on each side means the transformers are more distinctive and easier to identify, a big problem I had with the later bayverse films&lt;br/&gt;- i didnt understand some scenes where it looked like the characters were talking to some kind of human soldier but I can&amp;rsquo;t see him?&lt;br/&gt;- foolish humans!&lt;br/&gt;- there is a &amp;ldquo;mid-credits&amp;rdquo; scene; I say &amp;ldquo;mid-credits&amp;rdquo; because they really only show the director credit before immediately going into the &amp;ldquo;mid-credits&amp;rdquo; scene&lt;br/&gt;- magugustuhan ba ni mama: no, she&amp;rsquo;s not into giant robots. the movie is family-friendly, other than the violent explosions&lt;br/&gt;- after the movie, I went to the CR to pee, and I overheard two kids talking: &amp;ldquo;Ano pangalan nung autobot na pula? Christopher?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Cliffjumper!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181926569205/181926569205_huf9e3058d4702a20330a95b2179790058_213102_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: December 2018
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/watching-lately-december-2018/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/watching-lately-december-2018/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I very much enjoyed &lt;strong&gt;Elseworlds&lt;/strong&gt;, the Arrowverse crossover this year. I mean sure, a lot of it didn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense, but it was like a love letter to DC fans. I actually consider myself more of a Marvel fan than DC, but I still loved it! I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/181046297550/aquaman-spoiler-free-review-i-came-in-with-low&#34;&gt;a spoiler-free review over on the Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;strong&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/strong&gt; on a couple of &amp;ldquo;Best TV of 2018&amp;rdquo; lists so I decided to catch up with it since it was on Netflix. I was actually two seasons behind. This series is great, and I really enjoy Bob Odenkirk&amp;rsquo;s portrayal, but it might be just a bit overhyped for me. We already know where Jimmy/Saul, Mike, the Salamancas, and Gus Fring end up given &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;, so that kind of takes away a bit of tension. Still, it&amp;rsquo;s a fine TV show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got caught up with &lt;strong&gt;The Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a weird show for me to watch given how hillbilly it is, but I find the perspective strangely refreshing. Also, Elisha Cuthbert really helps. I was surprised that they had killed off Danny Masterson&amp;rsquo;s character (oops spoilers), apparently it was a #MeToo thing or such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Into the Spider-Verse&lt;/strong&gt; was great, especially for a fan of the comics. You can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/181171084805/into-the-spider-verse-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;my spoiler-free review on tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;Aquaman&lt;/strong&gt; with a friend at UPTC, my first time watching at the theaters there. I had low expectations, but the movie was a surprisingly fun spectacle. You can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/181046297550/aquaman-spoiler-free-review-i-came-in-with-low&#34;&gt;my spoiler-free review on tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At home, I watched &lt;strong&gt;Incredibles 2&lt;/strong&gt; with the niece, who has a bad habit of spoiling things for movies she&amp;rsquo;s already seen. To the tune of &amp;ldquo;Oh, did you know &lt;code&gt;Character&lt;/code&gt; is actually &lt;code&gt;Villain&lt;/code&gt;?!?&amp;rdquo;. Still, the movie was nice, exceeded my expectations. It expanded the Incredibles&amp;rsquo; superhero universe and there was even some surprise Bob Odenkirk!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also watched &lt;strong&gt;Solo: A Star Wars Story&lt;/strong&gt; on Christmas eve (since we didn&amp;rsquo;t get a Christmas Star Wars film this year). We didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to finish it before we went to mass though, so I finished the movie myself a couple of days later. I had skipped watching this in the theater given the mediocre ratings, but now that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it, that&amp;rsquo;s a decision I&amp;rsquo;ve come to regret. It&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable movie with a servicable plot, especially given it&amp;rsquo;s basically meant to expound upon a couple of throwaway lines from the original trilogy. The plot even leaves some dangling threads that could have picked up in succeeding movies, had Disney not decided to scrap (at least for now) the Star Wars spinoff movies. The movie compares unfavorably to &lt;em&gt;Rogue One&lt;/em&gt;, which had the far superior heist scheme. In both movies we expected many of the introduced characters to be killed off, but the Rogue One deaths were much better than the Solo ones. Still, it&amp;rsquo;s an okay addition to the Star Wars universe. I read that it also has some tie-ins to the various animated series, which I&amp;rsquo;m not too familiar with. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get into those someday.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/181171084805/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 16:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/181171084805/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;
Into the Spider-Verse spoiler-free review
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- this is a great animated comic book movie, it makes me happy&lt;br/&gt;- I may have been a bit overhyped by the early reviews, but it was very entertaining, funny and had brilliant presentation, melding the medium of movies with comic books in a way that has never been seen before&lt;br/&gt;- again, the presentation is fantastic, the animation is great and intentional and the funky alternate universe stuff is represented well&lt;br/&gt;- IDK if I would call it the best comic book movie of all time, or even the best Spider-Man movie of all time, but definitely one of the best animated movies of all time, for a comic book fan (highly specific lol)&lt;br/&gt;- in fact, much respect to the writers who dared to bring this story to life. imagine the challenge of pitching a story idea to Sony about not just one new Spider-man, but several alternate universe versions of them. Its not exactly comparable to a Disney movie plot after all, but they pulled it off&lt;br/&gt;- between this movie and the PS4 game, Im happy that Miles is making further inroads into the cultural zeitgeist&lt;br/&gt;- Miles appearance here reminds me of Hey Arnolds black friend lol&lt;br/&gt;- maybe I would have appreciated the movie a bit more if I was into hip-hop or such&lt;br/&gt;- comic book fans will be happy to know that this movie does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; follow the actual Spider-Verse comic book arc along with its convoluted background of the inheritors. The plot and the opposition are much more straightforward&lt;br/&gt;- Will Mama like it? Well like all animated movies, with enough viewings at home by my nieces/nephews, maybe.&lt;br/&gt;- This movie has the best post-credits scene of all time&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/181171084805/181171084805_hu0c2c1a0f92fa5ba5b2cf07594a16512b_113340_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/10157118256658912/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 21:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/10157118256658912/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Aquaman Spoiler-Free review!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I came in with low expectations (given DC&amp;rsquo;s history), but the movie turned out pretty good, even though it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the best comic book related thing I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this week (see previous post)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s fun and action-packed, some fun set pieces and action sequences. Lots of CGI (as can be expected)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the plot is fairly predictable, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen similar story arcs for this character more than once, things pretty much happen as you expect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also the plot kinda feels a bit like black panther, except in reverse? does that make sense?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the first act felt a bit longish, but not really draggy or anything, it&amp;rsquo;s just that there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of set up to be done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the director&amp;rsquo;s horror movie background shines through a bit in one of the sequences around the second act&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had the urge to pee about 1 hour in, but I had to hold it in until the end of the movie, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to miss stuff. So much water didn&amp;rsquo;t help!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arthur&amp;rsquo;s dad looks like a Pinoy lol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t watch in IMAX3D, but I suspect there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of 3d given the volume of CGI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is one mid-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s family-friendly even though there is quite a bit of bloodshed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;magugustuhan ba ni Mama. Eh, maybe? Not really her type of movie, but maybe if I explain it a bit?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spider-verse this weekend!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/10157118256658912/_hu587ef13a5b182ae3696bfd15162b706b_32828_dfc53f04782ccce364738df15d400b87.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: November 2018
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/watching-lately-november-2018/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/watching-lately-november-2018/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, I watched two biopics this month. The first one is &lt;strong&gt;Hidden Figures&lt;/strong&gt;, about three black women who were instrumental during the early days of NASA leading up to the Friendship 7 mission piloted by John Glenn. The movie is fairly interesting if you are even remotely interested in either the challenges faced in black history or math and science or the early days of the space program competition between the USA and Russia. It feels even more appropriate to have watched this since it helps me appreciate the recent Insight mission. (The Oatmeal has &lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/insight&#34;&gt;a fun preview of this event&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second biopic was &lt;strong&gt;Bohemian Rhapsody&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a magnificent film, both for the music and the Freddie Mercury story. I guess it appeals more to those who are familiar with Queen music though. I&amp;rsquo;ve read that the movie isn&amp;rsquo;t super accurate especially with regards to the timeline, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s fine. Both the liberties they take and the music serve to construct a compelling narrative. The movie ends with a ten-minute recreation of the 1985 Live Aid concert and they do a good job of communicating the insane energy at Wembley Stadium back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In less-biographical movies, I also watched &lt;strong&gt;Teen Titans Go To The Movies&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of Teen Titans Go, it&amp;rsquo;s way too silly and it&amp;rsquo;s obviously for kids, I much preferred the previous Teen Titans series. I only got a copy of this movie because my niece said they watched this all the time back home, so now they can watch it when they&amp;rsquo;re over here either. I did enjoy the ridiculous plot and the Stan Lee cameo, but this isn&amp;rsquo;t something I would have watched in the theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In rewatch land, since I finished the Spider-Man PS4 game lately, I also watched &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man 2&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man 3&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Amazing Spider-Man&lt;/strong&gt;, they&amp;rsquo;re nice movies to have playing in the background while you&amp;rsquo;re working on other stuff. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/07/movies-spiderman-2/&#34;&gt;Tobey 2&lt;/a&gt; was pretty good and I think it aged well, I&amp;rsquo;d say comparable with Tobey 1 even. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/05/spider-man-3/&#34;&gt;Tobey 3&lt;/a&gt; was trying to do way too much what with Venom and Sandman and Harry-Goblin. Andrew 1 had a lot of potential, but I think this series leaned too much into the dark and mysterious and sinister plot route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, nothing much other than the usual superhero series, though I&amp;rsquo;m still behind on Gifted and Doctor Who. I caught Trevor Noah&amp;rsquo;s new Netflix special, it was okay, but too exceptionally. Netflix also added a couple of &amp;ldquo;best of&amp;rdquo; seasons of Jeopardy which I thoroughly enjoyed. Watching these makes me think I&amp;rsquo;d never be able to win an episode of Jeopardy, but of course I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s fair to compare myself to some of Jeopardy&amp;rsquo;s all-time champions.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: October 2018
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/october-2018-watching-lately/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 05:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/october-2018-watching-lately/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s Jack Ryan (on Amazon Prime)&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; surprisingly good, even if I&amp;rsquo;m not too familiar with the Jack Ryan stuff. I only know John Krasinski from &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoilers for Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s Jack Ryan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The story starts with Ryan tracking down Suleiman&amp;rsquo;s network via financials, but they never follow-up on who was financing his group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what was the point of the whole drone pilot side story (including the weird trip to the casino and the night with the couple), although it was admittedly kind of entertaining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daredevil season 3 (on Netflix)&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I enjoyed the season a lot. I posted a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/179331448050/daredevil-season-3-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;spoiler-free review over on the ireadcomicbooks tumblr&lt;/a&gt;. Over here I can post spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Murdock&amp;rsquo;s parentage from the comics, so the Maggie reveal came as a surprise to me. A+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sad that there was no Bullseye namedrop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ending kind of flubbed it a bit, could have used an explanation of at what point Matt decided not to kill Fisk. It&amp;rsquo;s not clear if it was something he decided on the spot or if the compromise was part of a plan he devised after interrogating Manning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venom&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I initially wasn&amp;rsquo;t planning on watching this given the terrible early reviews, but eventually I was like, hey I watched &lt;em&gt;X-Men Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt; so might as well watch this too. It turned out not so bad (low expectations helped), although I find the movie&amp;rsquo;s enhancements to the symbiote abilities a bit disconcerting. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/179008685600/venom-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;Read my spoiler-free review here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Batman Ninja &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/179485492410/i-found-out-batman-ninja-is-on-netflix-so-i&#34;&gt;I found out this was on Netflix and went ahead and watched it&lt;/a&gt;. The animations and character designs are nice, but the plot is just ridiculous lol. Feels like someone wrote a Batman fanfic.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/10156982241303912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 19:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/10156982241303912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;VENOM spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if I would watch this, given the poor critical response, but it&amp;rsquo;s an ok movie overall, fun to watch but nothing to write home about (though I wouldnt spend extra for Imax). I would say comparable with Thor: Dark World or Iron Man 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the first 15 mins or so felt draggy, but after that things happen quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;overall plot slightly predictable, and not too long, very straightforward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a tiny bit of humor thrown in, not enough to make it feel like an MCU movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not sure if there&amp;rsquo;s something with the sound editing or some of the actors weren&amp;rsquo;t delivering their lines properly, but I had trouble with understanding the lines in some scenes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Venom symbiote seems to have some extra powers here (as compared to the comics)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tom Hardy does a good job here, I feel like he was having fun during this movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a mid-credits scene and a post-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would Mama like it? Hard no.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>My Top 10 Favorite Movies of All Time
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 01:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This started as one of those silly Facebook memes where you post one thing every day and didn&amp;rsquo;t have to explain and you tagged other people and they continued with the meme. I was very bad at following the meme instructions, but I did find the exercise interesting. I found it difficult to identify 10 specific movies, and since I didn&amp;rsquo;t explain during the FB posts, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d make a blog post about them instead. So here we go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Back to the Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#211954650e5fab190b25a1faa13dc56b-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/35972673_10156725021203912_4346463077705711616_n1_hu9dfa9b6a66ad488017a14ca3b0a59a39_92346_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The meme was supposedly to post movie posters, but for the first few ones I was feeling inspired enough to try to draw the movie posters instead.&#34; title=&#34;The meme was supposedly to post movie posters, but for the first few ones I was feeling inspired enough to try to draw the movie posters instead.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The meme was supposedly to post movie posters, but for the first few ones I was feeling inspired enough to try to draw the movie posters instead. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;211954650e5fab190b25a1faa13dc56b-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/35972673_10156725021203912_4346463077705711616_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The meme was supposedly to post movie posters, but for the first few ones I was feeling inspired enough to try to draw the movie posters instead.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I started the meme, this was the only movie I was sure would be on my list, the only real easy pick. The rest of the list took a lot more thinking. Back to the Future (and the rest of the trilogy, really it&amp;rsquo;s hard to take them separately) is undoubtedly my favorite movie of all time. (And unquestionably the best time travel of all time, fight me!) There is not much to say: it came out when I was growing up and instilled with me a great love for time travel stories of all kinds. I was especially fond of how cleverly all three movies tied together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Star Wars&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#875308872ffa50d886359ed09811a51c-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/13124658_10154577028233912_132731298121342553_n1_hu5cad911239373995ab8d84b28b83ed34_103940_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Han looks terrible in this drawing. I have yet to master capturing RL human faces properly.&#34; title=&#34;Han looks terrible in this drawing. I have yet to master capturing RL human faces properly.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Han looks terrible in this drawing. I have yet to master capturing RL human faces properly. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;875308872ffa50d886359ed09811a51c-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/13124658_10154577028233912_132731298121342553_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Han looks terrible in this drawing. I have yet to master capturing RL human faces properly.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of both Star Wars and Star Trek, but was a fan of light sabers before phasers. The original Star Wars actually came out the year before I was born, and I never saw any of the original trilogy in the theaters (or at least I don&amp;rsquo;t remember doing so). My earliest memory of these movies was watching A New Hope via betamax at my &lt;em&gt;ninong&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; house during one of our visits there when I was a child. ANH is my choice here, but Empire and Jedi hold up really well for me as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Dark Knight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#e616091f8ede1ba0372b1fa03c796486-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36314767_10156731563033912_3316285489241128960_n1_hu1b8f59cb036cf5e37dc07c18e0d2bb4f_78432_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;e616091f8ede1ba0372b1fa03c796486-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36314767_10156731563033912_3316285489241128960_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dark Knight is still easily the best superhero film of all time. Marvel&amp;rsquo;s MCU films have been good and entertaining, but nothing still comes close to Nolan&amp;rsquo;s second outing with the Batman. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of movie where I wish I could watch it again for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Few Good Men&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#aa957a74f77ff856ef90a720b1afb93a-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36233305_10156735952983912_6853244375221141504_n1_hudb065ff79c960b1fd51551660b2710fd_78682_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;aa957a74f77ff856ef90a720b1afb93a-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36233305_10156735952983912_6853244375221141504_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I may or may not have reenacted that final showdown between Caffy and Jessop more than once. This movie is my favourite lawyer movie and/or show of all time, and was a big reason why I enjoyed lawyer shows like&lt;em&gt;The Practice&lt;/em&gt; moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zoolander&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#50b899abdfa867731026ecdc511b3cb3-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36616232_10156747344928912_7709216556856639488_n1_hu9e56f213d8103841d7ca4e585642761b_77187_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;50b899abdfa867731026ecdc511b3cb3-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36616232_10156747344928912_7709216556856639488_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certain elements of pop culture that have a shared special meaning for certain groups of people. Zoolander is one of them. For some reason, me and a group of work friends latched onto the movie and kept quoting it in our internal chats for ridiculous reasons. The movie isn&amp;rsquo;t of the best quality, but it&amp;rsquo;s hilarious and we still randomly say&lt;em&gt;Merman!!&lt;/em&gt; when we see each other. (The sequel did not make any particular impression on our group.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toy Soldiers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#73af35b4e06b140252ea792c276c576e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36606393_10156750051318912_2937498257388994560_n1_huf8c3987b7acfaf1c139350f312ef52f4_94344_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;73af35b4e06b140252ea792c276c576e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36606393_10156750051318912_2937498257388994560_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those weird instances where I can&amp;rsquo;t tell why I like this movie so much. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen it in the theatres or TV nor do I have any digital copy, but I do believe we had a betamax copy of it back in the day and that me and my brother watched it several times. I have fond memories of this movie and being especially excited at the sequence where they use the flying drone thing to create a distraction while one of the kids sneaks out avoiding the hostage takers in order to communicate information to law enforcement, and he has to sneak back in in time for roll call, which he misses and he has to pretend he was in the shower all along. Actually, that&amp;rsquo;s mainly the only part of the movie that I can clearly remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#17915e2f8b54952267619aeb9d3f2f58-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36849180_10156758886428912_8944807849674932224_n1_huebca6b4e75d9adaa678438e6973b744f_111072_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;17915e2f8b54952267619aeb9d3f2f58-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36849180_10156758886428912_8944807849674932224_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit strange for me to have a kind of a sappy romance movie on this list, but it&amp;rsquo;s also an awesome time loop movie that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many, many times. I thought about putting&lt;em&gt;Ghostbusters&lt;/em&gt; on this list as the representative Bill Murray movie, and it was close but&lt;em&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/em&gt; won out, probably because I really really like stories that mess with the flow of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain America: Winter Soldier&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#35cceb2d82c2bc44c509e0b7744cd9e1-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36825371_10156761814598912_5429857823523602432_n1_hu784036112c08a86a93886e8addaada1c_91677_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;35cceb2d82c2bc44c509e0b7744cd9e1-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36825371_10156761814598912_5429857823523602432_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve greatly enjoyed the MCU over the past ten years, so I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure it deserved at least one slot on this list. I waffled between choosing&lt;em&gt;Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt; or&lt;em&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/em&gt; for this, but while the space adventure was fun, I chose the Captain America one because of the timely themes of government surveillance and the government being controlled by evil Nazis and well-meaning civil servants having to defy orders to save the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Street Fighter the Movie&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#0148429c1b9b3104fba412708b5c4543-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36866236_10156763524533912_7213879159724965888_n1_hu78273c5fd6613c6ece6abcc2614de68e_107837_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;0148429c1b9b3104fba412708b5c4543-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36866236_10156763524533912_7213879159724965888_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like&lt;em&gt;Zoolander&lt;/em&gt; was the cult classic for my work friends,&lt;em&gt;Street Fighter The Movie&lt;/em&gt; is the so-bad-its-good cult classic for me and my high school friends. The person who tagged me to make this list had to comment that he wishes he had added this one to his list since we basically quote it all the time whenever we get together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transformers the Movie&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#dd543702ac753002ea253fdb22727625-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36915645_10156766339513912_8749918855305887744_n1_hu93c80739fed7dc6b145b65068e735fa2_166614_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;dd543702ac753002ea253fdb22727625-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36915645_10156766339513912_8749918855305887744_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;12 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Transformers the Movie&lt;/em&gt; is basically a summary of everything that was awesome about childhood pop culture in the 1980s. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad no one ever thought about making a series of live-action movies in this franchise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started this list I had trouble getting beyond the first item, but after having thought about it a while, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of other movies I&amp;rsquo;d have liked to be able to fit in this list._Ghostbusters, Die Hard, the Indiana Jones trilogy, Con Air, Shawshank Redemption, Inception, Infinity War, The Lord of the Rings trilogy,_and that&amp;rsquo;s just off the top of my head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! What are your top ten favourite movies of all time?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/13124658_10154577028233912_132731298121342553_n1_hu5cad911239373995ab8d84b28b83ed34_103940_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Han looks terrible in this drawing. I have yet to master capturing RL human faces properly.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/35972673_10156725021203912_4346463077705711616_n1_hu9dfa9b6a66ad488017a14ca3b0a59a39_92346_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;The meme was supposedly to post movie posters, but for the first few ones I was feeling inspired enough to try to draw the movie posters instead.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36233305_10156735952983912_6853244375221141504_n1_hudb065ff79c960b1fd51551660b2710fd_78682_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36314767_10156731563033912_3316285489241128960_n1_hu1b8f59cb036cf5e37dc07c18e0d2bb4f_78432_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36606393_10156750051318912_2937498257388994560_n1_huf8c3987b7acfaf1c139350f312ef52f4_94344_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36616232_10156747344928912_7709216556856639488_n1_hu9e56f213d8103841d7ca4e585642761b_77187_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36825371_10156761814598912_5429857823523602432_n1_hu784036112c08a86a93886e8addaada1c_91677_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36849180_10156758886428912_8944807849674932224_n1_huebca6b4e75d9adaa678438e6973b744f_111072_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36866236_10156763524533912_7213879159724965888_n1_hu78273c5fd6613c6ece6abcc2614de68e_107837_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/my-top-10-favorite-movies-of-all-time/36915645_10156766339513912_8749918855305887744_n1_hu93c80739fed7dc6b145b65068e735fa2_166614_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/05/10156645641128912/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 23:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/05/10156645641128912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Deadpool 2 SPOILER-FREE REVIEW:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;entertaining enough; kind of a popcorn movie. i kinda liked the first movie better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you watched the first movie, you kinda know what to expect in terms of tone and humor and all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dont bring your kids. but if it matters to you, there is significantly less sex in this movie than the first one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the plot did go in ways i was not expecting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i did not watch in imax, it seemed fine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is a mid credits scene. well, scenes. like five of them strung together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is no end credits scene but there is a&amp;hellip; small bonus near the end if you pay attention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;would i recommend na panoorin ni mama: definitely not&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/05/991719391380176896/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 16:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/05/991719391380176896/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I watched Baby Driver. Great movie. Might have been a bit better if I knew sign language. Kind of makes me want to visit that parallel universe where Edgar Wright got to finish Ant-Man. No post-credit scenes.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Spoiler Alert!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/05/spoiler-alert/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 01:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/05/spoiler-alert/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;When Game of Thrones entered its sixth season in 2016, it was true spoiler territory for those of us who had read the GRRM books before HBO&amp;rsquo;s TV adaptation turned the property into a worldwide phenomenon. Due to the author&amp;rsquo;s glacial writing pace, at this point the TV series went past the point that the novels had reached. Thus nobody &amp;ndash; book readers or tv viewers &amp;ndash; knew what events would unfold in the story. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t watch the episodes until a few days after they air. On the day the first episode aired I found while scrolling through my social media feeds that one of my friends (who shall remain nameless) posted what turned out to be the resolution to the cliffhanger ending of both the previous TV season and the last available book. It was of course followed by immediate comments of &amp;ldquo;Spoiler!&amp;rdquo; from me and a few other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people might say, what&amp;rsquo;s the big deal? When you&amp;rsquo;re invested in a story, getting unintentionally spoiled as to future plot points is a terrible feeling. It robs of you of the the experience, as you now go into the story with certain expectations. You only ever get one chance to watch/read/experience a story for the first time. If you enjoyed that experience, you should be considerate of others and not take that same experience away from them. (Unless they ask for it of course.) Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s just a story. But hey, life is stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The need to talk about what happened in a story is certainly understandable. You&amp;rsquo;re excited about the story and you can&amp;rsquo;t wait to talk to people about it and tell them what you think and speculate about what happens next and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s akin to coming back to school/work on Monday and discussing what happened in your favorite TV shows over the weekend. (Back in high school we probably had multiple Monday morning conversations along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Can you believe Goku is still running down the snake road?&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when it&amp;rsquo;s you and your buddies talking about it over the water cooler after everybody&amp;rsquo;s seen the episode in question that&amp;rsquo;s fine. But in the modern age, we have social media, and with social media comes the tendency to broadcast your thoughts to the world. If you&amp;rsquo;re not careful you&amp;rsquo;re going to accidentally spoil everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing about this because of Avengers Infinity War of course. I normally post a spoiler-free review on Facebook after watching a movie, but there&amp;rsquo;s so much to unpack in this movie I had to get down my thoughts and write &lt;a href=&#34;http://nedstarkdies.com/avengers-infinity-war/&#34;&gt;a spoiler-filled review over on NedStarkDies.com&lt;/a&gt;. Marvel themselves were well aware of the dangers spoilers poised in ruining people&amp;rsquo;s experience of the movie. In the weeks running up to the movie, they ran a campaign to encourage people to avoid spreading spoilers using the hashtag &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23ThanosDemandsYourSilence&amp;amp;src=typd&#34;&gt;#ThanosDemandsYourSilence&lt;/a&gt;. The campaign included a letter from the Russo brothers and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NhLsx3BzsvY&#34;&gt;video message from the cast&lt;/a&gt;. The campaign seems to have been largely successful, which is amazing to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note: I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to watch the movie on the opening day, so it was a bit brave for me to still be scanning my feeds in the days before I was able to watch. But I think I got away mostly unscathed. I will say however, that I do consider as mild spoilers reactions like &amp;ldquo;I need a hug&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;that wasn&amp;rsquo;t good for kids&amp;rdquo;. I mean, that already implies the tone of the ending. But then again, I&amp;rsquo;m probably more finicky about spoilers than most &amp;ndash; these days I tend to avoid all but the first trailer for any movies I plan to watch since I feel that succeeding trailers already tend to spoil too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last spoiler-related anecdote: my brothers and I are big fans of profession wrestling (WWE). We used to follow all the storylines and whatnot. Back in 2005, up-and-comer Dave Batista (who also happens to appear in Infinity War) got his first title shot at Wrestlemania 21. One of my brothers was unable to watch the show at the time that it aired on local TV. But he didn&amp;rsquo;t want us to spoil the match outcome for him until he got a chance to find a copy that he could watch. We didn&amp;rsquo;t want to download it because it would have taken too long on our very slow internet back then. It took him a couple of months to find a store that had DVD copies of the event. As the lady behind the counter handed him the DVD she commented something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;Batista was so good in this event sir, he became the champion!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/04/10156599221698912/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 23:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/04/10156599221698912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Avengers Infinity War Spoiler Free Review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m amazed that so little of this movie has been widely spoiled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movie was fantastic. the movie somehow managed to do everything it needed to do while not doing disservice to any of the bazillion characters involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the plot moves quickly. there is no good time to pee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is one post-credits scene.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;very happy to have watched in imax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/03/973965286964523008/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 16:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/03/973965286964523008/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I just finished watching Annihilation. I have no idea what happened in this movie&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/02/964486985447436293/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 13:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/02/964486985447436293/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;BLACK PANTHER spoiler-free review!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s a fun, action-filled romp and Wakanda is amazing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tchalla was ok, killmonger and nakia were great, shuri was badass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some of the actions scenes didnt seem too well-shot/edited, making them hard to follow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I realize I&amp;rsquo;m saying this about a universe where there are talking raccoons and magic hammers, but some of the Wakandan tech push the boundaries of my suspension of disbelief&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my expectations were probably set a bit too high what with some people saying it&amp;rsquo;s the best MCU movie since Iron Man or calling it revolutionary or eye-opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;off the top of my head I&amp;rsquo;d say I consider Civil War, Spider-Man Homecoming and Thor Ragnarok better than this one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand that it&amp;rsquo;s revolutionary in the sense that it&amp;rsquo;s a major hollowood motion picture filled with a cast of mostly african descent and that some of the characters are motivated by real world racial issues. But the plot itself was typical for an MCU first movie (maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve seen too many MCU movies? lol). I dont think it presents the issues it covers under any new or revolutionary context. I guess I kind of went in hoping to be impressed on the level of The Dark Knight or such, but I was disappointed in that regard. It&amp;rsquo;s a very straightforward movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t watch in Imax, which I kind of regret, as I can imagine some of the scenes being pretty good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Possibly, pero baka mahirapan sya intindihin accent ni Chadwick Boseman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a mid-credits scene and a post-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/12/10156259186658912/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 00:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/12/10156259186658912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;THE LAST JEDI Spoiler-free (promise) review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;great movie, but there was this weird draggy part around the middle that they maybe could have done away with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my brother whom I watched with says he thinks it was the best Star Wars movie ever. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adam Driver needs to either speak up or work around his accent a bit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;because we didn&amp;rsquo;t plan this movie outing so well, we ended up with terrible seats (i.e. very first row, slightly off-center) in the Imax theater. I think the Imax was fine, but being so up close made for some weird angles sometimes and sometimes the 3d didn&amp;rsquo;t work so well from where we were seated. And medyo nakakapagod sa mata. Never again!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;walang post-credit scene lol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/11/931540341919965184/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 15:11:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/11/931540341919965184/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;JUSTICE LEAGUE Spoiler-Free Review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Movie was OKAY. Started out fine, build-up was good, kind of surprised with what happened in the middle, then a disappointing conclusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Movie was SHORT. IMDB says 120 minutes but my watch told me it was &amp;lt; 2h. Probably could have spent more time putting the team together or setting up the characters or such&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie does pander a lot to comic/DC fans; Batman/Superman themes play in the background when they first appear; References to some other DC characters during the exposition, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ugh Steppenwolf so boring and terrible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think Ezra Miller and Gal Gadot were the best here out of the lead roles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A number of fight scenes reminded me of Injustice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the best part of this movie was the Black Panther trailer that I somehow hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen or heard of yet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for some reason the other comic book movie that came to mind was X-Men Apocalupse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gary Oldman should play JJJ in the next Spider-Man so that he and JK Simmons will have effectively role-swapped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one mid credits scene for fun and one end credits scene as a portent of things that may come later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imax was okay. There was one scene where I instinctively moved my head to avoid an incoming projectile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: It&amp;rsquo;s very much a fantasy action movie so probably not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we still get Batman with guns and Superman who threatens to kill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no title drop and no Superfriends reference = LAME&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/10156133009878912/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 22:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/10156133009878912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;THOR RAGNAROK spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a fun, action-packed romp that shakes up the Thor status quo significantly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easily the best of the three Thor movies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a number plot points are fairly predictable, yet still fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Marvel formula is generally action mixed with witty banter here and there, and it&amp;rsquo;s what we get here, although some of the jokes feel like they&amp;rsquo;re stretched a bit too much&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some great-looking cinematic scenes here and there. One particular flashback scene looked really great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I kind of like how the older franchises need to be some sort of team effort nowadays. Like Civil War, this felt a bit like some kind of mini-Avengers crossover &amp;ndash; in space!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;speaking of space, one of the positive things about this installment is that they didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the need to tie Thor&amp;rsquo;s adventures to Earth anymore (not that the movie is 100% Earth-free), and they get to go a bit wild with space and aliens and all that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand the need to highlight Hulk&amp;rsquo;s involvement as part of the film&amp;rsquo;s marketing, but man, it would have been so awesome to just find out right then and there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This movie had that Star Wars: Last Jedi trailer I was trying to avoid D:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 mid-credits scene and 1 post-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think Imax was good for this movie. The 3d wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much and it definitely made some scenes pop. The film is a visual delight so I think the larger screen is important too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Probably not. Maybe I should stop including this section kasi parang same na parati ang answer. Unless for some reason I decide to watch some Tagalog romcom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>