<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>weeknotes on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/weeknotes/</link>
      <description>Recent content in weeknotes on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 02:37:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/weeknotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2021-01-31 Stonks!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-31/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 02:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-31/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s February tomorrow! Somehow, the world still turns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world&#34;&gt;The world:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Somehow the most viral world news this week doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have been about any kind of politics, but rather about capitalism. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1354670019045584899/&#34;&gt;Gamestop/stock market brouhaha&lt;/a&gt; was a sage of retail investors on reddit going head-to-head with hedge funds over the stock price of a dying gaming company (among others) that dominated most of my feeds for the week. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a lot more compliced than that. If you want a more in-depth look, I recommend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/authors/ARbTQlRLRjE/matthew-s-levine&#34;&gt;Matt Levine&amp;rsquo;s Money Stuff column over on Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;, he covered the whole thing for most of the week. You can start &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2021-01-25/the-game-never-stops&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-of-interest&#34;&gt;Links of interest:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tony Hawk, age 52, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tonyhawk/status/1354305117982400514&#34;&gt;can still hit a 720&lt;/a&gt;, probably his last one ever. I think it&amp;rsquo;d kind of a bittersweet blessing to be doing something you love and knowing that it&amp;rsquo;s going to be the last time you get to do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hillelwayne.com/post/crossover-project/are-we-really-engineers/&#34;&gt;excellent series of posts by Hillel Wayne&lt;/a&gt; comparing software engineering to other engineering disciplines by interviewing people who have crossed over from other fields into ours. It addresses interesting questions like whether what we do can really be called &amp;ldquo;engineering&amp;rdquo; and what can software engineering and other engineering fields learn from each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kottke.org/21/01/.usa-downgraded-from-democracy-to-anocracy-part-democracy-and-part-dictatorship&#34;&gt;USA has been downgraded from a democracy to an anocracy&lt;/a&gt;. This was the first time I heard of this term, anocracy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.engadget.com/facebook-political-content-news-feed-mark-zuckerberg-232846266.html&#34;&gt;Facebook says they want to deprioritize political content&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if that holds, given that generating political heat is good for their engagement metrics. But if such a thing were to happen (and applied to the PH), it would seriously reduce the reach of government propaganda.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of Facebook, they appear to have recently &lt;a href=&#34;https://lincoln.metacannon.net/2021/01/facebook-disabled-my-account-after-i-criticized-them.html&#34;&gt;banned someone for criticizing them.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have yet to read through all of it, but there&amp;rsquo;s this metafilter thread full of all sorts of recommendations: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ask.metafilter.com/351766/What-do-you-always-recommend-to-people&#34;&gt;What do you always recommend to people&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This set of Wikimedia &lt;a href=&#34;https://meta.wikimedia.org/wiki/So_you%27ve_made_a_mistake_and_it%27s_public...&#34;&gt;guidelines about how to handle mistakes&lt;/a&gt; is great and people should apply it liberally to most situations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chris Kiehl talks about &lt;a href=&#34;https://chriskiehl.com/article/thoughts-after-6-years&#34;&gt;software dev topics he&amp;rsquo;s changed his mind on after the last 6 years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rands talks about &lt;a href=&#34;https://randsinrepose.com/archives/doomscrolling-at-scale/&#34;&gt;doomscrolling at scale&lt;/a&gt; using Tweetdeck, an app &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/why-twitter/&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always recommended&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://baileye.tumblr.com/post/640943200394231808/andrea-zittel-these-things-i-know-for-sure&#34;&gt;Andrea Zittel: These things I know for sure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The current US senate&amp;rsquo;s President pro tempore has &lt;a href=&#34;https://edition.cnn.com/2021/01/23/us/senator-patrick-leahy-batman-trnd/index.html&#34;&gt;appeared in multiple Batman movies&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://noahpinion.substack.com/p/how-homogeneous-is-japan&#34;&gt;How homogenous is Japan?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-stuff&#34;&gt;My stuff:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily sketches in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook/&#34;&gt;the sketchbook album&lt;/a&gt;, somehow I still haven&amp;rsquo;t fallen behind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started watching the current NCIS season (TIL Fez from That 70s Show is a cast regular there now!) and also a bunch of Mike Birbiglia standup specials on Netflix. I do have other more interesting series on my backlog to watch, but somehow I found myself falling back to procedurals and standup comedy. The main reason is that these things don&amp;rsquo;t require a lot of attention, so I can leave them running in the background while I do other things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I will admit I was a bit meh on &lt;strong&gt;WandaVision&lt;/strong&gt; episodes 1-3 (and even for the rest of the MCU offerings this year), but episode 4 was just fantastic and has renewed my MCU hype. If they manage to hit this level of quality for their other series, we have a lot to look forward to. It makes me a bit sad that the Netflix series/Agents of SHIELD never received the kind of MCU integration these series are getting, but what can you do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of gaming for me this week!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played three whole games of &lt;strong&gt;Civilization VI&lt;/strong&gt; over the past week, two of them before the latest New Frontier Pass drop even. I won one game with the new Civ Vietnam. (I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yJFiA4HBCi8&#34;&gt;streamed a bit of this game&lt;/a&gt; if you want to watch me be dumb.) I&amp;rsquo;m glad I got one already, because I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d play them again, as the terrain restrictions are very challenging. The Corporations mode is nice, but I feel like I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet maximized it too much. It does feel like I&amp;rsquo;ll be enabling this by default from now on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because of reasons, I purchased a copy of &lt;strong&gt;Princess Maker 2 Refine&lt;/strong&gt; on Steam. I played a bunch of the original game back in the day, and it was weird reading through the old guides on GameFAQs and some of them would have advice on configuring old-timey things like &lt;code&gt;config.sys&lt;/code&gt; and such. Anyway, I played almost 5 hours of this in one session, which was really bad for my eyestrain. This was one of the first calendar-based life sims I played, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the reason I really enjoyed the Persona series? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why I found this game in particular so engaging, as it&amp;rsquo;s kind of like watching spreadsheet numbers go up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kaldheim&lt;/strong&gt; is out on Magic Arena! I only had time to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1355164547842248704/&#34;&gt;do a Sealed&lt;/a&gt; so far, but I expect to be drafting (and streaming on Twitch) a few times a week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books:&lt;/strong&gt; Still reading Scott Berkun&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Year-Without-Pants-WordPress-com-Future/dp/1118660633&#34;&gt;The Year Without Pants&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finances:&lt;/strong&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t talk about my finances a lot in this space, but I will note that a couple of weeks ago I started investing in the US markets via an app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etoro.com/&#34;&gt;eToro&lt;/a&gt;. I got lucky with an initial trade that had a bit too much leverage for my taste, because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t reading too carefully. Luckily the NASDAQ spiked that day so I made it out with a bit of profit. I used a bit of that profit to buy-in a minimal amount of Gamestop, trying to cash in on the trend, unfortunately I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get in on a low price. Well, I can afford to risk (and lose) this profit, so that&amp;rsquo;s fine. I just hope the Gamestop thing doesn&amp;rsquo;t crash the markets entirely, that would be just my luck for such a thing to happen just when I started.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz:&lt;/strong&gt; We were still ahead in the AboutQuiz league going into this week&amp;rsquo;s Price is Right-themed game, but we only finished 5th this time, so IDK if that will still hold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had a lot of family errands during the week as well, mostly financial stuff and helping my folks with medical appointments and such. I think this was the week where I had the most trips out of the house since the pandemic lockdowns began.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;site-updates&#34;&gt;Site updates:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you follow this site via an RSS/feed reader (both of you), you may want to know that I&amp;rsquo;ve added a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/daily/feed/&#34;&gt;daily feed&lt;/a&gt; to the site, it will cough up a single post per day with a summary of all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve posted for that day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;looking-forward-to-this-coming-week&#34;&gt;Looking forward to this coming week:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new WandaVision episode!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a new thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to learn/get into, hoping to get started on it this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2021-01-24
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-24/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 05:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-24/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Wow, January is almost done. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you know it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world&#34;&gt;The world:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biden inaugurated as US president, world celebrates US getting rid of Trump. Biden isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly unproblematic, but he is at least sane and boring. There will be time enough to criticize him later, for now let them be enjoy victory. My expectations of him are at least moderately higher than &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/822558467265335297/&#34;&gt;the ones I had for Trump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the internet gets inundated with an inordinate amount of Bernie Sanders memes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;locally: the govt continues to bombard us with controversies, this time stirring up a red-tagging hornests nest by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phkule/status/1351128229462028288&#34;&gt;abrogating the DND-UP accord&lt;/a&gt;, paving the way for militarization of campuses and stifling of free expression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-of-interest&#34;&gt;Links of interest:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone made &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IJH_RbnrGUs&#34;&gt;a Mandalorian trailer in the style of old-school spaghetti westerns&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like this &lt;a href=&#34;https://myk.ninja/loremen&#34;&gt;random lore generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wrote a bunch of words about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/tech-censorship/&#34;&gt;my thoughts on tech censorship and social media&lt;/a&gt;; there are some relevant links in there, if that kind of thing interests you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.idrlabs.com/difficult-person/test.php&#34;&gt;difficult person test&lt;/a&gt; did the rounds in some of my online groups this week (and sparked some silly discussions about gaming self-assessments)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wow, did I not internet that much or was the internet just boring this week? Boring can be good though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-stuff&#34;&gt;My stuff:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily sketches in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook/&#34;&gt;the sketchbook album&lt;/a&gt;, ongoing, streak yet unbroken.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1352137686614564867/&#34;&gt;World War Z&lt;/a&gt;, though I kinda wish I had seen it back at the start of the pandemic, seemed like it would have been appropriate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WandaVision ep 3: So weird! I don&amp;rsquo;t mind the sitcom stuff, though I&amp;rsquo;m mostly here for the Marvel plots. The pacing is fine, with just enough easter eggs and plot teasing to not be annoying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kicked off a second run of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1349796416042856448/&#34;&gt;Fire Emblem Three Houses&lt;/a&gt;! Now in hard/classic, and going down the red/Black Eagle path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG: &lt;strong&gt;Kaldheim&lt;/strong&gt; previews are done, and set is out on Arena next week!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regular Saturday gaming group tried to do some Jackbox games via Discord, but we ran into audio issues, so we ended up just playing Sentinels and Root again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books: I finished reading Katie Mack&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;End of Everything&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;, here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/end-of-everything/&#34;&gt;a short review&lt;/a&gt;. For the next book, I started on Scott Berkun&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Year-Without-Pants-WordPress-com-Future/dp/1118660633&#34;&gt;The Year Without Pants&lt;/a&gt; of which I&amp;rsquo;ve had a copy forever. It&amp;rsquo;s about remote work back in the early 2010s, which is a fun contrast to our current remote work-heavy world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz: We actually won the online Wheel of Fortune-themed AboutQuiz the week before this (forgot to mention in last week&amp;rsquo;s notes), so we were defending champs in this week&amp;rsquo;s Weakest Link-themed quiz, but we were too conservative with our banks and only finished 3rd place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health: Still have muscle pains in my left upper bicep and shoulder, though they seem to be in different places compared to before? Am using this hand massager to massage the area occassionally while I&amp;rsquo;m at the computer, and still continuing the warm compress. Hoping this fixes it up soon, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to ask a stranger to come in and massage me or whatever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the first time since March, I put on pants! I had only been going out in shorts when going to the grocery or the nearby pharmacy, but this week I had to do an errand at a hospital a bit farther away, so I figured it would be a good time to figure out where my pants were. Hospital protocols were strict, as expected. We had to wait in like 3 different waiting areas before we could get to our appointment. This hospital was one of the hotspots back in the early days of the pandemic, so their vigilance is reassuring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PC died unexpectedly today. As in, lost power while I was using it and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t turn back on, power light just blinking. This has happened once before, towards the end of 2020. Back then I had tried unplugging the power supply and opening it up, then reconnecting to see what happened, and it just miraculously fixed itself. This time, I just unplugged the PS, then left it alone for a while. When I came back later and reconnected everything and booted up, it was fine. So I guess there&amp;rsquo;s some issue with the power supply? I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to upgrade just yet, although this rig is already more than 5 years old, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping I can get a couple more years out of it at least. (That and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to go to a shop to have one assembled during the pandemic, and I don&amp;rsquo;t wanna do the assembly myself.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I filled up an online application form for Quezon City&amp;rsquo;s new QC id, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how this goes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;looking-forward-to-this-coming-week&#34;&gt;Looking forward to this coming week:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new WandaVision episode!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kaldheim releases on Magic Arena!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new drop in Civ6&amp;rsquo;s New Frontier pack!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2021-01-17 There May Or May Not Be Sea Shanties
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-17/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-17/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This is 2021 week 3. Or week 2. Two and a half? How do calendars work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world&#34;&gt;The world:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;relatively calm compared to the chaos of the previous week. However in the US, a storm may be brewing over Biden&amp;rsquo;s inauguration next week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;locally: still a lot of confusion/inconsistencies around the vaccination plan. Or at least &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.philstar.com/headlines/2021/01/17/2071005/senate-seeks-further-hearings-vaccines&#34;&gt;some senators think so&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile, we are close to breaching 500k cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-of-interest&#34;&gt;Links of interest:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a lot about personal note taking recently, in a bid to find ways to improve my own systems. I skimmed this book from like 2004ish: &lt;a href=&#34;https://users.speakeasy.net/~lion/nb/html/&#34;&gt;How to Make a Complete Map of Every Thought You Think&lt;/a&gt;, which is like a super paper-heavy system. Probably totally impractical (for me at least), but some ideas there worth considering. The modern day equivalent would be something like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://zettelkasten.de/posts/overview/&#34;&gt;Zettelkasten method&lt;/a&gt;, something I&amp;rsquo;ve also been considering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read this Substack &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulskallas.substack.com/p/is-culture-stuck&#34;&gt;post about culture being stuck in the mid-2000s&lt;/a&gt;, presumably because the Internet became mainstream and people started forming a hivemind around what was popular, and creators responded accordingly by creating more of the same stuff. I think there&amp;rsquo;s still some space for fringe tastes out there, but it is true that pop culture has seemed monolothic recently. What hits me most from the article is the phasing out of rock n roll in favor of hip hop, because a more diverse crowd favors it. I&amp;rsquo;m not really a hip hop person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cory Doctorow &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/13/two-decades/&#34;&gt;blogs about his daily linkblogging process&lt;/a&gt; to celebrate 20 years of blogging. This reminded me that during my recent blog-hopping I also ran across &lt;a href=&#34;https://althouse.blogspot.com/2021/01/another-bloggiversary-this-blog-is-17.html&#34;&gt;Ann Althouse&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;, which has been posting daily for 17 years without breaking the streak! I kind of wish I could be that prolific.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I learned that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liebeck_v._McDonald%27s_Restaurants&#34;&gt;McDonald&amp;rsquo;s coffee lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;, often held up as an example of frivolous ambulance-chasing lawsuits, was much more complicated than that. The woman was hospitalized for more than a week and had to have skin grafts, and McDonald&amp;rsquo;s refused to settle for more than $800, which wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have even covered medical expenses, leading to the huge jury award.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tom Critchlow asks &lt;a href=&#34;https://tomcritchlow.com/2021/01/14/new-browsers/&#34;&gt;why we can&amp;rsquo;t write code in our browsers&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daniel B. Markham argues that &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielbmarkham.com/the-platform-is-the-enemy/&#34;&gt;platforms might be turning us into idiots&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enjoyed this (kinda old) story about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.damninteresting.com/who-wants-to-be-a-thousandaire&#34;&gt;a guy who hacked a TV game show&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not a big fan of Tiktok, but I admit I have been enjoying some of the sea shanty performances coming out of it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/etelsverdlov/status/1348654717036093440&#34;&gt;Example one&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/EKingstonBooks/status/1349906687537373189&#34;&gt;example two&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PH stuff: A trailer came out for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XJ4ChZPlikM&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34;&gt;Voltes V Legacy&lt;/a&gt;, which will be airing on GMA. I don&amp;rsquo;t have high expectations, but the animation seemed decent enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-stuff&#34;&gt;My stuff:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily sketches in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook/&#34;&gt;the sketchbook album&lt;/a&gt;. I used to crosspost them all to &lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/roytang0400&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt; pretty consistently, but now I only do it when I feel like it. Been thinking of getting off instagram anyway, but that&amp;rsquo;s something for another time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finished &lt;strong&gt;Spectacular Spider-Man&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. I liked it, even if it was a kids&amp;rsquo; show. Too bad it was cut off abruptly due to licensing issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also started (re-?) watching Attack on Titan, from season 1, as the final season has been getting some hype. Anime is hard to background-watch though (due to subs), so this might take a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watched my first two movies of the year: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350042544567029763/&#34;&gt;The Godfather&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350361902149324800/&#34;&gt;The Godfather Part II&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First two eps of WandaVision are in! It&amp;rsquo;s so weird. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing how things unfold. Series runs until March, I feel like I should do one of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/spoiler-free-review/&#34;&gt;spoiler-free reviews&lt;/a&gt; when it&amp;rsquo;s done (haven&amp;rsquo;t done any of those in a while) but it feels weird to do it for a show that drops weekly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1349796416042856448/&#34;&gt;Fire Emblem Three Houses&lt;/a&gt;! Will probably kick off the 2nd run sometime this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG: &lt;strong&gt;Kaldheim&lt;/strong&gt; preview season in progress. I am fairly excited for the new set to come in, because I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to draft, the limited environment looks exciting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like I should be starting one of the many Steam RPGs on my backlog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books: Been reading Katie Mack&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;End of Everything&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m around 2/3rds in, so hopefully I can finish it and at least get 1 book in this month lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health: My muscle pains in the left upper arm are still there, although they&amp;rsquo;ve tapered off a bit, I think because I&amp;rsquo;ve been applying warm compresses twice a day for most of the week. Hopefully it will be gone by next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;looking-forward-to-this-coming-week&#34;&gt;Looking forward to this coming week:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biden inauguration (chaos?!?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometime this week, I will probably put on pants for the first time since March.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2021-01-10 Now With More Links
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-10/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 07:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-10/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;We are barely more than a week into 2021 and it has already been quite a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world&#34;&gt;The world:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the week started off with something as innocuous as a guy going viral for making his daughter work six hours to figure out how to use a can opener and open a can of beans. I can&amp;rsquo;t explain &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.billboard.com/articles/news/9506541/bean-dad-explainer-reactions/&#34;&gt;Bean Dad&lt;/a&gt;, but it was so weird and surreal the way it took over the internet for a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;impossible to discuss the last week without mentioning the violent attack by Trump supporters on the US capitol upon incitement by the president himself
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching the events unfolding on the news &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1347017186317983745/&#34;&gt;gave me the same feeling as watching the 9/11 twin towers assault almost two decades ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the subsequent condemnation and consequences not just from US politicians but worldwide, including Trump himself subsequently getting booted off/banned from almost every social media service (of course sparking many opinions about the first amendment and the disproportionate control by tech giants over the public sphere).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s talk of second impeachment and 25th amendment calls (I know about the 25th amendment mostly due to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1347018337990021122/&#34;&gt;Air Force One&lt;/a&gt;), although Pence has thumbed that down. If Trump faces no consequences for this one, they might be looking at something much worse down the line, possibly as soon as the Biden inauguration on the 20th.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s consequences for the actual rioters though: many are being identified on social media and some have already been fired from their jobs. Nascent social media app Parler, used to coordinate the attacks, has been booted off Apple and Google mobile stores AND off their Amazon webhosting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also, gootecks showed himself to be once again a MAGA idiot supporting the violence, so his emote got banned from Twitch, which was a weird piece of news.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yesterday (Saturday) was the feast of the Black Nazarene, a big deal in Manila. It was reported that &lt;a href=&#34;https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1381685/doh-to-quiapo-crowd-watch-for-symptoms&#34;&gt;up to 400,000 devotees&lt;/a&gt; crowded the streets of Manila in what is probably a COVID19 super-spreader event. I mean sure, we held back and stayed at home for Holy Week/Easter/Christmas but somehow we can&amp;rsquo;t avoid celebrating the Black Nazarene. This when our local case counts have been rising since the holidays. Sigh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-of-interest&#34;&gt;Links of interest:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started these weeknotes, I sometimes put in a section with recent links I&amp;rsquo;ve found interesting during the week. It kind of died off, mostly because I haven&amp;rsquo;t been good about going through my backlog of feeds and sources to get much content for the section. I&amp;rsquo;m bringing it back here as a regular section (for now), so that (a) I force myself to go through all that stuff at least once a week; and (b) people who aren&amp;rsquo;t super interested in what&amp;rsquo;s going on with me have more stuff to read in these weeknotes. I also considered just having a separate weekly &amp;ldquo;linkblog&amp;rdquo; post with the links of interest section, but figured maybe I&amp;rsquo;d check first if I can keep up with the volume needed for that sort of thing? Also, a lot of these are available on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/links/&#34;&gt;links&lt;/a&gt; list, which I also share to Twitter/Masto as they come, so if you follow me there, you might have seen me tweet some of these, and this is just sort of a weekly recap. Anyway, for this week, here we go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for gamers, the wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.engadget.com/spotify-persona-5-4-3-fes-2-pq-dancing-arena-soundtracks-104349652.html&#34;&gt;Persona 4 and 5 soundtracks are now officially available on Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for people who like old-school blogs and personal websites: Robin Rendle writes &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.robinrendle.com/essays/newsletters&#34;&gt;a nicely-formatted post about newsletters and writing on the web&lt;/a&gt;, Desmond Rivet wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://desmondrivet.com/2020/04/28/writing-reasons&#34;&gt;about using his blog to manage his thinking&lt;/a&gt; back in Apr 2020, and I realized I never shared this &lt;a href=&#34;https://matthiasott.com/articles/into-the-personal-website-verse&#34;&gt;2019 post from Matthias Ott about personal websites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For self-improvement, ideopunk &lt;a href=&#34;https://ideopunk.com/2020/12/22/100-tips-for-a-better-life/&#34;&gt;talks about 100 tips for a better life&lt;/a&gt;. Probably not all of these are for you, but maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll get some stuff of interest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For optimists, it can be nice to know there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://reasonstobecheerful.world/the-year-in-cheer/&#34;&gt;quite a few bits of good news in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, in spite of everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=snAhsXyO3Ck&#34;&gt;video about lockdown productivity&lt;/a&gt; came out early on in the pandemic, but a lot of the advice still seems sound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enjoyed this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.damninteresting.com/who-wants-to-be-a-thousandaire/&#34;&gt;old story about a guy who gamed one of the earliest game shows&lt;/a&gt; by studying the RNG patterns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some recent Twitter threads of interest:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently, it&amp;rsquo;s a thing for teens &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/unikunka/status/1346602536904523777&#34;&gt;to disbelieve in Hellen Keller&lt;/a&gt;, wth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are told that abusers and white supremacists &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lilithsaintcrow/status/1347293759155838976&#34;&gt;absolutely do not believe their own bullshit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to determine if &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NomeDaBarbarian/status/1338876619205746688&#34;&gt;something is a sandwich&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone compiled some ridiculous &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/paulisci/status/1340764722811957248&#34;&gt;2020 headlines of the year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-stuff&#34;&gt;My stuff:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hey, the new daily habits I kicked off starting the New Year are holding strong so far. Well, except for daily blog posting, I missed yesterday. But I never claimed that as a resolution, so maybe I don&amp;rsquo;t count that.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily sketches in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook/&#34;&gt;the sketchbook album&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;rsquo;re not super good, but maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll like that kind of thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I binged season 3 of &lt;strong&gt;Cobra Kai&lt;/strong&gt; in under 24 hours. Still greatly enjoying it, despite the high school drama. I really like the evolving dynamic between Johnny and Daniel, and the callbacks to all 3 Karate Kid movies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For my background watching I started &lt;strong&gt;Spectacular Spider-Man&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. Not bad for a kids&amp;rsquo; show, covers most of the mythos fairly well, though I&amp;rsquo;m disappointed at how Peter treats Gwen like a sidekick given in the comics she&amp;rsquo;s the love of his life. I&amp;rsquo;m only halfway through, maybe that changes later? I always felt Spider-man was better as a serialized TV series than the constant movie reboots. He has a lot of nice street-level villains and supporting cast that can only feature in a longer storyline than blockbuster movies can afford. Oh well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; Season 3 finale was this week. Nothing too exceptional, I mean, we knew they were going to pull out a win somehow, there were very few surprises. Star Wars wins 2020 I guess lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fire Emblem Three Houses&lt;/strong&gt; still ongoing. I actually took a few days break this week because I felt like I was playing it a bit too much lol. I think I&amp;rsquo;m fairly close to the end though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG: &lt;strong&gt;Kaldheim&lt;/strong&gt; preview season kicked off this week, but nothing too exciting for me so far, though there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of interesting cards of course. Lore-wise, I do like how they translated a lot of the Norse myth stuff into card form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books: Been reading Katie Mack&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;End of Everything&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty interesting so far, but I&amp;rsquo;m less than halfway in, not a good rate. To help reinforce my book reading, I&amp;rsquo;ve switched up my evening meals reading from the day&amp;rsquo;s news to whatever book I have on tap at the moment. It works I guess, but I eat quickly, so I don&amp;rsquo;t get to read much per session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for the past week or so I&amp;rsquo;ve had some kind of strange muscle (?) pain in my upper left bicep, but only when I hold up the arm or stretch it at certain angles. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of annoying, like I slept on it wrong. I thought it would just go away on its own, but now I&amp;rsquo;m thinking maybe it&amp;rsquo;s one of those old age things where things just hurt randomly and you have to live with it?!? Friends recommended trying a warm compress and/or self-massage on the arm, gonna try those out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;looking-forward-to-this-coming-week&#34;&gt;Looking forward to this coming week:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WandaVision kicks off on Disney+! I think we&amp;rsquo;re getting two episodes this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more Kaldheim previews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2021-01-03 Every New Beginning Is Some Other Beginning&#39;s End
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-03/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-03/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a brand new year, a brand new week, a brand new day. There&amp;rsquo;s no real reason to believe 2021 will be a better year, but we can choose to try to be better, and maybe that in itself is better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week&amp;rsquo;s New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve transition played out pretty much as expected. We just stayed at home, actually had an early media noche dinner (around 9ish) and observed the fireworks for a little bit. Yes, there were still fireworks, despite the supposed ban at the LGU level. I would estimate a drop in fireworks volume of maybe 20% at best. Ma says maybe most of those are &amp;ldquo;sanctioned&amp;rdquo; fireworks in common areas, but I remain unconvinced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/2020-year-in-review/&#34;&gt;year in review blog post&lt;/a&gt; covered most of the stats for the past year. I enjoyed putting this together, I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker both for reflecting over the past and for gathering stats, so it&amp;rsquo;s a pleasant combination for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really believe in New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions anymore, but I did decide to try to restart a few daily habits and see which ones stick. Don&amp;rsquo;t feel like talking about them all here, but a couple are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the daily walking, but this time I only do a small loop right in front of the house and still inside our subdivision. It&amp;rsquo;s super boring, so I can&amp;rsquo;t tolerate doing it for too long, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get used to it. I&amp;rsquo;ve started listening to a trivia podcast while walking, maybe that will help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/&#34;&gt;sketchdaily&lt;/a&gt;! This might be the most ambitious one. You can check all my sketches via &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook&#34;&gt;the sketchbook album&lt;/a&gt; on this site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;: Fire Emblem run ongoing! And the usual Eternal, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1344593852154347520/&#34;&gt;Magic Arena&lt;/a&gt;, regular Saturday gaming, etc. I paused on the new Humble Monthly, seems meh. There&amp;rsquo;s still time to get stuff from the Steam sale, but there&amp;rsquo;s nothing particularly interesting. FOR NOW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching&lt;/strong&gt;: I finally watched Wonder Woman 1984. Kind of meh. First one was definitely better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;: I purchased Katie Mack&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;ldquo;The End of Everything&amp;rdquo; on Kindle because it was on sale, hopefully to restart the book reading habit for the New Year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to this coming week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Trek Discovery season finale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG Kaldheim preview season kicking off!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shenanigans in the US congress/senate when they try to certify the EC results. Also Georgia elections determine whether Biden will have Senate support!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-12-27 Season Finale
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-27/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-27/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I started doing these weeknotes at &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/weeknotes-01-12/&#34;&gt;the top of 2020&lt;/a&gt;, so this one signals one complete year of doing my weekly reviews/notes in public. I thought it appropriate for a review!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did it turn out to be a good practice? I think for me yes! Not necessarily for anyone following the blog (all 3 of you), since a lot of the weeknotes stuff might seem boring or irrelevant to you. But for me, forcing me to publicly write some thoughts about the past week has been good for my own self-awareness and keeping me writing regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned this in the first weeknotes linked above, but I used to do private weekly reviews before this. I haven&amp;rsquo;t found much need to supplement the public weeknotes with private ones over the year, but that&amp;rsquo;s basically because (a) my other tracking systems have evolved this year to better capture more data, so less review was actually needed; and (b) this silly pandemic keeping me at home most of the year means there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much to report most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I&amp;rsquo;ll be carrying the weeknotes practice into 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the past week, it was of course Christmas week, which went about as expected. Noche buena night was just me and the folks at home, although the brothers and their families did pass by for a short while on the morning of that day for some gift exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world was relatively quiet. Well, there&amp;rsquo;s finally a post-Brexit trade deal, and Trump seems to be screwing over everybody as expected, and there&amp;rsquo;s a new Covid19 variant, and our government is still being dumb. So, same old same old?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good chunk of my week went towards playing &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1340074409961222146/&#34;&gt;Fire Emblem Three Houses&lt;/a&gt;. As is typical of JRPGs, the startup is a bit slow, but once you get into the whole Persona-like loop of tasks and battles, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty addictive. Pretty sure this will take a while to finish though!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steam Christmas Sale is still ongoing. Thinking of actually getting Hades, because of all the GOTY accolades it&amp;rsquo;s getting. On the other hand, Fire Emblem&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regular weekly gaming with friends: Root, Sentinels of the Multiverse. I also played a couple more Civ6 games for achievement hunting purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new Jeopardy eps on Netflix ran out quickly. Haven&amp;rsquo;t really started on anything seriously yet, though I did watch first episodes of The Expanse S5 and Kimetsu no Yaiba, but I&amp;rsquo;m not feeling like binging either series yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of cramming a few more movies into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;2020 movies list&lt;/a&gt; this week, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if I get around to it or just play more Fire Emblem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To whoever is reading this: despite everything about this year, I hope you somehow managed to have a good holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This coming week: end of year stuff!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-12-20
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-20/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-20/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the penultimate week of the year, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not the only who&amp;rsquo;s had enough of this accursed year and looking forward to moving on to the next one. I know that&amp;rsquo;s silly since the world won&amp;rsquo;t magically become better when the calendar flips over to January the first, but I think it helps our mental health to have this sort of &amp;ldquo;fresh start&amp;rdquo; mentality, even if it&amp;rsquo;s on an arbitrarily chosen date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holiday season continues to be weird, thanks to the pandemic. My brothers and I have been trying to hash out how to have the usual holiday gift exchange among the four households. In theory nobody will be coming inside the house, just parking outside and dropping off and picking up gifts, but they need to coordinate since they also need to exchange gifts with each other. They&amp;rsquo;re trying to see if they can synchronize their visits so that the exchanges can happen, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if that works out. Meanwhile, the usual family and extended family reunions will probably happen on Zoom, like many of my friends&amp;rsquo; recent company Christmas parties. Hopefully they go smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the pandemic and the holiday, cases continue to rise locally. This trend will probably carry on into January as a result of holiday gatherings. In pandemic related government screwups recently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;requiring face shields everywhere in public, even for joggers or bikers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a pilot for face to face classes in January because the education secretary says they are more likely to get infected at home anyway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apparently we could have had vaccines as early as the first quarter of 2021, but the health secretary dropped the ball during negotiations with pfizer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I guess they were working with some sort of backlog due to the holiday sales, but my local gaming store took an entire week to ship me my copy of Fire Emblem Fates. It finally arrived last Friday so yay! I haven&amp;rsquo;t started playing yet, beyond opening the package and checking that the cartridge works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead this week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a bit of achievement hunting in Civilization VI, since a new patch with balance updates dropped last week. I also tried resuming my Wasteland 2 game. It took me a while to get my bearings, but the game just seems so fiddly, I have a hard time getting into it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG: Kaldheim previews started this week! We don&amp;rsquo;t get any more until January though. The metal-themed previews reminded me of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1339627168947601408/&#34;&gt;something from 10 years ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finished The Big Bang Theory rewatch, I totally did not almost tear up at Sheldon&amp;rsquo;s speech in the finale. TBBT gets a lot of flak for being terrible, but I think it holds up reasonably well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caught up with Mandalorian and Discovery. Discovery was so-so, but wow, the Mandalorian. What a fantastic season finale. I watched it around half a day after the episode dropped and I was very happy I wasn&amp;rsquo;t spoiled by the internet. The team behind the show are doing a great job with the Star Wars franchise. After the problematic sequel trilogy (which I still enjoyed), maybe the real future of the franchise is on episodic TV. Looking forward to all the new Star Wars content next year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New background binge watching: There&amp;rsquo;s new episodes of Jeopardy on Netflix! Not a lot, but more trivia is always fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, most of my time was again spent on digging through and sorting old files. Additionally, one of my old external hard drives had also started getting errors, so I ordered and got a new 1tb one, and spent some time trying to move old backup files across from the old drive to the new one. It was annoying because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t play any games that use a controller while this was happening, for fear of disturbing the long file transfers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m kind of looking forward to doing my year in review blog post for this strange and accursed year.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-12-13
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-13/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-13/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Time passes yet again. I think I have to get used to not having much personal stuff to report in the weeknotes on certain weeks (aside from the watching/gaming parts), especially given the pandemic where I&amp;rsquo;m at home 90% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the pandemic, the UK started vaccinations last week, and the US FDA approved the Pfizer vaccine as well, so hopefully this is where things start to turn around. Sadly, it may be a while before vaccinations get widespread, especially here in the Philippines. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping things clear up by mid next year for us here, but I&amp;rsquo;m not optimistic about it. It would be really sad if the pandemic restrictions reach next year&amp;rsquo;s holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that people here seem to realize there&amp;rsquo;s still a pandemic going on, if pictures coming out of Divisoria are any indication. I get that not everyone has access to online shopping, but are there no other options for holiday gift shopping than walking through such dense crowds? This may be one instance where our generous gift-giving culture is bad for us, since people are still out trying to buy gifts when the pandemic is a perfectly good excuse for scaling back on the shopping. Capitalism ho!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The saddest part of this pandemic for me has that my brothers and their families can&amp;rsquo;t come over to visit, which means my parents don&amp;rsquo;t get to see their grandkids (and I don&amp;rsquo;t get to see the pamangkins). Sometimes we push back a bit on that envelope, but it&amp;rsquo;ll be a while before we all really get to see each other and enjoy company in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I managed to finish Batman Arkham Knight! The main story at least. Achievement completion seems unlikely, given the multiplayer achievements, and even some of the single-player ones seem a bit too challenging. I was able to enjoy the game despite the graphical issues I encountered early on. Lowering the settings helped a lot I think, though things still weren&amp;rsquo;t 100% good. I really take to these style of games where there&amp;rsquo;s an open world and you have a lot of things to collect and such.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ordered Fire Emblem Fates for the Switch yesterday! I was also considering Paper Mario Origami King, but that had some mixed reviews, so holding off for now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt; Currently doing a binge re-watch of The Big Bang Theory as my background watching, I&amp;rsquo;m up to season 7 at the moment. I think the show holds up better than some of its contemporaries such as How I Met Your Mother. I know the geek portrayals can be a bit exaggerated or patronizing, so a lot of geeks don&amp;rsquo;t like it, but for me it&amp;rsquo;s fine. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of doing a bad comic book movie marathon sometime this month, covering the ones I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother watching, stuff like Ben Affleck Daredevil, Michael B Jordan Fantastic Four, and the recently released New Mutants. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if I get around to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just under two weeks until Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-12-06
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-06/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-06/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This week felt like another set of those moments-in-between, where not much seemed to happen, but it somehow still went by quickly anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the household and the family has slowly gotten used to the idea that any big Christmas celebration isn&amp;rsquo;t happening. My niece&amp;rsquo;s birthday was last weekend, so we sent her gifts via Grab delivery instead of being able to get together. Most likely something similar&amp;rsquo;s going to happen for gift exchanges on Christmas. We&amp;rsquo;re still trying to figure out what we can do in the meantime. The extended family has proposed a zoom call on the day of, instead of our traditional annual get-together, I&amp;rsquo;ll let them manage the logistics of that, they have a lot of digital natives to figure it out I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past couple of weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve made improvements to one of my side projects which is an app I use for personal data tracking. Improvements to that app&amp;rsquo;s feature set meant I could also take the time to do some digital housekeeping. That mostly means digging into a whole bunch old files to process their contents and possibly extract them the tracking app. Also regular maintenance things like backing up what needs backing up, deleting what can be deleted. It feels appropriate as a near-year-end activity to be going through junk from the past. (Although I should get started on going through actual physical junk as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;: In the never-ending quest to defeat the  gaming backlog, I started working on Arkham Origins. I believe I&amp;rsquo;ve had  my Steam copy for years now, well before I finished Arkham Knight, and  never got around to it. It&amp;rsquo;s not a particularly new game, so I figured  my five-year old PC could handle it fine. However I&amp;rsquo;m experiencing graphical  slowdowns, especially when dealing with bug groups of enemies. I&amp;rsquo;ve  already tried turning the graphics down to minimum settings, but still  experiencing some issues. My suspicion is that it may have something to  do with me currently using an AMD graphics card (the game does say it&amp;rsquo;s  optimized for NVidia when starting up). So maybe I should have gotten  around to it before my old GeForce card started having trouble. It&amp;rsquo;s  still mostly tolerable, and I did manage to get through some of the  quick-time event sections despite framerate drops. I&amp;rsquo;ll stick with it a  bit to see if I can crawl my way to the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt; Finished the binge watch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/perfect-strangers/&#34;&gt;Perfect Strangers&lt;/a&gt;, and have caught up with Mandalorian and Discovery. I also blazed through S4 of My Hero Academia. I&amp;rsquo;d read the manga already, so just skipped ahead through the boring parts. I kind of want them to catch up with the current manga arc, as I want to see some of the more recent fights animated, but I guess that&amp;rsquo;s going to take a while. I also started rewatching The Big Bang Theory as my background show of choice, it&amp;rsquo;s aged reasonably well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned recently that I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write more, and I did manage to churn out one blog post per day last week! Maybe I went overboard? And that says nothing about their quality of course. Still, writing more + going through the past should help me focus my thoughts to help me figure out what I want for the upcoming year (aside from the to-be-expected wish for the end of the pandemic of course.) I&amp;rsquo;m not committed to daily posting, but let&amp;rsquo;s see if I can keep up the writing pace.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-29
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-29/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-29/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;December is almost upon us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had an opportunity last week to take on some additional work, but on further reflection, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d pass on it. I am in general, averse to working during the Christmas season (that is to say, more so than during the entire year in general). Even back when I was working full-time, I&amp;rsquo;d prefer taking most of my leaves during December. It&amp;rsquo;s really a result of the terrible traffic in Metro Manila, which gets significantly worse during Christmas season, a trauma that lingers even when I&amp;rsquo;m home all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past week went by quickly. Not so much because of anything stressful or such, but more like there were a bunch of errands to be done. I also did a bunch of maintenance work for some of my smaller side projects (adding questions to the trivia bot, fixing some bugs in this site&amp;rsquo;s code, adding some minor features to some of my tracking stuff, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t been writing much lately, other than these weeknotes. Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve also found my thoughts wandering a lot and been having difficulty focusing on anything productive. I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel these things are related, and that I should be writing more to help me focus and get back into the habit of thinking better. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if I can get a few more blog posts out in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; Nothing much new. A new drop in the Civ6 New Frontier pass was released a couple of weeks ago, so I played a few Civ6 games this week to try things out. The new leader/civ (Hammurabi of Babylon) was pretty fun, kind of a unique experience, and I like the Heroes and Legends mode. I actually want to try the other new game modes added by the NFP recently, it&amp;rsquo;s just that Civ games always take so long, so it&amp;rsquo;s hard to fit them in when I have other single-player games I want to play. Steam Autumn sale is currently ongoing, but so far I have taken no damage (though I did let myself get billed for November&amp;rsquo;s humble choice). I kind of wanted to buy a couple of additional Switch games, but I might just start something on my very extensive Steam backlog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books:&lt;/strong&gt; I finished &lt;em&gt;Rhythm of War&lt;/em&gt;! Fun book, I may write a longer review, as I kind of regret not having a review for the previous book Oathbringer, as I had nothing to go back to as a bit of review before starting on Rhythm of War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt; I think I&amp;rsquo;ve only been watching more Perfect Strangers this week. Two more seasons to go! This also means I&amp;rsquo;m behind on the Mandalorian and Discovery, which means I risk spoilers lol. Should try to catch up this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; December? Christmas? Not really, not so much, though it can&amp;rsquo;t hurt, but I&amp;rsquo;m counting the days until we are rid of this accursed plague year.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-22 The Moments In Between
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-22/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-22/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This week felt weird. It kind of went by quickly for me, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like anything important really happened. Its kind of like those moments in-between other events, where you&amp;rsquo;re just coasting along and waiting for the more significant things to happen. My country is still recovering from the storms of the past few weeks, Trump is still flailing around trying to overturn democracy, and our own president is still insecure when someone gets more attention than him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These moments feel fleeting, but they&amp;rsquo;re a pretty good time for some self-reflection. I probably need a bit more of that, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found my mind has been wandering through parallel universes lately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I pushed the post-game completion on Super Mario Odyssey, but I might just be at my limit. I have 7 moons remaining, and 5 of those are for minigames, and the last 2 are for the super frustrating Breakdown Road stage. All of these probably require a great deal more patience than I have available, so that might be it for me. Still, it was a great ride, and I&amp;rsquo;m proud I can even get this far given I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself great at platformers nowadays. Still looking around for a new single-player game to dig into, not sure if I want to do another platformer or look for an RPG or such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magic:&lt;/strong&gt; Still been drafting a bit of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgkld/&#34;&gt;Kaladesh Remastered&lt;/a&gt;, although it seems the draft format doesn&amp;rsquo;t like me very much. I&amp;rsquo;ve gone a single 5-3 and three 0-3s, so it&amp;rsquo;s pretty bad! Still, I can keep doing at least one draft a week until Kaldheim comes out next year I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Rhythm of War&lt;/em&gt;, fourth book in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s Stormlight Archive came out this past week! I got a Kindle copy off Amazon and have been reading a few chapters every night. I&amp;rsquo;m about a third of the way through I think. The problem with this book is I didn&amp;rsquo;t do a re-read of the previous books (they&amp;rsquo;re pretty long!) so every few chapters I&amp;rsquo;m like &amp;ldquo;Who is this person again and why is she here?&amp;rdquo;. This is a typical problem for epic fantasy series like this, so I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have this same problem if/when GRRM manages to get &lt;em&gt;Winds of Winter&lt;/em&gt; out. (I think these two are the only unfinished fantasy series I&amp;rsquo;m still following.) I will say that Sanderson still writes quite well, and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this gets me back into the habit of reading regularly again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I caught up with the Mandalorian, pleasant surprise to see Katie Sackhoff around, apparently playing a character she voiced in Clone Wars (which I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen). Since I caught up with both Mandalorian and Discovery mid-season, now I have to wait every week for new episodes, like some kind of peasant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For my background binge watching, I found some old copies I had of Perfect Strangers, so I&amp;rsquo;ve burned through a few seasons of that already. I loved this series when it was on TV back when I was young. It&amp;rsquo;s not particularly deep; most episodes have the same plot of &amp;ldquo;Balki does/says something naive and/or Larry overreacts and gets them into trouble and hilarity ensures&amp;rdquo;, but it&amp;rsquo;s still fun, and has probably one of the best ever TV show opening themes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;hellip; don&amp;rsquo;t know? US thanksgiving is next week, which is mainly relevant for me because there&amp;rsquo;s usually a bunch of gaming sales at the time, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in yet. There&amp;rsquo;s also some family events coming up (my eldest niece&amp;rsquo;s birthday), but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to get excited about those since we can&amp;rsquo;t actually get together.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-15 Winds and Rain
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-15/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-15/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Weather this past week was very bad for those of us in Metro Manila (and many other places in Luzon). Howling winds and strong rains dominated for 2-3 days of the week due to typhoon Ulysses. This typhoon wasn&amp;rsquo;t as strong as Rolly a couple of weeks ago, but it seems that it brought a lot more rains, causing flooding and loss of power in a whole lot of places. Metro Manila was hit quite badly, even drawing comparisons to Ondoy back in 2009. Even up to today I&amp;rsquo;m still reading about a ton of people who need assistance, relief or rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fortunately got off relatively unscathed. The howling winds and pouring rain meant it was heard to sleep at some point, but we experienced no other bad effects and in fact were a bit more comfortable due to lower temps. Oh, and we still don&amp;rsquo;t have cable service until today, a minor inconvenience. A lot of my friends lost power and some in the more Northern provinces were subject to severe flooding as well. It also took us a couple of days to get in touch with some relatives on the southern side of Luzon, but it seems they are fine, power issues notwithstanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; Still playing Super Mario Odyssey, hopefully to completion. Although given how difficult some of these minigames are for me, I&amp;rsquo;m not optimistic. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how close I can get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magic:&lt;/strong&gt; Kaladesh Remastered is out on Arena! I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten started on a sealed and a draft, you can follow along via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgkld/&#34;&gt;MTGKLD tag&lt;/a&gt;, if you&amp;rsquo;d like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Boys S2: Surprisingly the Boys kind of got a &amp;ldquo;good ending&amp;rdquo; this time, although there are still threats lurking around. I went back and reread the first Omnibus of the comic book after finishing the season, and the differences are really stark, as in the comics Butcher is really portrayed as a bastard, maybe even as much as Homelander, while in the series they&amp;rsquo;re pretty tame by comparison. Somehow a lot of the issues raised in this season feel topical too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Trek Discovery S3: Season isn&amp;rsquo;t done yet, but I went ahead and got this started. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a trip. Discovery is charting an unknown future now in the Star Trek timeline, and there are a lot of fun moments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Queen&amp;rsquo;s Gambit: This Netflix limited series has been getting a lot of buzz so I decided to give it a go. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly good, in a sports anime kind of way.  It&amp;rsquo;s a testament to how good and realistic the portrayal of the 1960s chess scene is that for a while I thought it was based on a real-life chess prodigy. Apparently, the show is based on a novel instead, a well-researched one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Misc:&lt;/strong&gt; In the starting-yet-another-side-project department, I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with this library called the Dragonruby Game Toolkit, which I got from the itch.io Racial Justice bundle a while back. I tried building a simple platformer using a Kenney asset pack that I also got from the bundle. Here&amp;rsquo;s the WIP: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MDRShB4psyU&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MDRShB4psyU&lt;/a&gt;. I like that I can work with the framework using only my text editor (as compared to some big bulky IDE like Unity), and it&amp;rsquo;s fairly quick to start up, as it makes a lot of assumptions for you so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about things like screen resolution, screen coords, fps, etc. I don&amp;rsquo;t doubt that using Unity might have made the platforming physics a bit easier, but I did enjoy figuring things out on my own. Not sure if this is going anywhere, I&amp;rsquo;m mostly just dabbling with it at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trivia:&lt;/strong&gt; we actually won an online quiz this past week! Amazing. We had so much fun, we even went ahead and had our own internal 2-hour trivia quiz right after: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=no0sYBcU5LA&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=no0sYBcU5LA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; I just found out that the next book in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Stormlight Archive&lt;/em&gt; is coming out next week! That&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a huge book, hopefully I can manage to finish it before year-end (so that I can at least get my books read stat for the year up a tiny bit)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-01 A Collective Sigh of Relief
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-08/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-08/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The World&lt;/strong&gt;: Somehow the week seemed to go by both quickly and agonizingly slowly, mostly because of the US presidential elections held this week. Slowly because after the initial burst of results on Tuesday night (US time), the remaining states&amp;rsquo; results trickled in very slowly. Quickly because much time was spent doomscrolling and refreshing election-related updates. I think the world collectively breathed a sigh of relief this weekend as the US networks finally called the race for former VP and now president-elect Joe Biden. Celebrations on the streets in many cities in the US, notably New York and Philadelphia. Trump still won&amp;rsquo;t concede and vows legal action, but that seems unlikely to go anywhere except make him look immature and pathetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biden isn&amp;rsquo;t even the best or most exciting candidate, and it&amp;rsquo;s still to be seen how he handles crises like the BLM and police brutality stuff and even healthcare, but at the very least the US will now have a coherent leader and hopefully will be able to address the pandemic better. I would guess that Harris as VP will ultimately end up the more historic win. But I imagine the celebrations are less about Biden winning and more about Trump losing. It must be weird to be a fanatic Trump supporter seeing all these people celebrating his loss. He still got a lot of votes - America remains a deeply divided nation, but at least under Biden there&amp;rsquo;s a chance of that being rectified at least a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have written a lot of words on this topic, considering I&amp;rsquo;m not an American. My stakes in this are a bit lower, but I still found myself glued to the ever-changing blue and red numbers. The US leadership affects the rest of the world of course, especially in terms of climate change and multilateralism moving forward, so it&amp;rsquo;s serious business. But I admit, I also enjoyed the drama and the memes. I had more than one chat groups where some of the members were living in the US, and let me tell you, they were super active during this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of all this drama has to be the whole &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/trump-four-seasons-total-landscaping_n_5fa6e08bc5b6f21920dc14f7&#34;&gt;Four Seasons Total Landscaping&lt;/a&gt; brouhaha. Basically, Trump announced his lawyers would have a press conferencce at Four Seasons in Philadelphia, then later corrected himself saying it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the Four Seasons Hotel, but rather Four Seasons Total Landscaping. Basically a parking lot in an industrial area, next to a dildo shop. It smacks of incompetence and miscoordination of the highest order. It&amp;rsquo;s the kind of comedy that TV shows just can&amp;rsquo;t make up, proving indeed that reality can be stranger (and funnier) than fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump&amp;rsquo;s loss is a repudiation of his style of populist, lying leadership. I wish I could say I was as hopeful for similar positive change in my own country in two years, but that remains to be seen&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, back to my stuff lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server migration update:&lt;/strong&gt; Today, I&amp;rsquo;ve closed my account at the old hosting provider, so there is no more turning back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I started and finished Super Mario Odyssey! Just about a week, but that was main game only, finished with a bit over 400 moons. (I believe I can get up to 999 in the game?). Immediately proceeding into the post-game, since I only borrowed this game, so I want to get as close to completion as I can before I have to give it back. That being said, there are some moons gated behind annoying minigames like jump rope, RC racing, etc, which I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d have the patience to grind through, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see. After Odyssey, I&amp;rsquo;ll take it easy on the Switch games for a little bit, though I am already considering getting either Fire Emblem or the new Paper Mario. Would be good to get back to an RPG after all these platformers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt; About halfway through The Boys season 2 now. More thoughts when I finish I guess? I thought about watching a Sean Connery James Bond flick when he died this week, but neither Netflix nor Prime had any, sadface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got a new pair of glasses last Wednesday, but up to today my eyes still feel like they are adjusting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not start Nanowrimo. I started trying something else instead, not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s gonna go anywhere though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing I was anxious about last week never pushed through. I should care less about things!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; Kaladesh Remastered comes out next week on Arena, so there&amp;rsquo;s that!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-01 Storm&#39;s comin&#39;
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-01/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-01/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now:&lt;/strong&gt; Stormy weekend here in Manila. Supposedly the &amp;ldquo;strongest storm of 2020&amp;rdquo; so far, typhoon Rolly made landfall earlier today and is currently battering many of the provinces south of Metro Manila. Storm signals are as high as number 5. As of this writing, weather is currently cold and nippy but not particularly rainy where I am. We expect stronger winds and rain to hit us as evening approaches as well. On top of everything, a second typhoon has entered the PH area of responsibility and is expected to affect us over the next couple of days as well. If those two typhoons get together, it may be very bad. Hoping for the best. (I thought about doing these weeknotes end of day&amp;hellip; but we might lose power, so here we go.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server migration update:&lt;/strong&gt; Migrating the final domain now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/&#34;&gt;Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening!&lt;/a&gt; Full heart and seashell completion even! It was fun and a great throwback to classic games like Link to the Past. I never played the original on Gameboy, though maybe that&amp;rsquo;s for the best, as I liked how this one looked and my memory is not tainted by nostalgia over GB graphics. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a particularly long game, especially compared to other Zeldas, but there is a custom dungeon feature (new to this remake) which probably adds some replay value, though I don&amp;rsquo;t have much interest in it at the moment. On to Super Mario Odyssey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I did terribly at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal/&#34;&gt;Eternal Card Game&lt;/a&gt; worlds LCQ, but I must admit their current celebration promo was super effective in getting me back into the game, as I&amp;rsquo;m now doing daily grinds in both Eternal and Magic Arena again. I managed to hit Mythic in Magic Arena before month end, but didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough time for Eternal, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if I can keep it up next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying games of &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/965580/Root/&#34;&gt;Root&lt;/a&gt; with the Saturday gaming group. It&amp;rsquo;s a multifaction boardgame where each faction plays differently and has different ways of scoring victory points, and the factions will naturally clash with each other. The main challenge is finding a fine balance between advancing your agenda and interfering with the others. Disrupting the other factions might lose you some momentum compared to the others, but if no one keeps the others in check, someone might run away with victory! Pretty fun. And given that the game supports asynchronous games (up to 3 days per turn), the term &amp;ldquo;Saturday gaming group&amp;rdquo; is a bit obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Done:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober2020&#34;&gt;the Inktober thing&lt;/a&gt;! I managed to get through the whole thing without missing a day! Doing daily drawings with a pen are hard for me, given my poor manual dexterity at this age (and it was never that good in the first place). My hands got tired so easily, and a lot of my lines were shaky. Still, I enjoyed doing a lot of the sketches, and while I don&amp;rsquo;t want to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/&#34;&gt;commit to daily drawings&lt;/a&gt; again (at least for now), maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll warm up the old Apple Pencil every so often and do some digital stuff? Maybe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching lately:&lt;/strong&gt; I finished Season 4 of The Expanse. I didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy it as much as the first 3 seasons, though the second half was better than the first. Things were ramping up too slowly, and a lot of things didn&amp;rsquo;t seem relevant to the what was going on with the Roci crew (and turned out to be mostly geared towards next season&amp;rsquo;s big crisis apparently?). As I said to a friend, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m here for the scifi protomolecule stuff not OPA terrorist or earth politics BS.&amp;rdquo; Still, looking forward to the next season. Also: Finished five seasons of NCIS (that&amp;rsquo;s all they had on Prime Video). In the queue: The Boys S2, Star Trek Discovery S3, Mandalorian S2. Where&amp;rsquo;s my Orville?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skipped:&lt;/strong&gt; Hacktoberfest. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Considering:&lt;/strong&gt; Nanowrimo. Haven&amp;rsquo;t done any prep, so if ever it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a late start. I do have some ideas rolling around in my head, but I also have some other stuff to do, so for now let&amp;rsquo;s say this is &amp;ldquo;low probability&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anxiety:&lt;/strong&gt; Low, most of it due to awaiting a call back about something that hasn&amp;rsquo;t pushed through yet, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really need? Why am I anxious about it then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Random:&lt;/strong&gt; This storm reminded me of my worst typhoon experience in Metro Manila, Ondoy back in 2009, so I wrote a short &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/09/ondoy/&#34;&gt;back-dated retrospective on it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad luck:&lt;/strong&gt; The hinge on one side of my glasses&amp;rsquo; frame broke while I was at the cashier at the grocery yesterday! D: I have a slightly older pair I can use in the meantime, but it&amp;rsquo;ll probably be a few days before I can even go to get a real replacement, given the storm and the long weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; the US presidential elections, with a mix of morbid dread and anticipation, like an onlooker at a car crash.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-10-25
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-25/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-25/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Server migration update: I had encountered some trouble with the Travis-CI -based Hugo build generating this here website last week. Luckily, most of the migration work to the new backend was already done, so I went ahead and switched over the servers. So this site is no longer plain-old deployed HTML, but rather powered by a Django backend. The site should be mostly the same, though I did take the opportunity to move some stuff around. There&amp;rsquo;s probably some bugs floating around, and maybe some secrets even. Probably need a longer blog post writing about the migration itself, though it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too complicated. I also have a bunch of notes about the server setup that I&amp;rsquo;ll also carve into a blog post when I have time. Things should be mostly done for this site, but I have one other domain I have to migrate, and I have scheduled that for the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means that hopefully all my apps/domains will be on the new server after the first week of November. My account at the old webhost is paid until Nov 15th, and I&amp;rsquo;ve already indicated I don&amp;rsquo;t plan to migrate to whatever new system they have, so it&amp;rsquo;s just in time I think. Hoping things go smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming: I did &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1318238520251621377/&#34;&gt;the 120 stars &amp;ldquo;completion&amp;rdquo; for Super Mario Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;, although that&amp;rsquo;s really more like half of actual completion. I put down the Switch for a few days after that to cool down on it for a bit, as I have been playing it a lot since I got it. Still deciding whether to play Odyssey next or try Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming: I haven&amp;rsquo;t played &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal/&#34;&gt;Eternal Card Game&lt;/a&gt; in months, which meant falling behind on the collection as new sets came out and such. But they&amp;rsquo;re running an event right now where all accounts have access to all cards, and there are qualifiers for their worlds event. I figured why not and gave it a shot, running a deck I got from their recent tournaments, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1319794495395745793/&#34;&gt;managed to qualify for the LCQ on my first try&lt;/a&gt;. Eternal has always been a fun game, but the past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve preferred playing on MTG Arena. The timing of this Eternal event was pretty nice, as it came up just after Arena got a patch that severely downgraded the UX, with bugs being reported everywhere and general laggy performance. The Eternal client was, as always, snappy and had no issues. Arena dev team needs to get their act together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still ongoing: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober2020&#34;&gt;the Inktober thing&lt;/a&gt;. Still haven&amp;rsquo;t missed a day! This week is the final stretch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not ongoing: Hacktoberfest. I mentioned before that I was planning to do it, but&amp;hellip; I haven&amp;rsquo;t. Less than a week to go, so doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem likely I can get into it, especially since other things have come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my current webhost finally decided to give me a deadline, the long and short of it is that my new server needs to be ready by December the 9th, giving me a bit under a month to get things in order. I&amp;rsquo;m already in the middle of setting up the new server, so I think I&amp;rsquo;ll be ready by early November anyway. Most of the code to run the new blog is also mostly ready (who knows how many bugs there are though!) I am (re-)learning a lot about server setups though, so hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have quite a few blog posts to write the migration is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching lately: Mostly old NCIS seasons still, and I&amp;rsquo;m just past the halfway point on The Expanse season 4. Slow going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward to November, and am awaiting the outcome of the US presidential elections with morbid interest.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-10-18
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-18/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-18/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So my current webhost finally decided to give me a deadline, the long and short of it is that my new server needs to be ready by December the 9th, giving me a bit under a month to get things in order. I&amp;rsquo;m already in the middle of setting up the new server, so I think I&amp;rsquo;ll be ready by early November anyway. Most of the code to run the new blog is also mostly ready (who knows how many bugs there are though!) I am (re-)learning a lot about server setups though, so hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have quite a few blog posts to write the migration is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming: Hey, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1317023064555548672/&#34;&gt;finished Super Mario Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;! There&amp;rsquo;s 15 post-game stars only available after beating the game, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to work through them before moving on to Odyssey, alhough some of them are quite stressful. (Apparently there&amp;rsquo;s an entire 120 stars again afterwards in some kind of second quest, but I figure I can come back to that some other time.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still ongoing: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober2020&#34;&gt;the Inktober thing&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s surprising that I haven&amp;rsquo;t missed a day yet. (Hopefully I haven&amp;rsquo;t jinxed it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching lately: I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to having old seasons of NCIS running in the background (via Prime Video) recently, they&amp;rsquo;re the sort of show you can just leave running while you&amp;rsquo;re doing other things, and if you miss something it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. I also started on Expanse season 4, but that requires more focused watching so the going is slow. I have some backlog to work through, since The Boys season 2 and Star Trek Discovery season 3 are both out now.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-10-11
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-11/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-11/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The world continues to be terrible. The PH government wants people to get back to work and everything to spur the economy (with health precautions and everything). A lot of people have no choice, but I&amp;rsquo;m fortunate enough to not have to go out there yet, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure people like me will still hold back. This all would have been a lot easier if the government had gotten control of this pandemic early on but it is what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still not writing blog posts apparently. I have a lot of thoughts swirling in my head, I&amp;rsquo;m sure they&amp;rsquo;ll pop out sooner or later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming: Hey, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1314224120490389504/&#34;&gt;finished Super Mario Sunshine&lt;/a&gt;! I started Super Mario Galaxy right afterwards. It&amp;rsquo;s actually interesting playing through these 3d Mario games for the first time, since I can see how things evolve. Will hopefully have some good thoughts for the eventual review, probably after I also play Odyssey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still ongoing: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober2020&#34;&gt;the Inktober thing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still ongoing: The site rewrite project. It&amp;rsquo;s going reasonably well, and might be ready soonish (famous last words), so I started looking into the new server as well. I&amp;rsquo;ve also mentioned before that I&amp;rsquo;ve been planning to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/rip-webfaction/&#34;&gt;migrate to a new webhost because GoDaddy etc.&lt;/a&gt;, and I had been leaning towards getting a VPS on Linode so I tried to do that this week, but for some reason they kept rejecting my application, so I just went with DigitalOcean instead. They give free two months $100 credit, so I&amp;rsquo;m not paying for anything until December or such, so that&amp;rsquo;s nice. I spent a couple of hours wrangling with Nginx + uWSGI + my app on Ubuntu, with permission problems and everything. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll figure it out eventually!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some recent fun things on the internet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Toadsanime/status/1312880060899233797&#34;&gt;Twitter thread about free indie games&lt;/a&gt;. Not like I have time to play all of these, but I find it fun to browse these lists and fantasize about my lifelong dream of being an indie game developer that I still hope to eventually get back to someday (why not today)? Anyway, check them out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vulture.com/article/most-influential-best-scenes-animation-history.html&#34;&gt;100 Sequences that shaped animations&lt;/a&gt;. Some fun history of animation stuff to go through.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vBpxhfBlVLU&#34;&gt;Why do mirrors flip horizontally but not vertically?&lt;/a&gt;(Youtube video). I always have trouble explaining this, so this one was nice to watch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.playstation.com/2020/10/07/ps5-teardown-an-inside-look-at-our-most-transformative-console-yet/&#34;&gt;Sony released a PS5 teardown video&lt;/a&gt;. My biggest takeaway from this is that this console is HUGE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-10-04 Switching It Up
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-04/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-04/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the news this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donald Trump, who for some reason is still the US president, has tested positive for Covid19, adding even more chaos and uncertainty to the US election season. The rest of the world has no choice but to pay attention, given how much US politics affects the rest of us&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Philippines is now #20 worldwide in total Covid cases, yay! Yay?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some drama about the PH congress leadership? IDK, whatever man.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annoyingly, I&amp;rsquo;ve not been doing any blog posts other than these weeknotes during the past few weeks. It is what it is though. I guess I haven&amp;rsquo;t really had time for longer writing things lately?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; busy, but the I have felt busy during the past week. Part of it is probably becaause I&amp;rsquo;ve started &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober2020&#34;&gt;doing the Inktober thing&lt;/a&gt;, so that&amp;rsquo;s an additional daily task. Another part of it is probably the fact that I purchased a Nintendo Switch last week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, gaming then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the aforementioned Nintendo Switch. I got Super Mario 3D All Stars and Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening together with the purchase. I originally wanted to get Mario Odyssey, Fire Emblem and Paper Mario as well, but I figured two games (really four) was plenty for a first set, and my brother was going to lend me Odyssey anyway. I started playing &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/1310497720117784577/&#34;&gt;Mario 64&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not too far in, but I found the camera really problematic, and I can&amp;rsquo;t play it for too long without getting dizzy. I also started playing Super Mario Sunshine, which was a noticeable improvement camera-wise, and I can play it for extended periods without dizziness problems, so I&amp;rsquo;m quite a bit farther along there. I hope to get back to Mario 64 eventually, but it&amp;rsquo;s no big loss if I don&amp;rsquo;t. I understand it&amp;rsquo;s a classic game a lot of people look back fondly on, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s aged well, and not just because of camera problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also tried the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1311655542008377346/&#34;&gt;free Super Mario 35 battle royale game&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s reasonably fun, although when you&amp;rsquo;re at the last 2-3 players, it takes a while to get to a winner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally managed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1311602939891535872/&#34;&gt;hit the 7 wins in Zendikar Rising draft&lt;/a&gt;! Standard is still terrible though. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll just play 1 draft a week and that&amp;rsquo;s it? The MTG community was also in an uproar the past few weeks, both due to the poor state of standard and due to some controversy over an upcoming Secret Lair crossover with The Walking Dead. WOTC has implied they are looking at expanding Magic mechanics to other IPs, so the TWD thing is mostly a trial balloon, I think. Many people are upset and are predicting the death of Magic, but the game has been pronounced dead before. We&amp;rsquo;ll see what happens. I&amp;rsquo;m not personally affected (since I don&amp;rsquo;t Commander), my primary concern is the health of Standard formats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday gaming group picked up a new multiplayer game, it&amp;rsquo;s Root, from Leder Games (and published for digital by Dire Wolf, creators of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal-or-eternal-primer-for-mtg-players/&#34;&gt;Eternal&lt;/a&gt;). It&amp;rsquo;s reasonably complicated, and thematically and mechanically quite different from the last digital boardgame we were doing (Blood Rage).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned last week that I was planning to participate in &lt;a href=&#34;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/&#34;&gt;Hacktoberfest&lt;/a&gt;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet, and there was some controversy over the past few weeks, with OSS maintainers complaining about spam PRs due to the event. Apparently, it was the fault of a Youtube who had a few hundred thousand followers. He had made a video showing how easy it was to make PRs and win the event swag, and a lot of people were following his low effort examples. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll still participate, though I have been looking around a few repos here and there, we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched anything of note the past week. A couple of standup specials on Netflix, that&amp;rsquo;s it. I guess the Switch took most of my entertainment time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IFTTT, a service I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/ifttt/&#34;&gt;been using for a while now&lt;/a&gt;, has &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1312652625511280640/&#34;&gt;obnoxiously been insisting I upgrade to their Pro tier&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;rsquo;re going to start severely restricting free accounts, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking to minimize my usage of the service moving forward. All of the social media syndication stuff can be handled by the new blog backend I&amp;rsquo;m writing, so that&amp;rsquo;s fine. The only things that should remain are stuff I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked into automating myself yet, mainly backing up of SMS, so I&amp;rsquo;ll probably look into that soonish. I&amp;rsquo;m not against paying for services, but in this case it&amp;rsquo;s simply not worth it for me, since I can trivially write my own replacement software for most of my usage of the service. So long IFTTT, it&amp;rsquo;s been swell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no closing words of wisdom today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-09-27
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-27/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-27/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;October is imminent! There are two distractions I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to in the coming month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one is &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober/&#34;&gt;Inktober&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing since 2016. Basically it&amp;rsquo;s just to do 30 ink drawings in October, one per day. There are some &lt;a href=&#34;https://inktober.com/rules&#34;&gt;official prompts&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;ll probably follow. I haven&amp;rsquo;t really done any serious &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook&#34;&gt;sketching&lt;/a&gt; in a while, maybe this will help me get back into the groove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one is &lt;a href=&#34;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/&#34;&gt;Hacktoberfest&lt;/a&gt;! Basically it&amp;rsquo;s an event where you have to submitted some number of GitHub PRs in October, and there&amp;rsquo;s some swag for people who finished. I last &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/hacktoberfest/&#34;&gt;participated in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, skipped last year because I was a bit busy. I have a bit more free time this year, so hopefully I can get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these are welcome distractions, as the world continues to suck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on the Django-based rewrite for my personal site (this one!). It&amp;rsquo;s one of those projects where I find myself being productive not because of deadlines or anything like that, but because I genuinely enjoy working on it. When I find myself thinking of of new things that need to be done, or a new feature, or a way to solve an interesting problem, I am cursed (blessed?) with restlessness until I get it done. There are a number of challenges with the way I chose to approach this problem, most probably the subject of a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned this before, but I went ahead and paid for a year of the Micro plan on Migadu.com. The email in/out limits aren&amp;rsquo;t that high, but the price is decent, and I don&amp;rsquo;t really use my personal email that much anyway (I&amp;rsquo;m no spammer!). I&amp;rsquo;ll re-evaluate next year whether I want to migrate. (Sets a calendar event.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I went ahead and watched the second season of Umbrella Academy. It&amp;rsquo;s more or less structured like the first season: each member has their own problems; five discovers an upcoming apocalypse, so he tries to bring everyone together; also, there&amp;rsquo;s people who want to kill them. The ending of this is more satisfying than S1 though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enola Holmes on Netflix. It was ok, but it&amp;rsquo;s more of a young adult story, maybe a bit above the Nancy Drew/Hardy Boys level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming this past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;managed to get in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgznr/&#34;&gt;couple more Zendikar Rising drafts&lt;/a&gt;. Fun format, but I continue to have a terrible record, with only one draft actually going well. I did get a refund for that last one, so let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can&amp;rsquo;t do better this coming week!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;additional drop on the Civ6 New Frontier pass came out, giving us Gaul and Byzantium. A friend and I tried it in a multiplayer game. I played Byz and he went with Gaul; we only played for a couple of hours, but both new civs seem quite powerful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my SC2 group managed to finish the Wings of Liberty coop campaign! Pretty fun, and it was fun to relive the story too, as I had already forgotten a lot of it. We started the Heart of the Swarm version the next day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday gaming group have been playing Blood Rage over the past few months, and it even came out with a new DLC/expansion a couple of weeks ago. The game client is a bit buggy, but we tolerate it because it&amp;rsquo;s a fun/deep game anyway. We&amp;rsquo;re looking at maybe trying out a different game next week though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trivia was meh this week, the topics weren&amp;rsquo;t really to our liking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I purchased last month&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humblebundle.com/subscription&#34;&gt;Humble Choice&lt;/a&gt; (or rather, let it lapse into purchase). It&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable, there&amp;rsquo;s some games there I can try like Forager and Evoland, and given my recent streak of Mario playing, I was wanting a platformer for the PC, so Yooka Layle isn&amp;rsquo;t a bad idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Late-breaking Sunday news: I have kind of impulse bought a Nintendo Switch. Well, I was agonizing over it for a while, but stores were selling it just a bit overpriced. Today I found that there was a slight price drop (around $40 worth) of the Labo bundle at one of my local stores, so I impulsively went ahead and ordered it. Maybe should have waited a day or so? regardless, it&amp;rsquo;s on the way, along with Zelda: Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening and Super Mario 3D All Stars. No interest in the Labo personally, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll try to sell it off?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried using Messenger Rooms for a family conf call today, in lieu of Zoom which limits us to 40-minute calls. Might have been bad luck or poor internet, but the experience was substantially worse. Disconnections, lag, poor video quality, etc. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if they want to switch back to Zoom next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems weird that we are so close to the end of 2020 now. Still no idea what Christmas is going to look like. I&amp;rsquo;m sure many other people are also looking forward to closing out 2020 and going to 2021, even though that holds no logical promise of things being better than they are now. But we can always dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-09-20
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-20/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-20/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine this is already the 3rd week of September, it feels like the month is passing by quickly, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t been particularly busy recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did do some paid work this past week; not a lot, just filling in to provide some emergency support/consultation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess the reason it feels like the week passed by quickly is that I started a new side project (like many programmers, I am afflicted by the curse of wanting to start too many side projects). This one will probably get finished: I&amp;rsquo;m writing a Django based server for this website. I am generally happy with the current Hugo workflow I use for publishing things here, but the build times have struggled with the sheer number of posts I have. This started back when I decided to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/archive-of-my-own/&#34;&gt;start importing my social media activity to this site&lt;/a&gt;, which increased the post count from a couple of thousand to more than twenty thousand now. Even the automated builds take forever, and I can&amp;rsquo;t even run the local Hugo build on my laptop due to too many open files error on Mac. And Hugo is already one of the faster static site generators, so I have doubt that other SSGs would be able to solve this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I briefly considered moving back to Wordpress, but that seems like a step back. I also briefly considered writing a new backend using a new programming language like Rust, giving me an opportunity to learn something new as well. But I kind of needed to get this done quickly, given that I have a pending server migration within the next couple of months; it&amp;rsquo;s not necessary, but it would be nice to have the new system up in place by the time I do that, so that all the migration happens in one go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still generally happy with the workflow of writing using my local editor and pushing markdown files to git, so I plan to retain that. The Django webapp will have a database, but that will be a secondary data structure used mainly for indexing and searches. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be some kind of weird file system/database storage, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes. Anyway, probably more details on all that when I am ready to deploy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching this past week: I finished both seasons of Cobra Kai. The series is decent. I&amp;rsquo;m here mostly for the Karate Kid nostalgia and the Lawrence/LaRusso rivalry. Season two had a lot of high school drama, which I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too interested in, so I liked the first season a lot more. Will still probably watch S3 when it comes out on Netflix. Now to figure out what to watch next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming this past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zendikar Rising is out on Magic Arena! I&amp;rsquo;ve already played a couple of drafts, but things didn&amp;rsquo;t go as well as I hoped, so now I am poor, will probably be able to draft again in a couple of days. Hopefully I get better at this format, as I&amp;rsquo;ve been planning to draft this set a lot; posts on these should be under &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgznr/&#34;&gt;the mtgznr tag&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t play much else this week other than the regular multiplayer games with the gaming groups SC2, Blood Rage, etc. I have yet to find a new game to knock off the backlog. I have also been considering trying out some of the smaller indie games in my collection, and maybe streaming some let&amp;rsquo;s play/reviews for them, as a bit of support for indie game devs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this week was the much awaited PS5 announcement, with pricing and release dates and everything! The $499 price tag is reasonable, but I probably won&amp;rsquo;t be getting one on launch, since there&amp;rsquo;s not a lot of games I want immediately. I will admit to getting a bit excited at the FF16 reveal, but that&amp;rsquo;s probably a ways off. I&amp;rsquo;m probably more likely to get a Switch first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trivia team put up a new chaotic video of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U52L9c2kB8M&#34;&gt;us playing some trivia&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out, like, subscribe, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big news from the other side of the pacific is that US SC Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg has died. &amp;ldquo;No no no&amp;rdquo; was trending on Twitter for a little bit, and a lot of people on my timeline were swearing. I had a short discussion with some friends living on the west coast about it. Many of my US friends also have some level of anxiety/worry about what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen during/after their elections. It&amp;rsquo;s actually annoying how informed I am about US politics, although it doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect me directly. Like it or not though, the US further sliding into single-party autocracy will likely be bad for the rest of the world, so let&amp;rsquo;s all hope they get their shit together.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-09-13
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-13/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-13/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It has certainly been a week, yes it has. The world continues to turn (and burn even).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy. Not so much with work, though there was a bit of that due to a required emergency software change (aren&amp;rsquo;t they always emergencies?). I wasn&amp;rsquo;t doing the emergency work myself, more like consulting and advising how to approach it, so not much to tell there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did quite a bit of work on my personal data processes/backups/workflows. It involved streamlining my backups, dedepulication, going through old records and cleaning them up, and so on. Some combination of Python scripts and manual work was required. One specific thing I did was to get a whole bunch of my old photos out of Google Photos and onto disk backups, and also had to do some deduplication there. I was able to remove around 1300 duplicates from over 12000 photos, so around 10% ish duplication rate, not too bad. My original intent was to remove them from Google Photos, dedupe, then add them back, but now I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure I need to add them back. The main advantage of Google Photos has been that they make the photos more searchable, but I don&amp;rsquo;t seem to have an urgent need for that anyway, and probably there are other ways to do that? I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll look into it when the time comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also been browsing some old (physical) albums stored around the house. There&amp;rsquo;s another few thousand photos there, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of eventually digitizing them, as a means of backup, but that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of work, so maybe in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming was good again this week. I finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/&#34;&gt;Uncharted 4&lt;/a&gt;! I guess any week where I manage to tick something off the backlog is a good week. Last weekend I mentioned I was near the end, that was so untrue lol. Turned out more than half the game was still to come. My SC2 buddies and I started to play this 3-player coop version of the Wings of Liberty campaign (avaiable as custom arcade things), that&amp;rsquo;s been fun. Then the usual stuff: Blood Rage with the Saturday group. Quiz nights/codenames with the trivia team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kind of want to get into SFV again, presumably there&amp;rsquo;s a flood of new players coming in recently since it was free on PS+ this past month, so hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t be so hard to find matches this time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My desire for a Nintendo Switch is being tempered by two things at the moment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rumors of a new, upgraded Switch coming out next year. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the first time that I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased a console just before it&amp;rsquo;s successor came out though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;frustration at the difficulty of the special stages in Super Mario 3D Land lol. It&amp;rsquo;s a stark reminder that I&amp;rsquo;m getting old and I&amp;rsquo;m not as good at these games as I used to be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this week, I binged four seasons of Superstore. It&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable enough ensemble comedy, though it&amp;rsquo;s no Brooklyn Nine Nine. A lot of the characters&amp;rsquo; problems are of their own making due to selfishness, that&amp;rsquo;s always annoying. But it&amp;rsquo;s good enough for side-watching while I&amp;rsquo;m doing other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also started watching Cobra Kai, not even halfway through the first season yet. It&amp;rsquo;s slightly painful, since it casts Johnny Lawrence as the POV character/protagonist, and he&amp;rsquo;s kind of a loser asshole, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My desktop PC seems to be showing it&amp;rsquo;s age. It&amp;rsquo;s like recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been hitting 100% CPU and/or RAM much more often. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried uninstalling some unneeded software, hopefully that helps. I got this PC back in 2015, so it&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable that I might need an upgrade soon, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I want to spend that money yet. I&amp;rsquo;m kind of hoping it can still hold on for a few years still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same thoughts for the rest of the world, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-09-06
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-06/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-06/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s September! The last six months were a blur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s considered &amp;ldquo;Christmas season&amp;rdquo; over here already I guess. The local memes are that once the clock hits midnight between Aug 31 and Sep 1, your neighbor&amp;rsquo;s Christmas lights are magically up. Also of course the famous Jose Mari Chan gets famous starting September, since malls and stores love to play his Christmas songs during this time. IDK what to expect for Christmas season this year though, since we are still in a pandemic. I keep telling my mom not to get her hopes up that we (i.e. my brothers and their families) will all be able to get together as tradition dictates. It&amp;rsquo;s possible, but I&amp;rsquo;m not optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My week was kinda busy. Not really in terms of work, but in terms of&amp;hellip; high school stuff, I guess? My high school batch hosted our 25th year alumni homecoming this past weekend. Since we were unlucky enough to have it in the middle of the pandemic, it was an online-only affair, with presentations and raffles and whatnot. And a quiz night! A lot of my batchmates did a lot more work, my participation was mostly limited to some tech stuff, since I had access to the database of registrants for the raffle, and also representing the batch at the Pisay Quiz Night held online. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only PQN team member, I was just the one assigned to join the zoom and show the whiteboard; I was drafted against my will due to my past quiz night experience. My other batchmates were supporting me from a Discord, I basically streamed the Zoom call to them via Discord (which is really troublesome, always has tech issues) and they fed me possible answers etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting my PQN participation to take too much time, but there was like a tech rehearsal and a dry run before the event proper, to make sure everything worked well and that all the team got it, plus my team also got together a couple of times for &amp;ldquo;practice.&amp;rdquo; I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to take it seriously, as with all online quiz nights I&amp;rsquo;m mostly there for the fun since it&amp;rsquo;s super likely for at least some people on some teams to be googling their answers lol. The PQN is super competitive though, I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s to be expected given the nature of Pisay. We didn&amp;rsquo;t win, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen the final scores yet, but I guess that we finished around middle of the pack among the 22 teams, but we had a good time (more or less!) and it was fun hanging out with the batchmates virtually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming this week was pretty good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/1301222471568297984/&#34;&gt;and finished Disco Elysium&lt;/a&gt; during the first half of the week. Fantastic game, and I was probably unhealthily engrossed in it for like 2-3 days. I was so into the whole mystery thing, when the game warned me that I was at a critical point and that proceeding further would end other sidequests, I just created a save and pushed to the finish anyway. I went back later to load and finish the other side stuff. It&amp;rsquo;s the kind of game you&amp;rsquo;d enjoy if you like getting your Speech skill to 100 in Fallout. It&amp;rsquo;s very well-written and had some really great/shocking moments. Since it has very little actual &amp;ldquo;action&amp;rdquo; aside from delving inside the MC&amp;rsquo;s thoughts, I understand that it&amp;rsquo;s not for everybody, but it&amp;rsquo;s certainly a worthwhile experience. I thought about writing a full review post, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for when/if I manage full achievement completion (looks tough!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;after getting distracted by Disco Elysium, I went ahead and resumed my Uncharted 4 game. I think I&amp;rsquo;m close to the end on this one, should finish it this coming week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;already half way through the Super Mario 3D Land special worlds. Speaking of Mario, Nintendo announced a bunch of new Mario releases for the Switch this past week, which significantly increases my want for a Switch. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how long I can hold off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;still playing my regular games with the playgroups: Starcraft 2 Coop, Blood Rage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it&amp;rsquo;s September, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing my regularly quarterly data backups/exports. One of them is Google Takeout. The last one was back in April, and that last export was 27 chunks (they split it into 2GB or less chunks). The new one is 44 chunks! I suspect the huge increase is because I&amp;rsquo;ve been streaming on Twitch and exporting them to Youtube, so they&amp;rsquo;re probably part of this current export. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even export everything this time, since I don&amp;rsquo;t need to re-export data from those services I&amp;rsquo;m no longer using. One of my ongoing projects is reducing my Google footprint, so I need to figure out how to get the size of this export down.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-08-30
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-30/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-30/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This last week was weird. I feel like I didn&amp;rsquo;t really get much done in terms of productivity, yet I don&amp;rsquo;t feel I was unproductive. A very relaxed and chill week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again a tiny bit of work done this past week, some fixes, including to side projects. I also spent some time preparing for some events next weekend. Although I wasn&amp;rsquo;t productive this week, I did outline a bit of a roadmap of new features for one of my side projects, hopefully I can get into that in the coming weeks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still in a pandemic! But I did have my first dine-in meal at a restaurant last Monday. It was because I went to get blood drawn for routine medical reasons, and I had needed to skip breakfast for the test (spoiler: my blood sugar levels were very, very normal). So after getting the blood drawn I was super hungry and decided to have breakfast at the nearby Pancake House. I was the only customer since it was super early (and you know, pandemic), although a second guy came in after I had given my order. I almost subconsciously picked up the glass of water to sip from it as soon as it was served, luckily I remembered I was wearing a face mask and a face shield. I decided to hold off on removing the gear until the actual pancakes were served, to minimize the exposure time. The next day I also decided to have a snack at a Starbucks after running some errands, mainly because I had a free coffee from Globe Rewards. It was afternoon so there were a few other customers there. The cashier said it was ok to dine in, but for a maximum of one hour only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a longish post I was writing, but it felt too raw to publish and might break it up into smaller posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We actually managed to win an online quiz night this week! It&amp;rsquo;s been a while, good job trivia team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels great to no longer be following the covid19 stats regularly, even though they are still fairly terrible. UP experts are projecting that we get the reproduction rate to below 1 in like a month though, so that&amp;rsquo;s some good news, though we may still be a ways away from getting this under control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching and playing the past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still playing a lot of SC2 Coop, trying to unlock the new prestiges. Levelling the commanders again can be a pain, but at least they managed to provide new goals/objectives for the players, breathing back a bunch of life into this game mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still drafting Amonkhet Remastered, although the last few drafts haven&amp;rsquo;t gone well. Need to save up gems, so I&amp;rsquo;ll do one last one draft once I get enough gold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huh, I guess I kind of paused Uncharted 4 for most of the week, not sure why. I should get back to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started re-playing Super Mario 3D Land (on the 3DS) lately, mostly to stave off my desire to get a Nintendo Switch (prices are still inflated here due to supply issues!). I had forgotten a lot about this game, so even when I finished the first 8 worlds and rescued Princess Peach, I was pleasantly surprised to find there were another 8 &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; worlds to play!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watched the video game history documentary &lt;strong&gt;High Score&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. Pretty good, although there&amp;rsquo;s some Dragon Quest erasure going on in the RPG episode!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watched &lt;strong&gt;Bill and Ted Face the Music&lt;/strong&gt;, this was a most excellent sequel. I found the start a bit clunky (I always find it awkward watching characters be awkward), but the rest of it was a fun and sweet adventure that echoed elements of both of the first two movies. A lot of the time travel stuff didn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense if you sat down and thought about it, but I was smiling through a lot of it. Little Billie and Theda are great!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also watched &lt;strong&gt;Superman: Man of Tomorrow&lt;/strong&gt;, the first entry in the new DC animated universe (following the reboot at the end of Justice League Dark: Apokolips). Yet another Superman origin story here. Not too happy with this one. Not fond of the animated style, and the writing and plot seemed weird at many points. I felt like there could have been a better way to resolve the whole situation with the big bad that felt more &amp;ldquo;Superman&amp;rdquo;-like, and the movie doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to earn the monicker &amp;ldquo;Man of Tomorrow&amp;rdquo; for the hero.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for one reason or another, I also ended up watching a few standup specials on Amazon Prime. A couple from Craig Ferguson, and one from Jimmy Yang.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cobra Kai is now on Netflix! Yet another thing to add to the ever-increasing backlog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tech stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have about three months left on my Webfaction hosting, which I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/rip-webfaction/&#34;&gt;been planning to migrate away from&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m currently leaning towards getting a cheap $5/mo VPS from Linode, although I&amp;rsquo;m still willing to accept any recommendations. Switching to a VPS means more effort (since it won&amp;rsquo;t be a managed service anymore), but that should provide some learning opportunities. It&amp;rsquo;s just as well anyway, my apps have been pushing the memory limits on the current hosting, and even the cheapest Linode VPS provides more RAM.  I&amp;rsquo;ll probably start looking into the migration in September.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wrote before about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/gmail-migration/&#34;&gt;migrating away from GMail&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Migadu.com&amp;rsquo;s free tier for about half a year now. This past week, they wrote that they are sunsetting the free tier. Totally understandable, given the economy. They are also introducing a new Micro tier at $20 a year, with slightly better limits than the old free tier, so I may migrate to that near the end of September (when the free tier runs out). In theory, I could just try to run a mail server on whatever VPS I set up (see above bullet), but that&amp;rsquo;s a big hassle. This cost + the $5/mo for the VPS is still less than what I was paying for at Webfaction, so I don&amp;rsquo;t mind paying for this for a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was notified by a local bank that their old web platform is being sunsetted and I needed to migrate to the new system, so I did that. But whenever I tried the migration steps, the process never completed, it just kept telling me it was processing. I finally had to message someone I knew on the dev team lol. Hopefully it can getr resolved next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-08-23
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-23/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-23/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The week after I posted about phoning in the weeknotes, here I am with one where there&amp;rsquo;s nothing much to report. Not that surprising, given how busy I was over the previous few weeks, I took the opportunity to take a more relaxing week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a bit of work to be done, but very miniscule by comparison. Minor fixes here and there, including to some side projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did get to write on the blog more, as expected. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope I can keep it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These week&amp;rsquo;s quiz nights were terrible for our team, but on the bright side, I got to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/quiz-night-sketches/&#34;&gt;do a couple of sketches&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching and playing the past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued drafting Amonkhet Remastered, although the last few drafts went a bit poorly. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgakr/&#34;&gt;mtgakr tag&lt;/a&gt; on this site has all the records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After finishing D:OS2 and FF7R, I looked around for a new game to start and decided on Uncharted 4, which I guess I got free from Plus or something. I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten very far yet, but unsurprisingly Nathan Drake&amp;rsquo;s antics still really challenge one&amp;rsquo;s suspension of disbelief. He has to be one of the most peak-performance athletes in the world to consistently pull of the jumping and wall climbing stunts he regularly does. Not to mention being able to win over basically hordes of heavily-armed mercenaries in gunfights. Not that it&amp;rsquo;s not fun and engaging as a game, it just feels so ridiculous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dcfandome.com&#34;&gt;DC Fandome&lt;/a&gt; was today, I watched some panels and new trailers and such. I enjoyed the Suicide Squad reveals and the Wonder Woman 1984, Shazam 2 and Justice League Snyder cut trailers, plus previews for the new Gotham Knights and Suicide Squad games, looking forward to those. (I should probably get around to Arkham Origins first.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuing to play SC2 coop and Blood Rage with the regular groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that there&amp;rsquo;s anything wrong with a bit of relaxing downtime, but I am hoping to eventually ramp up to being more productive in the coming weeks, especially with the side projects.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-08-16 The Sameyness Report
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-16-the-sameyness-report/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-16-the-sameyness-report/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;These weeknotes are coming in late in the day because of reasons. (The reasons being laziness and procrastination.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve been kind of phoning in the weeknotes over the past few weeks, they&amp;rsquo;ve mostly been &amp;ldquo;hey, I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy, so nothing of significance happened, but here are some things I watched/played.&amp;rdquo; Supposedly one of the side effects of writing regular updates is that you tend to look out for more interesting things to do so you have something to write about, even on an unconscious level. In the past few weeks, that has been problematic because (a) as mentioned, I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy with some things, so my excess time is devoted to less mentally taxing things like just watching movies/shows or destress with games; and (b) we are still in the middle of a pandemic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the pandemic, I read this piece recently on the Financial Times: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ft.com/content/32d79c87-1ade-4b63-8d14-7af1a553d963&#34;&gt;We wont remember much of what we did in the pandemic&lt;/a&gt;, about how the sameyness of our days in quarantine means our brains compress that data since so little of it is meaningful, affecting our perception of time. When 99% of your activities take place in the same environment, in your room during a zoom call, everything just tends to blur together. And I guess that reflected in the weeknotes too! (For that reason, I&amp;rsquo;m switching up the weeknotes format today to be more freeform prose, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if it sticks.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the pandemic part 2, one thing I have been doing since the pandemic started is writing a regular series of notes, first as &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;one long post that I kept updating every couple of days or so&lt;/a&gt; then later I transitioned to regular weekly update notes, on the same day as these weeknotes. The idea was that in the future I could just browse the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/covid19/&#34;&gt;covid19 tag&lt;/a&gt; on the site and I could recall what things were like during the days of quarantine and the quality of the government response. And this was fine during the start, since things happened and unfolded quickly. But these past few months, the updates have fallen in the quagmire of sameyness as well: I only went out once every 1 or 2 weeks, everything was always getting worse, cases were always going up, government response was always terrible, and so on. One thing the last few months has made clear for me is that the government has no clear plan on controlling this thing and so I am highly pessimistic that things will change anytime soon. For that reason, I&amp;rsquo;m just going to pause on doing the covid19 update notes for now, unless some drastic change happens.(I have no expectation of Russia&amp;rsquo;s vaccine having any effect on our status quo anytime soon!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, so how was my week? I wrapped up the things causing my busy-ness towards the middle of the week, so I expect to be less busy/stressed during the coming weeks. At the very least, I should be able to write on the blog more, and maybe do some work on some of my other side projects. I actually thought about writing some posts already last week but I was like you know what, I&amp;rsquo;ll just relax and watch things and play things and leave the writing to next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching and playing the past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marvel&amp;rsquo;s Agents of SHIELD had their series finale last Thursday. I enjoyed the first half of this season, but the second half and the finale were just ok, maybe slightly meh. Still, the series finale was pretty good, wrapping things up nicely with a big bow. This series had a lot of haters, I think mostly because of mismatched expectations, because people wanted it to be more directly tied-in to the MCU movies, but that was never going to happen (maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll get that more with the coming Disney+ series). But I like it, it had a lot of fans, and it had a pretty good run. And it had Ghost Rider!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One things I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing a bunch is Amonkhet Remastered, which came out on Magic Arena last Thursday. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing drafts over on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;the twitch channel&lt;/a&gt;, and archiving them to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jsD8jNRlYkw&amp;amp;list=PLmU0vkKslGXg6Pdu3_kaKx5oumTwftUUe&#34;&gt;this playlist on the Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly fun, though I need to play better. Watch me on Twitch/Youtube, or like and subscribe, all that jazz, if you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oh, I also finally finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1293051269129486337/&#34;&gt;Divinity Original Sin 2&lt;/a&gt;! I really dragged out that last act for a few months, but I finally got there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1294146833359364097/&#34;&gt;tried out Fall Guys on PS4&lt;/a&gt; (free on PS+!). It&amp;rsquo;s fun but kind of frustrating, I guess this is why I don&amp;rsquo;t really play these battle royale kind of things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played a little bit Street Fighter x Tekken because of a reddit thread and am once again disappointed that (a) it was such a missed opportunity; and (b) up to now it&amp;rsquo;s still not available on Steam in SEA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so one of the reasons I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing these &amp;ldquo;watching/playing lately&amp;rdquo; posts and segments is because I want to track what I have been watching/playing at any particular point in the past. And maybe I can have like a widget on the site with things like &amp;ldquo;Recently played&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Last movie watched&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;d also want to be able to search/query for things like &amp;ldquo;what year did I watch so-and-so movie?&amp;rdquo; (Helps with trivia quizzes!) I feel like I need to be recording these detail in more of a machine-readable format or a database in order to do those kinds of things. Maybe some kind of Goodreads-like system? It&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;d need to figure out how to implement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, this is already longer than I thought it would be. More things will be posted to the blog (hopefully!) later this week!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-08-09
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-08-09/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-08-09/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Still kind of busy, although there&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of things I hope I can finally wrap up this week, so I can move on to the long list of other things I want to be doing. The world continues to be bleak, so I&amp;rsquo;m still hiding from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/forty-two/&#34;&gt;Forty-two.&lt;/a&gt; I thought about just merging these into a single post for the day, but nah, this seems better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworking the old charity side project still ongoing. I was hoping to finish all the changes last week and next week would be testing and deployment, but stuff got in the way (and estimates may have been a bit off), but the spillover is small and we should still be fine for finishing everything next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots more SC2 coop this week, mostly in the wee hours to destress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost impulse-bought a Switch yesterday; a friend&amp;rsquo;s logic and my inexorably large gaming backlog held me back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG Arena: Nothing of significance, but Amonkhet remastered comes out this week so looking forward to that!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actually did a bit better in 1 of the two quizzes we played this week, but I think we had way more fun playing Codenames online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background watching: Jeopardy on Netflix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binged the new Transformers Netflix series, since it was fairly short (six episodes). A very bleak take on the Autobots&amp;rsquo; struggle against the Decepticons on Cybertron, and also a very obvious tie-in to the current War for Cybertron toy line since most of the main characters have toys in that line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also watched Craig Ferguson&amp;rsquo;s Netflix special Tickle Fight, mainly because I happened to have watch a few of his late night segments on YT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also started watching the last season of Agents of SHIELD, since I&amp;rsquo;m told the season finale is coming up next week. First three episodes seem pretty good for network TV, hopefully I have time for the rest of the (short) season in the next couple of weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links: Nothing of note this week. Even though I have read some interesting stuff, I think my link-capturing workflow really needs improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still in a pandemic!&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/covid19-08-09/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2020-08-09 00:00:00&#34;&gt;9 Aug 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Pandemic thoughts and updates, Aug 9 edition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, NCR got sent back into MECQ, a stronger quarantine lockdown. I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually felt the difference, since I&amp;rsquo;m at home most of the time. We went out yesterday for a grocery run, and not much seemed different out there either, still a lot of cars and people out of doors. I don&amp;rsquo;t actually remember what the last MECQ was like, but I kind of assumed things would be closer to how they were at the onset of the lockdowns in March, but this feels still mostly like the GCQ of past weeks. IDK if this 2-week MECQ stretch really serves any purpose except to show the government is trying something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching mass via Facebook again today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As of last night, we are at 126,885 cases (+4226 from the day before, +28653 from last week, huge jump week-on-week), 2,209 deaths (+41 from the day before, +170 from last week, thankfully not as big a jump as from last week), 67,117 recoveries (+287 from the day before, +1852 from last week, a predictably much smaller jump after last week&amp;rsquo;s miraculous &amp;ldquo;mass recoveries&amp;rdquo;). We hit record high daily deaths again over the first few days of the MECQ. We seem to have settled at a much higher average daily rate since then. Luckily, the death rate hasn&amp;rsquo;t gone up that much. We are now #1 in confirmed cases in SEA, overtaking Indonesia. The govt claims nothing to worry about, it&amp;rsquo;s only because we are testing more, but our relatively large positivity rate (around 8.6% as of this writing) implies transmission is outpacing testing? &lt;a href=&#34;https://covid19ph.com/&#34;&gt;Reference.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worldwide, we are at around 19.8 cases (+1.8M from last week, slope holding steady for maybe 3 weeks now?) and almost 730k deaths. Caveat: these numbers are from &lt;a href=&#34;https://edition.cnn.com/interactive/2020/05/world/worldometer-coronavirus-mystery/index.html&#34;&gt;Worldometer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;




            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-08-02
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-08-02/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-08-02/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Kind of a busy week for me again, so the week kind of passed me by quickly. It&amp;rsquo;s August! In one month it will be (PH) Christmas season! It feels like July went by more quickly than other quarantine months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A bit of consulting work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworking the old charity side project still ongoing. I was hoping to finish all the changes last week and next week would be testing and deployment, but stuff got in the way (and estimates may have been a bit off), but the spillover is small and we should still be fine for finishing everything next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starcraft 2 came out with a 10th anniversary patch that had some sweet new features and changes for coop. They added unlockable prestige talents for each of the 18 commanders, each talent alters their gameplay so they play out a bit differently. We had actually been getting a bit bored with SC2 coop and had been playing it less, this patch did a lot to invigorate our enthusiasm for it. We&amp;rsquo;ve been playing it quite a bit to unlock the prestige talents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG Arena: Didn&amp;rsquo;t hit mythic last month, but that&amp;rsquo;s fine. I switched my historic deck to Monored for faster games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only played 1 quiz last week for reasons. Instead, trivia group played some online Codenames (via &lt;a href=&#34;https://codenames.game/&#34;&gt;https://codenames.game/&lt;/a&gt;) on Saturday night, with voice chat over discord. It was a bunch of fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s new episodes of Jeopardy on Netflix, so that quickly replaced Family Guy as my background watching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s actually a bunch of new stuff to watch too: Umbrella Academy S2 is out, there&amp;rsquo;s a new Transformers series on Netflix etc. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get around to all of these things someday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some fixes to the trivia app backend, but I can&amp;rsquo;t really get too much into the (other) side projects until I get past my current busyness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet seems to be having some DNS issues this past week. Occasionally can&amp;rsquo;t access various URLs, but is fine on refresh. Problem survived multiple router reboots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right-click button on this gaming mouse I got last year is starting to get less responsive. I only got for $13 in Walmart, but even then it&amp;rsquo;s one of the more expensive mice I&amp;rsquo;ve bought, so I hope it doesn&amp;rsquo;t die too quickly. Maybe I should clean it out?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Couple of somewhat related blog posts resonated with me: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rubenerd.com/why-arent-you-more-serious/&#34;&gt;Why arent you more serious?&lt;/a&gt;, asserting the personal blog&amp;rsquo;s right to write about whatever the blogger wants, and not just to focus on specific serious or technical topics; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://om.co/2020/07/30/write-like-a-human/&#34;&gt;Write like a human&lt;/a&gt; is kind of self-explanatory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great follow-up to a previous survey on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pudding.cool/2020/07/song-decay/&#34;&gt;Defining the 90s Music Canon&lt;/a&gt;. Also had an &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/1288899712112717824&#34;&gt;interesting exchange about this with a friend over on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; re:how this might reflect locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IDK, maybe I&amp;rsquo;m getting used to the pandemic. Is this what they mean by &amp;ldquo;new normal&amp;rdquo;? I&amp;rsquo;ll move the pandemic notes to the end of these weekly updates.&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/covid19-08-02/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2020-08-02 00:00:00&#34;&gt;2 Aug 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Pandemic thoughts and updates, Aug 2 edition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We ended July with around 90k active cases. Despite the threat of sending Metro Manila back to ECQ if we breached the 85k mark, the govt did not push through. Over the weekend, this led to a clamor from doctors and other frontliners to have a &amp;ldquo;time out&amp;rdquo; of 2 weeks for the NCR, a temporary quarantine, to give the healthcare system some breathing room. The knee-jerk response from the palace was to say it wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessary, but they quickly flipped their flops and said the IATF would discuss it. Enraging people and doctors, a certain outspoken-on-social-media doctor tried to shame doctors for not being heroic enough, and a certain senator implied that we can&amp;rsquo;t afford it so frontliners just need to work harder and be more passionate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching mass via Facebook again today. Churches have actually been holding limited physical services, but in solidarity with the call for ECQ, they said they will temporarily suspend such services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I went to get some Jollibee takeout last Thursday; apparently they are already allowing limited dine-in customers, that seems unwise, eh. Was anxious the entire time I was waiting for my takeout order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As of last night, we are at 98232 cases (+4963 from the day before, +19820 from last week, huge jump week-on-week), 2039 deaths (+17 from the day before, +142 from last week, moderate jump), 65265 recoveries (+93 from the day before, +39513 (!) from last week, a miraculous jump). We hit record high daily deaths over the past few days, and the huge spike in recoveries is because the DOH decided to do a &amp;ldquo;mass recovery&amp;rdquo; of mild/asymptomatic cases that are already 14 days or older, supposedly in line with WHO guidelines. I can kind of see some logic behind this, but the communication was not handled very well. &lt;a href=&#34;https://covid19ph.com/&#34;&gt;Reference.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worldwide, we are at around 18M cases (+1.8M from last week) and almost 690k deaths. Caveat: these numbers are from &lt;a href=&#34;https://edition.cnn.com/interactive/2020/05/world/worldometer-coronavirus-mystery/index.html&#34;&gt;Worldometer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;




            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-07-26
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-26/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-26/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The world:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hm. I was a bit busy this week, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t paying too much attention, so I don&amp;rsquo;t have too much to rail against today. Well of course, things are still ongoing. There&amp;rsquo;s still the pandemic, fascist police state philosophy continues to rear it&amp;rsquo;s ugly head in the US, PH gov&amp;rsquo;t continues to be dumb, etc., but this week seemed a bit tame comparably.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/covid19-07-26/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2020-07-26 00:00:00&#34;&gt;26 Jul 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Pandemic thoughts and updates, July 26 edition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching mass via Facebook again today. The nearby Church actually holds services, but last I heard it was only 10 people per mass, and need to call ahead of time. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem likely we&amp;rsquo;ll be going anytime soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grocery run yesterday, without incident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;last Thursday I finally &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/1286105826743091201/&#34;&gt;got a haircut&lt;/a&gt; my last one was around New Year&amp;rsquo;s Day, so this was around six and a half months of hair cut off. I didn&amp;rsquo;t go to a barbershop, this was a home service haircut, care of a lady who works at a neighboring salon, who actually came over to do some home care service for my mom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As of last night, we are at 78412 cases (+2019 from the day before, +13108 from last week, slight acceleration week-on-week), 1897 deaths (+20 from the day before, +224 from last week, lower jump than last week), 25752 recoveries (+1278 from the day before, +3685 from last week, much less than last week&amp;rsquo;s jump). The admin claims that if we breach 85k cases by end-July, Metro Manila may go back to NCQ. First, that seems likely to happen so we&amp;rsquo;ll see. Second, it seems a bit unfair and illogical to make Metro Manila&amp;rsquo;s quarantine status dependent on national case numbers, but whatever. &lt;a href=&#34;https://covid19ph.com/&#34;&gt;Reference.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worldwide, we are at 16.2M cases (+1.8M from last week, slight acceleration) and almost 650k deaths. The US retains a comfortable lead over second placer Brazil. Caveat: these numbers are from &lt;a href=&#34;https://edition.cnn.com/interactive/2020/05/world/worldometer-coronavirus-mystery/index.html&#34;&gt;Worldometer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Busy with rebuilding the UI for the old project. I&amp;rsquo;m having fun with it, so that&amp;rsquo;s something. I think this week went by more quickly for me because of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake completed! Review &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r-review/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I played through a couple of Civ6 games, trying out the new civs and game modes from the New Frontier pass. Fun and challenging. Apocalypse mode: it&amp;rsquo;s an insane feeling the first time you see a comet strike take out a city. I was actually streaming the gameplay to a friend on Discord when this happened and we both went &amp;ldquo;Woah!&amp;rdquo; and he said that pushed him to get the DLC as well. Secret societies: Only tried Voidsingers so far; their cultists are great for culture victory since they&amp;rsquo;re a constant source of relics for tourism, and the Old God Monument gives you GW slots for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG: Still playing a bunch of JumpStart, but also put together Bant Ramp for Historic. Currently at Diamond 4, I&amp;rsquo;ll see if I can grind Mythic for constructed before end of month. Related: I watched Maro&amp;rsquo;s Comic-con stream for Zendikar Rising last night, but left kinda underwhelmed. Set boosters are neat, but I kind of wanted more info/spoilers about the set itself. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to be excited about the set boosters when my MTG involvement is primarily through Arena these days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only played 2 online quizzes this week (the third one didn&amp;rsquo;t fire due to not enough participants). There was a fun Scientists/Inventors round which I could have perfected if I had gone with my gut answer (Rutherford) and not listened to my teammates lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a new season of Family Guy on Netflix, so I&amp;rsquo;ve started to watch that in the background while I&amp;rsquo;m working on other things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watched a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ew.com/events/comic-con/scott-pilgrim-cast-reunion-table-read/&#34;&gt;for-charity cast-reunion live-table-read for Scott Pilgrim vs the World&lt;/a&gt; last week. I enjoyed it so much, I went and rewatched the movie on Netflix as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technically, this old project I&amp;rsquo;m revamping used to be a &amp;ldquo;side project&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing of note.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-07-19
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-19/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-19/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My country:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are days when I have to consciously temper my rage at the shenanigans of this government. I can&amp;rsquo;t write about them today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/covid19-07-19/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s pandemic notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had a busy work week again; at the same time I also picked up an older charity project where the client asked for UI updates. Had issues with running the old code, and it was small enough, so I decided to rewrite it in a new tech stack. Might write about it at some point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am like 98% through the FF7R hard mode run. I&amp;rsquo;m totally making these percentages up, but I do have only one trophy left, and it&amp;rsquo;s this annoying minigame.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started trying out some of the new leaders/civs in the Civ6 New Frontier pack. Another drop should be coming this week, so looking forward to that!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG JumpStart is out this week! I tried it a couple of times on Arena. Some combinations are much better than others; the sad things is if you picked a miserable pair you have to stick with it longer before you can get your requisite two wins. Here&amp;rsquo;s an (ongoing) &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/1283901490206109698/&#34;&gt;thread of my JumpStart results&lt;/a&gt; will probably update it through the month it&amp;rsquo;s available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t win any online quiz this week, boo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After watching Atomic Blonde last week, I watched the Old Guard for back-to-back Charlize Theron action flicks. Pretty fun, although some plot points might make you go what?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of stuff coming out in July that I might watch: new season of Umbrella Academy, and there&amp;rsquo;s a Transformers anime coming out on NF, and well, there&amp;rsquo;s also a long backlog of things to watch&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing to note, too busy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/sections/coronavirus-live-updates/2020/07/09/889394605/please-scream-inside-your-heart-japanese-amusement-park-tells-thrill-seekers&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Please scream inside your heart&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; should be the motto for 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-07-12: Media Shutdown Edition
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-12/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-12/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My country:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday afternoon the House of Representatives voted to deny the franchise application of the nation&amp;rsquo;s biggest broadcaster ABS-CBN. This despite all agencies of the executive testifying that the company had no violations. Justifications cited were mostly personal reasons. The Palace claims they remained neutral on this issue, but no one really believes that. Probably not even then. What now, Philippines?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/covid19-07-12/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s pandemic notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had a busy week work-wise. Learning a lot about Vue and Laravel though, so that&amp;rsquo;s fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am like 95% through the FF7R hard mode run. Only a 5% difference from last week, progress is slow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I bought a few games off the Steam Sale: Civ 6&amp;rsquo;s New Frontiers Pass (not actually on sale), Disco Elysium, and Garou Mark of the Wolves. You can watch me struggling in Garou &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2yQ6B9IlwHU&amp;amp;t=70s&#34;&gt;on Youtube&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We only played one online quiz this week, didn&amp;rsquo;t do too well D:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watched Atomic Blonde yesterday. I thought it was like a John Wick style action flick. That&amp;rsquo;s true, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a Cold-War era spy thriller with lots of double-crosses and whatnot. Fairly engaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing to note.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.dev/one-line-layouts/&#34;&gt;Ten modern layouts in one line of CSS&lt;/a&gt;. I could have used this two weeks ago!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really enjoyed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.swiss-miss.com/2020/07/alike-an-animated-short-film.html&#34;&gt;Alike, an Animated Short Film&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an allegory for modern life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-07-05: Anti-Error Edition
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-05/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-05/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My country:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friday afternoon the president sighed the controversial &amp;ldquo;Anti-terror law&amp;rdquo; that vastly expands police powers, allows people to be arrested without warrants on mere suspicion of terrorism etc. Interesting timing, right after China applies a new anti-terror low to Hong Kong (and rightly gets castigated for it by countries all over the world) and also right after the PNP (who &lt;em&gt;promise&lt;/em&gt; not to abuse their newfound powers) are under criticism for killing some soldiers in a &lt;em&gt;misencounter&lt;/em&gt; and tampering with the crime scene to cover it up. Many are afraid of the chilling impact on freedom of speech, but I like to think that I will be as complain-y as I used to be. I am privileged to be able to do that, so might as well keep going.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Congressmen &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/abscbn-bias-press-freedom/&#34;&gt;tightening the screws on ABS-CBN&lt;/a&gt; during the franchise hearings reminds me that: given how complicated the various laws and statutes are, anyone with an agenda who wants to harass you can always find some obscure laws or regulations that you allegedly violated. That is not to say we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t follow such regulations, but given when one randomly keeps digging up new issues, it becomes obvious that there is a vendetta at work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I often ruminate about what I can do to help the state of my country today. Or maybe even the state of the world? I used to think being a good citizen and making good voting choices was enough, but it&amp;rsquo;s not. The systems are rigged to perpetuate inequality, exploitation, and bad people in power. I read somewhere recently that one should imagine the path towards the future he wishes to claim and take the steps to make it happen, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think my imagination is up to the task at the moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/covid19-07-05/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s pandemic notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fair bit of consulting work for this coming week, might be busy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have already &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/quitting-facebook/&#34;&gt;deactivated Facebook&lt;/a&gt;. If I would be honest, I still find myself sometimes instinctively thinking about checking the Facebook feed. Hopefully, it&amp;rsquo;s an instinct that gets weaned away with time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am like 90% through the FF7R hard mode run, but I&amp;rsquo;m currently stuck at a certain point trying to beat the so-called &amp;ldquo;hardest fight in the game&amp;rdquo;. Hopefully I can finish it this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divinity OS2 inched along slightly as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday gaming group picked up a new board game on Steam, it&amp;rsquo;s Blood Rage, about vikings trying to earn glory for Ragnarok. A bit more violent than Scythe, lots more fighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG: I did six twitch streams/yt episodes of M21 drafting, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kXZO7Ukg5Xk&amp;amp;list=PLmU0vkKslGXiz0shcCJgV1YTP5emzWgr4&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Able to play a couple more online quiz nights this week, but still didn&amp;rsquo;t do well lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some new movies on Netflix lately. Decided to watch Mission Impossible Fallout. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I ever watched Rogue Nation though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need to plan out the next set of updates for the trivia thing, but I might be too busy in the coming weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I changed the fonts on this blog. Again. Someday I&amp;rsquo;ll probably try Comic Sans just for the heck of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Again: I should probably write more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This list of &lt;a href=&#34;https://whimsical.club/&#34;&gt;websites that spark joy&lt;/a&gt; is great, have some new sites to browse!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A walk back through the history of web trends and standards: &lt;a href=&#34;https://pavellaptev.github.io/web-dark-ages/&#34;&gt;dark ages of the web&lt;/a&gt;. As someone &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.technology/@schwartz/104450459330476402&#34;&gt;commented on Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; though: &amp;ldquo;dark ages for development, golden age for content.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-06-28: Internet Outage Edition
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/weeknotes-06-28/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/weeknotes-06-28/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/covid19-06-28/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s pandemic notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily the most annoying thing this week: our broadband modem conked out Wednesday night. Customer support isn&amp;rsquo;t super responsive for local telcos: I called their support line the next day (support line is not even available 24/7!), got put on hold for 45 minutes TWICE before they agreed to send a repair crew over the next day (Friday). Friday morning I got a text that the technician visit was actually scheduled for SATURDAY morning. They arrive Saturday AFTERNOON, due to traffic apparently. And unluckily, they are out of spare modems for the replacement. They promise to come back first thing in the morning SUNDAY. They come back Sunday LUNCHTIME. And I finally have internet back. An annoying experience, and I&amp;rsquo;m also worried that my mobile plan might be charged for the two one-hour calls I had to do to their support line (hopefully I can clear that up), and I&amp;rsquo;m told I can also call them up to ask for a rebate for their days we had no service, but eh, I&amp;rsquo;d have to sit through another long on-hold period!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One would think that being offline for half a week would lead to some kind of gigantic productivity boost, but no such luck. I still had my mobile internet for my doomscrolling after all. I did manage to read/write/watch a few more things than usual I guess?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finished Final Fantasy VII Remake (before the internet outage)! So I spent a lot of the outage (including my time on hold with tech support) playing through hard mode, already about half-way through. Still not sure I&amp;rsquo;m going to do achievement completion, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see. Hard mode is actually an enjoyable challenge, nothing too insane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divinity OS2 inched along slightly as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;won my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/1274581114628108289/&#34;&gt;first Trivia Royale&lt;/a&gt;, I can quit now lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the internet outage coincided with the start of this week&amp;rsquo;s Steam Summer Sale. There&amp;rsquo;s some games/DLC I&amp;rsquo;m considering buying, but realistically in terms of backlog I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t lol. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if willpower holds out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the new MTG core set also came out on Magic Arena during the outage. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get back into regular streaming for M21 limited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still tried to join the Zoom and voice chats for the online quizzes with only my tethered mobile internet, but that was kind of a miserable experience. Still, I was able to contribute a bit, though we didn&amp;rsquo;t actually do too well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching lately:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finished watching season 2 of Harley Quinn. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve written about the show before. The whole Harley/Poison Ivy dynamic isn&amp;rsquo;t really for me, but I like the show&amp;rsquo;s take on Gotham and the wider DC universe and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun characters like King Shark and Clayface. Also, Riddler was recognizably voiced by Dean Pelton from Community, and that was fun lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also did a rewatch of Spider-Man Far From Home on Netflix, before the internet problems and all. Still a pretty good movie, and watching it made me eager to get back to the MCU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also watched the Sonic the Hedgehog movie while things were offline. The best thing about this is Sonic being recognizably voiced by Ben Schwartz, who apparently &lt;a href=&#34;https://thesuperheroesnetwork.tumblr.com/post/622121477003739136/supernova-swirls-gothammite-he-really&#34;&gt;voices everyone blue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As soon as my internet came back, I started watching Ghost Fighter/Yu Yu Hakusho, which came out on Netflix (as you guessed it, during the outage)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also tried reading a book. It was a Discworld book. &amp;ldquo;Tried&amp;rdquo; being the operative word. I&amp;rsquo;ll write about it if I manage to get to the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uh, proceeding apace I guess?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Again: I should probably write more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://slatestarcodex.com/2020/06/22/nyt-is-threatening-my-safety-by-revealing-my-real-name-so-i-am-deleting-the-blog/&#34;&gt;NYT threatened to doxx Scott Alexander of Slate Star Codex&lt;/a&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t really follow SSC too strictly, but that seemed like a bad thing. I also read up some more on &lt;a href=&#34;https://rationalwiki.org/wiki/Scott_Alexander&#34;&gt;Scott Alexander / SSC&lt;/a&gt; because of this, and it looks like he had a lot of problematic views, so I don&amp;rsquo;t really think I want to support him lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great essay from Ankit Shah about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ankit.fyi/being-alone&#34;&gt;Being Alone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gomakethings.com/always-bet-on-html/&#34;&gt;Always Bet on HTML&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-06-21: There&#39;s no gettin&#39; off this train we&#39;re on
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/weeknotes-06-21/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/weeknotes-06-21/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/covid19-06-21/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s pandemic notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some days still hot, but weather beginning to turn for the better. Sleep kind of better and a bit more regular too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did my quarterly medical checkup this past week (slightly delayed). No issues, but I need to do an FBS test for next time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep schedule kind of settling back into my usual biphasic sleep. Although the second phase seems to move around a lot&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not much work-wise the past week, and a bit more family-related expenses. Medical and government stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;still playing a lot of Final Fantasy VII Remake. I think I&amp;rsquo;m already in the final chapter. I am quite happy with the adaptiation, bit I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I&amp;rsquo;m going to bother with achievement completion for this one; it requires hard mode completion, but that&amp;rsquo;s not the issue. The problem is the abundance of these dexterity-based minigames! I thought everything was fine when I did the squats thing, but then later there&amp;rsquo;s a harder pull-ups thing! And I haven&amp;rsquo;t even cracked the bottom of that darts leaderboard&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divinity OS2 inching along slightly. But probably will be finished after FF7R at this rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s a new trivia app by the makers of the QuizUp, which we used to play a lot back in the day. The name is Trivia Royale, it&amp;rsquo;s currently iOS only and it&amp;rsquo;s basically battle royale quizup: you join a game with 1000 players, and you play 10 head-to-head matches until you get a winner. Took me most of the wook to actually win my first one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;did poorly in the AboutQuiz and PopQuiz games this week. Actually, we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing poorly for a while now lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching lately:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing to log. Maybe a good thing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More work on &lt;a href=&#34;https://triviastorm.net/&#34;&gt;triviastorm&lt;/a&gt; stuff this week. Most of it are some backend fixes to make later planned new features easier to build. Planning to clear/reset leaderboards at the end of the month. Some roadmap things:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;allowing users to submit their own questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make the discord bot usable for public usage, i.e. let other people add it to their discord&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I should probably write more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a lot of posts off &lt;a href=&#34;https://lobste.rs&#34;&gt;lobste.rs&lt;/a&gt; lately, so I finally pulled the trigger and asked around for an invite to the site. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.gamedev.place/@ignaloidas&#34;&gt;helpful person&lt;/a&gt; provided me one via Mastodon. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting site, basically an invite-only reddit-like site, mostly focused on tech stuff, so in theory the discussion quality should be fairly high. The chain of invites is public too, each user&amp;rsquo;s profile shows you who invited him, so in that way it&amp;rsquo;s kind of similar to a certificate chain of trust? We&amp;rsquo;ll see if this scales up well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enjoyed this &lt;a href=&#34;https://mxb.dev/blog/the-return-of-the-90s-web/&#34;&gt;recent article about the 90s web&lt;/a&gt;. I will easily admit that I am an easy sucker for any post that appeals to my nostalgia for how the web was better &amp;ldquo;back in the doy&amp;rdquo;, rose-tinted glasses or no.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always enjoyed the song Fast Car, so it was interesting to read about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-features/tracy-chapman-fast-car-revival-luke-combs-khalid-1014843/&#34;&gt;its origins and its surprising popularity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The founders of BaseCamp recently released &lt;a href=&#34;https://hey.com&#34;&gt;Hey&lt;/a&gt;, a new email service that has &lt;a href=&#34;https://hey.com/features/&#34;&gt;some interesting ideas about new features&lt;/a&gt; to support the typical email workflow. I don&amp;rsquo;t nearly use email enough on a personal basis to pay for it (though I do have an invite!), but I&amp;rsquo;m glad someone is innovating in this space, although they don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be using open standards. They promptly &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/18/21296180/apple-hey-email-app-basecamp-rejection-response-controversy-antitrust-regulation&#34;&gt;got into a fight with Apple over App Store policies&lt;/a&gt; which has sparked some debate in the tech community on the value of curated app stores. So maybe they&amp;rsquo;re actually going to push for innovation in two different areas?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-06-14
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/weeknotes-06-14/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/weeknotes-06-14/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, no new crises have emerged during the past week. I think. More of the same crises, carrying on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Friday was the PH independence day holiday. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like celebrating. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like we are free. In any case, a protest rally against the yet-to-be-signed terror bill took place at the university that morning, inspite of threats from the authorities that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t allowed. The protestors spaced themselves out and everything. Some friends reported trouble getting into the university though. Apparently a heavy police/military presence was manning many of the entrances for some reason. &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/DailyGuardianPH/posts/3416858255000782&#34;&gt;Basta&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rappler.com/move-ph/263710-police-blocks-entry-protesters-rally-independence-day-2020&#34;&gt;News report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/covid19-06-14/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s quarantine notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Much better weather this week, some nights were comfortably rainy and chilly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep schedule kind of settling back into my usual biphasic sleep. Although the second phase seems to move around a lot&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disappointed in the PS5 reveal. None of the shown games are must buys from me, and I was hoping for a price and release date. Highly unlikely I&amp;rsquo;d get a PS5 on launch though. Historically I&amp;rsquo;ve waited at least a year to get consoles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divinity OS2 run stalled this week because&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip; most of my gaming this week spent on Final Fantasy VII Remake. I&amp;rsquo;m only around 12ish hours in. Game is pretty great, and not just for the nostalgia bit. There is a large amount of added content, and some plot details play out differently. Looking forward to how this all ends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also purchased the &lt;a href=&#34;https://itch.io/b/520/bundle-for-racial-justice-and-equality&#34;&gt;itch.io BLM bundle&lt;/a&gt; this week. Wow that&amp;rsquo;s a ton of value. Over 1600+ games, assets, etc for minimum $5? I was originally hesitant since I didn&amp;rsquo;t have an itch.io account and really I don&amp;rsquo;t need more backlog, but it&amp;rsquo;s for a good cause, and did I mention also a ton of value? Better than Humble Bundles ever were.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Somehow managed to win Geekfight this week, and it&amp;rsquo;s the last one until July. We got third place in PopQuiz and as usual did poorly in AboutQuiz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team Camote Pop Culture Trivia Challenge S01E01 is out: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZQytLl61PCQ&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZQytLl61PCQ&lt;/a&gt;. We had a lot of fun, and we recorded this around a month ago I think, editing took a while. We have a few more episodes in the queue, feel free to like and subscribe!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching lately:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My dad has been watching a lot of Two and A Half Men, which means a lot of incidental watching from me whenever I&amp;rsquo;m in that same room. The Charlie Sheen firing came really abruptly since he was binging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huh, I guess not much TV/movies for me last week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked a bit more on &lt;a href=&#34;https://triviastorm.net/&#34;&gt;triviastorm&lt;/a&gt; stuff this week. Cleaning up the old questions, prepping new question sets, etc. Will probably load new question sets and reset both the twitter bot and discord leaderboards around the end of the month, and hopefully can expand upon the app after that, and prepare it for more general use and other cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My urge to completely revamp the site has passed&amp;hellip; for now. Other plans proceed apace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slatestarcodex.com/2018/10/30/sort-by-controversial/&#34;&gt;Sort By Controversial&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s two years old, but it&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic read, a fictional (or maybe not so fictional?) take on how society can easily be cleaved apart by the right discussions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-06-07: Mad World
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/weeknotes-06-07/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/weeknotes-06-07/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The world isn&amp;rsquo;t letting up. The virus is still around, but both the US and my own country have gotten distracted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US is in its second week of police brutality/black lives matters protests. Meanwhile, our government took on a sidequest of trying to enact a wide-ranging and easily abusable anti-terror bill, triggering some smaller (by comparison to the US).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t written about the terror bill, mainly because I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the opportunity to dig into it too deeply. But my general impression leaves me two points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what is the justification for asking for increased police/anti-terrorism powers? We don&amp;rsquo;t actually get that many terror attacks pulled off, the last big one was Marawi (which I heard some Congressmen citing, tbf), which was back in 2017. And that was mostly a problem with Islamic militants. I don&amp;rsquo;t hear any of the bill proponents talking about how specifically the limits on govt powers holds them back. How would these added powers prevent another Marawi? Did they actually have intel leading up to the Marawi siege that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t act on due to limited powers? I find this difficult to believe because&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what about the authorities&amp;rsquo; history of impunity? It&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe that they are being restricted by the law in anti-terror activities when they don&amp;rsquo;t seem to let the law get in the way for much lesser things. I guess this is the crux of the issue for most people, one of trust. Even if you say there are safeguards in the law, they are still easily abusable. The bill extends the detention period for terror suspects to I think is it 30 days, extendable? But given the speed (or lack thereof) of local courts, even if you challenge any violation of the safeguards, the challenge may take longer to resolve than the detention period. Maybe we should consider cleaning up our justice system first? People wouldn&amp;rsquo;t object if our systems were trustworthy&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, also China banned mocking their national anthem in HK, or something to that effect. China being China. Better not to lose track of what is probably the greatest threat to democracy in the coming century&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/covid19-06-07/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s quarantine notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was hoping the weather would get much cooler than this. Where&amp;rsquo;s our &lt;em&gt;hanging amihan&lt;/em&gt;?!?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tiny bit of consulting work again this week, mostly integration work. And it&amp;rsquo;s in PHP, which means I&amp;rsquo;m once again tempted to write a &amp;ldquo;bad things about PHP&amp;rdquo; post lol. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll collect a few more gripes before I do that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep schedule slightly better and more regular, but my eyes seem to be heavy a lot more often.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m like in the final act for Divinity OS2. Need to finish it soonish because&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip; my PS4 is back! My brother finally passed by the house to pick up some stuff and returned my console. I already hooked it up and did the installation things for FF7R. Will probably start it this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;new Humble choice is up, but it&amp;rsquo;s meh again. Will probably pass.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was looking forward to the PS5 reveal this week, but it got rescheduled due to everything happening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least previews for the next Magic set have already started. Some cool stuff. Instant planeswalker abilities! Phasing! Prowess! &lt;a href=&#34;http://mythicspoiler.com/m21/cards/peerintotheabyss.html&#34;&gt;Really creepy art&lt;/a&gt;! We also got some bans and an actual rule change to address companions, both of which are sure to shake up the formats. I finally caved and paid gems for the Ikoria mythic pass on Arena (I&amp;rsquo;ve saved up a bunch anyway. Still totally F2P!). Hopefully I can max out the levels/rewards before the mastery rotation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz:&lt;/strong&gt; Geekfight was fun this week (theme was Marvel comics, right up my alley), although I didn&amp;rsquo;t win. We did poorly in the other two online quizzes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching lately:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legends of Tomorrow season finale was weak and didn&amp;rsquo;t really make sense, but still somehow the best of the Arrowverse finales this season. Oh well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By contrast, I really liked the Rick and Morty season finale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also started watching Space Force; only 3 episodes in, it&amp;rsquo;s a bit meh. Not super funny or anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worked a bit on &lt;a href=&#34;https://triviastorm.net/&#34;&gt;triviastorm&lt;/a&gt; stuff this week. I&amp;rsquo;m preparing new questions and cleaning up the old ones, and also some work on a tighter checking algorithm. There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of features I want to add to this side project, let&amp;rsquo;s see if I manage to get around to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also spent a couple of hours fantasizing about rewriting the site again, maybe back to a dynamic backend, or some kind of hybrid, mostly to address the issues scaling with so many posts. Lol, will probably not do this yet, but it&amp;rsquo;s in the back of my mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No recent links for now. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll be more diligent about this next week.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-05-31
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-05-31/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-05-31/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It seems difficult to write about stuff today, when the world seems like it is on fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For historical context, for the past few days the USA, presumably a first-world nation, has been in the grip of massive protests and riots and police brutality following the murder of a black man by four police officers was captured on video and went viral. Basically, many states are responding to protests against police brutality with&amp;hellip; police brutality. Bold move Cotton. I&amp;rsquo;m not an American, but this resonates with me a lot because to see this kind of thing happening in a country that purports to champion human rights, how much worse can it be in a country like ours or a dictatorship like China where they don&amp;rsquo;t even give lip service to the concept? (Spoiler: we already know police brutality and EJKs are a thing in my country.) I give my support to those protesting, and hope they achieve the reforms their country needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One would question why I (and maybe the world) focuses so much on what happens in the USA, given that violence and brutality happen in a lot of other countries too. The main difference is that the USA is presumably a superpower and provide some semblance of leadership to democratic countries. The USA needs to shape up, they&amp;rsquo;re making democracy look bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s weird watching a hegemony fall apart in real time to weight of its own excesses. It&amp;rsquo;s like they&amp;rsquo;re trying to hard to make &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Past_Tense_(Star_Trek:_Deep_Space_Nine)&#34;&gt;Deep Space Nine&amp;rsquo;s 2020s prediction&lt;/a&gt; come true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: I should also highlight in this space that this past week China rammed its National Security Law through Hong Kong, bypassing the HK legislature and essentially ending HK&amp;rsquo;s autonomy through one country, two systems. I&amp;rsquo;ve been to Hong Kong multiples times and know and have worked with people there, so this one hits a lot closer to home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/covid19-05-31/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s quarantine notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weather slightly cooling off, with more thunderstorms happening in the afternoons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep schedule completely out of whack again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; Moved along my Divity OS2 game. A friend got me some Steam keys for the older Jackbox Party Packs, so I have more access to games to play. I tried streaming via Twitch, but seems difficult due to streaming delay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz:&lt;/strong&gt; We didn&amp;rsquo;t really do too well in the quiz nights this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We have uploaded some gaming videos to our trivia team&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCptXvNbp4ETVttb_k-1oOww&#34;&gt;Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;, check it out!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching lately:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watched Zombieland: Double Tap. My friends and I really enjoyed the first movie when it came out ten years ago. This one was fun, but pretty much more of the same&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caught up with Legends of Tomorrow in anticipation of their season finale this coming week. I have to say I had low expectations but once again Legends may be the best of the Arrowverse shows this season. I really enjoyed the penultimate episode where they had parodies of other shows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site updates: Nothing to announce!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do have some social media related thing to announce, maybe tomorrow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent Links of Interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/&#34;&gt;Rediscovering the small web.&lt;/a&gt; Great post here, and I like the term &amp;ldquo;small web&amp;rdquo; to describe what I&amp;rsquo;ve been missing on the internet lately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slim pickings this week apparently. Been distracted by other things.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-05-24
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-05-24/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-05-24/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/covid19-05-24/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s quarantine notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the weather has been so hot lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to shifting my sleep schedule to afternoons so that I can maximize the use of the air-conditioning to when it&amp;rsquo;s most needed. It also helps me be more productive, since I can get more things done if I&amp;rsquo;m awake during the cooler hours of the day. I think I&amp;rsquo;m more looking forward to the end of summer than the end of quarantine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a bit of consulting work this week, actually had to code some stuff. Mostly integration work, API calls, that sort of thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/hyperx-cloud2/&#34;&gt;fancy new headset&lt;/a&gt; I ordered off Lazada came in last Saturday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Gaming: **Not much gaming this week surprisingly. The Saturday playgroup started playing Scythe, a Steam version of an actual boardgame. Games take a long time, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty terrible at it because it seems to need a lot of advance planning. We&amp;rsquo;re also planning to play some Jackbox games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz:&lt;/strong&gt; So we&amp;rsquo;re up to 3 regular online quiz nights now. Sadly, we didn&amp;rsquo;t too well in this week&amp;rsquo;s quizzes. I did win the Geekfight one last Wednesday, but the other two were a wash. As if that weren&amp;rsquo;t enough, we also decided to do internal trivia team quizzes, with the intent of putting them up on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCptXvNbp4ETVttb_k-1oOww&#34;&gt;relatively-new Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt; (Subscribe, etc). I hosted the first one last Wednesday, and the video will be up on YT as soon as our editor gets done with it. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably upload the slides once it&amp;rsquo;s up as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching lately:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Caught up with the &amp;ldquo;season finales&amp;rdquo; for Supergirl and Flash. In quotes because they literally just cut their seasons short and left a lot of cliffhangers to be resolved next season. Understandable, but so weird.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;various streaming shows have started up again their seasons that I&amp;rsquo;ve started watching: Rick and Morty, Patriot Act with Hasan Minaj&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site updates: Nothing to announce! Been busy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent Links of Interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;great &lt;a href=&#34;https://tonsky.me/blog/disenchantment/&#34;&gt;post on software bloat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not big on sudoku, but I enjoyed watching &lt;a href=&#34;https://kottke.org/20/05/solving-the-the-miracle-sudoku&#34;&gt;this &amp;ldquo;miracle sudoku&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; that made the rounds last week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@steve.yegge/saying-goodbye-to-the-best-gig-i-ever-had-a33736833c1e?source=rss-c1ec701babb7------2&#34;&gt;Steve Yegge has left Grab&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with him, he used to work at Google and wrote a bunch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://steve-yegge.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;longish but really good software development related articles&lt;/a&gt; back in the day. I like this recent post because he highlights some of the differences he noticed while working with people from this side of the world. It was actually a year ago that he last &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/1131993395738468352/&#34;&gt;wrote about being at Grab&lt;/a&gt;. Although ick, Medium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the Worldometer site to track worldwide Covid19 stats, but it turns out it &lt;a href=&#34;https://edition.cnn.com/interactive/2020/05/world/worldometer-coronavirus-mystery/index.html&#34;&gt;might not be super accurate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capcom has re-released &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.capcom-unity.com/2020/05/21/street-fighter-april-fools-mini-games-have-returned/&#34;&gt;some old April Fools joke Street Fighter themed minigames&lt;/a&gt;! I liked the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/1263976021444816896/&#34;&gt;Street Fighter Academy one&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s a trivia game!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theringer.com/2020/5/20/21264342/online-trivia-learned-league&#34;&gt;Great writeup of LearnedLeague&lt;/a&gt;, a long-running trivia league that&amp;rsquo;s invite-only. I kind of want to try to find a way to join, but it seems really tough! &lt;a href=&#34;https://learnedleague.com/&#34;&gt;Their website&lt;/a&gt; has an archive of all the past sets and their questions. I browsed through a month&amp;rsquo;s worth of questions and they&amp;rsquo;re really hard, I could answer maybe 1-2 in 10 questions on average.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-05-17
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-2020-05-17/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-2020-05-17/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My Stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/covid19-05-17/&#34;&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s quarantine notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt;: A bit of Laravel work, and a bit of server management and deployment. Nothing too ridiculous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching&lt;/strong&gt;: Haven&amp;rsquo;t watched much this week. There was the really great &lt;strong&gt;Justice League Dark: Apokolips War&lt;/strong&gt; which came out last week. Apparently it&amp;rsquo;s the last one for the DC AMU, or this particular timeline at least.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quiz&lt;/strong&gt;: We are now up to 3 locally produced online quiz nights per week, which seems like a lot because we only used to attend 2-3 live events per month. I managed to tie for first place in the Geekfight one this week, but we didn&amp;rsquo;t win either of the other two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I played a lot of Divinity Original Sin 2 this week, probably much more than a healthy amount. Really started to get into it, but I think I&amp;rsquo;m not even halfway into the game?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday group also played some Scythe from the Asmodee bundle. It&amp;rsquo;s a challenging worker placement-like boardgame with some combat, but the UI for the PC version is pretty terrible. I did not win during our first session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech&lt;/strong&gt;: Got tired of my terrible audio jack which has been emitting static to my speakers and earphones. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t clean it, instead I went ahead and ordered some fancy HyperX gaming headphones from Lazada, which has already started selling nonessentials again. Might take a couple of weeks to get here though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site Updates&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this site used to have a live backup available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.github.io/&#34;&gt;roytang.github.io&lt;/a&gt;, but starting this week the builds have been failing. I assume it&amp;rsquo;s because my repository has gotten too large. Most of it is images and videos. I may need to consider an alternative approach where only the text stuff is in the repos, to keep the repo size down, otherwise we are really gonna have scaling issues down the road. Need to think about this for a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent Links of Interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I always like it when a &lt;a href=&#34;http://tttthis.com/blog/if-i-could-bring-one-thing-back-to-the-internet-it-would-be-blogs&#34;&gt;post about blogs&lt;/a&gt; makes it to the front page of Hacker News. It means the &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23205588&#34;&gt;ensuing discussion&lt;/a&gt; has a lot of people talking about why blogs aren&amp;rsquo;t actually dead and many sharing their own blogs which I get to take a look at. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll write a post detailing how I think about this particular post. If I feel like it. After reading through all the blogs from these links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://macwright.org/2020/05/10/spa-fatigue.html&#34;&gt;This post by Tom MacWright&lt;/a&gt; encapsulates much of how I feel by the modern push toward React and other frameworks in web development. Old-school web dev forever!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2020/may/09/the-real-lord-of-the-flies-what-happened-when-six-boys-were-shipwrecked-for-15-months&#34;&gt;Fascinating story&lt;/a&gt; about a real-life Lord of the Flies situation that turned about much better than the very pessimistic book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for this week!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-05-10
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-2020-05-10/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-2020-05-10/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My Stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early this morning I took a walk outside for the first time since the lockdown started. Previously I had only gone out for groceries and meds. Only for less than 30 mins, and only in our subdivision, walking up and down the street. It&amp;rsquo;s good to be walking again, although this short and limited route is quite boring and full of neighbor&amp;rsquo;s dogs barking at me, so I&amp;rsquo;m not too fond of it, but it&amp;rsquo;s better to get the habit started again since I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling the fatness piling on due to the quarantine and the lack of exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work&lt;/strong&gt;: A few consultation meetings here and there, but starting next week I may need to do some actual coding work for other people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching&lt;/strong&gt;: Watched a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;few movies this week&lt;/a&gt;, The Siege (caught it on TV during my lunch break), Skull Island (because Brie Larson), Ready Player One (it&amp;rsquo;s Cyclops!), and also watched Ang Huling El Bimbo the Musical (Not really a movie, but ok). I also ended up watching the 2 episodes of the Battlestar Galactica miniseries; apparently I had not watched this before watching the 2004 series. I also watched the hilarious Middleditch and Schwartz improv comedy specials on Netflix, fun times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;: Played a bunch of Divinity Original Sin 2 this week, though I guess I&amp;rsquo;m still not that far along in the story? I also purchased the Humble Asmodee bundle, for more boardgames-converted-to-PC-games that my weekend playgroup can do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Site Updates&lt;/strong&gt;: Been putting up some content elsewhere on this site. You can find it easily if you look around, but nothing to announce publicly yet. Need to think about how to present properly, good permalinks, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent Links of Interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of starting a separate regular type of post where I just post links to things I found on the internet. Kind of like the links page, except with more commentary? I know people like &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralistic.net/&#34;&gt;Doctorow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kottke.org/&#34;&gt;Kottke&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://waxy.org/&#34;&gt;Waxy&lt;/a&gt; have been doing this kind of thing for a while, thinking of something along the same lines I guess? Something I can maybe turn into some kind of newsletter later on? We&amp;rsquo;ll see if it pans out. For now, let&amp;rsquo;s keep it in the weeknotes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Somewhat related to the first bullet: Great post from &lt;a href=&#34;https://secondbreakfast.co&#34;&gt;secondbreakfast.co&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://secondbreakfast.co/its-too-late-to-collect-sand&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s too late to collect sand&lt;/a&gt;. Basically saying if there&amp;rsquo;s something you regret not being able to start earlier on, it would be a trap to think that you can&amp;rsquo;t just start it today. I say somewhat related to the first bullet because as I was reviewing some older blog entries during the past few weeks I was wondering if I could have made it as a &amp;ldquo;successful blogger&amp;rdquo; like the people mentioned above if I had only been more consistent with my content. Such regrets are ridiculous, as the post implies, because I could always just ramp up my linkblogging now if I wanted. Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ve also scanned a few of the other posts on secondbreakfast.co, and many of them are fairly good reads, so this one might end up being added to the regular follows and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/blogroll/&#34;&gt;blogroll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AirBNB is laying off one-fourth of its staff and refocusing its priorities. This is not exactly unexpected given the current situation and the bleak outlook for the travel industry in the near term, but what I found exceptional was &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.airbnb.com/a-message-from-co-founder-and-ceo-brian-chesky/&#34;&gt;CEO Brian Chesky&amp;rsquo;s message to their employees&lt;/a&gt;. Announcing layoffs is obviously a feel-bad, but this note was handled extremely well, walking through the rationales and the painful decision and giving their staff clear expectations on what will happen moving forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One tech company that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been treating their employees too well however, has been Amazon. Last week, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/202x/2020/04/29/Leaving-Amazon&#34;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; from Amazon VP, Senior Engineer, and XML spec-writer Tim Bray made the rounds as he publicly declared he was resigning from his position (costing him around a million dollars) because of how the company has fired whistleblowers who were complaining about Covid-19 safety concerns at their warehouses. Good for Bray, and boo for Amazon. One may also find the links he posted in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/202x/2020/05/06/Answers&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Responses&amp;rdquo; post&lt;/a&gt; of interest as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/23/magazine/closing-prune-restaurant-covid.html&#34;&gt;Great article in the NY times&lt;/a&gt; (Annoying paywall warning!) about what it&amp;rsquo;s like owning and having to shutdown a restaurant in these times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kk.org/thetechnium/68-bits-of-unsolicited-advice/&#34;&gt;68 bits of unsolicited advise&lt;/a&gt; from Kevin Kelly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying Tom Scott&amp;rsquo;s Youtube channel recently (unsurprisingly, he&amp;rsquo;s a very popular Youtuber). I recently found out his background is actually in linguistics! Anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l4bmZ1gRqCc&#34;&gt;a video from him about confusing differences in numbers across languages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Singapore, they have &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2020/5/8/21251788/spot-boston-dynamics-robot-singapore-park-social-distancing&#34;&gt;a robot dog making sure people are social distancing in public&lt;/a&gt;. This is why &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yahoo.com/entertainment/no-black-mirror-episodes-creator-162238548.html&#34;&gt;the creator of Black Mirror isn&amp;rsquo;t even bothering right now&lt;/a&gt;, reality is just too much already.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hoping we have a good week incoming, despite the current situation!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-05-03
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-2020-05-03/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-2020-05-03/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;First week of May. At least two more weeks of quarantine remain. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;COVID19 Diary&lt;/a&gt; still exists, only updated every so often. I stayed in the entire week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week was slightly more productive than the last one, at least in terms of personal projects. I moved a couple of them forward. And also spent a bunch of time spring cleaning and moving stuff around here on the site. Details to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quizzes: I watched the Geekfight, but I could only personally answer like 4 questions maybe. My teammate who was an official player did much better. We joined the PopQuiz one, but got a cursed ace and finished low. Looking forward to next week&amp;rsquo;s quizzes, and there may even be a new organizer setting up an online quiz!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;watching-lately&#34;&gt;Watching lately&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I burned through the remaining 5 seasons of Psych and the 2017 Psych movie as well. Overall it&amp;rsquo;s a really fun series, despite usually sticking to a formula. Chock-full of pop culture references and shout-outs and in-jokes and such, just the kind of thing I enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only other thing I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this week was the Parks and Recreation reunion special (quarantine edition), fun episode and happy to see these guys all together again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least I can watch other things now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kind of want to be filling out a &amp;ldquo;things of interest&amp;rdquo; section in these weeknotes every week, basically collecting interesting things I found on the internet during the week. I do find/read a bunch of interesting things over the week, but the problem is I seldom log them down for future posting. Will need to correct moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gaming&#34;&gt;Gaming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ikoria drafting is done for me, for now at least. You can view all my Ikoria drafts at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgiko&#34;&gt;MTGIKO tag&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My FF7 Remake Deluxe Edition copy &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/ff7r/&#34;&gt;got delivered last Friday&lt;/a&gt;! I briefly considered asking my brother to drive over and bring my PS4 home, but that isn&amp;rsquo;t really essential travel so I thought better of it. Cloud and company will have to wait. I&amp;rsquo;m not in a hurry, and really, there&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of other games to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humblebundle.com/subscription/may-2020&#34;&gt;Humble Choice for May&lt;/a&gt; is out, but not too happy with the choices. I already have X-Com II, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even come with the War of the Chosen DLC! Probably passing on this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other things: Trivia team set up a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCptXvNbp4ETVttb_k-1oOww&#34;&gt;Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;. I suspect the videos will be more gaming-related than trivia-related though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site updates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cleanups of old content (mostly stuff that got mangled during import from Wordpress or elsewhere)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;together with the pass over the old content, I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting together some &amp;ldquo;media diet&amp;rdquo; pages. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this in a few other blogs, where they track all their media (TV/movies/books) consumption. I&amp;rsquo;m already doing this more often with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately&#34;&gt;Watching lately posts&lt;/a&gt; (and in the weeknotes), and my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/lists/2020/movies&#34;&gt;2020 movies list&lt;/a&gt;, but I wanted it to include other media types too (including games), so I started putting together the lists. For the older years, I have to reconstruct the media list from old blog posts and so on, so they&amp;rsquo;re bound to be incomplete and probably inaccurate, but it is what it is. I started from 2002 and working my way back to the present. It&amp;rsquo;s still WIP, but the list should be &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/media/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;adding some other new stuff/sections, but nothing linked publicly yet. Need to arrange everything correctly, may take a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-04-26
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/weeknotes-2020-04-26/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/weeknotes-2020-04-26/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the last week of April, but thanks to an extension, we are still in for three more weeks of quarantine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;COVID19 Diary&lt;/a&gt; is still being updated sporadically. Only went out once this week, for groceries. We tried to buy a bit more than usual, hoping to reduce the number of times we need to go out. We also celebrated a couple of birthdays in the family, through a zoom call, complete with the grandkids blowing on a candle from across the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week wasn&amp;rsquo;t very productive. Lots of sitting or lying around, scrolling through feeds, instead of doing something &amp;ldquo;productive&amp;rdquo;. I mean, I used to do this even before the quarantine, but these days I&amp;rsquo;m just more inclined, I think?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lot less consulting work this week, as I wrapped up most of the stuff I needed to do last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We skipped this week&amp;rsquo;s online Geekfight, because the categories were not in our favor. We did watch the stream, and I could only answer at most one question per round. We were hoping to do well in the PopQuiz one, since it was a rerun of a 90s-themed quiz that we actually won a few years ago. The competition was tougher this time though, and we ended up in the lower half of the pack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;watching-lately&#34;&gt;Watching lately&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t watch anything this week other than the Brooklyn Nine-Nine season finale (great episode!) and seasons 2-3 of Psych (the series can be uneven, but is still entertaining to watch).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things of interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just a week after writing about using &lt;a href=&#34;https://bibliogram.art/&#34;&gt;Bibliogram&lt;/a&gt; for instagram RSS feeds, they ended up disabling them on their instance due to the increased load. I&amp;rsquo;d like to think that was my fault. They provided some alternatives, including other instances or even running your own. I instead ended up just using &lt;a href=&#34;https://rssbridge.co.uk/&#34;&gt;RSS Bridge&lt;/a&gt;. Hope it works out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gaming&#34;&gt;Gaming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ikoria drafting is proceeding apace, with me doing at least one draft a day. All the records available at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgiko&#34;&gt;MTGIKO tag&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My LGS has contacted me saying they can now deliver my FF7 Remake Deluxe Edition preorder! I made the payment last Friday, and hopefully I can receive it later this week. Now how to get my PS4 from my brother&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I purchased the Jackbox Party Pack 5 from Steam last week and played a few YDKJ games with the quiz team, with streaming via Discord. Not bad, reasonably entertaining (although US-centric). The rest of the games in the pack seem boring though. Might need the right crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Divinity: Original Sin 2 is proceeding apace. Somehow top-down isometric RPGs aren&amp;rsquo;t as enticing to me now compared to FF-style games. I guess they do feel similar to Baldur&amp;rsquo;s Gate back in the day and Pillars more recently, but the immersion is a bit more challenging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site updates: Nothing of significance this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should have a sign-off. How about &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t drink bleach?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-04-19
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/weeknotes-2020-04-19/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/weeknotes-2020-04-19/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This week went by quickly, for some reason. And despite the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s summer, the rains have started coming in early, although only sporadically. inb4 &amp;ldquo;the world is healing&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;COVID19 Diary&lt;/a&gt; is still being updated every few days. Actually went out 3 times this week, once for groceries, and twice for meds for the parental units (one would assume they would coordinate so I can just buy everything in one go, but nooooo.) Maybe that contributed to why the week went by so fast for me. Going out these days saps your energy a lot more than it used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiny bit of consulting work this week. Wrapped up something I was checking for a client, and helped another one optimize their Wordpress install. It&amp;rsquo;s simple, but it&amp;rsquo;s honest work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were two online quiz nights again this week. I didn&amp;rsquo;t play in the Geekfight one, only watched, as the theme (musicals) was out of my wheelhouse. We actually attended the original one for this back in 2016, and correspondingly did quite poorly lol. The second one was team based and was literature-themed, with four rounds based on specific authors each: Stephen King, Agatha Christie, Michael Crichton and Neil Gaiman. I actually rewatched the Agatha Christie Doctor Who ep for this, but the relevant question was super easy anyway, doh! We did reasonably well, but only managed to finish second. Facebook Live continues to be a horrible experience for this given the lag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;watching-lately&#34;&gt;Watching lately&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed that Psych was on Prime Video and have now accidentally binged the entire first season. I recommended this series to a friend, but upon watching the first season (I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve seen any of these eps before) I can&amp;rsquo;t explain why I&amp;rsquo;m so entertained by it. Shawn&amp;rsquo;s antics are over-the-top, and the cases he solves are often ridiculous, but I enjoy it anyway. (Edit: After reading some old convos with people, I suspect it might because I also on occasion attempt to pretend to be a psychic lol.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only movie I watched last week was Spirited Away. Check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;2020 movies page&lt;/a&gt; for my commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things of interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cory Doctorow is blogging again outside of BoingBoing via a new blog called &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralistic.net/&#34;&gt;Pluralistic&lt;/a&gt;. Each daily entry contains some number of links, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of like a newsletter really.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bibliogram.art/&#34;&gt;Bibliogram&lt;/a&gt; is a privacy-focused write-only web frontend for Instagram, that also provides RSS feeds. This kind of site can be fragile to maintain since I doubt they are using the closed official Instagram API. I fully expect whatever integration they are using to break sometimes and at some point in the future, permanently. Nonetheless, I used it to move some of my follows from Instagram to my feed reader (mostly less important ones like comic book artists). There is also an equivalent web front end for Twitter called &lt;a href=&#34;https://nitter.net/&#34;&gt;Nitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is also a web extension called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/SimonBrazell/privacy-redirect&#34;&gt;Privacy Redirect&lt;/a&gt; that automatically redirects twitter and instagram requests (among others) to the privacy-focused equivalents (as described above). I tried this for a bit, and it&amp;rsquo;s ok if you only use these sites in a read-only manner. But you can&amp;rsquo;t reply or repost, etc. And if I want to share something via tweet, it attempts to redirect the twitter dialog to nitter, which has no equivalent URL. I also logged an issue &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zedeus/nitter/issues/146&#34;&gt;re:trailing slashes on Nitter&lt;/a&gt;. Since I&amp;rsquo;m still using these sites on a read-write basis, I can&amp;rsquo;t use this extension myself, but maybe some of you may find it useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gaming&#34;&gt;Gaming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ikoria is out on Magic Arena! I&amp;rsquo;ve done a few drafts already, you can check them out at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgiko&#34;&gt;MTGIKO tag&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Saturday gaming group recently switched our multiplayer game from Sentinels of the Multiverse to Armello. Quick review: It&amp;rsquo;s a fun, four player competitive board-game like where you try to beat each other to become king of a land of anthromorphized animals. I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s a real-world board game equivalent for it though, some of the mechanics don&amp;rsquo;t seem feasible IRL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also thought about buying one of the Jackbox party packs so I could play online trivia with the quiz team, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten much positive feedback. And they&amp;rsquo;d all need Steam accounts so I could stream the screen to them, that&amp;rsquo;s a barrier. I&amp;rsquo;ll think about it some more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Divinity: Original Sin 2 is still my current ongoing RPG. Haven&amp;rsquo;t been playing it too often, but making some progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site updates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I added a link to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ko-fi.com/roytang&#34;&gt;support me via Ko-fi&lt;/a&gt;, if you&amp;rsquo;d like. I don&amp;rsquo;t really expect anybody to use it, but maybe someone finds one of my posts useful and is generous? My expectations are low, so anything that comes through this channel will be a pleasant surprise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve disabled the comment form from blog posts. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of spam that gets submitted, despite the Google Captcha. They don&amp;rsquo;t show up on the site since I have to review them, but it&amp;rsquo;s a mild annoyance. And for some reason, the spam comments tend to focus on specific posts, an example is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2020/01/new-years-checklist/&#34;&gt;2020 New Year Checklist&lt;/a&gt; post. They used to focus on some older posts, but a while back I disabled comments on posts older than a year. I wonder if spammers share these links and are like &amp;ldquo;hey, this would be a good post to spam comments on!&amp;rdquo; Anyway: on a rare occasion some of my friends will comment via the form, but the majority of interaction with my posts these days is via bridgy webmention, so it probably wasn&amp;rsquo;t worth keeping around. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what to expect in the weeks to come. The future is so uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-04-12 Easter Sunday Edition
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/weeknotes-2020-04-12/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/weeknotes-2020-04-12/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I stopped updating the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;COVID19 Diary&lt;/a&gt; for a few days (last update was on Maunday Thursday), and I feel like that was a healthier choice overall. It helped that nothing significantly newsworthy happened over the long weekend. (Well, there&amp;rsquo;s still thousands of deaths worldwide, but somehow our bar for &amp;ldquo;significant&amp;rdquo; has shifted quite a bit.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lockdown has of course been extended to the end of April. I expect it will go beyond that though, likely the earliest chance for things to start going back to normal might be by June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got some consulting work done in the first half of the week, mostly setting up some automation for a client. Looks like they&amp;rsquo;ll have more to do for me next week so at least I&amp;rsquo;m keeping busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also managed to do two online quiz nights again, doing more poorly this time, but still pretty fun. The second one was held last night (Black Saturday), and it was a team effort, so it involved our trivia team on an FB Messenger call while watching the quiz via FB live. FB Live sucks for this kind of thing due to lag, but we had fun (but still did not do well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it&amp;rsquo;s Easter Sunday and the folks haven&amp;rsquo;t seen their grandkids for a while, me and the bros set up a Zoom call so all the grandkids could see the grandparents, everyone all together at once. As could be expected, it was kind of chaotic, but also all kinds of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;watching-lately&#34;&gt;Watching lately&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the weekend to watch a few movies, notably completing the Hobbit trilogy. This trilogy wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good as the LotR one (talk about high bar to meet right?), but pretty watchable in its own right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also watched The Departed, pretty intense movie. Gradually building up to watching the Irishman on Netflix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I watched this fantastic collaborative fan-made shot-by-shot remake of Back to the Future II put together during quarantine, featuring all kinds of ridiculousness: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GcUUjWbVc4I&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GcUUjWbVc4I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;2020 movies page&lt;/a&gt; for my commentary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, I also rewatched the last two seasons of Community (now surprisingly available on both Netflix and Prime Video at the same time!), mostly to prep for a trivia round, but also because it&amp;rsquo;s a fun underrated show and more people should watch it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some things of interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ai-art.tokyo/en#/&#34;&gt;Al Gahaku&lt;/a&gt;, an AI &amp;ldquo;artist&amp;rdquo; that takes an existing photograph and modifies it to look like a renaissance-style painting. Pretty fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this &lt;a href=&#34;https://ncase.me/contact-tracing/&#34;&gt;great comic&lt;/a&gt; summarizing a privacy-respecting bluetooth-based contact tracing protocol. Nice way to present information for easier consumption by the general public.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gaming&#34;&gt;Gaming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Been playing mostly Magic Arena (wasting my gold on &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/1248178769275256832/&#34;&gt;cube sealed&lt;/a&gt;, really fun), Divinity: Original Sin 2 (kind of a slow burn) and a bit of Megaman Legacy Collection (currently about halfway through Megaman 3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake is out this week. I had a Deluxe edition preorder with our local game store, but given they&amp;rsquo;re all closed IDK how that&amp;rsquo;s going to work now. The store collected information from everyone who preordered so that they can give out info, but no updates yet. I suspect they&amp;rsquo;re going to try to set up some kind of delivery service, but don&amp;rsquo;t want to promise too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas even if I could get my FF7R copy, I don&amp;rsquo;t even have my PS4 at home as it was borrowed by my brother in February. I was planning to get it back right before the FF7R release, but eh, life in quarantine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dug up some old draft blog posts that I never published, so I polished them up and we should have some new content for the coming week (other than these weeknotes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, I&amp;rsquo;ve been considering re-organizing how this blog/site is organized. I was recently reading Kev Quirk&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://kevq.uk/why-i-dont-use-a-static-site-generator/&#34;&gt;post about why he doesn&amp;rsquo;t use a static site generator&lt;/a&gt;, it kind of tempted me to consider switching back to Wordpress. The main problem with Hugo running this site at the moment is that the build time is quite long, so feedback can take a while. (Still the same issue I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/one-year-with-hugo/&#34;&gt;reported in November&lt;/a&gt;.) Anyway, I considered going back to Wordpress, and while that&amp;rsquo;s certainly a viable solution, there are some things that I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of doing that would be complicated to do in Wordpress&amp;rsquo;s data structure. Also, my gut doesn&amp;rsquo;t like the idea, although there are certainly some pros. I&amp;rsquo;ll need to think about this a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someday, we&amp;rsquo;ll find our way back to the world we once knew, but it will have moved beyond us.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-04-05
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/weeknotes-2020-04-05/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/weeknotes-2020-04-05/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;COVID19 Diary&lt;/a&gt; is still ongoing, and I have yet to find a solution for the TOC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today is Palm Sunday. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this early in the morning, so IDK yet how the church will adapt the usual fanfare to this whole pandemic thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summer heat has begun to settle in during the last few weeks of quarantine. I can&amp;rsquo;t sit without a shirt or rest or my arms anywhere without sweat threatening to accumulate on the contact surface. Coincidentally around the first week of the lockdown, our aircon in the only airconditioned room in the house started making funny noises so we&amp;rsquo;ve stopped using it. At least we get to save electricty?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall this week much less productive than the last. I felt a stronger tendency to &amp;ldquo;veg out&amp;rdquo; as it were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to write any new blog posts this week (other than the weeknotes). It seems kind of difficult to get your thoughts together when your brain is constantly distracted by the state of the world. I mean, how could I ever finish a post titled &amp;ldquo;Things learned from a crisis&amp;rdquo; when things are moving so quickly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work has gotten a bit busier this week, as there are some things a client is asking me to do that he says are urgent, but really is little more than just saving them a bit of effort by automating stuff. I will say however that I&amp;rsquo;m amazed how strong his business still seems to be going, given they&amp;rsquo;re an industry that I don&amp;rsquo;t really consider essential. Still, more work is fine, as it helps distract me from the prevailing mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did two online quiz nights again. I even managed to win one of them! These are a fun distraction (even though there are no prizes!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;watching-lately&#34;&gt;Watching lately&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Season 4 of Kim&amp;rsquo;s Convenience came out on Netflix. It continues to be an light, enjoyable and easy to binge show, though the season was only 13 eps long so it was over quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also finished watching Star Trek: Picard S1, via Prime Video.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It started off slow, and I was worried it would be one of those conspiracy theory shows where the conspiracy part dragged on forever (X-Files may have traumatized me a bit).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t! It started picking up the pace around episode 5 or 6, as the elements behind the conspiracy came back into view.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And while Picard&amp;rsquo;s new crew seemed so motely and largely unnecessary during the first half, they each ended up with satisfying character arcs and backstories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    although the reveal Rios&amp;rsquo; history that ties in to the whole synth issue seems awfully convenient.
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad we got to revisit old friends like Seven of Nine, Data, Riker and Troi, and even Hugh, just to see what they&amp;rsquo;ve been up to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I must admit I felt a great deal of satisfaction when 
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    Riker shows up near the end with a whole armada (although realistically it seems logistically impossible for Starfleet to have put such a large number of top-of-the-line ships together so quickly)
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;only 1 new movie watched this week, the first of the Hobbit trilogy. I meant to watch all three, but you know, distractions happened.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not many links to share today, but I will say that a new update to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickscondor.com/hrefhunt/&#34;&gt;Kicks Condor&amp;rsquo;s Href Hunt&lt;/a&gt; is out, and I&amp;rsquo;m still in the process of going through all the featured sites. If you like perusing people&amp;rsquo;s personal sites, this one is always fun to check out, and the current release has a ton of sites!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gaming&#34;&gt;Gaming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Humble&amp;rsquo;s Choice is kind of meh for me. I may pause again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of multiplayer gaming again this week. SC2 with my usual gaming group. Armello with my other gaming group. And now even my brothers are asking around if we all have Left 4 Dead 2 installed (but we haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to a session yet.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No progress on Megaman LC this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I purchased Divinity: Original Sin 2 a couple of weeks ago in anticipation of an extended lockdown and finally started it up this week. I played a premade character first to get a feel of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this week was the start of spoiler season for the next MTG set, Ikoria. And it&amp;rsquo;s kind of crazy; they&amp;rsquo;re doing a crossover with Toho to feature Godzilla-themed alters for certain cards. There was a leak before that Godzilla would be in the set, which seemed ridiculous, but here we are! I think the set comes out in a week, and it looks pretty sweet, looking forward to playing it on Arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal projects: Thinking of finally adding a set of new trivia questions to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://triviastorm.net/&#34;&gt;trivia app&lt;/a&gt;. Mostly because our quizzing activity has kind of gone up while in quarantine (including random friends sharing quizzes etc.) A lot of the older questions/answers are kind of low quality too, so I want to implement some kind of weighted random selection so that newer questions are more likely to be picked. But first I need to cobble together a decent data set. Most of it will be movie and TV related I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent site changes: Not much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s highly probably that our lockdown is going to be extended by at least a month. Sigh.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-03-29 Time Is Meaningless
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-29/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-29/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;COVID19 Diary&lt;/a&gt; is still ongoing, although that TOC is starting to get unwieldy. Need to think of a better UX solution for that.&lt;/p&gt;








    
    
        
    
    
    
        
            
            
            
            
              
            
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#ebaca044327af45cfc02b507f864565e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
                &lt;figure&gt;
                  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1242953238497751040/ET_bYDoUMAA8vty_hu61559ea2fb5b54ac6f28ab0474d68098_8100_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;ldquo;Time is meaningless under extreme enhanced community quarantine&amp;rdquo;&#34; title=&#34;&amp;ldquo;Time is meaningless under extreme enhanced community quarantine&amp;rdquo;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
                  &lt;figcaption&gt;Time is meaningless under extreme enhanced community quarantine (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
                &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;ebaca044327af45cfc02b507f864565e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1242953238497751040/ET_bYDoUMAA8vty.png&#34; /&gt;
              &lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Time is meaningless under extreme enhanced community quarantine&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;29 Mar 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;29 Mar 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1242953238497751040/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;            
        
    

&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;rsquo;s probably unrealistic, but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the lockdown somehow gets lifted sooner rather than later. It&amp;rsquo;s not that I crave social interaction (I don&amp;rsquo;t), but I miss going out for food. I miss pizza. And japanese curry. And fancy sandwiches with sesame seeds and such. The food at the house is fine and all, but tends to get repetitive. And during the last grocery run, the only mayonnaise they had was Best Foods Mayo Magic. Bleah. I&amp;rsquo;m so gonna eat at so many places after all of this is over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the upside, I did get to do much more stuff this work compared to last week, among other things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/blog/&#34;&gt;few posts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;participated in 2 online quiz nights!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a bit more consulting work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some room cleanup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some cleanup/sorting of old files and stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;did the groceries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;paid my dad&amp;rsquo;s credit card bills online (he was actually planning to go to the bank to pay them!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;watching-lately&#34;&gt;Watching lately&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ll retire the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately/&#34;&gt;watching lately tag&lt;/a&gt; and just include my media notes here in the weeknotes. More convenient, and more fine-tuned. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it works out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;4 new movies&lt;/a&gt;. Rate has slowed down a lot, but I figure I could get to a 100 for the year still. Princess Mononoke and Logan Lucky were particularly good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also started watching Picard (via Amazon Prime Video), since all the episodes have aired. I&amp;rsquo;m only a couple of episodes in, but I can already tell it has a completely different feel than TNG (or any of the TV series pre-Discovery for that matter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;greatly enjoyed Brooklyn Nine-Nine this week with JK Simmons!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gaming&#34;&gt;Gaming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since everyone&amp;rsquo;s at home, I&amp;rsquo;m getting a lot of multiplayer gaming done. This week our gaming group got into team Starcraft 2 vs AI battles. (We find ladder too stressful!). Since we have discord these days for voice, there is much more coordination in the team battles. And we even have some post-match analysis going on in our discord channel!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the singleplayer side, I managed to finished Megaman 1 in the Legacy Collection! Easily the toughest of the early Megaman games. Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MiWhBlrGiK8&#34;&gt;a video of me struggling to beat the yellow devil/cyclops&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to be able to beat all 6 of the games in the collection. I&amp;rsquo;m old and rusty and don&amp;rsquo;t have the reflexes of 1990s Roy, but at least I have savescumming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I passed on this month&amp;rsquo;s Humble Choice. I kind of wanted Fell Seal, but not that badly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal projects: Minor bug fixes mostly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent site changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I added the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums&#34;&gt;albums&lt;/a&gt; section under photos (similar to how FB has albums I guess?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mass formatting cleanup of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/quora&#34;&gt;old posts imported from quora&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minor CSS changes in various places&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything specific to look forward to in the coming week. Time under the lockdown moves at a different scale, we just take everything one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-03-22 Quarantine Edition
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-22/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-22/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Past week has been difficult productivity-wise. I mean, the isolation isn&amp;rsquo;t really a problem for me since I&amp;rsquo;m usually at home anyway. But it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to find the energy to be productive about anything. It&amp;rsquo;s like the whole pandemic situation manifests as a lingering ball of anxiety in the back of my head. My parents are prayerful and hopeful that things get resolved quickly, but I&amp;rsquo;m not super optimistic - I think it&amp;rsquo;s likely to go long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;COVID19 Diary&lt;/a&gt; is still ongoing if you want more day-to-day thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When thinking about how the world is handling this pandemic, the words of one of my boardgame friends comes to mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everyone&amp;rsquo;s playing like idiots!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s my excuse anyway, for no other posts this week. I did have some ideas for posts, but not the energy or clarity to write them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my time this week went into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;consulting work (the show must go on)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gaming: I started playing Stellaris again. New build has much better late game performance. I tried playing a Hive Mind race this time, and had a false start because apparently completing the Old Gods event and becoming spiritual breaks the hive mind. Second attempt I made it to a late game, waiting for final crisis to emerge. If I get impatient I&amp;rsquo;ll just conquer everyone else!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gaming: friends who are also stuck at home means we&amp;rsquo;re trying more multiplayer stuff as well. Aside from the usual SC2, we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing Orcs Must Die 2 and are planning to do Left 4 Dead 2 and/or Monaco. (Shades of 5-10 years ago!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;gaming: In lieu of this month&amp;rsquo;s Humble Choice, I got the bottom tier of Humble&amp;rsquo;s current Capcom bundle, mostly for Megaman Legacy Collection. I tried playing Megaman 1 for a bit, but it&amp;rsquo;s much harder than I remember and my hands are not so used to this controller stress and got tired quickly. Still, I might stream this in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watching: I took the opportunity to clear out the backlog of Jeopardy eps on Netflix (new sets not as good as the previous ones), and also finished up the back half of The Expanse S3. The Expanse still pretty good, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I like how Holden is becoming some kind of central messiah figure because of his connection to Miller. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how S4 goes I guess.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;side note: one would assume I would take this time to add some more entries to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;2020 movies list&lt;/a&gt;, but I really haven&amp;rsquo;t felt like it at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;quiz: in lieu of our regular quiz nights, two of our friendly quiz providers decided to try hosting online quizzes this week! They had different formats; one was via Zoom with people showing whiteboards at their cameras, while another was via Facebook Live with answers in the comments. Both had technical issues, but were fun nonetheless. A welcome respite and a little bit of online community interaction in these dark times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal projects: Minor movement and bug fixes on one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also took some time to clean up some stuff both physically (around the house) and digitally. The digital part mostly involves moving some of my notes off the online platforms I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying lately and into plain text files in Dropbox. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably write about those online platforms I tried and why I didn&amp;rsquo;t think they worked out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site changes this week: Not much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure what the next week will bring, but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping as we settle further into this new normal (however long it may last), we are better able to mentally cope with it and maybe even find some source of optimism for the days ahead.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-03-15. The world is chaos, be kind.
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-15/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-15/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s chaos, be kind&amp;rdquo; - Michelle McNamara on the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current events:&lt;/strong&gt; This past week has been&amp;hellip; challenging to say the least. Especially if you&amp;rsquo;re the sort who experiences anxiety over the smallest uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was originally going to write about local COVID19 happenings in this space, but it ended up being way too many words. I spun it off into &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;a separate post&lt;/a&gt;, and intend to update it periodically as events unfold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to remember the events of the week other than the COVID19 stuff, but the first half was still mostly normal. I went out for a client meeting on Monday and did some filial errands and bill payments over Tuesday and Wednesday. For me, the crisis mostly escalated on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I mentioned last week how I got into Frostpunk. I streamed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1237749177741914122/&#34;&gt;second session of a blind run&lt;/a&gt;, but after getting a bit stressed at the news, I decided to keep playing into the early morning and finished the run without streaming or recording it. Game is pretty good, and sufficiently challenging. I finished a couple of other scenarios during the week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also tried a couple of other multiplayer games this week: one was the multiplayer Bannerlord beta, I got an invite middle of the week. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of meh, mostly just people spawning, running around maybe killing 1-2 other people, then dying and respawning. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really into Mount and Blade for this kind of combat anyway, more for the simulation side. The other game was Orcs Must Die 2, which I already had in my library but hadn&amp;rsquo;t played yet, but a friend suggested it when we were looking for games to coop. Fun game, fairly similar to the first one, I think coop is the only major addition, but haven&amp;rsquo;t explored it too much so I could be wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been holding off on starting any longer games since I&amp;rsquo;m anticipating &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/upcoming-gaming-things/&#34;&gt;the release of Final Fantasay VII Remake in early April&lt;/a&gt;, but now the release date is going to be near the tail-end of the Metro Manila lockdown (and with some uncertainty as to what happens after), I&amp;rsquo;m wondering if I should reconsider&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links:&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m maintaining &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/blogroll/&#34;&gt;a blogroll&lt;/a&gt; now, and I try to update it every so often, but I thought I&amp;rsquo;d highlight some of the sites listed there and why I chose to follow them and have them there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://paulcapewell.com&#34;&gt;Paul Capewell&lt;/a&gt; tagged me in a couple of posts last month (thanks webmentions!) so I checked out his blog. I enjoy his &amp;ldquo;stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve seen and read recently&amp;rdquo; kind of posts, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulcapewell.com&#34;&gt;this one here&lt;/a&gt;. It helps me find other nice blogs to read and at the very least highlights some interesting articles. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to incorporate something like these into the weeknotes (or maybe into a separate monthly post?). We&amp;rsquo;ll see - the challenge here is actually logging down interesting things I read online, given I read &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; and don&amp;rsquo;t have the habit of noting everything. I share some of interest via pocket, which goes into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/links&#34;&gt;Links page&lt;/a&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;m fairly sure I could do better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One blog I found via Paul&amp;rsquo;s site is &lt;a href=&#34;https://frankchimero.com/&#34;&gt;Frank Chimero&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt;. I enjoyed Frank&amp;rsquo;s series of &amp;ldquo;redesign&amp;rdquo; posts where he talks about design decisions for his site&amp;rsquo;s ongoing redesign. The latest post is &lt;a href=&#34;https://frankchimero.com/blog/2020/gridniking/&#34;&gt;this one on grid layouts&lt;/a&gt;. I consider myself to not have a &amp;ldquo;design eye&amp;rdquo; as it were, so this kind of thing is mostly educational for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ve known of &lt;a href=&#34;https://nedbatchelder.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Ned Batchelder&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt; for at least a decade. He was one of the early developer blogs I followed. He writes mostly about Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://testkeis.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Testkeis&lt;/a&gt; is run by an IRL friend of mine who I don&amp;rsquo;t have much contact with these days (Hi Keis!), but I&amp;rsquo;m glad she&amp;rsquo;s gotten back into blogging over the past couple of years. She mostly posts about software testing as that&amp;rsquo;s her specialization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal projects: Minor movement on one I haven&amp;rsquo;t touched in a while, but for the most part idle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site changes this week: Not much either. I added a &amp;ldquo;Pinned items&amp;rdquo; section to the front page, mostly for the Covid19 post. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if this turns out to be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next week I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Damnit IDK, too much uncertainty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We originally had a quiz night scheduled, but it looks like most such events are postponed indefinitely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are infinity backlogs I could get around to though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s to hoping we survive the coming weeks!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-03-08
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-08/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-08/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The Week That Was: The COVID19 pandemic is starting to pick up steam, both internationally (including the US) and here in the Philippines. The Trump administration seems to be handling things poorly, which would be typical to expect of an administration not used to transparency or integrity. For all our sakes they need to get their act together. The PH government appears to be doing slightly better (assuming no hidden epidemic), although their messaging still seems to be all over the place. Some local governments have started suspending classes and private business are now requiring self-quarantines, and rumor has it the Greenhills business district was a ghost town the last few days after a confirmed case identified in that area. Bill Gates famously warned a few years ago that a global pandemic may be the most predictable threat to the world in modern times, but let&amp;rsquo;s hope our governments can get their act together and get this thing under control. Otherwise, the future may look like this:&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1236252441600872449/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2020-03-07 11:28:45&#34;&gt;7 Mar 2020 11:28am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The year is 2034. Everybody has COVID19, toilet paper is but a distant memory. A young woman claims to be immune. Crowds flock around to watch her touch her own face.&lt;/p&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like how the weeknotes give me space to do a little commentary on world events without needing to do a full blog post about them. So let&amp;rsquo;s talk US politics for a bit. I&amp;rsquo;m not an American so my opinion isn&amp;rsquo;t worth much, but US politics disproportionately affects the rest of the world, so I think we get to comment too. Besides, a vast majority of the Americans I follow on Twitter are either liberal or quiet on politics, so I&amp;rsquo;m kind of accidentally exposed to the Democrats&amp;rsquo; POV a lot of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the Democratic Primaries: More or less down to Biden or Sanders. I think Biden is the favorite at the moment; my opinion on him is largely summarized by a meme I say (but can no longer find again) where his image was given the treatment similar to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barack_Obama_%22Hope%22_poster&#34;&gt;Obama hope poster&lt;/a&gt;, except with the caption &amp;ldquo;MEDIOCRE FOR ALL&amp;rdquo;. He seems like the type of candidate you get when the base is largely divided and people have to settle on a &amp;ldquo;least common denominator&amp;rdquo; kind of candidate. I like Sanders, but his electability is a real issue (because Americans are so indoctrinated against anything that could remotely be-called &amp;ldquo;socialism&amp;rdquo;) and so are his &amp;ldquo;Bernie bros&amp;rdquo;. If he&amp;rsquo;s able to move the needle towards the left even a little for the Democrat base/establishment, that would be great. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad the race is down to two old white guys. I liked Warren as a candidate more than Sanders, but her being a woman was also a downside in misogynist America. None of Sanders&amp;rsquo; or Warren&amp;rsquo;s progressive programs are going to mean anything if they can&amp;rsquo;t retake the Senate though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, the outcome of the US political process may very well affect the future of liberal democracy worldwide, as they have been slipping further and further away from that ideal during the past couple of decades, emboldening populists and strongmen in other countries, including my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a personal level, my week was exhausting. Mostly due to social events necessitating travel to far-flung parts of the Metro and also filial duties requiring me to spend inordinate amounts of time in hospital waiting rooms. Nothing serious, just accompanying some loved ones for regular tests and checkups, but am severely annoyed by the obvious lack of doctors causing severe waiting times for patients. One of the arguments against universal health care is that it would increase waiting times and such, I wonder if that&amp;rsquo;s something that&amp;rsquo;s happening here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming: I got &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humblebundle.com/subscription/february-2020&#34;&gt;last month&amp;rsquo;s Humble Choice&lt;/a&gt;, mostly by default. The main draw for me was &lt;strong&gt;Frostpunk&lt;/strong&gt; which some friends had been recommending. And I also promised someone that I would stream a survival game blind, so I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1235920529233776640/&#34;&gt;did that for Frostpunk last week&lt;/a&gt;. Otherwise, we&amp;rsquo;re kind of in a holding pattern until the FF7R release next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal projects: Not much progress the past week. I need to plan out some new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paid work: Billed a small amount of time, mostly for consulting meetings. Same old, same old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did two quizzes last week. The first was for fun, and I missed probably my only chance to win first place by enumerating Street Fighter II characters; the game mechanic was such that we needed to bid on how many we could enumerate (max 15 out of 20), and I initially wanted to bid 15 but I was talked down and made to doubt myself and we instead bid 10. I actually got 16 (forgot about the extra evil fighters in succeeding remakes), but since we only bid 10, that&amp;rsquo;s what we got and we ended up losing by 1 point. This decision may haunt me forever lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second quiz was for the Geekfight League we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this year. We only finished second place, but that was enough to give us the solo lead in the league rankings, so that was a better outcome than the previous quiz. (And this loss was more &amp;ldquo;we really didn&amp;rsquo;t know the answers&amp;rdquo; vs &amp;ldquo;we did know the answers but we screwed up&amp;rdquo; so it was less feels-bad)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site changes this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minor theme updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some older posts have been receiving a lot of spam via the comment form. I thought about disabling it completely, but instead for now I&amp;rsquo;ve disabled comments on posts older than 1 year, let&amp;rsquo;s see how that shakes out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to minimize JS on this site for a while. Changing my spoiler tags to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/pure-css-spoilers/&#34;&gt;pure css&lt;/a&gt; was a step in this direction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/blogroll&#34;&gt;Blogroll&lt;/a&gt; updated! Just a few new additions. I should figure out a way to do this automatically from my RSS reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This coming week I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more filial errands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more thinking about things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;moving stuff around&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more consulting meetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-03-01
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-01/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-01/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s March!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These weeknotes are coming in late in the day, for various reasons. The world news recently has mostly revolved around the COVID19 pandemic. Even the Americans are starting to get worried now. The PH still has surprisingly few cases, and we&amp;rsquo;ve even been commended by WHO for our containment efforts! Those of us who are used to our government&amp;rsquo;s usual level of competence are a bit wary - for all we know we might already have a hidden epidemic going undetected. Or maybe we managed to get lucky this time? Let&amp;rsquo;s hope this pandemic dies down soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming: &lt;strong&gt;Tales of Berseria&lt;/strong&gt; platinum run is almost complete, probably less than an hour of grinding to go. So maybe a blog post sometime this week. I&amp;rsquo;ll be glad to finally move on. I enjoyed the game, but that platinum grind, ugh. (Though still better than some of the other Tales&amp;hellip;). I also didn&amp;rsquo;t do any streaming this week (short break), will try to stream a new game this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal projects: Proceeding apace. Got a bunch of work done on one of them last week, adding reporting features and such. Gonna need to queue up some additional features. I think this was most of my busy time this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paid work: Billed a small amount of time, mostly for consulting meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday was a Holiday (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/different-revolution/&#34;&gt;EDSA&lt;/a&gt;), but that didn&amp;rsquo;t affect me much. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/1232493019292557313/&#34;&gt;Ash Wednesday&lt;/a&gt; was last Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site changes this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/redesign/&#34;&gt;Redesign&lt;/a&gt; finally pushed out!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some other behind-the-scenes stuff fixed to make things easier for me when I import content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This coming week I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;two quiz nights this week, apparently. Was only planning on one, but a second one popped up with a gaming theme, and that&amp;rsquo;s hard to turn down for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;family event on Saturday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planning out the coming months&amp;rsquo; worth of projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying out a new thing, hopefully I can talk about it soonish maybe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-02-23
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/weeknotes-2020-02-23/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/weeknotes-2020-02-23/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The week went by quickly for me for some reason. I suppose it was mainly because I actually did some paid work this week (just some planning and technical review for a future project) and that I had multiple events to attend (two quiz nights and there two birthdays in the family).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That and maybe doing the &lt;strong&gt;Tales of Berseria&lt;/strong&gt; platinum stuff might be taking up a lot of my time. One would think the plat grinding would be tedious, but I kinda enjoy ToB&amp;rsquo;s battle system, so it&amp;rsquo;s not so bad. I was even inspired to check out my old Tales of Hearts R save and see if I could plat that too. Then also checked Xillia and Graces. Lol, if I went back and platinumed all the Tales games I might never have time for any other games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both quiz nights were a wash however. I was pretty confident in our team for the Geekfight league game, but the competition was fierce and we didn&amp;rsquo;t end up placing, though we retained the tie for league first place. The other one was a love-song themed quiz in Quezon City. I suspected I would be next to useless for this one, but attended anyway to support and encourage more North-side quizzes. We ended losing a tiebreak question that would have gotten us third place, and had to settle for a mediocre fourth. Which was actually pretty amazing considering we had one round with only a single point!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat related: I spent some nontrivial amount of time over the past two weeks rewatching all of Rick and Morty, since that was one of the topics for the Geekfight league game. I also write like 8 pages of a Google doc worth of notes on trivia for each episode. The review was pretty useful, since I ended up answering 9 out of 10 questions correctly (the only miss being a non-episode related question), but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m doing that again. I was reminded however of how useful actual note-taking is for study, since the physical act of note taking reinforces the memory muscles somehow. I&amp;rsquo;m sure the retention would have been much stronger if I had done it by hand instead of digital (though my wrists might kill me). TLDR: Note-taking super useful, but probably not worth it just for a quiz. On the upside, I did enjoy the R&amp;amp;M rewatch. I might post my notes sometime this week as a blog post too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still doing some minor coding work on my personal projects throughout the week. Mostly QoL stuff, no big fixes/changes/features yet. I should block out some time to work on those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site changes this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;super minor QoL fixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;redesign still pending&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;site: continue the redesign things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;side project: work on some QoL improvements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;still haven&amp;rsquo;t watched Birds of Prey, might be running out of time. Also thinking about watching Sonic maybe?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There might also be some unscheduled work coming in, but for the most part it&amp;rsquo;s looking to be light (uncommitted) week, so I can probably work on stuff!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>