<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>comics on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/comics/</link>
      <description>Recent content in comics on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 02:06:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/comics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/1364758520885772288/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 02:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/1364758520885772288/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Action Comics #1 (1938) / Superman and Lois S01E01 (2021) #comicbooks #comics&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/1364758520885772288/1_1364758520885772288_EvCYd_6UUAM3FGy_hu93fe506786c472cd5beb4ed0853ace6b_408627_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/1364758520885772288/2_1364758520885772288_EvCYd_8U4AMw2n__hu67dc8d7085fe07cd986176b5dc387d19_93516_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1349377300593197057/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 15:26:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1349377300593197057/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Web of Spider-man (1985) no 1, Spectacular Spider-man S01E12, Spider-man 3 (2017) #comicbooks&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1349377300593197057/1_1349377300593197057_Ernzf2YUUAAShGw_hu1a63cec331888d14b5807477d5c30464_252702_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1349377300593197057/2_1349377300593197057_Ernzf2YVQAEPeAm_hu44cd7fa0cd6f1f60dd9caae4abe52369_61301_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1349377300593197057/3_1349377300593197057_Ernzf2aVcAAu9tP_hu30a76a241523b3a0e9db8f1222010dbb_70549_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Quiz Night Sketches
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/quiz-night-sketches/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 15:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/quiz-night-sketches/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I had nothing to contribute to tonight&amp;rsquo;s quiz night, so this is what I did instead.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/quiz-night-sketches/20200821_222447_hu585c19f5523eec847de2f02022a89b35_1785326_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/quiz-night-sketches/20200821_231948_hua6f51f1ab9c247d5ab00aa8ccafeecc8_1522439_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/1269209724555165696/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 10:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/1269209724555165696/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Far Sector #5 #BlackLivesMattters #comics&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/1269209724555165696/1_EZ0jgX2VcAUwZPY_hu497baa64753401e9e07a8e6a7f088d48_264096_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/1269209724555165696/2_EZ0jgX2UYAYN2b3_hu6be3f8bd8863588cc1ce883ee6b26ca3_288022_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by cabridges on &#39;From Batman&#39;s dinosaur to the desk of Supes, nothing is getting by our boy Bendis [from Superman 18]&#39; on /r/comicbooks at https://reddit.com/r/comicbooks/comments/ea44ji/from_batmans_dinosaur_to_the_desk_of_supes/fansdfe/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/fanwy2e/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 15:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/fanwy2e/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by cabridges on &amp;#39;From Batman&amp;#39;s dinosaur to the desk of Supes, nothing is getting by our boy Bendis [from Superman 18]&amp;#39; on /r/comicbooks at https://reddit.com/r/comicbooks/comments/ea44ji/from_batmans_dinosaur_to_the_desk_of_supes/fansdfe/:

            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the eventual storyline where he makes a deal with the devil for everyone to forget this reveal in exchange for ending his marriage.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Comics Review: House of X/Powers of X
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/hox-pox/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/hox-pox/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;While you slept, the world changed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t reviewed any comics on this blog for a while, so today we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about Jonathan Hickman&amp;rsquo;s triumphant (so far) return to Marvel: House of X/Powers of X and the upcoming Dawn of X wave of books. Spoilers abound so be aware. Also while writing this I realized how absurd comic books must seem to nonreaders, but really that&amp;rsquo;s what makes it all fun! (I mean, the Justice League is also crazy right now too!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the unaware, House of X and Powers are X are two 6-issue miniseries to chart a new direction for the X-Men books moving forward. The architect of this new direction is writer Jonathan Hickman, known for his big status quo-changing ideas. His previous run on Avengers culminated in the multiverse-changing events Infinity and Secret Wars 2, so expectations were high for his X-Men run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HoX/PoX is really two miniseries that are closely intertwined, enough to be considered a single 12-issue maxiseries. And Hickman is certainly presenting some big ideas, some of it retconning a lot of what was previously known in the X-Men&amp;rsquo;s history. The main conceit is that Moira MacTaggert is revealed to be (and always has been) a mutant - with the power to reset the timeline back to her birth if she dies after her mutant powers have manifested. Prior to the current storyline in HoX/PoX, Moira has lived through nine of her own timelines, and she has used each successive timeline to figure out how to get mutantkind to &amp;ldquo;winning&amp;rdquo; in the inevitable conflicts against humanity and technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 12 issues of HoX/Pox are told in a nonlinear fashion, with the opening issue of House of X showing Xavier&amp;rsquo;s new plan for mutantkind to become an independent nation on the living island of Krakoa - a far cry from Xavier&amp;rsquo;s dream of &amp;ldquo;coexistence&amp;rdquo; that has defined the X-Men since the very beginning. House of X tells the story of the establishment of this mutant nation, and the incredible resurrection workflow developed using a combination of mutant powers that means that the trope that X-Men don&amp;rsquo;t stay dead is now canon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powers of X covers the Moira affair, what happens in her different timelines and what she discovers. In this week&amp;rsquo;s final issue of Powers of X, we get the final revelation that she discovered in her sixth life: there is no victory. Mutantkind loses, and they always lose, inspite of the belief that mutants were the inevitable successor to humanity. This leads to her decision in her tenth life to try a completely new approach: to get all the mutants (heroes and villains) working together for a common cause. And to do this, she has to break Charles Xavier, whose optimistic dreams never work out and inevitably lead to conflict with others like Magneto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 12 issue maxiseries has concluded, but we are still left with a lot of burning questions. For me, foremost in my mind is: is this really the main 616 Marvel universe? All signs point to yes, but the main issue is that this is a massive upheaval of the X-Men status quo. Typically a writer during his run will introduce some fresh ideas but somewhere down the line some other writer will roll back some of those changes and we revert to some version of the status quo. This feels different, like there&amp;rsquo;s no coming back from it, because the fundamental nature of the mutants and their conflicts has forever been changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also unclear at this point what the endgame is for Moira and Charles this time around. How does the Krakoa plan change the inevitable loss to an artificially-evolved post-humanity? There are still redacted portions of Moira&amp;rsquo;s notes in the last PoX, and she refuses to let any precogs live on Krakoa, implying she (or they) still have something to hide about the future. It would have been naive to assume all our questions would be answered before the end of Hickman&amp;rsquo;s run (which may end up being 2-3 years long, comparable to his Avengers run.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a previous issue, precog Destiny also implied that Moira may live up to 10 or 11 lives, and Moira is only on her 10th. It is still possible that this current timeline gets &amp;ldquo;reset&amp;rdquo; at some point and Moira gets to live an 11th life, albeit she may have to do so without her mutant powers. That 11th life could still possibly be the 616 as we know it, although that would mean the rest of Hickman&amp;rsquo;s run would be reset later on, so that seems even more unlikely. In order for this current timeline (Moira X) to stick, she would have to be depowered, so that when she eventually dies the timeline doesn&amp;rsquo;t reset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying to imagine what the X-Men are going to look like post-Hickman. If it&amp;rsquo;s true that mutantkind &amp;ldquo;always loses&amp;rdquo;, then his run has one of two outcomes: (a) whatever Moira is planning succeeds and mutantkind wins, establishing itself as the successor to humanity, and in which case I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what future X-Men stories look like after that; or (b) Moira&amp;rsquo;s plans fall apart, and mutantkind loses yet again. (b) seems far more likely, with Destiny pretty much introduced as Chekov&amp;rsquo;s gun that Mystique is going to demand be used later on. Of course, knowing Hickman, all of this may very well culminate in some sort of status quo-shattering climax a few years down the line that nobody would have expected. (I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t predict a multiversal collapse at the start of his Avengers run!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other minor notes and questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I kind of still question the inevitability of mutants losing since there it at least one known timeline where mutants &amp;ldquo;won&amp;rdquo; and humanity was reduced to almost nothing, and that was Age of Apocalypse (though, the mutants kind of ruined that timeline for themselves).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the mutant resurrection engine seems quite fragile, since it&amp;rsquo;s reliant on five different mutants (six counting Xavier), so any one of them dying could disable the resurrections permanently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;while we understand why Charles behaves so radically different from previous incarnations (because Moira had succeeded in breaking him), a lot of the other X-Men still feel very out of character, especially the cultish behavior in House of X #5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the introduction of Dominions, godlike entities existing outside of space and time, is a completely new addition to Marvel cosmology AFAIK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why is all of this happening now? After all these years, why have Moira, Charles and Erik decided to start their Krakoa nation at this point in time? What was the triggering event?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t said much about the art in these two series, because the implications of the story are already a lot, but the art is great, although by the end  a lot of the faces seemed a bit samey to me. But I especially like a lot of the coloring work, especially in the X2 timeline and during the assault on the Mothermold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, there are a lot of other details and questions arising out of the maxiseries, which we assume Hickman will resolve during the next few years of X-books. Regardless of where his run ends, just the beginning of it is already a huge success in that it has sparked a lot of discussion about the X-Men and their future in the online communities, not to mention being the best-selling comic book titles for the past 12 weeks. The hype is real, and is a fresh shot in the arm to a franchise that was a bit weakening after years of the &amp;ldquo;mutant extinction&amp;rdquo; following House of M back in 2005. I have no idea where Hickman is taking us during this run, but I dig it, and I&amp;rsquo;m down for the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS I&amp;rsquo;m still angry about this (from House of X #1):&lt;/p&gt;








    
    
        
    
    
    
        
            
            
            
            
              
            
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#274311800566ef3afc3555fe9169ef39-lightbox&#34;&gt;
                &lt;figure&gt;
                  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/1159134490913988608/EBYSqotU4AEXMCK_hua7b7d377ee7f1ae65756de1ae4f7c242_140650_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Well, that’s annoying&#34; title=&#34;Well, that’s annoying&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
                  &lt;figcaption&gt;Well, that’s annoying (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
                &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;274311800566ef3afc3555fe9169ef39-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/1159134490913988608/EBYSqotU4AEXMCK.jpg&#34; /&gt;
              &lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Well, that’s annoying&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;10 Oct 2019 12:00am&#34;&gt;10 Oct 2019 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/1159134490913988608/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;            
        
    




            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by AporiaParadox on &#39;WPL: New Comics Discussion for 10/2/2019 - Pull of the Week: HOUSE OF X #6 [Discussion]&#39; on /r/comicbooks at https://reddit.com/r/comicbooks/comments/dc53up/wpl_new_comics_discussion_for_1022019_pull_of_the/f26flw9/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/f26xd39/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 14:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/f26xd39/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by AporiaParadox on &amp;#39;WPL: New Comics Discussion for 10/2/2019 - Pull of the Week: HOUSE OF X #6 [Discussion]&amp;#39; on /r/comicbooks at https://reddit.com/r/comicbooks/comments/dc53up/wpl_new_comics_discussion_for_1022019_pull_of_the/f26flw9/:

            &lt;p&gt;isnt gorgon one of the inhumans&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;Lemire&#39;s run is not as popular as others but it has one my favorite Hawkeye moments [All-New Hawkeye Vol.2 #6]&#39; on /r/comicbooks at https://reddit.com/r/comicbooks/comments/d3dxs5/lemires_run_is_not_as_popular_as_others_but_it/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/f02243j/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 21:02:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/f02243j/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;Lemire&amp;#39;s run is not as popular as others but it has one my favorite Hawkeye moments [All-New Hawkeye Vol.2 #6]&amp;#39; on /r/comicbooks at https://reddit.com/r/comicbooks/comments/d3dxs5/lemires_run_is_not_as_popular_as_others_but_it/:

            &lt;p&gt;i hope we get somehing like this in the upcoming disney+ show. Like maybe Clint saved Kate during the battle of new york&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/b2guhd1hyp6/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 09:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/b2guhd1hyp6/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Quick doodle. Sam and Bucky. #sketch #comics #marvel&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/b2guhd1hyp6/ED2jKMQWwAIAjgF_hu3efa448028557c361bd555c7ae9f450f_79550_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by krumble on &#39;Pure Hickman fashion. [House of X #1]&#39; on /r/comicbooks at https://reddit.com/r/comicbooks/comments/ch6bt3/pure_hickman_fashion_house_of_x_1/euq44zq/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/euq5nv8/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 12:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/euq5nv8/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by krumble on &amp;#39;Pure Hickman fashion. [House of X #1]&amp;#39; on /r/comicbooks at https://reddit.com/r/comicbooks/comments/ch6bt3/pure_hickman_fashion_house_of_x_1/euq44zq/:

            &lt;p&gt;It is not a continuity reset. But if you know who xavier and magneto are and know that mutants exist, tha should be the extent of background you need going into the book,&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/186514742325/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 12:08:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/186514742325/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;House of X (2019) #1&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/186514742325/186514742325_0_huc73c94d56c02aacc7ef9f7c20373deb1_580650_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>A Look Back at the Marvel Cinematic Universe
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/a-look-back-at-the-marvel-cinematic-universe/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/a-look-back-at-the-marvel-cinematic-universe/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I know I already made a &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/04/more-thoughts-on-avengers-endgame-and-the-mcu/&#34;&gt;whole post about the MCU after Endgame came out&lt;/a&gt;, but after the MCU Phase 4 announcements this past weekend at SDCC I was a bit hyped. I thought it would be fun to look back at the past 10 years of MCU Phase 1-3 and see what I wrote about the movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iron Man (2008)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, I had written nothing about watching this film at all, and I don&amp;rsquo;t remember going to the cinema to watch it. The movie came out between Batman Begins and The Dark Knight, so my hype was undeniably towards the Batman movies back then. Before the MCU, Iron Man was a B-list hero at best, and back then no one could ever have imagined how far the MCU would go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Incredible Hulk (2008)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/06/movies-june-2008/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Movies &amp;ndash; June 2008&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edward Norton is cast brilliantly here, a choice on the same level as Robert Downey Jr as Iron Man. And they addressed the issue of Hulk’s stretchy pants!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iron Man 2 (2010)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took them 2 years to get to a 2nd movie. They probably weren&amp;rsquo;t prepared for how well received Iron Man was!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I have for this movie is &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/13253318934&#34;&gt;from a tweet&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iron Man 2 was okay, but it was pretty much more of the same. Therefore it does not wow as much as the first movie did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thor (2011)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any notes about this movie either. Well, except that I thought it &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/82967835080527872&#34;&gt;was better than Green Lantern&lt;/a&gt; (an understatement). I do remember being impressed visually by the Asgard set-pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain America the First Avenger (2011)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/96637161473966080&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain America was fine. Definitely better than Thor/Green Lantern&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I started ranking them around this time, although maintaing an overall ranking was pretty much impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers (2012)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/195064455208501248&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avengers was very enjoyable, funny and action-packed. Re-reading Ultimates v1 now lol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I had more to say, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in the habit yet of more detailed reviews back then. On to phase two!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iron Man 3 (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/328877325867446273&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#IronMan3 It was ok. Not as great as some people have said, but probably better than 2. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/alvinjtang&#34;&gt;@alvinjtang&lt;/a&gt; says it&amp;rsquo;ll look worse in a few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thor The Dark World (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/396176381819621376&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thor2 was okay, I like it more than Iron Man 3, mostly because I like the Star Wars x High Fantasy style&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thor2 is generally considered one of the lowest-ranked movies of the MCU, but as a comic book fan I&amp;rsquo;m very forgiving and I guess this means I generally liked all of them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain America Winter Solider (2014)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/449064262581768192&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cap America 2 snap judgment: fun movie, better than Iron Man 3/Thor 2. Great for comic fans!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, an understatement, as I would later go on to consider Winter Soldier possibly my favorite MCU movie of all time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also said in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10152883332768912&#34;&gt;a Facebook post&lt;/a&gt; that the movie would have been perfect if he had only done Final Justice lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy (2014)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10153122948543912&#34;&gt;Facebook post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guardians was a very funny and fun movie, but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to say best Marvel movie so far, since I really liked Winter Soldier. And as a comic fan, I&amp;rsquo;m not that fond of how the Nova Corps was portrayed; I guess it&amp;rsquo;s understandable since they&amp;rsquo;re not the heroes here. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of stuff for comic fans to enjoy though&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2014 was a great year for the MCU, as both of these movies are among my MCU favorites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Age of Ultron (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10153724990238912&#34;&gt;Facebook post&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoiler-free Age of Ultron review: It&amp;rsquo;s great, go watch it. I loved it. I wish there had been less content made available ahead of time through trailers and casting announcements, but such are the times we live in. It is a good time to be a comic book fan. There is a short mid-credits scene. There is no post-credits scene&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was around this time that I started doing &amp;ldquo;spoiler-free reviews&amp;rdquo;. I also posted &lt;a href=&#34;http://nedstarkdies.com/avengers-age-of-ultron-by-hunter/&#34;&gt;a more detailed AoU review over on Nedstarkdies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ant Man (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10153946370273912&#34;&gt;Facebook post&lt;/a&gt; again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ant Man spoiler-free review: The first half felt a bit off, with some exposition coming off as forced and the pacing a bit awkward. Things picked up later on and while the plot was not entirely unpredictable there were a number of fun and surprising tangents. Overall a fun and entertaining movie with enough stuff for comic book Marvel fans to enjoy, probably close in quality to the first Iron Man movie, if not better&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized just now that both Ant Man movies have been used as a palate cleanser after an Avengers film. This first one also marked the end of phase two. On to phase three!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain America Civil War (2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10154562419893912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain America Civil War spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;great fight sequences, start to finish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the newcomers were great, airport big fight sequence had a great surprise (and not the one you already saw in the trailer - although you might have already been spoiled if you pay attention to certain toy lines), although I feel like a couple of the characters were pulled in to the conflict in a way that was a bit weak, but it&amp;rsquo;s still pretty good overall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the plot was ok. Justification for the civil war was ok. Some surprises. The villain motivation was slightly mediocre, but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t really the focus of the movie anyway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Martin Freeman&amp;rsquo;s role felt totally superfluous - it did not seem necessary to cast Martin Freeman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie kind of ends with the MCU and the Avengers in a weird place, some people might not like it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better than: Winter Soldier. The plot kind of develops in the same way but everything is on a much bigger scale now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are two post-credit scenes, one in the middle and one at the very end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imax worth it? Probably. Not very ostentatious use of 3d, but most of the fight sequences have it. You might get dizzy if you&amp;rsquo;re not used to it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama? Maybe, but I&amp;rsquo;d have to keep explaining who these characters are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started doing this format of &amp;ldquo;Spoiler-free reviews&amp;rdquo; around this time, with what would turn out to be the well-loved &amp;ldquo;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama?&amp;rdquo; (Translation: Will Mama like it?) section. When I tried removing this section at some point, people complained lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doctor Strange (2016)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10155041890913912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wow. Great visuals and fight-scenes, very trippy. Possibly the best fight scenes in all the MCU movies so far. You might get dizzy with all the things spinning around though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plot is typical of a MCU origin story. Hero&amp;rsquo;s journey, some light comedy bits, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was expecting them to go a different way with Mordo (if you&amp;rsquo;ve read the comics you know what I mean), but I&amp;rsquo;m happy with how things went down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stakes are high, but failure is not final&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The actors were great; I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen a lead this good for a role since RDJ&amp;rsquo;s Tony Stark. Swinton&amp;rsquo;s Ancient One, Eijofor&amp;rsquo;s Mordo, and even Wong&amp;rsquo;s Wong were great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doctor friends: Tell me if the medical parts were BS hohoho&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Probably not. She doesn&amp;rsquo;t like this kind of thing, and the dizziness thing is bad too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMAX or not? I think the 3d parts weren&amp;rsquo;t too exaggerated or critical, but the visuals might feel a bit flat and not as impressive if you don&amp;rsquo;t go IMAX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Midcredits scene? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postcredits scene? Yes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guardians of the Galaxy vol 2 (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10155588909688912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;overall a very entertaining movie to sit down and watch popcorn and to enjoy the jokes and the space battles and the different colored lights and the tiny adorable tree creature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GOTG&amp;rsquo;s humor was one of its strong points and for the 2nd movie, they push the comedy up a notch, perhaps a little too much in some places. Lots of funny gags and one-liners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt like some of the character/background development stuff was pushed a bit too hard as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the movie&amp;rsquo;s plot also felt a bit thin and straightforward. I mean, you could see some of the major plot points coming a mile away. Maybe from the trailers even&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Lord was ok. Gamora/Nebula felt poorly written. Rocket was a bit annoying. Drax and Mantis were ok, although the space they have for Mantis&amp;rsquo; character overlaps with Drax a bit.. I&amp;rsquo;m still not super happy with how Drax and Gamora are characterized in the MCU.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m less happy with this movie&amp;rsquo;s soundtrack compared to the first one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Certainly not. In fact, she chose to derp around the mall instead of coming with me and my cousin to watch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMAX or not: Some visuals used the 3d effect, but nothing too exaggerated or critical. I&amp;rsquo;d say IMAX optional, but it definitely adds something to some scenes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are five extra scenes near the credits (one of them is right before the credits roll, so I can&amp;rsquo;t really say &amp;ldquo;post-credit&amp;rdquo; screens). Most of them are just setting the tone for the inevitable GOTG3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additionally, just pay attention to the background of the credits roll as well, it&amp;rsquo;s great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I felt the movie was ok, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of just more of the same of what we got with the first movie, which felt a lot stronger overall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spider-man Homecoming (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10155834066513912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This movie is amazing. Possibly best in all MCU so far. It&amp;rsquo;s fun, it&amp;rsquo;s exciting, unexpected things happened. Maybe not watching the trailers helped lol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Covers a lot of ground the previous Spider-man movies didn&amp;rsquo;t. Helped along by not needing to rehash the origin story for the Nth time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots of great call outs for the comic book fans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was worried about the Vulture, but it was handled very well. Keaton is great here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This movie is tightly coupled to the MCU yo. IDK how they&amp;rsquo;re going to handle it if Sony breaks it off after the two-movie deal. By they I mean Sony. Obviously MCU can just ignore him forever afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TBH I was also really worried about the MCU coupling and having too much Iron Man in the movie, but it turned out okay. Maybe could have had a little bit less Tony Stark.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IMAX? Probably not worth it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s a mid-credits scene and a post-credits scene.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama? Possibly! There&amp;rsquo;s some shaky cam footage near the start that can be a bit nauseating though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That first line is high praise lol. Around this time I started avoiding watching more than the first trailer for the MCU movies, as I always felt like they gave too many jokes and plot points away. I will certainly watch them anyway, so there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much point building up more hype than I needed to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thor Ragnarok (2017)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10156133009878912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a fun, action-packed romp that shakes up the Thor status quo significantly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easily the best of the three Thor movies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a number plot points are fairly predictable, yet still fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the Marvel formula is generally action mixed with witty banter here and there, and it&amp;rsquo;s what we get here, although some of the jokes feel like they&amp;rsquo;re stretched a bit too much&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some great-looking cinematic scenes here and there. One particular flashback scene looked really great&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I kind of like how the older franchises need to be some sort of team effort nowadays. Like Civil War, this felt a bit like some kind of mini-Avengers crossover &amp;ndash; in space!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;speaking of space, one of the positive things about this installment is that they didn&amp;rsquo;t feel the need to tie Thor&amp;rsquo;s adventures to Earth anymore (not that the movie is 100% Earth-free), and they get to go a bit wild with space and aliens and all that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand the need to highlight Hulk&amp;rsquo;s involvement as part of the film&amp;rsquo;s marketing, but man, it would have been so awesome to just find out right then and there&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This movie had that Star Wars: Last Jedi trailer I was trying to avoid D:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 mid-credits scene and 1 post-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I think Imax was good for this movie. The 3d wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much and it definitely made some scenes pop. The film is a visual delight so I think the larger screen is important too&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Probably not. Maybe I should stop including this section kasi parang same na parati ang answer. Unless for some reason I decide to watch some Tagalog romcom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Damn Thor 3 was great. Looking forward to Love and Thunder!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black Panther (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10156423012653912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s a fun, action-filled romp and Wakanda is amazing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tchalla was ok, killmonger and nakia were great, shuri was badass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some of the actions scenes didnt seem too well-shot/edited, making them hard to follow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I realize I&amp;rsquo;m saying this about a universe where there are talking raccoons and magic hammers, but some of the Wakandan tech push the boundaries of my suspension of disbelief&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my expectations were probably set a bit too high what with some people saying it&amp;rsquo;s the best MCU movie since Iron Man or calling it revolutionary or eye-opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;off the top of my head I&amp;rsquo;d say I consider Civil War, Spider-Man Homecoming and Thor Ragnarok better than this one&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I understand that it&amp;rsquo;s revolutionary in the sense that it&amp;rsquo;s a major hollowood motion picture filled with a cast of mostly african descent and that some of the characters are motivated by real world racial issues. But the plot itself was typical for an MCU first movie (maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve seen too many MCU movies? lol). I dont think it presents the issues it covers under any new or revolutionary context. I guess I kind of went in hoping to be impressed on the level of The Dark Knight or such, but I was disappointed in that regard. It&amp;rsquo;s a very straightforward movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t watch in Imax, which I kind of regret, as I can imagine some of the scenes being pretty good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Possibly, pero baka mahirapan sya intindihin accent ni Chadwick Boseman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a mid-credits scene and a post-credits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers Infinity War (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10156599221698912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m amazed that so little of this movie has been widely spoiled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movie was fantastic. the movie somehow managed to do everything it needed to do while not doing disservice to any of the bazillion characters involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the plot moves quickly. there is no good time to pee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is one post-credits scene.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;very happy to have watched in imax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ant Man and the Wasp (2018)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/10155666240078912/posts/10156749941023912&#34;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this movie is great; it&amp;rsquo;s fun and and action-packed and there&amp;rsquo;s even more Luis than you thought you wanted; go watch it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s like the first movie, except better and more fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;best new character: FBI Agent Jimmy Woo played by Randall Park (sorry Michelle Pfeifer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are two mid/post-credit scenes. One of them is better than the other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watched in Imax. Some scenes were nice, but it&amp;rsquo;s probably more of a nice-to-have&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni Mama: Pwede, but kelangan ng kasama to explain things. Baka ok lang pag tagalized na sa tv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Captain Marvel (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around this time, I started &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/183266384975/captain-marvel-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;posting the reviews to Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; as well:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movie was pretty good, no major issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doesnt follow the typical MCU origin story ‘formula’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some weird pacing issues in a few places, but that just might be because of the chosen story direction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lots of little call-outs and tie-ins to the other MCU movies (although I feel like they could have done a bit more in some spots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am not a cat person. But if you are a cat person, you might like this: there is a cat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s some parts that made it obvious they were aiming for that Wonder Woman audience, so the movie may be better for you if you’re in that demo (but I think WW was a better movie overall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imax was pretty good, nothing too excessive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Midcredits scene, and postcredits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni mama? Possibly! Also, its a good idea to bring little girls to watch this movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avengers Endgame (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read my review &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/more-thoughts-on-avengers-endgame-and-the-mcu/&#34;&gt;right here on this blog&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spider-man Far From Home (2019)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read my review &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/&#34;&gt;right here on this blog&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was a fun walk through a decade of films, and it gave me an opportunity to fold some of my off-blog content back into this blog. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to be doing more movie reviews directly here on this blog instead of just on Facebook or Tumblr. Looking forward to more MCU in the years (decades?) to come!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Promised Neverland and Dr. Stone
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/promised-neverland-and-dr.-stone/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/promised-neverland-and-dr.-stone/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Many of the manga series I used to follow from long ago have since ended, the only ones still running now are One Piece and Hajime no Ippo. So I thought I&amp;rsquo;d follow some newer ones. Here are some short reviews:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Promised Neverland&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up this one due to a strong recommendation from someone I follow on social media. The premise starts out with some super smart kids who grew up in an orphanage without any knowledge of an outside world. Suddenly they find out that not all is as it seems and that they are actually captives in some kind of human farm for strange &amp;ldquo;demons&amp;rdquo; to consume. The first arc consists of the oldest kids trying to figure out a way to outsmart their captors and escape and find out the truth of what is happening in the outside world. (The previous two sentences aren&amp;rsquo;t too spoiler-y, this setup is pretty much established in the first issue.) The 3 oldest kids are supersmart, so much of the tension lies in them trying to stay two steps ahead of their captors who suspect they know the secret, and at the same time trying to figure out a way to escape with more than 30 kids, some of them toddlers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some spoilers for the second arc follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    The second arc after they manage to escape involves them trying to survive in a world that they find to be mostly populated by demons, some of them cunning like humans, and some wild and savage, all of them much stronger than humans. Sometimes writers won&amp;rsquo;t know what to do after their initial premise, but &lt;em&gt;The Promised Neverland&lt;/em&gt; handles it well; after the initial &amp;ldquo;Prison Break&amp;rdquo; story arc they successfully transitioned into a &amp;ldquo;Wilderness Survival&amp;rdquo; arc that reminds me a lot of Claymore. During the course of their journey to find a safe haven they learn the truth of why the world is like it is which eventually leads to a &amp;ldquo;Revolution&amp;rdquo; arc (currently ongoing) where the protagonists are trying to change the nature of this world. There were some fantastic battle scenes against overwhelming odds in the second arc as well, especially against Lewis and the other demons at Goldy Pond.
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Promised Neverland&lt;/em&gt; is currently at 130 issues and I enjoyed it a lot. The writing is good, the artwork is not too complicated yet dynamic and flowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Stone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember reading about this one a couple of years ago about promising new series in &lt;em&gt;Shonen Jump&lt;/em&gt;, but at that time I chose to start &lt;em&gt;Robot x Laserbeam&lt;/em&gt; instead, which didn&amp;rsquo;t last too long. I didn&amp;rsquo;t start this one back then because I honestly wasn&amp;rsquo;t a fan of the art style, but I gave it another shot last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premise is that sometime in 2015 (?), a mysterious petrification beam turned every human being (and swallow) on earth into stone. The protagonist Senku is a genius-level science nerd who manages to keep his consciousness alive for the 3,700 years that it takes until he is freed from his petrification by a mysterious liquid. By this time, human civilization has collapsed, and all that remains is the preserved stone statues of the humans (and swallows). A firm believer in science, Senku resolves to use his analytical skills to restore human civilization, his first task being to study the mysterious liquid that freed him and use it to free some other nearby humans - the first one being his friend Taiju, who has unnaturally high endurance making him suitable for doing the hard labor neded to support Senku&amp;rsquo;s science. While they are in the process of attempting to free a third human, they are beset upon by wild animals and have to run. They have no choice but to use their depetrification formula to free a nearby human who turns out to be a super-strong and athletic fighter who can defeat wild animals with his bare hands, Tsukasa. (All of this happens in the first three issues.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After things settle down, Senku finds out that Tsukasa hates the modern world and does not want to bring everyone back, and he starts smashing statues of older people. Fundamentally disagreeing on the way forward, this sets up the first major arc for the series, with Tsukasa taking control of the depetrification formula to establish his own empire, and Senku vowing to start a Kingdom of Science to advance human civilization and overcome Tsukasa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing about this series is how focused it is on science, detailing the steps needed to do complicated things like formulating chemicals or building complicated devices like a crossbow or a battery. The series is only 100 issues long so far, but thanks to Senku being ridiculously knowledgable, science advances quickly even in this &amp;ldquo;Stone&amp;rdquo; age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    By the 100th issue, Senku has advanced the cause of science enough to be able to create (with the help of a whole village of people) such advanced devices as mobile communicators, a steam engine-powered boat, and even a carbon-fiber tank.
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must admit I can&amp;rsquo;t follow the science myself too closely (since I&amp;rsquo;m not that well-versed in chemistry), so I can&amp;rsquo;t vouch for its accuracy, but I enjoy how it is presented and how Senku explains things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these series feature superoptimistic protagonists who are hypercompetent and very resolved to save everyone (sometimes even their enemies), no matter the ridiculous odds. A bit trope-y, but I enjoyed both series nonetheless, and both are still ongoing, so I have new manga to look forward to every week!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by [deleted] on &#39;Marvel Comics Announces Historic X-Men Milestone with &#39;House of X&#39; and &#39;Powers of X&#39;&#39; on /r/comicbooks at https://reddit.com/r/comicbooks/comments/b4og0x/marvel_comics_announces_historic_xmen_milestone/ej8ka4p/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/ej8tj5e/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 03:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/ej8tj5e/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by [deleted] on &amp;#39;Marvel Comics Announces Historic X-Men Milestone with &amp;#39;House of X&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;Powers of X&amp;#39;&amp;#39; on /r/comicbooks at https://reddit.com/r/comicbooks/comments/b4og0x/marvel_comics_announces_historic_xmen_milestone/ej8ka4p/:

            &lt;p&gt;You are missing out. AOA is one of the best xmen alternate universe stories and it holds up pretty well&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183662443174/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 02:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183662443174/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Justice League (2019) #20 Batman has a new favorite Robin. art by Jorge Jimenez, words by Scott Snyder&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183662443174/183662443174_0_huc31777a442761396b9160e28ec009fe1_2185359_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183416051826/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 02:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183416051826/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Captain Marvel (1989) #1 featuring Monica Rambeau as Captain Marvel. Will we see her with powers in the second Captain Marvel movie?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183416051826/183416051826_0_hu841beb412ce717bcdb2f77072411ecd1_1623568_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183413854964/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183413854964/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Green Lantern - Green Arrow #85 DC tackles the drug problem&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183413854964/183413854964_hudd12f2352811943b67d6d42ef6240e45_1383131_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183370747739/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 02:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183370747739/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Captain Marvel (2016) #1 cover by Kris Anka&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183370747739/183370747739_0_hufa6f18c094d474adabc532e72a5868fb_1326036_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Captain Marvel spoiler-free review!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/captain-marvel-spoiler-free-review/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 15:11:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/captain-marvel-spoiler-free-review/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;movie was pretty good, no major issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;doesnt follow the typical MCU origin story ‘formula’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some weird pacing issues in a few places, but that just might be because of the chosen story direction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lots of little call-outs and tie-ins to the other MCU movies (although I feel like they could have done a bit more in some spots)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am not a cat person. But if you are a cat person, you might like this: there is a cat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s some parts that made it obvious they were aiming for that Wonder Woman audience, so the movie may be better for you if you’re in that demo (but I think WW was a better movie overall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Imax was pretty good, nothing too excessive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Midcredits scene, and postcredits scene&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magugustuhan ba ni mama? Possibly! Also, its a good idea to bring little girls to watch this movie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183152764070/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 02:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183152764070/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The Flash #62 variant cover by Jae Lee&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/183152764070/183152764070_0_hub64a6f2338a70827c25ed997b147d813_446735_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182695960342/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 02:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182695960342/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It’s Spider-Man week on ireadcomicbooks! To cap off the week, here’s Amazing Spider-Man #583 guest starring Barack Obama. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182695960342/182695960342_hu665e357fe0fad7dd9dc29629ccce7b20_441182_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182670555663/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 02:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182670555663/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It’s Spider-Man week on ireadcomicbooks! During the DC/Marvel Amalgam crossover, Spider-Man got crossed over with&amp;hellip; Superboy? I always felt like Spider-Man got a poor deal here given how popular he was, he should have at least gotten an adult to cross over with! At least he retained the hyphen! Cover by Mike Wieringo&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182670555663/182670555663_hu29604ea02cfef7a5c52da3e18f035847_58448_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182645806857/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 02:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182645806857/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It’s Spider-Man week on ireadcomicbooks! Spider-Man was the only Marvel superhero to guest star in the Transformers comic series by Marvel which ran from 1984-1981. Here he is duking it out with Megatron in the cover to Transformers #3 by Frank Springer&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182645806857/182645806857_hua4294e730aff921961c15b2327b1339b_694198_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182619902345/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 02:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182619902345/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It’s Spider-Man week on ireadcomicbooks! Here’s Marvel Zombies #1 Amazing Fantasy tribute cover by 
Arthur Suydam&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182619902345/182619902345_hu4d25688faa0c6904e95a211a604e7d70_89342_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182593782519/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 02:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182593782519/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It’s Spider-Man week on ireadcomicbooks! Here’s the famous Amazing Spider-Man #300 cover by the amazing Todd McFarlane!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182593782519/182593782519_hu7655c818774fb8b9db97767e4cfa18c5_306799_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182567652118/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 02:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182567652118/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It’s Spider-Man week on ireadcomicbooks! Here’s the cover for Secret Wars #8 by Mike Zeck, where Spider-Man first acquired the Symbiote costume. (The actual first published appearance of the costume was in Amazing Spider-Man #252)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182567652118/182567652118_hu3d0e3f2db8f71ff13a8f7519725f5cd5_206301_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182540413501/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 02:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182540413501/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It’s Spider-Man week on ireadcomicsbooks! Here’s the cover to Amazing Spider-Man #660 by Stefano Caselli and Lorenzo de Felici, featuring the Future Foundation costume!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182540413501/182540413501_hu624b4dd477e141c2d6bd8cdf455f1142_959466_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/amrdvj/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 01:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/amrdvj/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;h4 id=&#34;posted-on-rcomicbooks-reddit-what-is-your-all-time-favorite-comic-book-coverhttpsredditcomrcomicbookscommentsamrdvjreddit_what_is_your_alltime_favorite_comic_book&#34;&gt;Posted on r/comicbooks: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/comicbooks/comments/amrdvj/reddit_what_is_your_alltime_favorite_comic_book/&#34;&gt;Reddit, what is your all-time favorite comic book cover?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182513007484/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 02:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182513007484/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Flash (Rebirth) #34 Justice League movie variant cover by McKone and Fajardo&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182513007484/182513007484_0_hu4e559bf0be3c65f87602fc139b9e73d4_528848_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182487760887/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 02:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182487760887/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;New Superman #1 cover by Bogdanovic and Shannon&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182487760887/182487760887_0_hu74552418222fc0db26f4897b237d692f_1739170_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182463223840/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 02:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182463223840/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Uncanny X-Men #136 (1980) and Crisis on Infinite Earths #7 (1985). I only now realized how similar these covers were&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182463223840/182463223840_0_huc26cf067db7b428fef4b8284970d9544_597158_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/182463223840/182463223840_1_hub0beb03db8d55b854da946234f51706f_586845_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Some Youtube Channels I Like
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/some-youtube-channels-i-like/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/some-youtube-channels-i-like/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some Youtube channels I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying recently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-dGYF1il5OP0lNHChHdhzg&#34;&gt;ComicTropes&lt;/a&gt; is a weekly show that does deep dives into various mainstream comics titles, and often includes the background history of characters and creators, so very interesting stuff for comic book nerds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCqJ-Xo29CKyLTjn6z2XwYAw&#34;&gt;GameMaker&amp;rsquo;s ToolKit&lt;/a&gt; talks about video game level design topics. His series &amp;ldquo;Boss Keys&amp;rdquo; does a deep dive into Zelda dungeons and analyzes them based on criteria like linearity. His level design analyses are strongly based on systems and gameplay and how they affect the player experience. Good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCVEDzEYSNi5FwEKmLY6LT0Q&#34;&gt;EmGo&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/transformers/&#34;&gt;Transformers&lt;/a&gt; toy reviewer that I watch sometimes. I don&amp;rsquo;t buy too many Transformers toys, and watching the toy reviews helps me hold back on buying. There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of such channels and EmGo is one of the more popular ones. He has a particular style of humor that may or may not appeal to everyone, but I like him.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182438184278/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 02:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182438184278/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Uncanny X-Force #1 cover by Esad Ribic&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182438184278/182438184278_0_hu764ea1e03d33eaf341d6f2283d22fca2_388640_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182283926466/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 02:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182283926466/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Captain America (2018) #1 cover by Alex Ross&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182283926466/182283926466_0_hu8f4ae4cf069cae7a1cdbf40c02b7c76c_605448_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182258322007/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 02:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182258322007/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Immortal Hulk #1 cover by Alex Ross&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182258322007/182258322007_0_hub51e80134dd240bb8341e38cd2eb8888_515998_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182232174722/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 02:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182232174722/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Punisher (2018) #1 cover by Greg Smallwood&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182232174722/182232174722_0_hue3c55ea5115e13280685d1726c439493_499132_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182178227976/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 02:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182178227976/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Fantastic Four (2018) #1 cover by Esad Ribic&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182178227976/182178227976_0_hu19f8e4e0dcce1b06fe7716a16d94328f_490315_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182150672586/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 02:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182150672586/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Sideways #1 cover by Kenneth Rocafort&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182150672586/182150672586_hu73893c3b2662d7087d4fc176062757ef_1049760_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182124799020/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 02:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182124799020/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The Green Lantern #2 - OA Splash page. Art by Liam Sharp&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182124799020/182124799020_hu28dc305204fc79f6f88358da86819e95_3133834_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Transformers!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/transformers/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/transformers/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I was at the mall last week and I decided to watch the new Bumblebee movie (it came out late over here because reasons). Here&amp;rsquo;s my &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/181926569205/bumblebee-spoiler-free-review-attached-image&#34;&gt;spoiler-free review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the link says, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a big fan of Transformers since I was a kid, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d talk about that for a bit. The 1980s cartoon obviously, though I think only the first two seasons of that aired on local TV. I had quite a few G1 toys as well, though I think some of them may have been Chinese knockoffs. I remember I had an Optimus Prime, a Megatron (yes, the walther ppk with the robot mode with super thin legs), a small Powerglide, something like 3 out of 5 Aerialbots (no Silverbolt!), and so on. During their first trip to the US, my parents bought me a Metroplex, which was huge, that thing brought me so much joy and playtime. So much playtime that at some point I broke the toy at the hip. D:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another favorite was a G1 Sixshot! Shown in this picture:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#12de95d264081033b692fc99389fa23e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/transformers/g1_sixshot_hud3e5db876aa9a07a38a08610e624671b_296183_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;12de95d264081033b692fc99389fa23e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/transformers/g1_sixshot.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Jan 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;18 Jan 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That toy was borrowed by a kid I knew from the school bus who lived nearby and he never gave it back! I haven&amp;rsquo;t forgiven him to this day lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually have a very large TF toy collection when I was a kid. I know buying the toys back then must&amp;rsquo;ve been quite expensive, so understandably my folks only got me Transformers on special occasions. Even now as an adult with disposable income I find Transformers toys to be a bit pricey, so I fully understand!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I really got into and had a large collection of was the Marvel Transformers comics series. I remember I had the entire 80-issue Marvel run, plus the Headmasters and Universe limited series. It was the first comic series I really followed, I would eagerly look forward to buying the next issue every month. The stories were a lot more compelling and had a lot more continuity than just watching the cartoon. The stories were a lot more complex - in the cartoons, the Autobots were recognized by humans as heroes and the Decepticons as villains. While in the comics one of the main plot points was the humans mistrusting all transformers. Sadly, I have no idea what happened to my collection D:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In modern times though, I have also seriously enjoyed IDW&amp;rsquo;s Transformers line of comics, which had a much more space/Cybertron focus. Freed from the need to sell new toylines every so often, the IDW line was able to give better characterization to the Transformers and had such great writing, especially towards the end. This continuity recently ended and they&amp;rsquo;re starting up a new one I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to this March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently over the past five years or so, I started buying a few modern Transformers toys as well. I&amp;rsquo;m not a big collector or anything, so I only buy one  every so often, preferably when they&amp;rsquo;re on discount/sale, and only the smaller ones. It&amp;rsquo;s fun seeing how they&amp;rsquo;ve updated modern toys to have a lot more articulation and so on. I mostly have them standing on my desk.&lt;/p&gt;








    
    
        
    
    
    
        
            
            
            
            
              
            
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#e67a1763814f415e146285eef24a270e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
                &lt;figure&gt;
                  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/bxqzgqtgnyj/5a8664d528f473b51d204a3cafb560c3_hu39b1d2c426b68b2c3a8ac114da2db0f5_106656_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Twinferno! #transformers&#34; title=&#34;Twinferno! #transformers&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
                  &lt;figcaption&gt;Twinferno! #transformers (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
                &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;e67a1763814f415e146285eef24a270e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/bxqzgqtgnyj/5a8664d528f473b51d204a3cafb560c3.jpg&#34; /&gt;
              &lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Twinferno! #transformers&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Jan 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;18 Jan 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/bxqzgqtgnyj/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;            
        
    









    
    
        
    
    
    
        
            
            
            
            
              
            
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#34578a082b6fba6ecf3602d861b89405-lightbox&#34;&gt;
                &lt;figure&gt;
                  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/bz6ml5japww/968b952f174b08a2e74d7aee290e949c_hu48ee178ede639c65ac0b6bff19b87609_112308_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hound! #transformers&#34; title=&#34;Hound! #transformers&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
                  &lt;figcaption&gt;Hound! #transformers (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
                &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;34578a082b6fba6ecf3602d861b89405-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/bz6ml5japww/968b952f174b08a2e74d7aee290e949c.jpg&#34; /&gt;
              &lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Hound! #transformers&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Jan 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;18 Jan 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/bz6ml5japww/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;            
        
    









    
    
        
    
    
    
        
            
            
            
            
              
            
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#fc7de5032265e5963e7fa341982d492e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
                &lt;figure&gt;
                  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/bsmx_nfh8zf/66a1b4d8293843011b97c2dba0e8e4a9_hu999cec51ffb334121089c828b057ca65_67445_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sunstreaker and Drag Strip #transformers #dilawan&#34; title=&#34;Sunstreaker and Drag Strip #transformers #dilawan&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
                  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sunstreaker and Drag Strip #transformers #dilawan (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
                &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;fc7de5032265e5963e7fa341982d492e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/bsmx_nfh8zf/66a1b4d8293843011b97c2dba0e8e4a9.jpg&#34; /&gt;
              &lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;Sunstreaker and Drag Strip #transformers #dilawan&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Jan 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;18 Jan 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/bsmx_nfh8zf/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;            
        
    

&lt;p&gt;Transformers was my first realy fandom, and something I&amp;rsquo;ll probably never get over, no matter how old I get. I have a couple of nephews, when they&amp;rsquo;ve grown up a bit, I plan to be that uncle who always gifts them Transformers, to set up the next generation of robot fans. Despite my lack of love for the Bayverse series of films, I am grateful that those movies led a resurgence in their popularity, leading to more modern-day comics, toys and animated series as well, so even the young&amp;rsquo;uns will be able more&amp;hellip; much more than meets the eye!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/transformers/g1_sixshot_hud3e5db876aa9a07a38a08610e624671b_296183_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182099251380/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 02:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182099251380/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Mister Miracle #11 variant cover by Mitch Gerads&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182099251380/182099251380_hu81f609479372dc08f0923b5bc7b99dc6_129139_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182072744758/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 02:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182072744758/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Superman Red Son cover by Dave Johnson&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182072744758/182072744758_0_hube1efd035832e9e21aea8e79cc16f322_227447_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182019455736/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 02:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182019455736/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Champions (2019) #1&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/182019455736/182019455736_hu1213d4e6397b6622b92072579e351741_933117_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181992975951/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 02:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181992975951/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;West Coast Avengers (2018) #1 cover by Stefano Caselli and Nolan Woodard&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181992975951/181992975951_0_hu3cace75adf21459a4fd4576d80f8edb5_413557_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181911857439/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 02:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181911857439/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;X-Factor #92 cover by Joe Quesada. This is one of my favorite covers of all time (despite the hologram), but I can no longer find my physical copy of it, not sure if I sold it off before. More annoying is that the Marvel Unlimited version of this issue does not include the wraparound cover! The above image is sourced from &lt;a href=&#34;http://marvel.wikia.com/wiki/X-Factor_Vol_1_92&#34;&gt;http://marvel.wikia.com/wiki/X-Factor_Vol_1_92&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181911857439/181911857439_hu7670406a6dd1768544b48216526fae6b_1936557_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181884473338/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 02:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181884473338/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Batman #1 cover by Greg Capullo&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181884473338/181884473338_0_hudcfa1249bf96ac50709a487e15ee9a94_467919_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181854723316/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 02:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181854723316/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Stormwatch #1 by Brandon Choi, Jim Lee, Scott Clark, Trevor Scott. I found my copy of this while cleaning up, the only issue I’ve ever read from this series. See that guy named Winter on the 2nd inside page? I remember reading this issue back in the 90s and wondering wth he was doing, it was never explained (in this issue)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181854723316/181854723316_0_hu926528ed8a9e54c970d615a2b5cb7e75_816300_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181854723316/181854723316_1_hub6aec5a8f4dc4dcbc9797ad05b2e491c_600432_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181854723316/181854723316_2_hu870aee8815b1148888f694052a250593_634771_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181854723316/181854723316_3_huf29ba9b60d1ed01cb40ef02ca52ea83e_609617_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181823324674/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 02:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181823324674/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;X-Men Alpha, cover by Joe Madureira and Tim Townsend&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181823324674/181823324674_0_hu07aa88a3b8257a3878a9217fbcf04e1c_615357_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181756540094/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 02:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181756540094/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Uncanny X-men #316 cover by Joe Madureira&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181756540094/181756540094_0_hu85d9ddc6a966303442a3c51a35ec4a7a_885213_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181725307993/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 02:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181725307993/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Spider-Men #1 cover by Jim Cheung&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181725307993/181725307993_0_hu2896c3e2e582a0a236cd522e570c3d4a_585502_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>