<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>starvethetrolls on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/tags/starvethetrolls/</link>
      <description>Recent content in starvethetrolls on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 15:01:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/tags/starvethetrolls/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2020/07/1282329311496695808/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 15:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2020/07/1282329311496695808/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;The screencapped tweet and the preceding discussions reveal a particularly insidious mindset among the fanatics: (a) they understand full well what this admin is doing despite the palace&amp;rsquo;s BS claims of &amp;ldquo;neutrality&amp;rdquo; (1/x)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;cite class=&#34;u-quotation-of h-cite&#34;&gt;
    Quoted &lt;a  href=&#39;https://twitter.com/MaoiArroyo/status/1282304531909361666&#39;&gt;MaoiArroyo&amp;#39;s tweet&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Nope. Never have and never will. I made my &amp;ldquo;fuck you&amp;rdquo; money investing in the Filipino people. It&amp;rsquo;s called &amp;ldquo;fuck you&amp;rdquo; money because I have enough saved up to say that if pressured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And nope never tagging you or your wife. #StarveTheTrolls&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(b) they see no need to hold the powerful to account for abusing their position in service of vindictiveness and personal agenda; and even worse  (2/x)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(c) they expect that everyone else should have to bend the knee, and stoop down to their level of transactional politics in order to do business in this country.  (3/x)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For them, the ABS shutdown is less a delivery of justice and more of a takedown of an &amp;ldquo;enemy&amp;rdquo; who refused to play the games they think should be played&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this is a dangerous pragmatism about the way the world works, the belief that we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t question how things are and just &amp;ldquo;play ball&amp;rdquo;, so to speak, instead of working to make things better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect, but for that reason we have to believe it can still be improved, and to speak truth to power where we can, so that we are not stuck in the &amp;ldquo;reality&amp;rdquo; these people seem to be content to muck around in.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2020/07/1282329311496695808/1_1282329311496695808_EcupLAfVAAE3kR3_huafef8c5d19915a8b6274755baaa0f307_86073_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>