<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/blog/</link>
      <description>Recent content on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The End of Everything by Katie Mack
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/book-review-the-end-of-everything-by-katie-mack/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 11:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/book-review-the-end-of-everything-by-katie-mack/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I finished the book The End of Everything (Astronomically Speaking) by Katie Mack. I got a Kindle copy on sale on Amazon at the top of the year, figured it was a good way to kick off a year of hopefully reading more books. This is a short review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figure it&amp;rsquo;s probably not a spoiler to tell you the book is all about how the universe ends. Or at least, the many possible ways it could end. The book gives a surface-level walkthrough of what we know about the nature, history and future of our universe through the lenses of physics and cosmology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me more than a couple of weeks to get through the book, as each chapter does discuss some challenging topics and I wanted to make sure I mostly got my head around it before continuing. I suspect those with less background in the sciences might have a bit of trouble with the text, but the author tries her best to not be too complicated (which can be challenging given the subject matter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that the text or prose is boring mind you. The author spices things up with a few humorous jabs here and there, although it might depend on your sense of humor. The author&amp;rsquo;s wit reminds me a bit of British-style humor, like in The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy, so YMMV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are able to power through the book, you are rewarded with a fascinating view of the current state of our knowledge of physics and cosmology, of how far we&amp;rsquo;ve come and much we still don&amp;rsquo;t know and how much there is yet to be discovered. Perhaps those who have not much background in science will come away with a deeper understanding of how scientific theories are formed, improved, discarded, iterated upon, and so on. I came away with a better understanding of things like the cosmic background radiation, dark matter, dark energy, and so on. Fascinating stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend the book to anyone with even a passing interest in physics. And even if you didn&amp;rsquo;t have such an interest, you could try it anyway, and maybe that will change.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/book-review-the-end-of-everything-by-katie-mack/end-of-everything_hubcde6db45a4b52971688d0f1eeaf446c_6603555_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2021-01-17 There May Or May Not Be Sea Shanties
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-17/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 06:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-17/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This is 2021 week 3. Or week 2. Two and a half? How do calendars work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world&#34;&gt;The world:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;relatively calm compared to the chaos of the previous week. However in the US, a storm may be brewing over Biden&amp;rsquo;s inauguration next week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;locally: still a lot of confusion/inconsistencies around the vaccination plan. Or at least &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.philstar.com/headlines/2021/01/17/2071005/senate-seeks-further-hearings-vaccines&#34;&gt;some senators think so&lt;/a&gt;. Meanwhile, we are close to breaching 500k cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-of-interest&#34;&gt;Links of interest:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a lot about personal note taking recently, in a bid to find ways to improve my own systems. I skimmed this book from like 2004ish: &lt;a href=&#34;https://users.speakeasy.net/~lion/nb/html/&#34;&gt;How to Make a Complete Map of Every Thought You Think&lt;/a&gt;, which is like a super paper-heavy system. Probably totally impractical (for me at least), but some ideas there worth considering. The modern day equivalent would be something like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://zettelkasten.de/posts/overview/&#34;&gt;Zettelkasten method&lt;/a&gt;, something I&amp;rsquo;ve also been considering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I read this Substack &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulskallas.substack.com/p/is-culture-stuck&#34;&gt;post about culture being stuck in the mid-2000s&lt;/a&gt;, presumably because the Internet became mainstream and people started forming a hivemind around what was popular, and creators responded accordingly by creating more of the same stuff. I think there&amp;rsquo;s still some space for fringe tastes out there, but it is true that pop culture has seemed monolothic recently. What hits me most from the article is the phasing out of rock n roll in favor of hip hop, because a more diverse crowd favors it. I&amp;rsquo;m not really a hip hop person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cory Doctorow &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralistic.net/2021/01/13/two-decades/&#34;&gt;blogs about his daily linkblogging process&lt;/a&gt; to celebrate 20 years of blogging. This reminded me that during my recent blog-hopping I also ran across &lt;a href=&#34;https://althouse.blogspot.com/2021/01/another-bloggiversary-this-blog-is-17.html&#34;&gt;Ann Althouse&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;, which has been posting daily for 17 years without breaking the streak! I kind of wish I could be that prolific.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I learned that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liebeck_v._McDonald%27s_Restaurants&#34;&gt;McDonald&amp;rsquo;s coffee lawsuit&lt;/a&gt;, often held up as an example of frivolous ambulance-chasing lawsuits, was much more complicated than that. The woman was hospitalized for more than a week and had to have skin grafts, and McDonald&amp;rsquo;s refused to settle for more than $800, which wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have even covered medical expenses, leading to the huge jury award.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tom Critchlow asks &lt;a href=&#34;https://tomcritchlow.com/2021/01/14/new-browsers/&#34;&gt;why we can&amp;rsquo;t write code in our browsers&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daniel B. Markham argues that &lt;a href=&#34;https://danielbmarkham.com/the-platform-is-the-enemy/&#34;&gt;platforms might be turning us into idiots&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enjoyed this (kinda old) story about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.damninteresting.com/who-wants-to-be-a-thousandaire&#34;&gt;a guy who hacked a TV game show&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not a big fan of Tiktok, but I admit I have been enjoying some of the sea shanty performances coming out of it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/etelsverdlov/status/1348654717036093440&#34;&gt;Example one&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/EKingstonBooks/status/1349906687537373189&#34;&gt;example two&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PH stuff: A trailer came out for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XJ4ChZPlikM&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34;&gt;Voltes V Legacy&lt;/a&gt;, which will be airing on GMA. I don&amp;rsquo;t have high expectations, but the animation seemed decent enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-stuff&#34;&gt;My stuff:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily sketches in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook/&#34;&gt;the sketchbook album&lt;/a&gt;. I used to crosspost them all to &lt;a href=&#34;https://instagram.com/roytang0400&#34;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt; pretty consistently, but now I only do it when I feel like it. Been thinking of getting off instagram anyway, but that&amp;rsquo;s something for another time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finished &lt;strong&gt;Spectacular Spider-Man&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. I liked it, even if it was a kids&amp;rsquo; show. Too bad it was cut off abruptly due to licensing issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also started (re-?) watching Attack on Titan, from season 1, as the final season has been getting some hype. Anime is hard to background-watch though (due to subs), so this might take a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watched my first two movies of the year: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350042544567029763/&#34;&gt;The Godfather&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1350361902149324800/&#34;&gt;The Godfather Part II&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First two eps of WandaVision are in! It&amp;rsquo;s so weird. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing how things unfold. Series runs until March, I feel like I should do one of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/spoiler-free-review/&#34;&gt;spoiler-free reviews&lt;/a&gt; when it&amp;rsquo;s done (haven&amp;rsquo;t done any of those in a while) but it feels weird to do it for a show that drops weekly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1349796416042856448/&#34;&gt;Fire Emblem Three Houses&lt;/a&gt;! Will probably kick off the 2nd run sometime this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG: &lt;strong&gt;Kaldheim&lt;/strong&gt; preview season in progress. I am fairly excited for the new set to come in, because I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to draft, the limited environment looks exciting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like I should be starting one of the many Steam RPGs on my backlog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books: Been reading Katie Mack&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;End of Everything&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m around 2/3rds in, so hopefully I can finish it and at least get 1 book in this month lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health: My muscle pains in the left upper arm are still there, although they&amp;rsquo;ve tapered off a bit, I think because I&amp;rsquo;ve been applying warm compresses twice a day for most of the week. Hopefully it will be gone by next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;looking-forward-to-this-coming-week&#34;&gt;Looking forward to this coming week:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biden inauguration (chaos?!?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometime this week, I will probably put on pants for the first time since March.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2021-01-10 Now With More Links
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-10/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 07:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-10/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;We are barely more than a week into 2021 and it has already been quite a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world&#34;&gt;The world:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the week started off with something as innocuous as a guy going viral for making his daughter work six hours to figure out how to use a can opener and open a can of beans. I can&amp;rsquo;t explain &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.billboard.com/articles/news/9506541/bean-dad-explainer-reactions/&#34;&gt;Bean Dad&lt;/a&gt;, but it was so weird and surreal the way it took over the internet for a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;impossible to discuss the last week without mentioning the violent attack by Trump supporters on the US capitol upon incitement by the president himself
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching the events unfolding on the news &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1347017186317983745/&#34;&gt;gave me the same feeling as watching the 9/11 twin towers assault almost two decades ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the subsequent condemnation and consequences not just from US politicians but worldwide, including Trump himself subsequently getting booted off/banned from almost every social media service (of course sparking many opinions about the first amendment and the disproportionate control by tech giants over the public sphere).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s talk of second impeachment and 25th amendment calls (I know about the 25th amendment mostly due to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1347018337990021122/&#34;&gt;Air Force One&lt;/a&gt;), although Pence has thumbed that down. If Trump faces no consequences for this one, they might be looking at something much worse down the line, possibly as soon as the Biden inauguration on the 20th.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s consequences for the actual rioters though: many are being identified on social media and some have already been fired from their jobs. Nascent social media app Parler, used to coordinate the attacks, has been booted off Apple and Google mobile stores AND off their Amazon webhosting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also, gootecks showed himself to be once again a MAGA idiot supporting the violence, so his emote got banned from Twitch, which was a weird piece of news.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yesterday (Saturday) was the feast of the Black Nazarene, a big deal in Manila. It was reported that &lt;a href=&#34;https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1381685/doh-to-quiapo-crowd-watch-for-symptoms&#34;&gt;up to 400,000 devotees&lt;/a&gt; crowded the streets of Manila in what is probably a COVID19 super-spreader event. I mean sure, we held back and stayed at home for Holy Week/Easter/Christmas but somehow we can&amp;rsquo;t avoid celebrating the Black Nazarene. This when our local case counts have been rising since the holidays. Sigh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;links-of-interest&#34;&gt;Links of interest:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started these weeknotes, I sometimes put in a section with recent links I&amp;rsquo;ve found interesting during the week. It kind of died off, mostly because I haven&amp;rsquo;t been good about going through my backlog of feeds and sources to get much content for the section. I&amp;rsquo;m bringing it back here as a regular section (for now), so that (a) I force myself to go through all that stuff at least once a week; and (b) people who aren&amp;rsquo;t super interested in what&amp;rsquo;s going on with me have more stuff to read in these weeknotes. I also considered just having a separate weekly &amp;ldquo;linkblog&amp;rdquo; post with the links of interest section, but figured maybe I&amp;rsquo;d check first if I can keep up with the volume needed for that sort of thing? Also, a lot of these are available on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/links/&#34;&gt;links&lt;/a&gt; list, which I also share to Twitter/Masto as they come, so if you follow me there, you might have seen me tweet some of these, and this is just sort of a weekly recap. Anyway, for this week, here we go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for gamers, the wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.engadget.com/spotify-persona-5-4-3-fes-2-pq-dancing-arena-soundtracks-104349652.html&#34;&gt;Persona 4 and 5 soundtracks are now officially available on Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for people who like old-school blogs and personal websites: Robin Rendle writes &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.robinrendle.com/essays/newsletters&#34;&gt;a nicely-formatted post about newsletters and writing on the web&lt;/a&gt;, Desmond Rivet wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://desmondrivet.com/2020/04/28/writing-reasons&#34;&gt;about using his blog to manage his thinking&lt;/a&gt; back in Apr 2020, and I realized I never shared this &lt;a href=&#34;https://matthiasott.com/articles/into-the-personal-website-verse&#34;&gt;2019 post from Matthias Ott about personal websites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For self-improvement, ideopunk &lt;a href=&#34;https://ideopunk.com/2020/12/22/100-tips-for-a-better-life/&#34;&gt;talks about 100 tips for a better life&lt;/a&gt;. Probably not all of these are for you, but maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll get some stuff of interest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For optimists, it can be nice to know there are &lt;a href=&#34;https://reasonstobecheerful.world/the-year-in-cheer/&#34;&gt;quite a few bits of good news in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, in spite of everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=snAhsXyO3Ck&#34;&gt;video about lockdown productivity&lt;/a&gt; came out early on in the pandemic, but a lot of the advice still seems sound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I enjoyed this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.damninteresting.com/who-wants-to-be-a-thousandaire/&#34;&gt;old story about a guy who gamed one of the earliest game shows&lt;/a&gt; by studying the RNG patterns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some recent Twitter threads of interest:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently, it&amp;rsquo;s a thing for teens &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/unikunka/status/1346602536904523777&#34;&gt;to disbelieve in Hellen Keller&lt;/a&gt;, wth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are told that abusers and white supremacists &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lilithsaintcrow/status/1347293759155838976&#34;&gt;absolutely do not believe their own bullshit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to determine if &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NomeDaBarbarian/status/1338876619205746688&#34;&gt;something is a sandwich&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone compiled some ridiculous &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/paulisci/status/1340764722811957248&#34;&gt;2020 headlines of the year&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-stuff&#34;&gt;My stuff:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hey, the new daily habits I kicked off starting the New Year are holding strong so far. Well, except for daily blog posting, I missed yesterday. But I never claimed that as a resolution, so maybe I don&amp;rsquo;t count that.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daily sketches in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook/&#34;&gt;the sketchbook album&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;rsquo;re not super good, but maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll like that kind of thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I binged season 3 of &lt;strong&gt;Cobra Kai&lt;/strong&gt; in under 24 hours. Still greatly enjoying it, despite the high school drama. I really like the evolving dynamic between Johnny and Daniel, and the callbacks to all 3 Karate Kid movies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For my background watching I started &lt;strong&gt;Spectacular Spider-Man&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. Not bad for a kids&amp;rsquo; show, covers most of the mythos fairly well, though I&amp;rsquo;m disappointed at how Peter treats Gwen like a sidekick given in the comics she&amp;rsquo;s the love of his life. I&amp;rsquo;m only halfway through, maybe that changes later? I always felt Spider-man was better as a serialized TV series than the constant movie reboots. He has a lot of nice street-level villains and supporting cast that can only feature in a longer storyline than blockbuster movies can afford. Oh well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; Season 3 finale was this week. Nothing too exceptional, I mean, we knew they were going to pull out a win somehow, there were very few surprises. Star Wars wins 2020 I guess lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fire Emblem Three Houses&lt;/strong&gt; still ongoing. I actually took a few days break this week because I felt like I was playing it a bit too much lol. I think I&amp;rsquo;m fairly close to the end though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG: &lt;strong&gt;Kaldheim&lt;/strong&gt; preview season kicked off this week, but nothing too exciting for me so far, though there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of interesting cards of course. Lore-wise, I do like how they translated a lot of the Norse myth stuff into card form.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books: Been reading Katie Mack&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;End of Everything&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty interesting so far, but I&amp;rsquo;m less than halfway in, not a good rate. To help reinforce my book reading, I&amp;rsquo;ve switched up my evening meals reading from the day&amp;rsquo;s news to whatever book I have on tap at the moment. It works I guess, but I eat quickly, so I don&amp;rsquo;t get to read much per session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for the past week or so I&amp;rsquo;ve had some kind of strange muscle (?) pain in my upper left bicep, but only when I hold up the arm or stretch it at certain angles. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of annoying, like I slept on it wrong. I thought it would just go away on its own, but now I&amp;rsquo;m thinking maybe it&amp;rsquo;s one of those old age things where things just hurt randomly and you have to live with it?!? Friends recommended trying a warm compress and/or self-massage on the arm, gonna try those out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;looking-forward-to-this-coming-week&#34;&gt;Looking forward to this coming week:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WandaVision kicks off on Disney+! I think we&amp;rsquo;re getting two episodes this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;more Kaldheim previews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Quotes!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/quotes/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 07:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/quotes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I used to collect quotes a lot. Maybe I still do. Here are a couple of collections I&amp;rsquo;ve posted online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/quotes/tic/&#34;&gt;Tang In Cheek&lt;/a&gt; - a list of quotes (allegedly by me)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/quotes/sig/&#34;&gt;Email signatures&lt;/a&gt; - a list of quotes I used as a pool to randomly select an email signature from. I rarely send email these days, and when I do it&amp;rsquo;s usually web-based, so I can&amp;rsquo;t use these anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s probably a better way to organize these. I mean, I kind of want some kind of upvoting system like they have at bash.org (to see which quotes the three readers of this blog like), but that&amp;rsquo;s a side project for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also a list page at &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/quotes/&#34;&gt;/quotes/&lt;/a&gt; which maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll add to the menus somewhere? For fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: There is also a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/quotes/&#34;&gt;quotes tag&lt;/a&gt;, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t been maintaining it too well.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Regular Reviews and Tracking
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/regular-reviews-and-tracking/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 12:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/regular-reviews-and-tracking/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;One habit I now have that I wish I had started much, much earlier in life would be conducting regular, periodic reviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These reviews are a sort of written introspection of the time period in question, the target audience being future me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of the important of this because I had been going through old files the last few months and I really enjoy reading through some older entries and basically traipsing through younger me&amp;rsquo;s mind. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a time machine in a way. And it helps me by providing a sort of foundation for my thinking, so I understand how my thinking has (or has not) evolved through the years, what mistakes I&amp;rsquo;m still prone to, or which ones I&amp;rsquo;ve overcome, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to start this habit on and off again since basically the early 2000s. This blog is part of that effort, as you can see by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/archives/&#34;&gt;archives&lt;/a&gt;. (Although, not everything can be logged publicly in a blog.) I really only managed to get into a regular discipline of reviews starting around 2017 though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current regular reviews/tracking systems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;daily tracker. This is a custom system I built for myself basically just to log things on a day-to-day basis, with categorization, search and summary metrics and graphs. Most useful for expense and tracking what I eat. This tracker is the reason I have a pretty good idea of where my money is going. (I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are OTS systems that can do this, building your own isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;weekly reviews. For things I&amp;rsquo;ve done throughout the week, any big expenses, etc. Helps me remember when I did things. I used to do this privately, via text files, but last year mostly moved it to regular weekly blog posts called &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/weeknotes&#34;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;. Having the weekly reviews on the blog gave me a regular public cadence. Most of the things I log in weekly reviews are ok to be public anyway; any private stuff stays in the daily tracker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;monthly finance checks. This is the review habit I&amp;rsquo;ve had the longest, but it&amp;rsquo;s also evolved a lot along the way. Basically I just go through all my bank accounts and credit cards and billing statements, make sure all transactions for the month check out/are legit, check if there are loans/investments I need to follow up on, make sure all bills are paid, and get a snapshot of what my current financial status is. I can cross check the deltas with the numbers from the daily tracker, to make sure there&amp;rsquo;s not any money I&amp;rsquo;m losing unnecessarily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yearly reviews. These are on the blog as &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/yearnotes&#34;&gt;yearnotes&lt;/a&gt;. There are entire years of my early career that seem like a blur - I have very little idea what I was up to in those years. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to lose that kind of time again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to all of that, I&amp;rsquo;ve recently also resumed doing &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/750words/&#34;&gt;750words&lt;/a&gt;, mainly because the old export files from that service were among the old files I was going through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this might seem overmuch for most people, but I find it works for me. It helps me with my thinking, helps me manage my anxiety, and having the past to scroll through is certainly better than doomscrolling all the time. (There is probably some danger of becoming too obsessed with the past, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth it as long as you&amp;rsquo;re aware of the risk.) The past informs the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/10/on-journalling-or-how-hard-it-is-to-keep-up-a-blog/&#34;&gt;On Journalling, or How Hard It Is to Keep Up a Blog (2005)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/05/logs-and-memories-and-audit-trails/&#34;&gt;Logs and Memories and Audit Trails (2018)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(there&amp;rsquo;s probably more. Not even I can keep up with all the things I write&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Pinoy Drawing Memes
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/pinoy-drawing-memes/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 06:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/pinoy-drawing-memes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A while back I saw &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thorstenball/status/1317488308285558784&#34;&gt;this tweet&lt;/a&gt; talking about drawing memes from before the internet, and I was reminded that was a thing we had around here too when we were kids!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had our own version of that &amp;ldquo;giraffe in the window&amp;rdquo; drawing, except the one I remember was made so that you could switch the answer to &amp;ldquo;cat hugging a pole outside the window&amp;rdquo; to troll whoever you were asking to guess:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#3e378b94e9485846954887298c03fb57-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/pinoy-drawing-memes/giraffe_huebf412353da86573fd7078a4d4fb0161_188068_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;3e378b94e9485846954887298c03fb57-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/pinoy-drawing-memes/giraffe.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;6 Jan 2021 6:25am&#34;&gt;6 Jan 2021 6:25am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common ones I remember were the ones involving a &amp;ldquo;man wearing a straw hat/salakot&amp;rdquo;, a typical depiction of rural people back in the day. The drawing would just be two concentric circles (see #1 below), representing the view of the man from above.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#f0de1164876f332a828c3de803eb311e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/pinoy-drawing-memes/pinoydrawingmemes_huf4f28bfa731bccee84b49fb821acd8a9_357895_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;f0de1164876f332a828c3de803eb311e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/pinoy-drawing-memes/pinoydrawingmemes.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;6 Jan 2021 6:25am&#34;&gt;6 Jan 2021 6:25am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest in the picture above are kind of specific to local flavor. Can you guess what they are? Answers in the spoiler tag below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#2: magtataho. Basically a man carrying two pails across a stick he carries on his shoulders; this is the typical way taho is sold on the streets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#3: sorbetero. An ice cream man on foot with a cart in front of him containing ice cream; a typical way ice cream used to be sold back in the day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#4: a guy peeing against a wall in public&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;#5: another guy peeing against a wall in public, except he&amp;rsquo;s laughing at a joke #4 is saying while they pee together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are others I can&amp;rsquo;t remember, and probably others that younger generations made up. Maybe some pinoy friends will chime in?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/pinoy-drawing-memes/giraffe_huebf412353da86573fd7078a4d4fb0161_188068_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/pinoy-drawing-memes/pinoydrawingmemes_huf4f28bfa731bccee84b49fb821acd8a9_357895_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>2020 Word Clouds
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/2020-word-clouds/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/2020-word-clouds/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Word clouds! They used to be a thing right? I was reminded of them yesterday and I wish I had thought of this in time for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/2020-year-in-review/&#34;&gt;2020 year in review&lt;/a&gt;, but here we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d generate some word clouds for the blog anyway!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the word cloud for all my blog posts for the year:&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#1e4410ff92a9c9ded87f6be7974f145f-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/2020-word-clouds/2020_word_cloud_hu8b57e42517547ed8fda9ff31b6689758_699553_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;2020 blog post word cloud&#34; title=&#34;2020 blog post word cloud&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;2020 blog post word cloud (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;1e4410ff92a9c9ded87f6be7974f145f-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/2020-word-clouds/2020_word_cloud.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;2020 blog post word cloud&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;5 Jan 2021 9:00am&#34;&gt;5 Jan 2021 9:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s a word cloud for all my tweets for the year:&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#864d680be21b9518c5cf38c1919e6e40-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/2020-word-clouds/2020_tweets_hub48e6a8417f2e4a3dcaff55defb18f14_688510_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;2020 tweets word cloud&#34; title=&#34;2020 tweets word cloud&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;2020 tweets word cloud (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;864d680be21b9518c5cf38c1919e6e40-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/2020-word-clouds/2020_tweets.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;2020 tweets word cloud&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;5 Jan 2021 9:00am&#34;&gt;5 Jan 2021 9:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if these word clouds are supposed to mean anything, except possibly that I use the words ONE TIME all too often? Oops, I did it again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/amueller/word_cloud&#34;&gt;this library&lt;/a&gt; for the actual generation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** I&amp;rsquo;ll see if I remember to do this again for succeeding year in review posts!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/2020-word-clouds/2020_tweets_hub48e6a8417f2e4a3dcaff55defb18f14_688510_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;2020 tweets word cloud&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/2020-word-clouds/2020_word_cloud_hu8b57e42517547ed8fda9ff31b6689758_699553_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;2020 blog post word cloud&lt;/p&gt;
    



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Goodbye Flipboard
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/goodbye-flipboard/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/goodbye-flipboard/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the Flipboard iOS app as my daily morning news reader pretty much since &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/10/ipad-first-impressions-and-snap-judgments/&#34;&gt;I first got an iPad&lt;/a&gt;. It offered a nice, magazine like UI where you can flip through pages full of images and short article blurbs until you can find something you want to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past couple of years and iOS versions though, the app has been performing terribly. Crashes a lot, reader view often fails to load, or flickers and reloads continuously and so on. Just not a very good experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure it&amp;rsquo;s not entirely their fault; recent iOS versions (starting from 13 I think?) have become more agressive with their memory management and garbage collection, so app processes seemed to regularly get killed for some reason. It sometimes happens in other apps too, but by far Flipboard is the worst offender. Maybe their code is poorly optimized, IDK. Oh, and they&amp;rsquo;ve started to have a lot more ads! In any case, I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most relevant Flipboard reading consists of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;latest world news/headlines (main)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tech news (secondary)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;comics/gaming news (when I just feel like scrolling through Flipboard)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a replacement, I assumed I could simply take their most common sources in each of the above categories and import them into my RSS reader of choice (right now that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inoreader.com&#34;&gt;Inoreader&lt;/a&gt;). But after doing that, I realized this won&amp;rsquo;t work, because I treat my mealtime news reading differently from feeds I follow via RSS. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have unread counts for the news stuff, just see what&amp;rsquo;s the most recent stuff and move on. I decided instead to revive my &lt;a href=&#34;https://feedly.com/&#34;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt; account, and import the news feeds there, and use the Feedly iOS app for my morning news reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have been doing this for a few days already; not all of the feeds render well (particularly some websites that did not have RSS feeds, I had to do workarounds), but it seems acceptable for now. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll revisit Flipboard again in a future iOS version and hope they get their stability together.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2021-01-03 Every New Beginning Is Some Other Beginning&#39;s End
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-03/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/weeknotes-2021-01-03/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a brand new year, a brand new week, a brand new day. There&amp;rsquo;s no real reason to believe 2021 will be a better year, but we can choose to try to be better, and maybe that in itself is better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week&amp;rsquo;s New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve transition played out pretty much as expected. We just stayed at home, actually had an early media noche dinner (around 9ish) and observed the fireworks for a little bit. Yes, there were still fireworks, despite the supposed ban at the LGU level. I would estimate a drop in fireworks volume of maybe 20% at best. Ma says maybe most of those are &amp;ldquo;sanctioned&amp;rdquo; fireworks in common areas, but I remain unconvinced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/2020-year-in-review/&#34;&gt;year in review blog post&lt;/a&gt; covered most of the stats for the past year. I enjoyed putting this together, I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker both for reflecting over the past and for gathering stats, so it&amp;rsquo;s a pleasant combination for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really believe in New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions anymore, but I did decide to try to restart a few daily habits and see which ones stick. Don&amp;rsquo;t feel like talking about them all here, but a couple are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the daily walking, but this time I only do a small loop right in front of the house and still inside our subdivision. It&amp;rsquo;s super boring, so I can&amp;rsquo;t tolerate doing it for too long, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get used to it. I&amp;rsquo;ve started listening to a trivia podcast while walking, maybe that will help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/&#34;&gt;sketchdaily&lt;/a&gt;! This might be the most ambitious one. You can check all my sketches via &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook&#34;&gt;the sketchbook album&lt;/a&gt; on this site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;: Fire Emblem run ongoing! And the usual Eternal, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1344593852154347520/&#34;&gt;Magic Arena&lt;/a&gt;, regular Saturday gaming, etc. I paused on the new Humble Monthly, seems meh. There&amp;rsquo;s still time to get stuff from the Steam sale, but there&amp;rsquo;s nothing particularly interesting. FOR NOW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching&lt;/strong&gt;: I finally watched Wonder Woman 1984. Kind of meh. First one was definitely better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books&lt;/strong&gt;: I purchased Katie Mack&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;ldquo;The End of Everything&amp;rdquo; on Kindle because it was on sale, hopefully to restart the book reading habit for the New Year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to this coming week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Trek Discovery season finale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG Kaldheim preview season kicking off!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shenanigans in the US congress/senate when they try to certify the EC results. Also Georgia elections determine whether Biden will have Senate support!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>2020 Year in Review
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/2020-year-in-review/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/2020-year-in-review/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s always weird for me when people do their &amp;ldquo;year in review&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;X of the year&amp;rdquo; any time before Jan 1st of the next year. You&amp;rsquo;re making Dec 31 feel left out. It&amp;rsquo;s one thing the Oscars get right. Anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s my personal year-in-review, such as it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;essay-writing-section&#34;&gt;Essay-writing section&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably impossible to talk about 2020 without talking about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/covid19&#34;&gt;Covid19 pandemic&lt;/a&gt; that has ravaged the world. My country is sadly still under a state of quarantine/lockdown, I believe the world&amp;rsquo;s longest. I am doing relatively well during the pandemic, nobody I know personally has been infected, and I&amp;rsquo;m not exactly averse to just staying at home all the time. Compared to other people, it has for me at worst been a minor inconvenience. For that I am grateful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I miss being able to go out to quiz nights or visit friends or eat at restaurants or even the occasional paper Magic tournament. We haven&amp;rsquo;t been visited by my the pamangkins in a while, most contact relegated to Zoom calls. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been unable to do my regular walks. Other than that my life remains relatively the same compared to last year, since any work I&amp;rsquo;ve done has been from home for the past couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like I have accomplished much in 2020, but maybe given all that we had to go through this year, just getting to the end is enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2020-statistics&#34;&gt;2020 Statistics:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;work-travel-learning-and-self-improvement&#34;&gt;Work, Travel, Learning and Self Improvement:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hours worked: ~100 hours (estimated) - down from ~200 hours last year
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still have the occasional support consultancy work, but for the most part work has wound down, and I opted not to take on additional work to replace it. Maybe someday I&amp;rsquo;ll write about how I can afford to work so few hours. (Hint: It involves being very frugal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming languages/frameworks learned: 1, same as last year
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I learned the Flutter mobile framework to rewrite a mobile app charity project I did for some friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some other stuff/projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I rebuilt this site in the latest version of Django&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrated this site to a new webhost, learned some server deployment stuff along the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Migrated my main email usage &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/gmail-migration/&#34;&gt;away from Google&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duolingo streak: 718 days (from 355 last year). It seems that I never broke the streak from 2019, so my longest streak continues. The numbers don&amp;rsquo;t add up - 355 + 366 should be 721 - but this may be because this wasn&amp;rsquo;t a true streak. I think I used the &amp;ldquo;streak freeze&amp;rdquo; powerups a few times throughout the year, so I probably actually broke the streak thrice lol. I don&amp;rsquo;t care, I&amp;rsquo;m counting it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other countries visited: 0!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;social-media&#34;&gt;Social media:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook activity:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;32 posts (down from 315 last year, and 1081 in 2018). I deactivated my Facebook account in the middle of the year, so I can say Operation: Reduce Facebook Usage has succeeded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;322 comments (up from 138 last year). I did however have more comments, because of quiz nights being held on FB live during the pandemic!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweets: 1037 (slightly down from 1124 last year)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/syndicated/instagram&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; photos: 46. Vs 108 last year. Most of these were for the usual &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober2020/&#34;&gt;Inktober&lt;/a&gt; thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reddit activity:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 submissions (20 last year)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;31 comments (172 last year)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Answers written on Quora: 0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0 words written for &lt;a href=&#34;https://nanowrimo.org/&#34;&gt;Nanowrimo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0 sketches submitted to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/sketchdaily&#34;&gt;r/sketchdaily&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;115 &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/blog/&#34;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt;, 98537 words worth; down from 224 posts and 119529 words last year. Some posts that I liked or got some reactions:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/old-web/&#34;&gt;Tales from the Old Web (Development)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/burnout/&#34;&gt;Burnout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/thinking-in-public/&#34;&gt;Thoughts on Blogging 2020 Edition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/quitting-facebook/&#34;&gt;Quitting Facebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;115 &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/links/&#34;&gt;links shared&lt;/a&gt; (all via Pocket)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;410 comments! Way up from 75 last year. But this was probably due to some integration stuff counting likes/shares from Mastodon/Instagram/Twitter (?) as comments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full stats for content on this blog and social media activity available &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/about/stats/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;media-consumption&#34;&gt;Media consumption:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Things watched on Netflix: 802 (as at 12/29) (416 last year). Pandemic meant more binge-watching. I also rewatched some old (and long) series like The Big Bang Theory, which really adds to the count.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(New) movies watched: 47. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books read: 2, half as much as last year T_T
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/atomic-habits/&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits by James Clear&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/rhythm-of-war/&#34;&gt;Rhythm of War by Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action item&lt;/strong&gt;: read more books (again)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music tracks played (Spotify/LastFM): 773. (1048 last year). See &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/stats/listening/&#34;&gt;listening stats here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;gaming&#34;&gt;Gaming:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I tried getting into &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/twitch&#34;&gt;game streaming via Twitch&lt;/a&gt;! Haven&amp;rsquo;t been super successful so far, but it&amp;rsquo;s been fun, especially when my friends are around to watch and keep me company. Subscribe at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;twitch.tv/twitchyroy&lt;/a&gt; or at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCwpuHIsvCAdmcZ4hIS3tQHA&#34;&gt;the youtube channel&lt;/a&gt; where I upload all the stream vids afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of gaming stats, so they&amp;rsquo;re collapsed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Games purchased (not including any I got for free for some reason): 67, again mostly from Humble bundles, up from 35 last year.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steam purchases:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ultimate Marvel vs Capcom 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divinity Original Sin 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jackbox Party Pack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garou Mark of the Wolves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disco Elysium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knightin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Root&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Civ6 New Frontier Pass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humble
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 games Feb Humble Choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6 games Humble Digital Tabletop Bundle 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 games Humble Capcom MEGA Bundle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 games and a lot of dlc Humble Asmodee Digital Play With Friends Bundle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 games Sep Humble Choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12 games Nov Humble Choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PS4
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake (physical)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nintendo Switch
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Super Mario 3d All Stars (physical)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening (physical)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fire Emblem Three Houses (physical)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My gaming spend is waaay up this year since I decided to get a new console (Nintendo Switch)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Games &amp;ldquo;finished&amp;rdquo; (story/campaign completed OR achievement complete): 11, up from 7 last year.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1235920529233776640/&#34;&gt;Frostpunk&lt;/a&gt;. Finished all of the non-DLC campaigns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-29/&#34;&gt;Megaman 1 via Megaman Legacy Collection&lt;/a&gt;. Hey, it counts!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/&#34;&gt;Tales of Berseria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r-review/&#34;&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1293051269129486337/&#34;&gt;Divinity: Original Sin 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/&#34;&gt;Uncharted 4: A Thief&amp;rsquo;s End&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/1301222471568297984/&#34;&gt;Disco Elysium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Super Mario Sunshine via &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/mario-3d-all-stars/&#34;&gt;Super Mario 3D All-stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Super Mario Galaxy via Super Mario 3D All-stars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/&#34;&gt;Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Batman: Arkham Origins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/super-mario-odyssey/&#34;&gt;Super Mario Odyssey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steam playtime this year: 675.68 hours (up slightly from 639.17 hours last year)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most played Steam games for the year:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sid Meier&amp;rsquo;s Civilization VI - 127.18 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tales of Berseria - 119.35 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eternal Card Game - 80.0 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divinity: Original Sin 2 - 67.43 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Root - 63.50 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blood Rage: Digital Edition - 40.10 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Armello - 30.67 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Batman™: Arkham Origins - 28.32 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scythe: Digital Edition - 17.30 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stellaris - 17.18 hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I went ahead and added &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/stats/gaming/&#34;&gt;a Gaming/Steam stats page&lt;/a&gt; on this site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nintendo Switch playtime this year: 159 hours (thanks Nintendo for providing a year-in-review!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also played a ton of Starcraft II Coop, up to the time they announced ending support for it, then me and my SC2 buddies got tired of it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magic The Gathering
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best MTGA Rank: Mythic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG paper tournament games played: 0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG paper tournament games win rate: N/A (See &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/about/stats/mtg&#34;&gt;my MTG stats&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG GPs attended: 0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I find that I don&amp;rsquo;t really miss paper Magic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average points per turn in Words with Friends: 29, +3 from last year!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;others&#34;&gt;Others:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fitbit activity: 657,713 steps, 513.03 km walked. Down from 1,766,878 steps, 1,378.15 km last year. Down to a bit more than 1/3 of last year! Largely because I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go out too much during the pandemic.  Looks like my counts for Jan and Feb were on track for hitting 1.8m steps for the year, but then dropped off drastically starting March. Sadface. Hopefully I can get back into it once things settle down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donuts eaten: 2, up from 1.5 last year. In my defense, they were Dunkin donuts, which seem to have gotten smaller during the pandemic!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baptisms attended: 1 (up from 0), managed to sneak one in right before the pandemic lockdowns started&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weddings attended: 0 (down from 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wakes attended: 0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New pamangkins: 2 (!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz nights attended: Unable to count, since the pandemic forced the shift to more frequent online quizzes!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grab:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trips: 3, down from 46 last year, for pandemic reasons obviously. All 3 rides were in January!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food delivery: 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Express delivery: 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Times I won the lotto: 0 (I declare in advance that I will remove this stat for 2021, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I won the lotto!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bears defeated in single combat: 0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;moving-forward-using-all-my-breath&#34;&gt;Moving forward using all my breath&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plans are still hazy for 2021. On a personal level, I have been feeling a bit lost in terms of direction, since there&amp;rsquo;s always so much stuff I want to do or try out. I have been considering taking the year off completely like I did in 2016, but that may need further evaluation. As always, we take it in stride, and move forward one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New Year&#39;s Checklist 2021
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/new-years-checklist/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/new-years-checklist/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! Something I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten used to as the New Year rolls in: make a checklist of things to do for the new year. I generally copy stuff over, but the list changes a bit every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ponder why people give so much significance to the transition between an arbitrarily-chosen pair of 24 hour periods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take stock and reflect on the past year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Count your blessings for the past year and be grateful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greet your loved ones and friends and anyone else you hold dear. Maybe even those you disagree with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about what you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn this year or how you want to improve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change your passwords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy a new toothbrush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a target of how many books you&amp;rsquo;ll read in 2021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose the first book to read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throw away a few things you no longer need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out what movies are coming out this year and which ones you want to watch (see below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audit your financials &amp;ndash; where is your money going, how much do you owe, how much are you earning, where should you invest, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick up your keyboard and shake out all the grime that&amp;rsquo;s gathered there over the past year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of projects you want to do in 2021&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose something from the past year that you&amp;rsquo;re going to stop watching or doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat your favorite food. Or ice cream. Ice cream is great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get rid of 2020 calendars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list for the new year!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean up the photos on your phone, tablet and computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete all files downloaded 2018 or earlier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow up on the people who owe you money or things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review your recurring luxury costs (Netflix, etc) and evaluate whether you still really need them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backup any important files on your computer/laptop/phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Export your Google, FB, Instagram and Twitter data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actually, maybe just &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/06/quitting-facebook/&#34;&gt;quit Facebook altogether&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wash your hands, keep your distance, avoid going out or meeting people unless absolutely necessary. We are still in a pandemic!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speak truth to power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be kind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some stuff I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to in 2021 (who knows if they will actually release as scheduled!):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Movies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No Time To Die&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 07&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Black Widow&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jun 11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ghostbusters Afterlife&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jun 25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Venom Let There Be Carnage&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jul 09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shang-Chi and the Legend of the Ten Rings&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jul 16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Uncharted&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aug 06&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Suicide Squad&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Oct 01&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Batman&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nov 06&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Eternals&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nov 09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mission Impossible 7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dec 17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Spider-Man 3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dec 22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Matrix 4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dec 22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Black Adam&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TBA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Justice League Snyder Cut&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TBA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dune&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nothing! Hey, maybe I can work on that backlog!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;!-- --&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Wandavision&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 19&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Falcon and The Winter Soldier&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Loki&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Summer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;What If?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dec&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Book of Boba Fett&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TBA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hawkeye&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;TBA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ms Marvel&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I think I&amp;rsquo;m most looking forward to James Gunn&amp;rsquo;s The Suicide Squad)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-12-27 Season Finale
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-27/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-27/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I started doing these weeknotes at &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/weeknotes-01-12/&#34;&gt;the top of 2020&lt;/a&gt;, so this one signals one complete year of doing my weekly reviews/notes in public. I thought it appropriate for a review!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did it turn out to be a good practice? I think for me yes! Not necessarily for anyone following the blog (all 3 of you), since a lot of the weeknotes stuff might seem boring or irrelevant to you. But for me, forcing me to publicly write some thoughts about the past week has been good for my own self-awareness and keeping me writing regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned this in the first weeknotes linked above, but I used to do private weekly reviews before this. I haven&amp;rsquo;t found much need to supplement the public weeknotes with private ones over the year, but that&amp;rsquo;s basically because (a) my other tracking systems have evolved this year to better capture more data, so less review was actually needed; and (b) this silly pandemic keeping me at home most of the year means there wasn&amp;rsquo;t much to report most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I&amp;rsquo;ll be carrying the weeknotes practice into 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the past week, it was of course Christmas week, which went about as expected. Noche buena night was just me and the folks at home, although the brothers and their families did pass by for a short while on the morning of that day for some gift exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world was relatively quiet. Well, there&amp;rsquo;s finally a post-Brexit trade deal, and Trump seems to be screwing over everybody as expected, and there&amp;rsquo;s a new Covid19 variant, and our government is still being dumb. So, same old same old?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good chunk of my week went towards playing &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1340074409961222146/&#34;&gt;Fire Emblem Three Houses&lt;/a&gt;. As is typical of JRPGs, the startup is a bit slow, but once you get into the whole Persona-like loop of tasks and battles, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty addictive. Pretty sure this will take a while to finish though!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steam Christmas Sale is still ongoing. Thinking of actually getting Hades, because of all the GOTY accolades it&amp;rsquo;s getting. On the other hand, Fire Emblem&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regular weekly gaming with friends: Root, Sentinels of the Multiverse. I also played a couple more Civ6 games for achievement hunting purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new Jeopardy eps on Netflix ran out quickly. Haven&amp;rsquo;t really started on anything seriously yet, though I did watch first episodes of The Expanse S5 and Kimetsu no Yaiba, but I&amp;rsquo;m not feeling like binging either series yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of cramming a few more movies into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;2020 movies list&lt;/a&gt; this week, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if I get around to it or just play more Fire Emblem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To whoever is reading this: despite everything about this year, I hope you somehow managed to have a good holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This coming week: end of year stuff!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Christmas Traditions
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/xmas-traditions/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/xmas-traditions/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This was the year when a lot of Christmas traditions were broken, due to the pandemic. There are &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/xmas-ph/&#34;&gt;cultural/country-specific Christmas traditions&lt;/a&gt; of course, but usually each person or family also has their own personal traditions that they do every Christmas. Here are some of mine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christmas Eve dinner, or as it&amp;rsquo;s popularly known here in the Philippines, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/nochebuena&#34;&gt;noche buena&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Growing up, our immediate family/household unit usually celebrates Christmas Eve with a late noche buena, an extra meal that happened after dinner and starting at around midnight. Then we&amp;rsquo;d open presents, usually with one of the uncles taking the role of &amp;ldquo;Santa Claus&amp;rdquo; and giving out gifts. And as kids, it was one night of the year where we were allowed to stay up late and play with the presents for a while. As we grew older, this usually meant playing video games for a few hours in the early morning!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typical noche buena food: some kind of bread, some kind of ham, some quezo de bola, some kind of pasta. Sometimes there&amp;rsquo;s other stuff too like barbecue or soup, but those seem to be the mainstays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We kept this tradition when we moved out of my grandparents&amp;rsquo; house. This tradition only started changing recently, when my brothers all got married and moved out in the past 10 years. They still come to visit with the kids on Christmas eve, but we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have the noche buena very late anymore, because they would need to drive back home, and some of the kids had early bedtimes. So the noche buena kind of got merged into the Christmas dinner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usually we&amp;rsquo;d all be dressed in red and take a family photo in front of the Christmas tree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This year, as you can imagine, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have that dinner together. Instead, my brothers came out on the morning of the 24th and we exchanged presents outdoors. It was the first time for the folks to see their grandkids in person a long while! We still had noche buena early (during dinner time), despite there only being three of us at home to celebrate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My mother&amp;rsquo;s side extended family usually has a reunion on Christmas day itself, the one time of the year we all get together.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re talking a few dozen people (best estimate, the number grew a lot over the years, as some of my cousins were very, um, productive). When we used to live at my grandparents&amp;rsquo; house, it was easy, because everyone else came to us. When that house was sold, one of my other uncles/aunts/cousins usually hosted (our house was way too small), but that usually involved driving out to some far corner of the Metro. Far for us, at least. (Driving across the Metro on Christmas day was tough, and there were some years where some of us had to get a taxi, that always took forever).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the get-together itself, there&amp;rsquo;s usually dinner, then some kind of party games or some cousins might be asked to perform, then presents exchange. We used to do the Santa Claus thing where one person stands in front of the tree and goes through the presents one by one and calls them out and the recipient comes forward and so on. But this didn&amp;rsquo;t really scale as the extended family grew and grew. Later on, the present exchange became more &amp;ldquo;underground&amp;rdquo;, with each household going around giving gifts to the others throughout the night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A tradition started by my grandfather was the &amp;ldquo;pasabog&amp;rdquo; where there would be a surprise throwing of money (usually coins or small bills) over the party area and everyone scrambled to grab some. My uncles carried on this tradition when my grandfather passed away, and in recent years my dad and I have been doing the pasabog ourselves (since at this point all of my uncles have passed away as well).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We do a big family photo in this gathering too, but it&amp;rsquo;s usually much more challenging since there&amp;rsquo;s way more people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obviously this year, the get together could not happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was also thinking the other day about how the people we greet on Christmas Eve/Day has evolved with technology.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I was young, we could only greet those people in our immediate household and sometimes the neighbors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When cellphones became popular, people greeted each other through those. Usually people had limited SMS, so they&amp;rsquo;d only pick and choose who they could greet. And during those days in particular, network congestion was so bad, it would sometimes be hours before your messages got through. I got a cellphone late and was never much into SMS, so this period didn&amp;rsquo;t last long for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the ubiquity of instant messaging these days, people just send greetings online, mostly to group chats and some to specific people (who are probably more &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; for you&amp;rdquo;). At least this is one tradition the pandemic can&amp;rsquo;t take away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, our government manages to get its act together and get this pandemic under control as soon as possible, so we can resume our Christmas traditions next year!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-12-20
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-20/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-20/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the penultimate week of the year, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not the only who&amp;rsquo;s had enough of this accursed year and looking forward to moving on to the next one. I know that&amp;rsquo;s silly since the world won&amp;rsquo;t magically become better when the calendar flips over to January the first, but I think it helps our mental health to have this sort of &amp;ldquo;fresh start&amp;rdquo; mentality, even if it&amp;rsquo;s on an arbitrarily chosen date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holiday season continues to be weird, thanks to the pandemic. My brothers and I have been trying to hash out how to have the usual holiday gift exchange among the four households. In theory nobody will be coming inside the house, just parking outside and dropping off and picking up gifts, but they need to coordinate since they also need to exchange gifts with each other. They&amp;rsquo;re trying to see if they can synchronize their visits so that the exchanges can happen, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if that works out. Meanwhile, the usual family and extended family reunions will probably happen on Zoom, like many of my friends&amp;rsquo; recent company Christmas parties. Hopefully they go smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the pandemic and the holiday, cases continue to rise locally. This trend will probably carry on into January as a result of holiday gatherings. In pandemic related government screwups recently:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;requiring face shields everywhere in public, even for joggers or bikers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a pilot for face to face classes in January because the education secretary says they are more likely to get infected at home anyway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apparently we could have had vaccines as early as the first quarter of 2021, but the health secretary dropped the ball during negotiations with pfizer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I guess they were working with some sort of backlog due to the holiday sales, but my local gaming store took an entire week to ship me my copy of Fire Emblem Fates. It finally arrived last Friday so yay! I haven&amp;rsquo;t started playing yet, beyond opening the package and checking that the cartridge works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instead this week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a bit of achievement hunting in Civilization VI, since a new patch with balance updates dropped last week. I also tried resuming my Wasteland 2 game. It took me a while to get my bearings, but the game just seems so fiddly, I have a hard time getting into it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG: Kaldheim previews started this week! We don&amp;rsquo;t get any more until January though. The metal-themed previews reminded me of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/1339627168947601408/&#34;&gt;something from 10 years ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finished The Big Bang Theory rewatch, I totally did not almost tear up at Sheldon&amp;rsquo;s speech in the finale. TBBT gets a lot of flak for being terrible, but I think it holds up reasonably well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caught up with Mandalorian and Discovery. Discovery was so-so, but wow, the Mandalorian. What a fantastic season finale. I watched it around half a day after the episode dropped and I was very happy I wasn&amp;rsquo;t spoiled by the internet. The team behind the show are doing a great job with the Star Wars franchise. After the problematic sequel trilogy (which I still enjoyed), maybe the real future of the franchise is on episodic TV. Looking forward to all the new Star Wars content next year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New background binge watching: There&amp;rsquo;s new episodes of Jeopardy on Netflix! Not a lot, but more trivia is always fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than that, most of my time was again spent on digging through and sorting old files. Additionally, one of my old external hard drives had also started getting errors, so I ordered and got a new 1tb one, and spent some time trying to move old backup files across from the old drive to the new one. It was annoying because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t play any games that use a controller while this was happening, for fear of disturbing the long file transfers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m kind of looking forward to doing my year in review blog post for this strange and accursed year.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>How Not to Mentor Software Developers
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/how-not-to-mentor-software-developers/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/how-not-to-mentor-software-developers/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve talked a bit about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/mentoring-in-software-development/&#34;&gt;mentoring in software development&lt;/a&gt; before, and how early on I used to get feedback about me being &amp;ldquo;intimidating&amp;rdquo;. I never got any concrete feedback regarding that, so I don&amp;rsquo;t know what problems I had specifically. Though I was recently reminded of one particular incident that was a bit cringey for me personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a bit more than 10 years ago I think. I was usually assigned to mentor new hires, which means fresh graduates who usually needed guidance with a Java (which was our primary programming language at that time) and with our in-house web framework, which could be a bit challenging to work with. That means a lot of my days are spent answering questions or guiding newbies through more complicated tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The incident I remember was with one particular newbie. After they completed a particular task, they asked me to check their work and everything was fine. I don&amp;rsquo;t have the actual wording of what I said but recall making an offhand in-jest remark congratulating them on getting an entire thing done with zero questions and no actual issues. I remember thinking almost immediately afterwards that it was a terrible thing to say since it implies that asking questions might be frowned upon. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of like the difference between just saying &amp;ldquo;Good job&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Good job, you didn&amp;rsquo;t screw this one up!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might have been overthinking it a bit back then as I don&amp;rsquo;t remember any actual negative reaction to that particular remark. That&amp;rsquo;s not really a good metric though, especially when you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with newbies on their first job. There&amp;rsquo;s power dynamics to consider, so they may not think it appropriate to complain even if something makes them feel bad or uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a mentor, it&amp;rsquo;s important to actually encourage the mentees to ask questions when things are unclear or to raise conceerns when there are problems. It&amp;rsquo;s an essential communication skill that all developers (maybe arguably all people) should have. And it&amp;rsquo;s not enough to say &amp;ldquo;Hey, you can ask me questions any time&amp;rdquo;, but you also have to reflect that openness in your actions, your feedback, and your comments.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-12-13
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-13/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-13/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Time passes yet again. I think I have to get used to not having much personal stuff to report in the weeknotes on certain weeks (aside from the watching/gaming parts), especially given the pandemic where I&amp;rsquo;m at home 90% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the pandemic, the UK started vaccinations last week, and the US FDA approved the Pfizer vaccine as well, so hopefully this is where things start to turn around. Sadly, it may be a while before vaccinations get widespread, especially here in the Philippines. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping things clear up by mid next year for us here, but I&amp;rsquo;m not optimistic about it. It would be really sad if the pandemic restrictions reach next year&amp;rsquo;s holiday season.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that people here seem to realize there&amp;rsquo;s still a pandemic going on, if pictures coming out of Divisoria are any indication. I get that not everyone has access to online shopping, but are there no other options for holiday gift shopping than walking through such dense crowds? This may be one instance where our generous gift-giving culture is bad for us, since people are still out trying to buy gifts when the pandemic is a perfectly good excuse for scaling back on the shopping. Capitalism ho!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The saddest part of this pandemic for me has that my brothers and their families can&amp;rsquo;t come over to visit, which means my parents don&amp;rsquo;t get to see their grandkids (and I don&amp;rsquo;t get to see the pamangkins). Sometimes we push back a bit on that envelope, but it&amp;rsquo;ll be a while before we all really get to see each other and enjoy company in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I managed to finish Batman Arkham Knight! The main story at least. Achievement completion seems unlikely, given the multiplayer achievements, and even some of the single-player ones seem a bit too challenging. I was able to enjoy the game despite the graphical issues I encountered early on. Lowering the settings helped a lot I think, though things still weren&amp;rsquo;t 100% good. I really take to these style of games where there&amp;rsquo;s an open world and you have a lot of things to collect and such.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ordered Fire Emblem Fates for the Switch yesterday! I was also considering Paper Mario Origami King, but that had some mixed reviews, so holding off for now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt; Currently doing a binge re-watch of The Big Bang Theory as my background watching, I&amp;rsquo;m up to season 7 at the moment. I think the show holds up better than some of its contemporaries such as How I Met Your Mother. I know the geek portrayals can be a bit exaggerated or patronizing, so a lot of geeks don&amp;rsquo;t like it, but for me it&amp;rsquo;s fine. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of doing a bad comic book movie marathon sometime this month, covering the ones I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother watching, stuff like Ben Affleck Daredevil, Michael B Jordan Fantastic Four, and the recently released New Mutants. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if I get around to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just under two weeks until Christmas!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-12-06
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-06/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/weeknotes-2020-12-06/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This week felt like another set of those moments-in-between, where not much seemed to happen, but it somehow still went by quickly anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the household and the family has slowly gotten used to the idea that any big Christmas celebration isn&amp;rsquo;t happening. My niece&amp;rsquo;s birthday was last weekend, so we sent her gifts via Grab delivery instead of being able to get together. Most likely something similar&amp;rsquo;s going to happen for gift exchanges on Christmas. We&amp;rsquo;re still trying to figure out what we can do in the meantime. The extended family has proposed a zoom call on the day of, instead of our traditional annual get-together, I&amp;rsquo;ll let them manage the logistics of that, they have a lot of digital natives to figure it out I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past couple of weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve made improvements to one of my side projects which is an app I use for personal data tracking. Improvements to that app&amp;rsquo;s feature set meant I could also take the time to do some digital housekeeping. That mostly means digging into a whole bunch old files to process their contents and possibly extract them the tracking app. Also regular maintenance things like backing up what needs backing up, deleting what can be deleted. It feels appropriate as a near-year-end activity to be going through junk from the past. (Although I should get started on going through actual physical junk as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming&lt;/strong&gt;: In the never-ending quest to defeat the  gaming backlog, I started working on Arkham Origins. I believe I&amp;rsquo;ve had  my Steam copy for years now, well before I finished Arkham Knight, and  never got around to it. It&amp;rsquo;s not a particularly new game, so I figured  my five-year old PC could handle it fine. However I&amp;rsquo;m experiencing graphical  slowdowns, especially when dealing with bug groups of enemies. I&amp;rsquo;ve  already tried turning the graphics down to minimum settings, but still  experiencing some issues. My suspicion is that it may have something to  do with me currently using an AMD graphics card (the game does say it&amp;rsquo;s  optimized for NVidia when starting up). So maybe I should have gotten  around to it before my old GeForce card started having trouble. It&amp;rsquo;s  still mostly tolerable, and I did manage to get through some of the  quick-time event sections despite framerate drops. I&amp;rsquo;ll stick with it a  bit to see if I can crawl my way to the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt; Finished the binge watch of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/perfect-strangers/&#34;&gt;Perfect Strangers&lt;/a&gt;, and have caught up with Mandalorian and Discovery. I also blazed through S4 of My Hero Academia. I&amp;rsquo;d read the manga already, so just skipped ahead through the boring parts. I kind of want them to catch up with the current manga arc, as I want to see some of the more recent fights animated, but I guess that&amp;rsquo;s going to take a while. I also started rewatching The Big Bang Theory as my background show of choice, it&amp;rsquo;s aged reasonably well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned recently that I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write more, and I did manage to churn out one blog post per day last week! Maybe I went overboard? And that says nothing about their quality of course. Still, writing more + going through the past should help me focus my thoughts to help me figure out what I want for the upcoming year (aside from the to-be-expected wish for the end of the pandemic of course.) I&amp;rsquo;m not committed to daily posting, but let&amp;rsquo;s see if I can keep up the writing pace.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Perfect Strangers
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/perfect-strangers/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 12:07:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/perfect-strangers/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;While digging through some old stuff recently I found a copy of the late 80s/early 90s US sitcom &lt;em&gt;Perfect Strangers&lt;/em&gt; and decided to binge through all 8 seasons of it (really more like 6 and a half, since seasons 1 and 8 were an abridged 6 episodes each).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up watching this series, on live tv even, before we had cable or Netflix or anything like that. During the binge-watch I remember a good number of the episodes from the first season all the way up to the end of season 7, which implies almost all of it was broadcast on local TV, kind of a rarity I think? Of course, given the primitive nature of broadcast tv (i.e. needing to be there at the time the show is on), a lot of the episodes were new to me too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, the premise of the show is simple: Balki Bartokomous, an immigrant from the small Mediterannean island-nation of Mypos, comes to America to pursue his dreams and somehow convinces his distant-cousin-that-he-has-never-seen-before Larry Appleton, who himself has just moved to the windy city of Chicago, to take him in and let him live with him. The series largely relies on the contrast between the two leads for its humor: Balki is portrayed as a naive, unassuming foreigner, honest and open and prone to hugging strangers, while &amp;ldquo;Cousin Larry&amp;rdquo; sees himself as this street-wise, savvy guardian who must introduce Balki to the realities of modern American life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, Larry is actually terribly neurotic, deceptive and manipulative, even to his closest friends. He often gives Balki advice that gets both of them into trouble; he typically overreacts to the situations they find themselves in; he is prone to being taken over by his greed when the opportunity presents itself. And when he does get the two of them into some trouble, his first instinct to try to lie and cheat his way out of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember enjoying the series a lot when I was young, and have a fond recollection especially of the theme song, which I consider one of the best TV show theme songs of all time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8vbnLYROCj8&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, the show isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly deep, as can easily be seen during a binge-watch. Most episodes will have a plot along the lines of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balki says/does something naive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Larry says &amp;ldquo;Balki, Balki, Balki&amp;rdquo; and gives some advice or some other action that gets them into trouble&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hijinks ensue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optionally: Larry overreacts to the hijinks and lies or something getting them into even deeper trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d say Larry is at fault maybe 80% of the time, though he does have some good/redeeming moments too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show&amp;rsquo;s overall story arc follow the two cousins as they grow both in terms of careers and relationships; they start out working as clerks in a used furniture store, and later move on to jobs at the presitigious Chicago Chronicle. Along the way, they form relationships with a pair of flight attendants (with decidedely 80s hair) who live in their apartment building, whom they eventually marry and have kids with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last part is a bit problematic for me, as I feel like Larry&amp;rsquo;s fiancee and eventual wife Jennifer deserves much better; Larry constantly lies to her and have put their group in mortal danger more than once. Although, once they are married, Jennifer does exhibit many of the same neurotic behaviors Larry has, including trying to lie her way out of bad situations, so maybe they deserved each other. I would guess this character arc is largely a product of its time, a time when society (and thus TV shows) focused on values such as building a career and a stable relationship and eventually a family (as opposed to the Friends era, where the characters would often be jumping across relationships constantly.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I did learn during this binge-watch run (and the accompanying Wikipedia check) is that &lt;em&gt;Perfect Strangers&lt;/em&gt; spawned a spin-off show, &lt;em&gt;Family Matters&lt;/em&gt;, that went on to be one of the longest-running shows on US tv. I don&amp;rsquo;t think that show ever aired on local tv.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, it was a reasonable binge-watch, good enough for watching in the background while doing other stuff. My nostalgia is not damaged, I never assumed it was a deep show. The best part remains the theme song, which I still somehow feel compelled to sing out loud with each episode.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Dress Codes
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/dress-codes/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/dress-codes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A while back someone I know went from working as a developer to working at a senior/management type position at a bank, and that new job came with the corresponding dress code, which meant he was now going to work in long sleeves or barongs. That kind of thing is not for me - back when I still considered a regular office job, one of the fastest ways to get me to run away from an &amp;ldquo;opportunity&amp;rdquo; would be an overly stringent and/or formal dress code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reminded of this because a few days ago, I read an article titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/latimes/status/1251152944717639680&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enough with the WFH sweatpants. Dress like the adult you&amp;rsquo;re getting paid to be.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;, which is like a hilariously bad take. (The account&amp;rsquo;s social media editor &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/latimes/status/1251175728940343298&#34;&gt;immediately followed up disavowing the tweet and admitting to working from home in his pjs&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s understandable if your job involved salesmanship or meeting with clients and such, but not for ordinary office work. I can fix bugs as easily in a t-shirt and jeans as I can in a suit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind of elitist too. Fancy clothes impractical for commuting or for tropical heat. Reinforces existing power structures. Obsolete signals/ideas of status/power/affluence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not saying you can&amp;rsquo;t dress up if you want, but maybe don&amp;rsquo;t judge others for not doing so, or otherwise require them to dress up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand the line needs to be drawn somewhere, but why does the line have to be something impractical and not simply comfortable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/06/casual-fridays/&#34;&gt;Previously.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Ephemeral Echoes
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/ephemeral-echoes/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/ephemeral-echoes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Last week, Twitter added Fleets, their own version of stories (short-lived posts). As could be expected, it&amp;rsquo;s not something I can relate to. I did post one (saying &amp;ldquo;This is dumb.&amp;quot;) just to see what the interface was like, but that&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about writing a blog post about how I dislike this sort of ephemeral social media, but it turns out that &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/ephemeral/&#34;&gt;something I&amp;rsquo;d already written about before&lt;/a&gt;. Things don&amp;rsquo;t change I guess, and they just come around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still can&amp;rsquo;t relate to this kind of thing, since I really prefer having a record of things I&amp;rsquo;ve posted for future reference. It&amp;rsquo;s generally my favorite feature of social media platforms; even when I was winding down my usage of Facebook, I was still using it regularly for the &amp;ldquo;On This Day&amp;rdquo; feature. And I even put an &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/onthisday/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;On this day&amp;rdquo; feature&lt;/a&gt; on this very site as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People do seem fond of this kind of thing though, a lot of my Twitter follows are already posting fleets. I don&amp;rsquo;t mind looking through other people&amp;rsquo;s fleets or stories, there&amp;rsquo;s some fun stuff there sometimes. So this might be the sort of feature we can expect social media platforms to keep putting out in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game Review: Super Mario Odyssey
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After playing through &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/mario-3d-all-stars/&#34;&gt;Super Mario 3D All Stars in October&lt;/a&gt;, I borrowed a copy of Super Mario Odyssey for the Nintendo Switch from my brother and played through it for most of November. Odyssey was the main reason I actually got a Switch; I played through a few worlds at a friends house during a single session and loved it, so I had been meaning to get the console just for Odyssey alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game deviates a bit from the formula established by Mario 64, Sunshine and Galaxy; Instead of a single hub that leads to small mission worlds, there are a number of different kingdoms, each of which have different residents. The plot is standard Mario fare; Bowser kidnaps Peach because he wants to marry her against her will (and apparently there&amp;rsquo;s nothing she can do about it?! You can say no girl!) You visit each kingdom in turn as you chase Bowser across the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each kingdom is a self-contained &amp;ldquo;open world&amp;rdquo; where there are many challenges you can complete to advance the story. Completing challenges earns you Power Moons (the analogue to 64/Galaxy&amp;rsquo;s stars and Sunshine&amp;rsquo;s shines) which ostensibly power your ship, the Odyssey. Examples of the Kingdoms are the Metro Kingdom featuring New Donk City, whose mayor is the girl you rescued from Donkey Kong so long ago; the Woodland Kingdom is populated by flower-growing robots; the residents of the Seaside Kingdom are slugs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  




&lt;a href=&#34;#0e296a63e8c5317e383ba1adf72d06a3-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/new-donk-city_hud58de80b5c48a33903c4e78adf89972c_330126_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;It&amp;#39;s so weird when you&amp;#39;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&#34; title=&#34;It&amp;#39;s so weird when you&amp;#39;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so weird when you&amp;rsquo;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;0e296a63e8c5317e383ba1adf72d06a3-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/new-donk-city.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s so weird when you&amp;#39;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#e484a0deecbc15a71ffd6173d9c64579-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/woodland_hu39148852bfe8193ef55eed0344c3d387_349647_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is the woodland kingdom&#34; title=&#34;This is the woodland kingdom&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;This is the woodland kingdom (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;e484a0deecbc15a71ffd6173d9c64579-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/woodland.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is the woodland kingdom&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#84526be5a48128edac1b70b29da91719-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/beach_hucc1160ff1649688cbfe46fb4ddd33ef0_299952_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&#34; title=&#34;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Mario wearing a parka at the beach (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;84526be5a48128edac1b70b29da91719-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/beach.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually finished the main story after around a week of play. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly straightforward, not especially challenging.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#7ba08eb041f1571ff133f4ee17ae133b-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/credits_hub108851206b98ce5466a0d64971ceaa1_272556_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&#34; title=&#34;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;7ba08eb041f1571ff133f4ee17ae133b-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/credits.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is however, a lot of post-game and completion stuff to do, that took me another couple of weeks and change. Odyssey&amp;rsquo;s completion revolves around collecting a rather large number of Power Moons. A good chunk of them are only available after beating the main story, though I did try to get as many as I could even before beating Bowser. And some worlds like Peach&amp;rsquo;s Mushroom Kingdom and the more challenging Dark Side/Darker Side of the Moon are available only in the post-game.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#313a380fa8b81e6d69b10f94691c3c60-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/mushroom-kingdom_hu0d6d184ea89cff2c96204967b79d565d_305312_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&#34; title=&#34;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;313a380fa8b81e6d69b10f94691c3c60-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/mushroom-kingdom.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite parts of the game are these segments where Mario becomes a 2D Mario and you have to play 2d Mario stages in 8-bit style, they appear in the open world as murals, often hidden, and they&amp;rsquo;re really nice throwbacks. They even made 8-bit versions of each Mario costume!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completion is a real challenge. There are much more difficult platforming challenges involved, and some moons like the Koopa racing ones will require you to master advanced moves and jumps to beat them. There&amp;rsquo;s also a whole lot of minigames to complete, moons hidden using art-based clues, and a whole lot of collectibles (including hats and costumes for Mario) that you can purchase from stores using coins and regional currency that you collect. I played most of the game in handheld mode, but there are some moons that are easier to get using motion controls, which requires you detach the joycons, so that&amp;rsquo;s something I sometimes had to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  




&lt;a href=&#34;#afa7f811401cc0b4aa2ed14482ff2296-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/clue_hu5c03d63d75cc02a67f36228a0ae744c9_163462_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;There&amp;#39;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&#34; title=&#34;There&amp;#39;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;afa7f811401cc0b4aa2ed14482ff2296-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/clue.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#8743a48562a1c5ef53ff66112e0af0d2-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/space-koopa_hu5a04ad347ee2589302cf1ada3c228395_130058_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mario doesn&amp;#39;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&#34; title=&#34;Mario doesn&amp;#39;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Mario doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;8743a48562a1c5ef53ff66112e0af0d2-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/space-koopa.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mario doesn&amp;#39;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#cf3c150025add34858ebdc88dd0872a9-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/hats_hu0fc2897e727a2efd79695b17b87b2564_246730_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Maybe there&amp;#39;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&#34; title=&#34;Maybe there&amp;#39;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team? (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;cf3c150025add34858ebdc88dd0872a9-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/hats.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maybe there&amp;#39;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get all but 7 of the unique 880 collectible moons. The 7 I missed were 5 for minigames (100 jumps in jump rope, 100 volleys in beach volleyball, and 3 bound bowl races) and 2 stage moons (for Breakdown Road in Dark Side). While none of these seem impossible to do, they all seem like they require much more patience than I am willing to give, so I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with this completion rate for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  




&lt;a href=&#34;#97e0ebef995f25880cec449204a6d666-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/874-moons_huac9045153cdd9a41641854a98f87ad17_219394_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;It&amp;#39;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&#34; title=&#34;It&amp;#39;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;97e0ebef995f25880cec449204a6d666-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/874-moons.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#3116ac381049afd75bad589d6cc5a45d-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/thank-you_hu7f88aae91c13a4ffff71119166449a0c_73671_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&#34; title=&#34;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;3116ac381049afd75bad589d6cc5a45d-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/thank-you.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only complaint is that at some point I found going for completion to be super tedious, especially with those last few moons. 880 moons is a ridiculous number, compare that to a paltry 240 stars in Galaxy. This might be a case of there just being too much stuff? I realize this is a weird thing to complain about. Overall it&amp;rsquo;s still a fun and engaging game, though I&amp;rsquo;m waffling over whether this one or Galaxy is the better game. (I probably still like Super Mario 3D World over either though!)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/874-moons_huac9045153cdd9a41641854a98f87ad17_219394_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;amp;rsquo;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/beach_hucc1160ff1649688cbfe46fb4ddd33ef0_299952_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/clue_hu5c03d63d75cc02a67f36228a0ae744c9_163462_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;There&amp;amp;rsquo;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/credits_hub108851206b98ce5466a0d64971ceaa1_272556_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/hats_hu0fc2897e727a2efd79695b17b87b2564_246730_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Maybe there&amp;amp;rsquo;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/mushroom-kingdom_hu0d6d184ea89cff2c96204967b79d565d_305312_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/new-donk-city_hud58de80b5c48a33903c4e78adf89972c_330126_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;amp;rsquo;s so weird when you&amp;amp;rsquo;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/space-koopa_hu5a04ad347ee2589302cf1ada3c228395_130058_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Mario doesn&amp;amp;rsquo;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/thank-you_hu7f88aae91c13a4ffff71119166449a0c_73671_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/woodland_hu39148852bfe8193ef55eed0344c3d387_349647_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;This is the woodland kingdom&lt;/p&gt;
    



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Rhythm of War by Sanderson, Brandon
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/rhythm-of-war/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/rhythm-of-war/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Rhythm of War is book four in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s epic fantasy Stormlight Archive series. Goodreads tells me I read the prior book Oathbringer back in Nov 2017, but didn&amp;rsquo;t bother writing a review, so I had to make sure I&amp;rsquo;d write one now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book&amp;rsquo;s launch day kind of caught me a bit unexpectedly so I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother doing a re-read of the previous three books. Which given an epic fantasy series of this scope might have been a mistake, but watch me do it again for book five. No review meant while reading every so often I&amp;rsquo;d stop and be like &amp;ldquo;Who is this character again, and why is she here?&amp;rdquo; Which is to be expected for this kind of thing, probably if GRRM ever manages to bring out Winds of Winter that&amp;rsquo;ll be a thing again. It&amp;rsquo;s a whole big sprawl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got this book on launch day last Nov 17. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/01/words-of-radiance/&#34;&gt;review for the second book Words of Radiance&lt;/a&gt; tells me it took me three weeks to get through it, so I was kind of expecting I might take until 2021 with this one. It only took me a around eight days, with the last third of the book taking me a single read in one long night. So, that says a lot about how good the book is and how the pacing is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a really fun book actually, things are happening, and there&amp;rsquo;s character growth and everything, and I feel like this one touched a lot more on the cosmere stuff. Or maybe I was just notificing more things because no review meant I was reading the wiki more. (Don&amp;rsquo;t worry I managed not to spoil myself!). It&amp;rsquo;s great that Sanderson manages to just put in a lot of stuff and give all of the lead characters significant things to do and character arcs and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s some happenings near the end that turn around some things the characters thought they knew about their history; not as big as the one in Oathbringer, but that&amp;rsquo;s always fun. And some things happen where I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how the next book is going to handle it, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to that. (Trying not to be too spoilery here of course!) At Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s rate, it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be at least 3 years before book 5 comes out, and even after that, the series is expected to have a second 5-book arc, plus there&amp;rsquo;s some side books that I feel like I should read because they introduce some relevant characters (Edgedanger, etc) so there&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of Stormlight Archive to look forward to!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>We Shouldn&#39;t Need Heroes
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/we-shouldnt-need-heroes/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/we-shouldnt-need-heroes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s National Heroes Day over here, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about heroics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In software development, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.c2.com/?HeroicProgramming&#34;&gt;Heroic Programming&lt;/a&gt; can have a negative connotation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HeroicProgramming is often the only course of action left when poor planning, insufficient funds, and impractical schedules leave a project stranded and unlikely to complete successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;rsquo;s not just in software development either. Many times heroics are an indicator of failed systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonifacio and other Philippine heroes were needed because Spanish colonialism had failed the Filipino people, necessitating a revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this pandemic, we hail the medical workers and other frontliners as heroes for their sacrifices during the pandemic, but they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to do so if we had better health care systems and the government had made better planning early on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whistleblowers are hailed as heroes, but it would be better if instead the people in charge knew better than to do the bad things that would need whistleblowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever there&amp;rsquo;s an election, we look among the candidates, searching for a hero who will fix all our problems and save our country, but a few good politicians won&amp;rsquo;t be enough, what we need are systems and institutions that work to serve the citizenship and can survive even bad leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will always be exceptionalism, and heroics always make for great stories, but there&amp;rsquo;s also something to be said for just having normal, working systems, institutions, and communities that don&amp;rsquo;t need heroes to keep going. We should celebrate our heroes and be grateful for their heroics, but even better would be a world where we need less heroes; a society that functions normally without people having to make sacrifices.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-29
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-29/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-29/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;December is almost upon us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had an opportunity last week to take on some additional work, but on further reflection, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d pass on it. I am in general, averse to working during the Christmas season (that is to say, more so than during the entire year in general). Even back when I was working full-time, I&amp;rsquo;d prefer taking most of my leaves during December. It&amp;rsquo;s really a result of the terrible traffic in Metro Manila, which gets significantly worse during Christmas season, a trauma that lingers even when I&amp;rsquo;m home all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The past week went by quickly. Not so much because of anything stressful or such, but more like there were a bunch of errands to be done. I also did a bunch of maintenance work for some of my smaller side projects (adding questions to the trivia bot, fixing some bugs in this site&amp;rsquo;s code, adding some minor features to some of my tracking stuff, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t been writing much lately, other than these weeknotes. Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve also found my thoughts wandering a lot and been having difficulty focusing on anything productive. I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel these things are related, and that I should be writing more to help me focus and get back into the habit of thinking better. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if I can get a few more blog posts out in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; Nothing much new. A new drop in the Civ6 New Frontier pass was released a couple of weeks ago, so I played a few Civ6 games this week to try things out. The new leader/civ (Hammurabi of Babylon) was pretty fun, kind of a unique experience, and I like the Heroes and Legends mode. I actually want to try the other new game modes added by the NFP recently, it&amp;rsquo;s just that Civ games always take so long, so it&amp;rsquo;s hard to fit them in when I have other single-player games I want to play. Steam Autumn sale is currently ongoing, but so far I have taken no damage (though I did let myself get billed for November&amp;rsquo;s humble choice). I kind of wanted to buy a couple of additional Switch games, but I might just start something on my very extensive Steam backlog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books:&lt;/strong&gt; I finished &lt;em&gt;Rhythm of War&lt;/em&gt;! Fun book, I may write a longer review, as I kind of regret not having a review for the previous book Oathbringer, as I had nothing to go back to as a bit of review before starting on Rhythm of War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt; I think I&amp;rsquo;ve only been watching more Perfect Strangers this week. Two more seasons to go! This also means I&amp;rsquo;m behind on the Mandalorian and Discovery, which means I risk spoilers lol. Should try to catch up this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; December? Christmas? Not really, not so much, though it can&amp;rsquo;t hurt, but I&amp;rsquo;m counting the days until we are rid of this accursed plague year.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-22 The Moments In Between
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-22/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-22/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This week felt weird. It kind of went by quickly for me, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like anything important really happened. Its kind of like those moments in-between other events, where you&amp;rsquo;re just coasting along and waiting for the more significant things to happen. My country is still recovering from the storms of the past few weeks, Trump is still flailing around trying to overturn democracy, and our own president is still insecure when someone gets more attention than him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These moments feel fleeting, but they&amp;rsquo;re a pretty good time for some self-reflection. I probably need a bit more of that, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found my mind has been wandering through parallel universes lately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I pushed the post-game completion on Super Mario Odyssey, but I might just be at my limit. I have 7 moons remaining, and 5 of those are for minigames, and the last 2 are for the super frustrating Breakdown Road stage. All of these probably require a great deal more patience than I have available, so that might be it for me. Still, it was a great ride, and I&amp;rsquo;m proud I can even get this far given I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself great at platformers nowadays. Still looking around for a new single-player game to dig into, not sure if I want to do another platformer or look for an RPG or such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magic:&lt;/strong&gt; Still been drafting a bit of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgkld/&#34;&gt;Kaladesh Remastered&lt;/a&gt;, although it seems the draft format doesn&amp;rsquo;t like me very much. I&amp;rsquo;ve gone a single 5-3 and three 0-3s, so it&amp;rsquo;s pretty bad! Still, I can keep doing at least one draft a week until Kaldheim comes out next year I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Books:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Rhythm of War&lt;/em&gt;, fourth book in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s Stormlight Archive came out this past week! I got a Kindle copy off Amazon and have been reading a few chapters every night. I&amp;rsquo;m about a third of the way through I think. The problem with this book is I didn&amp;rsquo;t do a re-read of the previous books (they&amp;rsquo;re pretty long!) so every few chapters I&amp;rsquo;m like &amp;ldquo;Who is this person again and why is she here?&amp;rdquo;. This is a typical problem for epic fantasy series like this, so I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have this same problem if/when GRRM manages to get &lt;em&gt;Winds of Winter&lt;/em&gt; out. (I think these two are the only unfinished fantasy series I&amp;rsquo;m still following.) I will say that Sanderson still writes quite well, and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this gets me back into the habit of reading regularly again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I caught up with the Mandalorian, pleasant surprise to see Katie Sackhoff around, apparently playing a character she voiced in Clone Wars (which I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen). Since I caught up with both Mandalorian and Discovery mid-season, now I have to wait every week for new episodes, like some kind of peasant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For my background binge watching, I found some old copies I had of Perfect Strangers, so I&amp;rsquo;ve burned through a few seasons of that already. I loved this series when it was on TV back when I was young. It&amp;rsquo;s not particularly deep; most episodes have the same plot of &amp;ldquo;Balki does/says something naive and/or Larry overreacts and gets them into trouble and hilarity ensures&amp;rdquo;, but it&amp;rsquo;s still fun, and has probably one of the best ever TV show opening themes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;hellip; don&amp;rsquo;t know? US thanksgiving is next week, which is mainly relevant for me because there&amp;rsquo;s usually a bunch of gaming sales at the time, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in yet. There&amp;rsquo;s also some family events coming up (my eldest niece&amp;rsquo;s birthday), but it&amp;rsquo;s hard to get excited about those since we can&amp;rsquo;t actually get together.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-15 Winds and Rain
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-15/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-15/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Weather this past week was very bad for those of us in Metro Manila (and many other places in Luzon). Howling winds and strong rains dominated for 2-3 days of the week due to typhoon Ulysses. This typhoon wasn&amp;rsquo;t as strong as Rolly a couple of weeks ago, but it seems that it brought a lot more rains, causing flooding and loss of power in a whole lot of places. Metro Manila was hit quite badly, even drawing comparisons to Ondoy back in 2009. Even up to today I&amp;rsquo;m still reading about a ton of people who need assistance, relief or rescue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fortunately got off relatively unscathed. The howling winds and pouring rain meant it was heard to sleep at some point, but we experienced no other bad effects and in fact were a bit more comfortable due to lower temps. Oh, and we still don&amp;rsquo;t have cable service until today, a minor inconvenience. A lot of my friends lost power and some in the more Northern provinces were subject to severe flooding as well. It also took us a couple of days to get in touch with some relatives on the southern side of Luzon, but it seems they are fine, power issues notwithstanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; Still playing Super Mario Odyssey, hopefully to completion. Although given how difficult some of these minigames are for me, I&amp;rsquo;m not optimistic. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how close I can get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magic:&lt;/strong&gt; Kaladesh Remastered is out on Arena! I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten started on a sealed and a draft, you can follow along via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgkld/&#34;&gt;MTGKLD tag&lt;/a&gt;, if you&amp;rsquo;d like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Boys S2: Surprisingly the Boys kind of got a &amp;ldquo;good ending&amp;rdquo; this time, although there are still threats lurking around. I went back and reread the first Omnibus of the comic book after finishing the season, and the differences are really stark, as in the comics Butcher is really portrayed as a bastard, maybe even as much as Homelander, while in the series they&amp;rsquo;re pretty tame by comparison. Somehow a lot of the issues raised in this season feel topical too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Trek Discovery S3: Season isn&amp;rsquo;t done yet, but I went ahead and got this started. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a trip. Discovery is charting an unknown future now in the Star Trek timeline, and there are a lot of fun moments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Queen&amp;rsquo;s Gambit: This Netflix limited series has been getting a lot of buzz so I decided to give it a go. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly good, in a sports anime kind of way.  It&amp;rsquo;s a testament to how good and realistic the portrayal of the 1960s chess scene is that for a while I thought it was based on a real-life chess prodigy. Apparently, the show is based on a novel instead, a well-researched one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Misc:&lt;/strong&gt; In the starting-yet-another-side-project department, I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with this library called the Dragonruby Game Toolkit, which I got from the itch.io Racial Justice bundle a while back. I tried building a simple platformer using a Kenney asset pack that I also got from the bundle. Here&amp;rsquo;s the WIP: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MDRShB4psyU&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MDRShB4psyU&lt;/a&gt;. I like that I can work with the framework using only my text editor (as compared to some big bulky IDE like Unity), and it&amp;rsquo;s fairly quick to start up, as it makes a lot of assumptions for you so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about things like screen resolution, screen coords, fps, etc. I don&amp;rsquo;t doubt that using Unity might have made the platforming physics a bit easier, but I did enjoy figuring things out on my own. Not sure if this is going anywhere, I&amp;rsquo;m mostly just dabbling with it at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trivia:&lt;/strong&gt; we actually won an online quiz this past week! Amazing. We had so much fun, we even went ahead and had our own internal 2-hour trivia quiz right after: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=no0sYBcU5LA&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=no0sYBcU5LA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; I just found out that the next book in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Stormlight Archive&lt;/em&gt; is coming out next week! That&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a huge book, hopefully I can manage to finish it before year-end (so that I can at least get my books read stat for the year up a tiny bit)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-01 A Collective Sigh of Relief
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-08/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-08/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The World&lt;/strong&gt;: Somehow the week seemed to go by both quickly and agonizingly slowly, mostly because of the US presidential elections held this week. Slowly because after the initial burst of results on Tuesday night (US time), the remaining states&amp;rsquo; results trickled in very slowly. Quickly because much time was spent doomscrolling and refreshing election-related updates. I think the world collectively breathed a sigh of relief this weekend as the US networks finally called the race for former VP and now president-elect Joe Biden. Celebrations on the streets in many cities in the US, notably New York and Philadelphia. Trump still won&amp;rsquo;t concede and vows legal action, but that seems unlikely to go anywhere except make him look immature and pathetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biden isn&amp;rsquo;t even the best or most exciting candidate, and it&amp;rsquo;s still to be seen how he handles crises like the BLM and police brutality stuff and even healthcare, but at the very least the US will now have a coherent leader and hopefully will be able to address the pandemic better. I would guess that Harris as VP will ultimately end up the more historic win. But I imagine the celebrations are less about Biden winning and more about Trump losing. It must be weird to be a fanatic Trump supporter seeing all these people celebrating his loss. He still got a lot of votes - America remains a deeply divided nation, but at least under Biden there&amp;rsquo;s a chance of that being rectified at least a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have written a lot of words on this topic, considering I&amp;rsquo;m not an American. My stakes in this are a bit lower, but I still found myself glued to the ever-changing blue and red numbers. The US leadership affects the rest of the world of course, especially in terms of climate change and multilateralism moving forward, so it&amp;rsquo;s serious business. But I admit, I also enjoyed the drama and the memes. I had more than one chat groups where some of the members were living in the US, and let me tell you, they were super active during this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of all this drama has to be the whole &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/trump-four-seasons-total-landscaping_n_5fa6e08bc5b6f21920dc14f7&#34;&gt;Four Seasons Total Landscaping&lt;/a&gt; brouhaha. Basically, Trump announced his lawyers would have a press conferencce at Four Seasons in Philadelphia, then later corrected himself saying it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the Four Seasons Hotel, but rather Four Seasons Total Landscaping. Basically a parking lot in an industrial area, next to a dildo shop. It smacks of incompetence and miscoordination of the highest order. It&amp;rsquo;s the kind of comedy that TV shows just can&amp;rsquo;t make up, proving indeed that reality can be stranger (and funnier) than fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump&amp;rsquo;s loss is a repudiation of his style of populist, lying leadership. I wish I could say I was as hopeful for similar positive change in my own country in two years, but that remains to be seen&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, back to my stuff lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server migration update:&lt;/strong&gt; Today, I&amp;rsquo;ve closed my account at the old hosting provider, so there is no more turning back!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I started and finished Super Mario Odyssey! Just about a week, but that was main game only, finished with a bit over 400 moons. (I believe I can get up to 999 in the game?). Immediately proceeding into the post-game, since I only borrowed this game, so I want to get as close to completion as I can before I have to give it back. That being said, there are some moons gated behind annoying minigames like jump rope, RC racing, etc, which I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;d have the patience to grind through, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see. After Odyssey, I&amp;rsquo;ll take it easy on the Switch games for a little bit, though I am already considering getting either Fire Emblem or the new Paper Mario. Would be good to get back to an RPG after all these platformers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching Lately:&lt;/strong&gt; About halfway through The Boys season 2 now. More thoughts when I finish I guess? I thought about watching a Sean Connery James Bond flick when he died this week, but neither Netflix nor Prime had any, sadface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got a new pair of glasses last Wednesday, but up to today my eyes still feel like they are adjusting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not start Nanowrimo. I started trying something else instead, not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s gonna go anywhere though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing I was anxious about last week never pushed through. I should care less about things!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; Kaladesh Remastered comes out next week on Arena, so there&amp;rsquo;s that!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Server Setup Notes: Ubuntu, Nginx, Django, MySQL
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/server-setup-notes/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 06:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/server-setup-notes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I recently did &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/site-migration-to-django/&#34;&gt;a server migration&lt;/a&gt; since I moved to new hosting, The move was from managed/shared hosting to a VPS, these are some notes I took during the process, which I figure might be helpful if I ever tried to  do this again. (And maybe someone else finds it helpful too). Links and references to helpeful resources are included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setting-up-a-webserver-and-wsgi-container&#34;&gt;Setting up a webserver and WSGI container&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already knew I wanted to use Nginx (managed hosting on the old server always used Apache), that meant needing to choose a WSGI container for the Django apps. The choices were either gunicorn or uwsgi. Readings suggest minimal performance difference between the two. I did try setting up both, and found uwsgi&amp;rsquo;s setup much more straightforward and with more helpful step-by-step documentation: &lt;a href=&#34;https://uwsgi-docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tutorials/Django_and_nginx.html&#34;&gt;https://uwsgi-docs.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tutorials/Django_and_nginx.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nginx itself was pretty straightforward to set up. This &amp;ldquo;common pitfalls&amp;rdquo; article was helpful in resolving issues: &lt;a href=&#34;https://origin-www.wp.nginx.com/resources/wiki/start/topics/tutorials/config_pitfalls/&#34;&gt;https://origin-www.wp.nginx.com/resources/wiki/start/topics/tutorials/config_pitfalls/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I will note that&amp;rsquo;s not in the article above is that for static files to be served by Nginx, it was easier to just have everything be under /var/www, for permission purposes. I initially had static files in a different folder in my user root, but really there&amp;rsquo;s no reason for that since you&amp;rsquo;re going to serve them statically anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setting-up-php-on-nginx&#34;&gt;Setting up PHP on Nginx&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed PHP since I had a few minor scripts/pages and a Wordpress install that needed PHP. For the setup on Nginx, I found this guide from askubuntu super helpful: &lt;a href=&#34;https://askubuntu.com/questions/134666/what-is-the-easiest-way-to-enable-php-on-nginx&#34;&gt;https://askubuntu.com/questions/134666/what-is-the-easiest-way-to-enable-php-on-nginx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide from DigitalOcean was also helpful: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-linux-nginx-mysql-php-lemp-stack-in-ubuntu-16-04&#34;&gt;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-install-linux-nginx-mysql-php-lemp-stack-in-ubuntu-16-04&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was encountering some issues with fastcgi not mapping requests to the correct PHP script if the Nginx location block was aliased. This was with me using the default &lt;code&gt;snippets/fastcgi-php.conf&lt;/code&gt; that was provided with the fastcgi install. I resolved the issue by adding an additional fastcgi_param to the php location block like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    location /sample-path {
        alias /var/www/sample-path;
        # autoindex on;

        location ~ \.php$ {
                include snippets/fastcgi-php.conf;
                fastcgi_param  SCRIPT_FILENAME    $request_filename;
                fastcgi_pass unix:/run/php/php7.4-fpm.sock;
        }
    }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The solution for this came from the Nginx common pitfalls article listed above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;choosing-a-database&#34;&gt;Choosing a database&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I initially wanted to use PostgreSQL (since that&amp;rsquo;s what I was using locally) and set that up first. Then I realized I had a Wordpress install I wanted to carry over, and apparently Wordpress needs MySQL, so oops. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to have two databases running, so that was out. Plan out your database usage boys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setting-up-mysql-for-django&#34;&gt;Setting up MySQL for Django&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created the initial MySQL database with character set &lt;code&gt;utf8&lt;/code&gt;, which apparently had the dumb implementation of only supporting 3 bytes for multibyte characters. This led to errors when I tried importing records into Django that had emojis and the like in text. Apparently the &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; character set to use is &lt;code&gt;utf8mb4&lt;/code&gt; (mb4 -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;multibyte 4&amp;rdquo; I guess?). It&amp;rsquo;s kinda dumb that they had to invent a &amp;ldquo;more utf8 character set&amp;rdquo; because of their initial dumb implementation. It&amp;rsquo;s also dumb that I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize this when apparently the MySQL databases on the old server were already using &lt;code&gt;utf8mb4&lt;/code&gt;! On the Django side, you need to specify the charset in the database settings. Helpful for resolving this issue was donturner&amp;rsquo;s answer on this SO question: &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2108824/&#34;&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2108824/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some initial testing, I also encountered a &amp;ldquo;MySQL has gone away&amp;rdquo; every so often. Turns out Django was holding on to connections for too long, so a timeout had to be set in the database settings as well. SO reference: &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/26958592/&#34;&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/26958592/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: I just encountered this a few hours after I wrote this post, when I tried to make the site display all times in Manila local time. Apparently, even if I set my Django app to be timezone, aware, additional setup needs to be done on the MySQL side so it knows what the actual timezones are (feels like they should really do this as part of the install!). Basically you need to run &lt;code&gt;mysql_tzinfo_to_sql&lt;/code&gt; to load the OS timezone info into the database. This is in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://django.readthedocs.io/en/stable/ref/databases.html&#34;&gt;Django documentation&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.mysql.com/doc/refman/5.6/en/mysql-tzinfo-to-sql.html&#34;&gt;MySQL documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;misc-stuff&#34;&gt;Misc stuff&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used cron to set up most of the batch jobs I usually run (like the Twitter bots, etc). Initially I had problems where it seemed like cron wasn&amp;rsquo;t running the jobs, even though syslog showed me the cron daemon was actually running. I don&amp;rsquo;t have notes on how I resolved this, but mentioning it here so that if this happens again in the future, I know to actuall take notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up log files for my cron jobs: I did it this way: &lt;code&gt;0 * * * * /path-to-batch/hourly.sh &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /var/log/cron/my-log-file.log 2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1&lt;/code&gt;. The &amp;ldquo;2&amp;gt;&amp;amp;1&amp;rdquo; at the end is necessary so that stderr is redirected to the same file (otherwise you&amp;rsquo;d only get stdout).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Log rotation: these is the kind of thing you don&amp;rsquo;t realize you need to do when you&amp;rsquo;re managing your own server. Anyway, I found this guide helpful: &lt;a href=&#34;https://linoxide.com/linux-how-to/setup-log-rotation-logrotate-ubuntu/&#34;&gt;https://linoxide.com/linux-how-to/setup-log-rotation-logrotate-ubuntu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed to set up AWStats on the new server (and migrate data from the old server). This guide was helpful: &lt;a href=&#34;https://larsee.com/blog/2020/06/awstats-on-ubuntu-20-04-with-nginx/&#34;&gt;https://larsee.com/blog/2020/06/awstats-on-ubuntu-20-04-with-nginx/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When migrating the old AWStats data files, the filename format from the oldserver was slightly different (new install needed to end with &lt;code&gt;*.roytang.net.txt&lt;/code&gt;), so I learned a bit of bash scripting to do the batch rename:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;for i in /path-to-tmp/awstats/*.txt ; do cp &amp;quot;$i&amp;quot; &amp;quot;/path-to-tmp/awstats/out/$(basename &amp;quot;$i&amp;quot; .txt).roytang.net.txt&amp;quot; ; done&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt SSL on Nginx: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nginx.com/blog/using-free-ssltls-certificates-from-lets-encrypt-with-nginx/&#34;&gt;https://www.nginx.com/blog/using-free-ssltls-certificates-from-lets-encrypt-with-nginx/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Lessons learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect from the migration from shared hosting to a VPS is how much memory I&amp;rsquo;d need. My old hosting plan was only on 512MB ram, and the lowest DigitalOcean droplet had 1GB RAM, so I figured that was fine! But MySQL occasionally had out of memory errors on startup even at 1GB ram, so I bumped up to the next level (2GB RAM). I guess the database RAM usage didn&amp;rsquo;t count against my limits on the shared hosting! The next tier isn&amp;rsquo;t much more expensive and is still manageable for my casual/hobby hosting purposes, but I will probably try to look into more detail into the memory situation at some point to see what I can optimize.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-11-01 Storm&#39;s comin&#39;
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-01/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/11/weeknotes-2020-11-01/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now:&lt;/strong&gt; Stormy weekend here in Manila. Supposedly the &amp;ldquo;strongest storm of 2020&amp;rdquo; so far, typhoon Rolly made landfall earlier today and is currently battering many of the provinces south of Metro Manila. Storm signals are as high as number 5. As of this writing, weather is currently cold and nippy but not particularly rainy where I am. We expect stronger winds and rain to hit us as evening approaches as well. On top of everything, a second typhoon has entered the PH area of responsibility and is expected to affect us over the next couple of days as well. If those two typhoons get together, it may be very bad. Hoping for the best. (I thought about doing these weeknotes end of day&amp;hellip; but we might lose power, so here we go.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server migration update:&lt;/strong&gt; Migrating the final domain now!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/&#34;&gt;Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening!&lt;/a&gt; Full heart and seashell completion even! It was fun and a great throwback to classic games like Link to the Past. I never played the original on Gameboy, though maybe that&amp;rsquo;s for the best, as I liked how this one looked and my memory is not tainted by nostalgia over GB graphics. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t a particularly long game, especially compared to other Zeldas, but there is a custom dungeon feature (new to this remake) which probably adds some replay value, though I don&amp;rsquo;t have much interest in it at the moment. On to Super Mario Odyssey!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I did terribly at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal/&#34;&gt;Eternal Card Game&lt;/a&gt; worlds LCQ, but I must admit their current celebration promo was super effective in getting me back into the game, as I&amp;rsquo;m now doing daily grinds in both Eternal and Magic Arena again. I managed to hit Mythic in Magic Arena before month end, but didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough time for Eternal, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if I can keep it up next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gaming:&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying games of &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/965580/Root/&#34;&gt;Root&lt;/a&gt; with the Saturday gaming group. It&amp;rsquo;s a multifaction boardgame where each faction plays differently and has different ways of scoring victory points, and the factions will naturally clash with each other. The main challenge is finding a fine balance between advancing your agenda and interfering with the others. Disrupting the other factions might lose you some momentum compared to the others, but if no one keeps the others in check, someone might run away with victory! Pretty fun. And given that the game supports asynchronous games (up to 3 days per turn), the term &amp;ldquo;Saturday gaming group&amp;rdquo; is a bit obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Done:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober2020&#34;&gt;the Inktober thing&lt;/a&gt;! I managed to get through the whole thing without missing a day! Doing daily drawings with a pen are hard for me, given my poor manual dexterity at this age (and it was never that good in the first place). My hands got tired so easily, and a lot of my lines were shaky. Still, I enjoyed doing a lot of the sketches, and while I don&amp;rsquo;t want to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/&#34;&gt;commit to daily drawings&lt;/a&gt; again (at least for now), maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll warm up the old Apple Pencil every so often and do some digital stuff? Maybe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching lately:&lt;/strong&gt; I finished Season 4 of The Expanse. I didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy it as much as the first 3 seasons, though the second half was better than the first. Things were ramping up too slowly, and a lot of things didn&amp;rsquo;t seem relevant to the what was going on with the Roci crew (and turned out to be mostly geared towards next season&amp;rsquo;s big crisis apparently?). As I said to a friend, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m here for the scifi protomolecule stuff not OPA terrorist or earth politics BS.&amp;rdquo; Still, looking forward to the next season. Also: Finished five seasons of NCIS (that&amp;rsquo;s all they had on Prime Video). In the queue: The Boys S2, Star Trek Discovery S3, Mandalorian S2. Where&amp;rsquo;s my Orville?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skipped:&lt;/strong&gt; Hacktoberfest. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Considering:&lt;/strong&gt; Nanowrimo. Haven&amp;rsquo;t done any prep, so if ever it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a late start. I do have some ideas rolling around in my head, but I also have some other stuff to do, so for now let&amp;rsquo;s say this is &amp;ldquo;low probability&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anxiety:&lt;/strong&gt; Low, most of it due to awaiting a call back about something that hasn&amp;rsquo;t pushed through yet, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really need? Why am I anxious about it then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Random:&lt;/strong&gt; This storm reminded me of my worst typhoon experience in Metro Manila, Ondoy back in 2009, so I wrote a short &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/09/ondoy/&#34;&gt;back-dated retrospective on it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad luck:&lt;/strong&gt; The hinge on one side of my glasses&amp;rsquo; frame broke while I was at the cashier at the grocery yesterday! D: I have a slightly older pair I can use in the meantime, but it&amp;rsquo;ll probably be a few days before I can even go to get a real replacement, given the storm and the long weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking forward to:&lt;/strong&gt; the US presidential elections, with a mix of morbid dread and anticipation, like an onlooker at a car crash.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Site Migration from Hugo to Django
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/site-migration-from-hugo-to-django/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/site-migration-from-hugo-to-django/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;h3 id=&#34;leaving-hugo&#34;&gt;Leaving Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit under two years since &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-migration-to-hugo/&#34;&gt;I migrated the site from Wordpress to Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. As discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/one-year-with-hugo/&#34;&gt;this post one year ago&lt;/a&gt;, I was very happy with the general workflow of managing posts through markdown files in git, but had big problems with the Hugo build time, largely a consequence of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/archive-of-my-own/&#34;&gt;my social media archiving&lt;/a&gt;. At that time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to invest effort into migrating to a different backend, but the problem has only gotten incrementally worse since then, so I decided to take the jump and started working on it last month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;migration-goals&#34;&gt;Migration goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main goal is to get rid of the unnecessary build time. I also don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to store all the pre-generated HTML files. It&amp;rsquo;s fine for a small site, but with the large number of posts here, there&amp;rsquo;s a large amount of unnecessary duplication, considering listing pages and such. That means reverting to a system where each page is generated on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to retain the current workflow of managing content via markdown files, so that rules out something like Wordpress. Still, I figured I needed some kind of database for indexing, so that things like listing and archive pages work properly. Given that we would be migrating away from a static site, I fully expect a performance hit, at least initially, but ideally it&amp;rsquo;s not too bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d also like to retain the current content written for Hugo as much as possible. This means the new system will need to be able to parse the custom Hugo shortcodes I&amp;rsquo;d set up for the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also be migrating to a new server which I would be managing myself, which means I would need to set up the deployment myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-django&#34;&gt;Why Django&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I naturally fell back on Django, it&amp;rsquo;s my ORM+backend framework of choice, and the one I&amp;rsquo;m most familiar with. Also, I already had a handful of small Django apps that I needed to migrate to the new server as well, so no matter what I needed to have a Django app on the server anyway. I also had a bunch of Python scripts that were doing already doing support functions for the site like search and ingestion of social media content, so that&amp;rsquo;s something to fold into the new backend as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-bother&#34;&gt;Why Bother?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will fully admit I spent far too much effort unnecessarily doing this, but the realization is that it&amp;rsquo;s actually work I enjoy. This site is primarily a project for myself, and I enjoy the time working on it and learning stuff and improving things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, the effort wasn&amp;rsquo;t too much. There was a lot of code to reuse and migrate, so most of the effort was testing and making sure things worked. Most of the new code was for parsing the markdown files to render the hugo shortcodes as HTML; I basically wrote Django templates for each Hugo shortcode to be supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;changes&#34;&gt;Changes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The migration was largely done in-place: site design remains mostly the same, post URLs should be more or less retained. I did take the opportunity to make one nontrivial change: Photos are now under &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/a&gt; category. I really only had a separate photos category before because in Hugo I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a way to query posts that have attached images. Even with everything under Notes, since I have a database now, I can do silly things like show &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/photos/random&#34;&gt;random photos&lt;/a&gt;. Also, now the notes section is closer to a microblog/tumblr-like feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source for the site content will still be &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/roytang/blog&#34;&gt;available publicly via Github&lt;/a&gt;, as it was before. Unfortunately, I am not ready to make public the source for this site, because (a) a lot of it is old code that I reused so it looks terrible; and (b) some level of security by obscurity I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that the site needs to be secure; there isn&amp;rsquo;t actually any critical/important data being stored anywhere. But the fact that a database now exists means I need to follow some kind of security practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The server is now hosted on DigitalOcean. Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.do.co/c/6c2e6b11b260&#34;&gt;my affiliate link&lt;/a&gt;. Since I&amp;rsquo;m on a self-managed VPS now, that means Github webhooks now work, so whenever I push new posts, they take less than a minute to now appear on the site. This is a vast improvement over the old system where it would take anywhere between 30-60 minutes depending on how Travis was feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Travis, I set up a new mirror, Travis now publishes to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net&#34;&gt;https://mirror.roytang.net&lt;/a&gt; once a day, hosted on Netlify. The mirror is still generated using Hugo! I don&amp;rsquo;t know how long I can keep up having the content generate correctly for both builds, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this actually went out much smoother than I thought it would. Took less effort than expected, deployment was a breeze. The listing pages have slightly worse performance, but individual pages are hitting 100 on Pagespeed, so that&amp;rsquo;s mostly fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was just the overview of the site changes. There&amp;rsquo;s still a bunch of technical notes to be written up, so that&amp;rsquo;s stuff for a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time I used a Django backend for my website was &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/12/roytang-net-site-update/&#34;&gt;waaaay back in 2008&lt;/a&gt;, and that didn&amp;rsquo;t last more than a year before I switched to Wordpress. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how long this one holds out!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-10-25
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-25/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-25/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Server migration update: I had encountered some trouble with the Travis-CI -based Hugo build generating this here website last week. Luckily, most of the migration work to the new backend was already done, so I went ahead and switched over the servers. So this site is no longer plain-old deployed HTML, but rather powered by a Django backend. The site should be mostly the same, though I did take the opportunity to move some stuff around. There&amp;rsquo;s probably some bugs floating around, and maybe some secrets even. Probably need a longer blog post writing about the migration itself, though it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too complicated. I also have a bunch of notes about the server setup that I&amp;rsquo;ll also carve into a blog post when I have time. Things should be mostly done for this site, but I have one other domain I have to migrate, and I have scheduled that for the end of the month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means that hopefully all my apps/domains will be on the new server after the first week of November. My account at the old webhost is paid until Nov 15th, and I&amp;rsquo;ve already indicated I don&amp;rsquo;t plan to migrate to whatever new system they have, so it&amp;rsquo;s just in time I think. Hoping things go smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming: I did &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1318238520251621377/&#34;&gt;the 120 stars &amp;ldquo;completion&amp;rdquo; for Super Mario Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;, although that&amp;rsquo;s really more like half of actual completion. I put down the Switch for a few days after that to cool down on it for a bit, as I have been playing it a lot since I got it. Still deciding whether to play Odyssey next or try Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming: I haven&amp;rsquo;t played &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal/&#34;&gt;Eternal Card Game&lt;/a&gt; in months, which meant falling behind on the collection as new sets came out and such. But they&amp;rsquo;re running an event right now where all accounts have access to all cards, and there are qualifiers for their worlds event. I figured why not and gave it a shot, running a deck I got from their recent tournaments, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1319794495395745793/&#34;&gt;managed to qualify for the LCQ on my first try&lt;/a&gt;. Eternal has always been a fun game, but the past few months I&amp;rsquo;ve preferred playing on MTG Arena. The timing of this Eternal event was pretty nice, as it came up just after Arena got a patch that severely downgraded the UX, with bugs being reported everywhere and general laggy performance. The Eternal client was, as always, snappy and had no issues. Arena dev team needs to get their act together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still ongoing: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober2020&#34;&gt;the Inktober thing&lt;/a&gt;. Still haven&amp;rsquo;t missed a day! This week is the final stretch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not ongoing: Hacktoberfest. I mentioned before that I was planning to do it, but&amp;hellip; I haven&amp;rsquo;t. Less than a week to go, so doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem likely I can get into it, especially since other things have come up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my current webhost finally decided to give me a deadline, the long and short of it is that my new server needs to be ready by December the 9th, giving me a bit under a month to get things in order. I&amp;rsquo;m already in the middle of setting up the new server, so I think I&amp;rsquo;ll be ready by early November anyway. Most of the code to run the new blog is also mostly ready (who knows how many bugs there are though!) I am (re-)learning a lot about server setups though, so hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have quite a few blog posts to write the migration is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching lately: Mostly old NCIS seasons still, and I&amp;rsquo;m just past the halfway point on The Expanse season 4. Slow going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am looking forward to November, and am awaiting the outcome of the US presidential elections with morbid interest.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game Review: Super Mario 3d All-stars
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/mario-3d-all-stars/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 14:03:35 +0800</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/mario-3d-all-stars/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/nintendo-switch/&#34;&gt;got a Nintendo Switch last month&lt;/a&gt;. One of the first games I had gotten for the system was the recently released Super Mario 3d All-Stars. I had really been wanting to play Super Mario Odyssey instead, but my brother had a copy of that game that I could borrow later, so I decided to get 3dAS first, as I had never really played the 3 games on the collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly played the 2d Mario games prior to this, with the exception of 3d Land (3DS) and 3d World (WiiU), although both of those games were closer in style to the the 2d mario games than to the games in this collection. The three games here share the same style of having a hub-like world from which you visit other worlds to accomplish missions to get stars/shines. The other worlds have multiple &amp;ldquo;episodes&amp;rdquo; so you have to replay each of them a bunch of times (doing different things each time) to get all the stars/shines available in those worlds. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a clever world to save on level design resources - each world is essentially multiple stages sharing the same maps and objects and so on. It can also mean the player might get tired of repeating the same worlds over and over, but the hub system means they can visit other worlds for a while if that happens. As you gather stars/shines, you unlock more areas of the hub world and thus more worlds/stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t optimistic about SM64 going in. I played a little bit of it on the DS when it was released there, didn&amp;rsquo;t really enjoy it. Released in 1996, I know it&amp;rsquo;s regarded as a classic and revolutionized 3d platforming in its day, but for me it hasn&amp;rsquo;t really aged very well. My problems with the title are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poor camera handling. You don&amp;rsquo;t have smooth right-stick control of the camera (since the N64 did not have a right analog stick), and the camera angles are often limited in how you can rotate them around. There&amp;rsquo;s a button to toggle the camera from Lakitu perspective to Mario perspective, which is annoying for me since I don&amp;rsquo;t find the over-the-shoulder Mario perspective useful, and I accidentally keep hitting the toggle button. There is a setting to disable the Mario perspective altogether (such that the toggle button now fixes the camera to a given position instead), but the setting resets every time you load your game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even when the camera is in Lakitu mode, it will often turn or rotate far too quickly for my taste, and for me this means if I play the game for around an hour or so I start getting dizzy, and this is the main dealbreaker for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I find it quite difficult to control Mario in this game as well. His normal movement is to run, not to walk, so a simple flick of the left analog stick moves him farther than I&amp;rsquo;d like, and the same goes for his jumps. I think it&amp;rsquo;s because this was their first 3d game, so they hadn&amp;rsquo;t really calibrated yet what would be a good walk/run speed and jump distance. Adding to that, some actions like turning Mario in a new direction combined with jumping can cause him to jump in a different direction/distance, it&amp;rsquo;s something to get used to. You don&amp;rsquo;t have much jump control once you are in mid-air either. So for difficult platforming segments, I often found it challenging to position Mario for precise jumps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many of the worlds/stages are also quite frustrating. You will be dying quite often. This is unsurprising for a Mario game, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that many of the sequences are a bit long so it can be annoying to re-do them. Combined with the finnicky controls and the often weird camera angles, it can cause unnecessary frustration. Even worse, when you die, you are not just kicked back to the start of the stage, but most of the time you are kicked out of the stage altogether and back to the hub world. A minor inconvenience, but it still means additional friction in the try-fail-retry cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of try-fail-retry, a lot of the missions really require you to spend multiple lives dying and trying again. This isn&amp;rsquo;t unexpected, but a lot of them can be extremely challenging. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking in particular of that one mission where you have to race a penguin down a twisty icy slope, where veering off the slope means death. Trying to get to the end of the icy slope is bad enough - it&amp;rsquo;s going to take you a lot of trial and error to do so - but then you have to make sure you get there ahead of the penguin too. I feel like a lot of the more challenging missions carry over some of the &amp;ldquo;Nintendo hard&amp;rdquo; mentality from the NES/SNES generation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to even finish SM64 yet, so I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are a lot more challenging stages ahead. As of this writing, my progress stands at a pitiful 17 stars obtained (out of a possible 120). The dizziness due to the camera is the main problem for me. I may try to come back to it later, but for now there are better games to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Super Mario Sunshine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released in 2002 for the GameCube, Sunshine is the mainline Mario I&amp;rsquo;ve never even tried before. I later found out that Sunshine is considered one of the most difficult 3d Mario games to date. I will tend to disagree; I think the average SM64 stage is more difficult than Super Mario Sunshine, given that I was actually able to beat Sunshine. I will concede that 120-shine completion is probably very difficult for Sunshine though, but more on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunshine provides some improvements over SM64:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most significant upgrade is graphically. It&amp;rsquo;s a huge jump over SM64&amp;rsquo;s blocky polygons, and Mario&amp;rsquo;s appearance here is already pretty close to his latest modern appearances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still find walk/run controls a bit slippery, but there is significant improvement in jump control since this game gives you FLUDD (the water jetstream firing thing), which has hover functionality making it easier to make difficult jumps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsurprisingly, the most challenging parts of the game are the &amp;ldquo;secret&amp;rdquo; platforming stages where Mario is denied the use of FLUDD. These secrets usually have to be accessed at a certain point in the composite worlds. Although these secret stages are difficult, the blow is kind of softened by two things: if you die, you are returned to the start of the secret stage (instead of kicked out to the containing/hub world); and most of the stages will have one or more 1-ups available, with one easily available near the start of the stage. You&amp;rsquo;re still going to need to grind a lot to finish these secret stages, but at least you&amp;rsquo;re not likely to run out of lives doing so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also most of the game&amp;rsquo;s worlds and settings are a lot more fun in terms of ambience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, I did manage &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1314224120490389504/&#34;&gt;to beat Super Mario Sunshine a couple of weeks ago&lt;/a&gt;. I finished with around 77 shines (out of a possible 120). I may eventually come back to it for completion, although that looks challenging. The main challenge would probably be completing the blue coins in each world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Super Mario Galaxy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally released in 2007, Galaxy is easily the best game in this collection. I tried playing this back when I first got a WiiU (by borrowing the game and a couple of WiiMotes from a friend). At the time I wasn&amp;rsquo;t thrilled with the WiiMote control scheme, especially with having to use the WiiMote as an imprecise pointer, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t get far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m obviously much happier with the Switch version. In handheld mode, you use touch controls on the screen to do the pointer stuff (like to collect star bits), which is much easier and more precise than using the WiiMote (or pointing the joycon in TV mode), so that&amp;rsquo;s my preferred mode of playing the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some stages that require motion controls, where I find I need to switch to TV control. Examples are the ones where you have to control a Mario riding a rolling ball, or Mario riding a manta ray surfing along a water track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game itself is very beautiful and significantly easier (or at least, less frustrating) than the first two games. You don&amp;rsquo;t have FLUDD this time, but Mario gets a spin jump that gives him additional jump control. And longer stages now have checkpoints in between so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to start over from the beginning if you die. Many of the stages are fun to play and do a lot of innovative things like playing around with gravity and such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still some challenging stages. Two of them specifically come to mind: The first one is Galaxy&amp;rsquo;s Greatest Wave, which is one of the aforementioned ray-surfing stages. The race course is very twisty and challening, and if you take each turn too fast or don&amp;rsquo;t turn just the right amount, you&amp;rsquo;re going to be falling off. There are a number of 1-ups along the course, and I managed to get to 99 lives in trying to finish the course. My personal estimate is that I probably re-did the course at least a hundred times. The second one that comes to mind is Luigi&amp;rsquo;s Purple Coins, a stage only available after beating the game the first time. It&amp;rsquo;s a stage where you have to be constantly jumping across disappearing platforms while collecting purple coins all within a time limit. It took me a lot less tries than the ray-surfing one, but each try was exhausting since you&amp;rsquo;re jumping all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I wish they would have done for this port was add more button support for the menus, instead of having to use tap/motion control for many of them (such as when retrying a level).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1317023064555548672/&#34;&gt;finished Galaxy for the first time&lt;/a&gt; last week, and completed the bonus Purple coin missions a few days later. That makes it the first game of this trilogy where &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1318238520251621377/&#34;&gt;I hit the goal of 120 stars&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike the first two games though, Galaxy has an additional &amp;ldquo;second quest&amp;rdquo;, an additional 120 stars to be earned while playing as Luigi. Again, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably come back to this at another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Switch is a great console for these games, since I can easily pick it up at any time and play a couple of stages in handheld mode. I was worried whether this purchase would be worth it, since to be honest I&amp;rsquo;m getting a bit old and am not as good as the platforming stuff as I used to be. Platforming in 3d only adds an additional level of difficulty for me personally. But overall, it was a good purchase. I somehow managed to beat two of the games, and it was nice to see how the 3d Mario games evolve through the years. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad they didn&amp;rsquo;t include Galaxy 2, which by all accounts is as good as Galaxy was. My fingers and wrists are tired from all the jumping though, so maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll put down the Switch for a few days before I get started with Odyssey.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-10-18
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-18/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-18/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So my current webhost finally decided to give me a deadline, the long and short of it is that my new server needs to be ready by December the 9th, giving me a bit under a month to get things in order. I&amp;rsquo;m already in the middle of setting up the new server, so I think I&amp;rsquo;ll be ready by early November anyway. Most of the code to run the new blog is also mostly ready (who knows how many bugs there are though!) I am (re-)learning a lot about server setups though, so hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have quite a few blog posts to write the migration is done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming: Hey, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1317023064555548672/&#34;&gt;finished Super Mario Galaxy&lt;/a&gt;! There&amp;rsquo;s 15 post-game stars only available after beating the game, I&amp;rsquo;m trying to work through them before moving on to Odyssey, alhough some of them are quite stressful. (Apparently there&amp;rsquo;s an entire 120 stars again afterwards in some kind of second quest, but I figure I can come back to that some other time.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still ongoing: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober2020&#34;&gt;the Inktober thing&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s surprising that I haven&amp;rsquo;t missed a day yet. (Hopefully I haven&amp;rsquo;t jinxed it.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching lately: I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to having old seasons of NCIS running in the background (via Prime Video) recently, they&amp;rsquo;re the sort of show you can just leave running while you&amp;rsquo;re doing other things, and if you miss something it really doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. I also started on Expanse season 4, but that requires more focused watching so the going is slow. I have some backlog to work through, since The Boys season 2 and Star Trek Discovery season 3 are both out now.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-10-11
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-11/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-11/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The world continues to be terrible. The PH government wants people to get back to work and everything to spur the economy (with health precautions and everything). A lot of people have no choice, but I&amp;rsquo;m fortunate enough to not have to go out there yet, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure people like me will still hold back. This all would have been a lot easier if the government had gotten control of this pandemic early on but it is what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still not writing blog posts apparently. I have a lot of thoughts swirling in my head, I&amp;rsquo;m sure they&amp;rsquo;ll pop out sooner or later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming: Hey, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1314224120490389504/&#34;&gt;finished Super Mario Sunshine&lt;/a&gt;! I started Super Mario Galaxy right afterwards. It&amp;rsquo;s actually interesting playing through these 3d Mario games for the first time, since I can see how things evolve. Will hopefully have some good thoughts for the eventual review, probably after I also play Odyssey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still ongoing: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober2020&#34;&gt;the Inktober thing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still ongoing: The site rewrite project. It&amp;rsquo;s going reasonably well, and might be ready soonish (famous last words), so I started looking into the new server as well. I&amp;rsquo;ve also mentioned before that I&amp;rsquo;ve been planning to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/rip-webfaction/&#34;&gt;migrate to a new webhost because GoDaddy etc.&lt;/a&gt;, and I had been leaning towards getting a VPS on Linode so I tried to do that this week, but for some reason they kept rejecting my application, so I just went with DigitalOcean instead. They give free two months $100 credit, so I&amp;rsquo;m not paying for anything until December or such, so that&amp;rsquo;s nice. I spent a couple of hours wrangling with Nginx + uWSGI + my app on Ubuntu, with permission problems and everything. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll figure it out eventually!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some recent fun things on the internet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Toadsanime/status/1312880060899233797&#34;&gt;Twitter thread about free indie games&lt;/a&gt;. Not like I have time to play all of these, but I find it fun to browse these lists and fantasize about my lifelong dream of being an indie game developer that I still hope to eventually get back to someday (why not today)? Anyway, check them out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vulture.com/article/most-influential-best-scenes-animation-history.html&#34;&gt;100 Sequences that shaped animations&lt;/a&gt;. Some fun history of animation stuff to go through.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vBpxhfBlVLU&#34;&gt;Why do mirrors flip horizontally but not vertically?&lt;/a&gt;(Youtube video). I always have trouble explaining this, so this one was nice to watch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.playstation.com/2020/10/07/ps5-teardown-an-inside-look-at-our-most-transformative-console-yet/&#34;&gt;Sony released a PS5 teardown video&lt;/a&gt;. My biggest takeaway from this is that this console is HUGE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-10-04 Switching It Up
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-04/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/weeknotes-2020-10-04/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the news this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donald Trump, who for some reason is still the US president, has tested positive for Covid19, adding even more chaos and uncertainty to the US election season. The rest of the world has no choice but to pay attention, given how much US politics affects the rest of us&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Philippines is now #20 worldwide in total Covid cases, yay! Yay?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some drama about the PH congress leadership? IDK, whatever man.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Annoyingly, I&amp;rsquo;ve not been doing any blog posts other than these weeknotes during the past few weeks. It is what it is though. I guess I haven&amp;rsquo;t really had time for longer writing things lately?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; busy, but the I have felt busy during the past week. Part of it is probably becaause I&amp;rsquo;ve started &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober2020&#34;&gt;doing the Inktober thing&lt;/a&gt;, so that&amp;rsquo;s an additional daily task. Another part of it is probably the fact that I purchased a Nintendo Switch last week!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, gaming then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the aforementioned Nintendo Switch. I got Super Mario 3D All Stars and Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening together with the purchase. I originally wanted to get Mario Odyssey, Fire Emblem and Paper Mario as well, but I figured two games (really four) was plenty for a first set, and my brother was going to lend me Odyssey anyway. I started playing &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/1310497720117784577/&#34;&gt;Mario 64&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not too far in, but I found the camera really problematic, and I can&amp;rsquo;t play it for too long without getting dizzy. I also started playing Super Mario Sunshine, which was a noticeable improvement camera-wise, and I can play it for extended periods without dizziness problems, so I&amp;rsquo;m quite a bit farther along there. I hope to get back to Mario 64 eventually, but it&amp;rsquo;s no big loss if I don&amp;rsquo;t. I understand it&amp;rsquo;s a classic game a lot of people look back fondly on, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s aged well, and not just because of camera problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also tried the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1311655542008377346/&#34;&gt;free Super Mario 35 battle royale game&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s reasonably fun, although when you&amp;rsquo;re at the last 2-3 players, it takes a while to get to a winner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally managed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1311602939891535872/&#34;&gt;hit the 7 wins in Zendikar Rising draft&lt;/a&gt;! Standard is still terrible though. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll just play 1 draft a week and that&amp;rsquo;s it? The MTG community was also in an uproar the past few weeks, both due to the poor state of standard and due to some controversy over an upcoming Secret Lair crossover with The Walking Dead. WOTC has implied they are looking at expanding Magic mechanics to other IPs, so the TWD thing is mostly a trial balloon, I think. Many people are upset and are predicting the death of Magic, but the game has been pronounced dead before. We&amp;rsquo;ll see what happens. I&amp;rsquo;m not personally affected (since I don&amp;rsquo;t Commander), my primary concern is the health of Standard formats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday gaming group picked up a new multiplayer game, it&amp;rsquo;s Root, from Leder Games (and published for digital by Dire Wolf, creators of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal-or-eternal-primer-for-mtg-players/&#34;&gt;Eternal&lt;/a&gt;). It&amp;rsquo;s reasonably complicated, and thematically and mechanically quite different from the last digital boardgame we were doing (Blood Rage).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned last week that I was planning to participate in &lt;a href=&#34;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/&#34;&gt;Hacktoberfest&lt;/a&gt;. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet, and there was some controversy over the past few weeks, with OSS maintainers complaining about spam PRs due to the event. Apparently, it was the fault of a Youtube who had a few hundred thousand followers. He had made a video showing how easy it was to make PRs and win the event swag, and a lot of people were following his low effort examples. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll still participate, though I have been looking around a few repos here and there, we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched anything of note the past week. A couple of standup specials on Netflix, that&amp;rsquo;s it. I guess the Switch took most of my entertainment time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IFTTT, a service I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/ifttt/&#34;&gt;been using for a while now&lt;/a&gt;, has &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1312652625511280640/&#34;&gt;obnoxiously been insisting I upgrade to their Pro tier&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;rsquo;re going to start severely restricting free accounts, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking to minimize my usage of the service moving forward. All of the social media syndication stuff can be handled by the new blog backend I&amp;rsquo;m writing, so that&amp;rsquo;s fine. The only things that should remain are stuff I haven&amp;rsquo;t looked into automating myself yet, mainly backing up of SMS, so I&amp;rsquo;ll probably look into that soonish. I&amp;rsquo;m not against paying for services, but in this case it&amp;rsquo;s simply not worth it for me, since I can trivially write my own replacement software for most of my usage of the service. So long IFTTT, it&amp;rsquo;s been swell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have no closing words of wisdom today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-09-27
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-27/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-27/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;October is imminent! There are two distractions I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to in the coming month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one is &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/inktober/&#34;&gt;Inktober&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing since 2016. Basically it&amp;rsquo;s just to do 30 ink drawings in October, one per day. There are some &lt;a href=&#34;https://inktober.com/rules&#34;&gt;official prompts&lt;/a&gt;, which I&amp;rsquo;ll probably follow. I haven&amp;rsquo;t really done any serious &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums/sketchbook&#34;&gt;sketching&lt;/a&gt; in a while, maybe this will help me get back into the groove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second one is &lt;a href=&#34;https://hacktoberfest.digitalocean.com/&#34;&gt;Hacktoberfest&lt;/a&gt;! Basically it&amp;rsquo;s an event where you have to submitted some number of GitHub PRs in October, and there&amp;rsquo;s some swag for people who finished. I last &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/hacktoberfest/&#34;&gt;participated in 2018&lt;/a&gt;, skipped last year because I was a bit busy. I have a bit more free time this year, so hopefully I can get into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both of these are welcome distractions, as the world continues to suck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past week, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on the Django-based rewrite for my personal site (this one!). It&amp;rsquo;s one of those projects where I find myself being productive not because of deadlines or anything like that, but because I genuinely enjoy working on it. When I find myself thinking of of new things that need to be done, or a new feature, or a way to solve an interesting problem, I am cursed (blessed?) with restlessness until I get it done. There are a number of challenges with the way I chose to approach this problem, most probably the subject of a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned this before, but I went ahead and paid for a year of the Micro plan on Migadu.com. The email in/out limits aren&amp;rsquo;t that high, but the price is decent, and I don&amp;rsquo;t really use my personal email that much anyway (I&amp;rsquo;m no spammer!). I&amp;rsquo;ll re-evaluate next year whether I want to migrate. (Sets a calendar event.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve watched this past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I went ahead and watched the second season of Umbrella Academy. It&amp;rsquo;s more or less structured like the first season: each member has their own problems; five discovers an upcoming apocalypse, so he tries to bring everyone together; also, there&amp;rsquo;s people who want to kill them. The ending of this is more satisfying than S1 though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enola Holmes on Netflix. It was ok, but it&amp;rsquo;s more of a young adult story, maybe a bit above the Nancy Drew/Hardy Boys level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming this past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;managed to get in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgznr/&#34;&gt;couple more Zendikar Rising drafts&lt;/a&gt;. Fun format, but I continue to have a terrible record, with only one draft actually going well. I did get a refund for that last one, so let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can&amp;rsquo;t do better this coming week!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;additional drop on the Civ6 New Frontier pass came out, giving us Gaul and Byzantium. A friend and I tried it in a multiplayer game. I played Byz and he went with Gaul; we only played for a couple of hours, but both new civs seem quite powerful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my SC2 group managed to finish the Wings of Liberty coop campaign! Pretty fun, and it was fun to relive the story too, as I had already forgotten a lot of it. We started the Heart of the Swarm version the next day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saturday gaming group have been playing Blood Rage over the past few months, and it even came out with a new DLC/expansion a couple of weeks ago. The game client is a bit buggy, but we tolerate it because it&amp;rsquo;s a fun/deep game anyway. We&amp;rsquo;re looking at maybe trying out a different game next week though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trivia was meh this week, the topics weren&amp;rsquo;t really to our liking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I purchased last month&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.humblebundle.com/subscription&#34;&gt;Humble Choice&lt;/a&gt; (or rather, let it lapse into purchase). It&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable, there&amp;rsquo;s some games there I can try like Forager and Evoland, and given my recent streak of Mario playing, I was wanting a platformer for the PC, so Yooka Layle isn&amp;rsquo;t a bad idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Late-breaking Sunday news: I have kind of impulse bought a Nintendo Switch. Well, I was agonizing over it for a while, but stores were selling it just a bit overpriced. Today I found that there was a slight price drop (around $40 worth) of the Labo bundle at one of my local stores, so I impulsively went ahead and ordered it. Maybe should have waited a day or so? regardless, it&amp;rsquo;s on the way, along with Zelda: Link&amp;rsquo;s Awakening and Super Mario 3D All Stars. No interest in the Labo personally, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll try to sell it off?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried using Messenger Rooms for a family conf call today, in lieu of Zoom which limits us to 40-minute calls. Might have been bad luck or poor internet, but the experience was substantially worse. Disconnections, lag, poor video quality, etc. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if they want to switch back to Zoom next time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems weird that we are so close to the end of 2020 now. Still no idea what Christmas is going to look like. I&amp;rsquo;m sure many other people are also looking forward to closing out 2020 and going to 2021, even though that holds no logical promise of things being better than they are now. But we can always dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-09-20
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-20/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-20/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to imagine this is already the 3rd week of September, it feels like the month is passing by quickly, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t been particularly busy recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did do some paid work this past week; not a lot, just filling in to provide some emergency support/consultation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess the reason it feels like the week passed by quickly is that I started a new side project (like many programmers, I am afflicted by the curse of wanting to start too many side projects). This one will probably get finished: I&amp;rsquo;m writing a Django based server for this website. I am generally happy with the current Hugo workflow I use for publishing things here, but the build times have struggled with the sheer number of posts I have. This started back when I decided to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/archive-of-my-own/&#34;&gt;start importing my social media activity to this site&lt;/a&gt;, which increased the post count from a couple of thousand to more than twenty thousand now. Even the automated builds take forever, and I can&amp;rsquo;t even run the local Hugo build on my laptop due to too many open files error on Mac. And Hugo is already one of the faster static site generators, so I have doubt that other SSGs would be able to solve this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I briefly considered moving back to Wordpress, but that seems like a step back. I also briefly considered writing a new backend using a new programming language like Rust, giving me an opportunity to learn something new as well. But I kind of needed to get this done quickly, given that I have a pending server migration within the next couple of months; it&amp;rsquo;s not necessary, but it would be nice to have the new system up in place by the time I do that, so that all the migration happens in one go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still generally happy with the workflow of writing using my local editor and pushing markdown files to git, so I plan to retain that. The Django webapp will have a database, but that will be a secondary data structure used mainly for indexing and searches. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be some kind of weird file system/database storage, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes. Anyway, probably more details on all that when I am ready to deploy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching this past week: I finished both seasons of Cobra Kai. The series is decent. I&amp;rsquo;m here mostly for the Karate Kid nostalgia and the Lawrence/LaRusso rivalry. Season two had a lot of high school drama, which I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too interested in, so I liked the first season a lot more. Will still probably watch S3 when it comes out on Netflix. Now to figure out what to watch next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming this past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zendikar Rising is out on Magic Arena! I&amp;rsquo;ve already played a couple of drafts, but things didn&amp;rsquo;t go as well as I hoped, so now I am poor, will probably be able to draft again in a couple of days. Hopefully I get better at this format, as I&amp;rsquo;ve been planning to draft this set a lot; posts on these should be under &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgznr/&#34;&gt;the mtgznr tag&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t play much else this week other than the regular multiplayer games with the gaming groups SC2, Blood Rage, etc. I have yet to find a new game to knock off the backlog. I have also been considering trying out some of the smaller indie games in my collection, and maybe streaming some let&amp;rsquo;s play/reviews for them, as a bit of support for indie game devs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;this week was the much awaited PS5 announcement, with pricing and release dates and everything! The $499 price tag is reasonable, but I probably won&amp;rsquo;t be getting one on launch, since there&amp;rsquo;s not a lot of games I want immediately. I will admit to getting a bit excited at the FF16 reveal, but that&amp;rsquo;s probably a ways off. I&amp;rsquo;m probably more likely to get a Switch first.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trivia team put up a new chaotic video of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U52L9c2kB8M&#34;&gt;us playing some trivia&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out, like, subscribe, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big news from the other side of the pacific is that US SC Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg has died. &amp;ldquo;No no no&amp;rdquo; was trending on Twitter for a little bit, and a lot of people on my timeline were swearing. I had a short discussion with some friends living on the west coast about it. Many of my US friends also have some level of anxiety/worry about what&amp;rsquo;s going to happen during/after their elections. It&amp;rsquo;s actually annoying how informed I am about US politics, although it doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect me directly. Like it or not though, the US further sliding into single-party autocracy will likely be bad for the rest of the world, so let&amp;rsquo;s all hope they get their shit together.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-09-13
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-13/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-13/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It has certainly been a week, yes it has. The world continues to turn (and burn even).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy. Not so much with work, though there was a bit of that due to a required emergency software change (aren&amp;rsquo;t they always emergencies?). I wasn&amp;rsquo;t doing the emergency work myself, more like consulting and advising how to approach it, so not much to tell there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did quite a bit of work on my personal data processes/backups/workflows. It involved streamlining my backups, dedepulication, going through old records and cleaning them up, and so on. Some combination of Python scripts and manual work was required. One specific thing I did was to get a whole bunch of my old photos out of Google Photos and onto disk backups, and also had to do some deduplication there. I was able to remove around 1300 duplicates from over 12000 photos, so around 10% ish duplication rate, not too bad. My original intent was to remove them from Google Photos, dedupe, then add them back, but now I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure I need to add them back. The main advantage of Google Photos has been that they make the photos more searchable, but I don&amp;rsquo;t seem to have an urgent need for that anyway, and probably there are other ways to do that? I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll look into it when the time comes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also been browsing some old (physical) albums stored around the house. There&amp;rsquo;s another few thousand photos there, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking of eventually digitizing them, as a means of backup, but that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of work, so maybe in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming was good again this week. I finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/&#34;&gt;Uncharted 4&lt;/a&gt;! I guess any week where I manage to tick something off the backlog is a good week. Last weekend I mentioned I was near the end, that was so untrue lol. Turned out more than half the game was still to come. My SC2 buddies and I started to play this 3-player coop version of the Wings of Liberty campaign (avaiable as custom arcade things), that&amp;rsquo;s been fun. Then the usual stuff: Blood Rage with the Saturday group. Quiz nights/codenames with the trivia team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kind of want to get into SFV again, presumably there&amp;rsquo;s a flood of new players coming in recently since it was free on PS+ this past month, so hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t be so hard to find matches this time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My desire for a Nintendo Switch is being tempered by two things at the moment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rumors of a new, upgraded Switch coming out next year. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the first time that I&amp;rsquo;ve purchased a console just before it&amp;rsquo;s successor came out though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;frustration at the difficulty of the special stages in Super Mario 3D Land lol. It&amp;rsquo;s a stark reminder that I&amp;rsquo;m getting old and I&amp;rsquo;m not as good at these games as I used to be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this week, I binged four seasons of Superstore. It&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable enough ensemble comedy, though it&amp;rsquo;s no Brooklyn Nine Nine. A lot of the characters&amp;rsquo; problems are of their own making due to selfishness, that&amp;rsquo;s always annoying. But it&amp;rsquo;s good enough for side-watching while I&amp;rsquo;m doing other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also started watching Cobra Kai, not even halfway through the first season yet. It&amp;rsquo;s slightly painful, since it casts Johnny Lawrence as the POV character/protagonist, and he&amp;rsquo;s kind of a loser asshole, but we&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My desktop PC seems to be showing it&amp;rsquo;s age. It&amp;rsquo;s like recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been hitting 100% CPU and/or RAM much more often. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried uninstalling some unneeded software, hopefully that helps. I got this PC back in 2015, so it&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable that I might need an upgrade soon, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I want to spend that money yet. I&amp;rsquo;m kind of hoping it can still hold on for a few years still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same thoughts for the rest of the world, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Late Game Review: Uncharted 4: A Thief&#39;s End
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 09:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I finished Uncharted 4: A Thief&amp;rsquo;s End yesterday, and I felt like making a post about it, since I had a bunch of screenshots. Late game review because the game came out in 2016. I think I got it from PS+? Certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first played the original Uncharted trilogy back in 2010-2011, but I found out just now while writing this post that I never finished Uncharted 3 (started yes, apparently), so that explains why some story elements seemed unfamiliar in the 4th game. (I think I may have also gotten the trilogy remaster via PS+, so maybe I should play the 3rd game too? Maybe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually have to thank the Uncharted series for getting my into this kind of single player adventure game in the first place. After Uncharted, I played some kinda similar games like Infamous, Tomb Raider etc, I was never that into the genre before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main complaint with the series is the sheer suspension of disbelief it requires to imagine a person like Nathan Drake could exist: basically a human at peak physical ability, able to fearlessly leap off high cliffs and cling onto walls with unbelievable grip and upper body strength, barely ever getting tired, while at the same time good enough at gunplay to go up against armies of battle-hardened mercenaries and come out on top. Oh, and he has an intimate knowledge of archaeology and is also able to find ancient lost treasures and cities all the time apparently. And also he&amp;rsquo;s pretty good at sketching. It&amp;rsquo;s fine, after all what are video games but power fantasies right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncharted 4 gives us a deeper look at Nathan Drake&amp;rsquo;s background and how he grew up to be like this, and we find out that not only is he this human at the peak of physical ability, he also has a brother who, despite 15 years rotting away in some backwater prison, is also at peak physical ability and also has all the rest of Nathan&amp;rsquo;s abilities (except the sketching though). (Cue Star Wars prequel meme &amp;ldquo;This is getting out of hand, now there are two of them!&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from that minor complaint, the games are pretty great though. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, the games are highly linear and story-driven, consisting of set pieces and sequences that are either platforming/exploratory (figure out how to get from point A to point B) or combat/stealth vs the aforementioned armies of battle-hardened mercenaries. Oh, and there&amp;rsquo;s the occasional puzzle too. Uncharted 4 adds some new elements such as letting you drive a car (4 wheel drive) around in what seems like an open world (it really isn&amp;rsquo;t), but it&amp;rsquo;s still mostly the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a big action game player, so I dislike the combat parts and I die a lot there. You can see in one of the screenshots later that my shooting accuracy rate was like 49%. For this reason, I&amp;rsquo;m not inclined to go for achievement completion on this one (or any of the Uncharted games for that matter), since there are many combat-related and difficulty-related trophies, and even one that requires me to finish the game with like a 70% accuracy rate. Good luck with that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dying a lot isn&amp;rsquo;t a problem, as the game is very forgiving. There are a generous number of checkpoints, and there&amp;rsquo;s really no penalty for dying too much. (Again, you can see in the stats screenshot that I failed checkpoints 105 times.) It&amp;rsquo;s kind of unavoidable with on-rails games like these - there are plenty of spots where if you don&amp;rsquo;t climb or run or jump in just the exact way the game wants, you&amp;rsquo;ll die and fail the checkpoint. It&amp;rsquo;s not super frustrating since you never really have to repeat too much, but it&amp;rsquo;s that kind of game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I guess Nathan Drake is famous now, because people know about his discoveries from the first 3 games, but I feel like he should be richer than he is portrayed. Not that he&amp;rsquo;s poor, but surely he got away with a few valuable trinkets here and there during his adventures right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Story-wise it feels like they planned this to be Nathan Drake&amp;rsquo;s final run, given the epilogue, but who knows? I mean in their universe, Sully is pretty old but he still also does ridiculous stunts with the rest of the gang. And they did introduce some new characters, so it&amp;rsquo;s not far-fetched there&amp;rsquo;ll be another Uncharted game later on, possibly with someone else as the lead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, game is pretty good, play it if you can, happy to have ticked it off the backlog! Have some screenshots:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200819161627_hue6c3d46fad30247253f2f08750550326_281237_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200819164051_hu46b1ea91c7bf31829b8523e65817aed1_284669_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200819171018_hu3cbaffc4a9258d8ccdc9fe76ff5ef790_353542_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200820145613_hu403aa6f2b7883be608292b34d31f0541_228256_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200820161032_hue6f0fc6e9cab95271fa5e49312e151f2_213537_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200821005232_hu77a464efa196223d535d5d166edbd702_249841_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824132714_hu393eb55f5daa77aa9578e357f0d401ab_256211_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824134711_hu60f27add9b976eaa32a0786b0fafffc3_359095_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824141635_hud98938188e653e52bd358edaf3726a73_235308_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824141841_hucb6379a5c5ac429b1d02a79d5e9bb792_219355_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824150416_hud82d76a20e0c21ff6f033155e898b0db_286617_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824153812_hu5c87c70b5272ab6a51e76853fd77ce96_516803_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200902155328_huc18a971ba541a72d57dc6c5d98f39d47_471881_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200902160409_hu9a09840b91ff174991e32f7dea81452a_328014_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200903175039_hu3c2c7a92b0c11ba087adae7a561ba05a_189250_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200904175427_hucb32ea5bdc2fb02d76116f411fec83b6_250565_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200907153040_hu32ec07853396cc30d7bf98038969beb3_483247_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200907154245_hu6d68b18cefb9e51e808b08e5061bdd28_382391_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200907160038_hu4b332f6f1c50aa46c7ba742bd2bd28af_353812_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200908161345_hu5166799124c3a256c98bdb0c7f9f6e6e_269790_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200908163738_hu06619873d0347acf0d171102042ab812_261645_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150307_hufe632e9a13baf3e08bccb13204b3cdd9_47663_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150314_hu1ba1ae46a319d73a2e0edad4107da04e_244973_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150318_hubbb4574ac2bcf446e9289a64bdadae3a_308505_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150405_hu9ff76feff73fe703f85ed92600715c00_113648_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150418_hu05256f8c3514656b4b5432360c346062_112211_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150432_hua574e1f093b45b31822fd1746cdf0fbb_113862_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150504_hu10f0f7c57b129ddae527f21ecafb9522_115195_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-09-06
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-06/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-2020-09-06/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s September! The last six months were a blur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s considered &amp;ldquo;Christmas season&amp;rdquo; over here already I guess. The local memes are that once the clock hits midnight between Aug 31 and Sep 1, your neighbor&amp;rsquo;s Christmas lights are magically up. Also of course the famous Jose Mari Chan gets famous starting September, since malls and stores love to play his Christmas songs during this time. IDK what to expect for Christmas season this year though, since we are still in a pandemic. I keep telling my mom not to get her hopes up that we (i.e. my brothers and their families) will all be able to get together as tradition dictates. It&amp;rsquo;s possible, but I&amp;rsquo;m not optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My week was kinda busy. Not really in terms of work, but in terms of&amp;hellip; high school stuff, I guess? My high school batch hosted our 25th year alumni homecoming this past weekend. Since we were unlucky enough to have it in the middle of the pandemic, it was an online-only affair, with presentations and raffles and whatnot. And a quiz night! A lot of my batchmates did a lot more work, my participation was mostly limited to some tech stuff, since I had access to the database of registrants for the raffle, and also representing the batch at the Pisay Quiz Night held online. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only PQN team member, I was just the one assigned to join the zoom and show the whiteboard; I was drafted against my will due to my past quiz night experience. My other batchmates were supporting me from a Discord, I basically streamed the Zoom call to them via Discord (which is really troublesome, always has tech issues) and they fed me possible answers etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually wasn&amp;rsquo;t expecting my PQN participation to take too much time, but there was like a tech rehearsal and a dry run before the event proper, to make sure everything worked well and that all the team got it, plus my team also got together a couple of times for &amp;ldquo;practice.&amp;rdquo; I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want to take it seriously, as with all online quiz nights I&amp;rsquo;m mostly there for the fun since it&amp;rsquo;s super likely for at least some people on some teams to be googling their answers lol. The PQN is super competitive though, I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s to be expected given the nature of Pisay. We didn&amp;rsquo;t win, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen the final scores yet, but I guess that we finished around middle of the pack among the 22 teams, but we had a good time (more or less!) and it was fun hanging out with the batchmates virtually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming this week was pretty good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/1301222471568297984/&#34;&gt;and finished Disco Elysium&lt;/a&gt; during the first half of the week. Fantastic game, and I was probably unhealthily engrossed in it for like 2-3 days. I was so into the whole mystery thing, when the game warned me that I was at a critical point and that proceeding further would end other sidequests, I just created a save and pushed to the finish anyway. I went back later to load and finish the other side stuff. It&amp;rsquo;s the kind of game you&amp;rsquo;d enjoy if you like getting your Speech skill to 100 in Fallout. It&amp;rsquo;s very well-written and had some really great/shocking moments. Since it has very little actual &amp;ldquo;action&amp;rdquo; aside from delving inside the MC&amp;rsquo;s thoughts, I understand that it&amp;rsquo;s not for everybody, but it&amp;rsquo;s certainly a worthwhile experience. I thought about writing a full review post, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for when/if I manage full achievement completion (looks tough!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;after getting distracted by Disco Elysium, I went ahead and resumed my Uncharted 4 game. I think I&amp;rsquo;m close to the end on this one, should finish it this coming week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;already half way through the Super Mario 3D Land special worlds. Speaking of Mario, Nintendo announced a bunch of new Mario releases for the Switch this past week, which significantly increases my want for a Switch. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how long I can hold off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;still playing my regular games with the playgroups: Starcraft 2 Coop, Blood Rage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it&amp;rsquo;s September, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing my regularly quarterly data backups/exports. One of them is Google Takeout. The last one was back in April, and that last export was 27 chunks (they split it into 2GB or less chunks). The new one is 44 chunks! I suspect the huge increase is because I&amp;rsquo;ve been streaming on Twitch and exporting them to Youtube, so they&amp;rsquo;re probably part of this current export. I didn&amp;rsquo;t even export everything this time, since I don&amp;rsquo;t need to re-export data from those services I&amp;rsquo;m no longer using. One of my ongoing projects is reducing my Google footprint, so I need to figure out how to get the size of this export down.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>On Mobile App Development
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/mobile-app-dev/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/mobile-app-dev/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This post is just quite a few thoughts on mobile apps and mobile app development, all mishmashed together. I don&amp;rsquo;t claim to be a mobile app specialist, at best I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;em&gt;dabbled&lt;/em&gt; in them, but enough to form some opinions I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-bit-of-history&#34;&gt;A Bit of History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first exposure to mobile app development when I got pulled to help my then-company&amp;rsquo;s then-fledgling mobile team with cleaning up the codebase for their iOS app. This was back in maybe 2011? It was one of those projects where some devs built a quick proof-of-concept demo using new technology, then management liked it and asked for new features and they kept adding new features haphazardly until there was just this huge unmaintainable mess of code. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a knock against Objective-C or iOS development specifically or the dev team; the fact is they were new to the stack and were learning as they went while still trying to meet deadlines. I also spent some time reviewing the corresponding Android team&amp;rsquo;s code as well. This was the bulk of my exposure to native mobile dev on iOS/Android. (This was before Swift, so I never got to experience that. Language looks neat though.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from a web dev background, I&amp;rsquo;ve always found the fragmentation of platforms annoying. Basically your effort gets multiplied by the number of platforms you have to support, and what would work well on iOS may not work well on Android and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on, this concern was alleviated a bit with the rise of common frameworks that could publish to both iOS and Android. The first one I tried of these was React Native. I tried it for a small mobile project I did around 3-ish years ago. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t tremendously happy with the experience. My mistake was probably diving head-first into React Native, when this was my first experience with React and front-end frameworks in general (something new to someone with &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/old-web/&#34;&gt;my jQuery background&lt;/a&gt;!), so a lot of concepts were new to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make matters worse, the React Native docs at that time seemed to assume some familiarity already with React, or at least similar frameworks like Angular. I had a bit of confusion with whether I should be using Expo or not, and how to eject, and it resulted in having to restart the project a couple of times. It was also my first encounter with NPM&amp;rsquo;s dependency management, and that annoyed me a lot. A lot of the third-party dependencies I used back then were still immature too, so I often had problems with things like accessing the camera roll and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, it was experience, and the ability to publish cross-platform to iOS and Android was invaluable. I went on to use React Native as my go-to mobile framework I would recommend for other projects afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I had to do a UI revamp for that small mobile app I wrote three years ago, and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t touched it for a while so I had some trouble with NPM trying to get it to run. In frustration, I gave up on it and decided to rewrite it in Flutter, of which I&amp;rsquo;ve heard good things. Flutter turned out to be great, and it took me just a little over two weeks, part-time to rewrite the app, probably slightly less effort than it took me to write it in the first place. I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough experience yet to have a detailed review of Flutter, but I was generally much happier with the experience compared to React. Part of that may be I&amp;rsquo;m much more familiar with the mobile landscape now and have a better idea of what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, but I really did encounter much fewer points of friction and Flutter seems to have much better documentation. I believe it will be my first choice of frameworks moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;not-everything-needs-to-be-a-native-app&#34;&gt;Not Everything Needs to Be a Native App&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things that annoys me about mobile apps is that people/companies unnecessarily want things to be native mobile apps when they would work perfectly fine as web apps. I can understand applications such as Uber may need numerous native functionality (GPS, timely notifications, offline functionality), so that&amp;rsquo;s fine (although many of those things are available using modern browser APIs as well!). Things like online newspapers, forums like Reddit, and so on, are perfectly fine as normal web apps, and should stop prompting me to install their native apps when they detect I am on mobile. Granted that you may get a much better UX experience with a native app, but you also have to install it locally and grant it more access than what the browser&amp;rsquo;s sandbox provides, and that feels like a tradeoff decision that the user needs to make, and not something to nag the user about constantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess part of it is that I grew up with the open web and have a significant bias towards it. In general, if I can just access an app via web, I will prefer that, unless the native app experience is vastly superior or otherwise necessary. And this focus on native apps can be bad for the web. This is apparent in apps like Instagram, which don&amp;rsquo;t allow you to use their primary function - uploading images - on a desktop browser. I also had a similar discussion with a freelance client a few years ago, when they wanted to make a mobile app, but not a corresponding web platform, when all of the app&amp;rsquo;s functionality was simple stuff that web could do easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;different-platforms&#34;&gt;Different Platforms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The differences in iOS and Android are particularly annoying to me as a developer, especially since I&amp;rsquo;m used to web development. With web, everything is open and standards-based, so you generally write everything using a single stack, and any reasonably standards-compliant web browser will work with the web app in a reasonably consistent way. (Granted, there will be browser-specific issues, but nowadays those aren&amp;rsquo;t too common.) With iOS and Android, you have to test on both platforms extensively, and the build processes and distribution methods are different for each. Frameworks like React Native and Flutter lighten this load considerably, but you still really have to devote more time and resources to testing on the different platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;backward-compatibility&#34;&gt;Backward Compatibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, this one may be an unfounded concern of mine since I don&amp;rsquo;t have much experience in the matter, but I have this worry that native mobile apps tend to &lt;em&gt;rot&lt;/em&gt; more easily, and by &lt;em&gt;rot&lt;/em&gt; I mean, get worse with time, as the mobile OSes upgrade themselves very rapidly. Unlike, say, Windows, which gets a new major version every few years, iOS and Android are constantly getting new versions and more importantly, deprecating APIs and adding new ones! Hence my worry that unmaintained, a perfectly functional app may become unworkable a few years down the line and no longer work on the latest mobile OSes. It&amp;rsquo;s my totally unfounded belief that this is a significant reason why &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/itunes-purchases/&#34;&gt;more than 50% of my lifetime App Store purchases are no longer listed on the App Store&lt;/a&gt;. (And also why I&amp;rsquo;ve pretty much disavowed making mobile purchases again.) Say what you will about Windows, but at least they have a pretty good record of backward compatibility when software I&amp;rsquo;ve written for Windows in the early 2000s is still very likely to run on Windows today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;closed-platforms&#34;&gt;Closed Platforms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another issue I have with native apps is that I have been used to working on open platforms. Windows, for all its faults, is still an open platform, and anyone can write software for it and distribute it using whatever method they desire. And the web is even more open and standards-based (for now at least). For mobile, Android is mostly open, but iOS is mostly a closed platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s tight control over the iOS platform has been in the tech news recently. First was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2020/6/18/21296180/apple-hey-email-app-basecamp-rejection-response-controversy-antitrust-regulation&#34;&gt;the kerfuffle with hey.com&lt;/a&gt; a few months ago, and more recently, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.macrumors.com/guide/epic-games-vs-apple/&#34;&gt;their removal of Fortnite and battle with Epic&lt;/a&gt; due to Epic&amp;rsquo;s objection to Apple taking a cut of all purchases on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a mobile developer, the most annoying things about Apple&amp;rsquo;s tight control over iOS apps are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;that $100 annual fee for an Apple Developer account. If you&amp;rsquo;re a 1st world developer, that cost isn&amp;rsquo;t much, but if you&amp;rsquo;re a young hobbyist developer in a poorer country who just wants to try making an app, it can be a significant hurdle. Google also charges you some token amount for Play Store access, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s just a one-time fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the fact that you need to use a Mac to publish apps to the App Store. This is another significant hurdle for hobbyist developers; Macs are typically very expensive computers. Granted Android development requires a beefy setup too, but at least you get a choice of platform for Android development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App store review can be unpredictable; sometimes things that were perfectly fine during a previous release are now flagged in the next review. It feels like you need to get lucky with the reviewer you get. And if the reviewer is unfair to your app, you may be out of luck unless you&amp;rsquo;re a big company like Epic or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitaltrends.com/news/wordpress-developers-says-apple-wants-30-percent-of-its-profits-from-app-store/&#34;&gt;Wordpress that can raise a stink about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the issues that could be levied against Apple for their monopoly over the App Store could be largely addressed if the platform allowed users to install apps via alternative methods, the same way Android does. I fully understand that Apple&amp;rsquo;s tight controls enable a safer environment for naive end users (presumably, assuming they don&amp;rsquo;t screw up), and I actually approve some of their controls like their iOS14 plans to restrict targetted advertising. But more advanced users should be given the option to use alternative methods if they so choose. They can still flag apps installed via alternative methods as &amp;ldquo;potentially unsafe&amp;rdquo; and add hurdles to prevent less capable users from being easily tricked by malicious actors, (Android does this, I believe).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-conclusion&#34;&gt;In conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really have a point here. Maybe I just want everything to be open? I like open platforms lol.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-08-30
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-30/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-30/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This last week was weird. I feel like I didn&amp;rsquo;t really get much done in terms of productivity, yet I don&amp;rsquo;t feel I was unproductive. A very relaxed and chill week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again a tiny bit of work done this past week, some fixes, including to side projects. I also spent some time preparing for some events next weekend. Although I wasn&amp;rsquo;t productive this week, I did outline a bit of a roadmap of new features for one of my side projects, hopefully I can get into that in the coming weeks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still in a pandemic! But I did have my first dine-in meal at a restaurant last Monday. It was because I went to get blood drawn for routine medical reasons, and I had needed to skip breakfast for the test (spoiler: my blood sugar levels were very, very normal). So after getting the blood drawn I was super hungry and decided to have breakfast at the nearby Pancake House. I was the only customer since it was super early (and you know, pandemic), although a second guy came in after I had given my order. I almost subconsciously picked up the glass of water to sip from it as soon as it was served, luckily I remembered I was wearing a face mask and a face shield. I decided to hold off on removing the gear until the actual pancakes were served, to minimize the exposure time. The next day I also decided to have a snack at a Starbucks after running some errands, mainly because I had a free coffee from Globe Rewards. It was afternoon so there were a few other customers there. The cashier said it was ok to dine in, but for a maximum of one hour only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a longish post I was writing, but it felt too raw to publish and might break it up into smaller posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We actually managed to win an online quiz night this week! It&amp;rsquo;s been a while, good job trivia team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels great to no longer be following the covid19 stats regularly, even though they are still fairly terrible. UP experts are projecting that we get the reproduction rate to below 1 in like a month though, so that&amp;rsquo;s some good news, though we may still be a ways away from getting this under control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching and playing the past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still playing a lot of SC2 Coop, trying to unlock the new prestiges. Levelling the commanders again can be a pain, but at least they managed to provide new goals/objectives for the players, breathing back a bunch of life into this game mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still drafting Amonkhet Remastered, although the last few drafts haven&amp;rsquo;t gone well. Need to save up gems, so I&amp;rsquo;ll do one last one draft once I get enough gold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Huh, I guess I kind of paused Uncharted 4 for most of the week, not sure why. I should get back to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started re-playing Super Mario 3D Land (on the 3DS) lately, mostly to stave off my desire to get a Nintendo Switch (prices are still inflated here due to supply issues!). I had forgotten a lot about this game, so even when I finished the first 8 worlds and rescued Princess Peach, I was pleasantly surprised to find there were another 8 &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; worlds to play!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watched the video game history documentary &lt;strong&gt;High Score&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. Pretty good, although there&amp;rsquo;s some Dragon Quest erasure going on in the RPG episode!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watched &lt;strong&gt;Bill and Ted Face the Music&lt;/strong&gt;, this was a most excellent sequel. I found the start a bit clunky (I always find it awkward watching characters be awkward), but the rest of it was a fun and sweet adventure that echoed elements of both of the first two movies. A lot of the time travel stuff didn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense if you sat down and thought about it, but I was smiling through a lot of it. Little Billie and Theda are great!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also watched &lt;strong&gt;Superman: Man of Tomorrow&lt;/strong&gt;, the first entry in the new DC animated universe (following the reboot at the end of Justice League Dark: Apokolips). Yet another Superman origin story here. Not too happy with this one. Not fond of the animated style, and the writing and plot seemed weird at many points. I felt like there could have been a better way to resolve the whole situation with the big bad that felt more &amp;ldquo;Superman&amp;rdquo;-like, and the movie doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to earn the monicker &amp;ldquo;Man of Tomorrow&amp;rdquo; for the hero.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for one reason or another, I also ended up watching a few standup specials on Amazon Prime. A couple from Craig Ferguson, and one from Jimmy Yang.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cobra Kai is now on Netflix! Yet another thing to add to the ever-increasing backlog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tech stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have about three months left on my Webfaction hosting, which I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/rip-webfaction/&#34;&gt;been planning to migrate away from&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m currently leaning towards getting a cheap $5/mo VPS from Linode, although I&amp;rsquo;m still willing to accept any recommendations. Switching to a VPS means more effort (since it won&amp;rsquo;t be a managed service anymore), but that should provide some learning opportunities. It&amp;rsquo;s just as well anyway, my apps have been pushing the memory limits on the current hosting, and even the cheapest Linode VPS provides more RAM.  I&amp;rsquo;ll probably start looking into the migration in September.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wrote before about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/gmail-migration/&#34;&gt;migrating away from GMail&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Migadu.com&amp;rsquo;s free tier for about half a year now. This past week, they wrote that they are sunsetting the free tier. Totally understandable, given the economy. They are also introducing a new Micro tier at $20 a year, with slightly better limits than the old free tier, so I may migrate to that near the end of September (when the free tier runs out). In theory, I could just try to run a mail server on whatever VPS I set up (see above bullet), but that&amp;rsquo;s a big hassle. This cost + the $5/mo for the VPS is still less than what I was paying for at Webfaction, so I don&amp;rsquo;t mind paying for this for a while.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was notified by a local bank that their old web platform is being sunsetted and I needed to migrate to the new system, so I did that. But whenever I tried the migration steps, the process never completed, it just kept telling me it was processing. I finally had to message someone I knew on the dev team lol. Hopefully it can getr resolved next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-08-23
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-23/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-23/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The week after I posted about phoning in the weeknotes, here I am with one where there&amp;rsquo;s nothing much to report. Not that surprising, given how busy I was over the previous few weeks, I took the opportunity to take a more relaxing week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a bit of work to be done, but very miniscule by comparison. Minor fixes here and there, including to some side projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did get to write on the blog more, as expected. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope I can keep it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These week&amp;rsquo;s quiz nights were terrible for our team, but on the bright side, I got to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/quiz-night-sketches/&#34;&gt;do a couple of sketches&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching and playing the past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued drafting Amonkhet Remastered, although the last few drafts went a bit poorly. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtgakr/&#34;&gt;mtgakr tag&lt;/a&gt; on this site has all the records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After finishing D:OS2 and FF7R, I looked around for a new game to start and decided on Uncharted 4, which I guess I got free from Plus or something. I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten very far yet, but unsurprisingly Nathan Drake&amp;rsquo;s antics still really challenge one&amp;rsquo;s suspension of disbelief. He has to be one of the most peak-performance athletes in the world to consistently pull of the jumping and wall climbing stunts he regularly does. Not to mention being able to win over basically hordes of heavily-armed mercenaries in gunfights. Not that it&amp;rsquo;s not fun and engaging as a game, it just feels so ridiculous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dcfandome.com&#34;&gt;DC Fandome&lt;/a&gt; was today, I watched some panels and new trailers and such. I enjoyed the Suicide Squad reveals and the Wonder Woman 1984, Shazam 2 and Justice League Snyder cut trailers, plus previews for the new Gotham Knights and Suicide Squad games, looking forward to those. (I should probably get around to Arkham Origins first.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuing to play SC2 coop and Blood Rage with the regular groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that there&amp;rsquo;s anything wrong with a bit of relaxing downtime, but I am hoping to eventually ramp up to being more productive in the coming weeks, especially with the side projects.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>On Podcasts, Audiobooks, and Newsletters
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/on-podcasts-audiobooks-and-newsletters/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/on-podcasts-audiobooks-and-newsletters/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Filed under &amp;ldquo;Things I Don&amp;rsquo;t Really Grok&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;podcasts-and-audiobooks&#34;&gt;Podcasts and audiobooks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These 2 are kind of in the same boat. Their main sin is that they are audio-only. When consuming content, my order of preference for formats is roughly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;text (+images I guess) (most preferred)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;video (with audio)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;audio only (least preferred)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think these preferences have to do with information density: I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I prefer text because text can convey the most amount of information in the least amount of bits. I&amp;rsquo;ll also watch informative videos, to a point. If it&amp;rsquo;s movie-length, it better be damn entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That leaves us with audio. I don&amp;rsquo;t see the appeal. I try podcasts, sometimes, when I&amp;rsquo;m out walking or such. Audiobooks, I&amp;rsquo;ve never tried. My main concern is the amount of attention you have to give the content. Because you only have the audio as a source of information, if you lose track of it, then why are you even bothering? And if I try to listen to an audiobook or podcast while doing something else that requires my attention, there&amp;rsquo;s a very low chance I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to absorb anything from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the few times I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to listen to podcasts while I&amp;rsquo;m out walking, I only dare to if I&amp;rsquo;m walking in this safe, short, and circular route inside our subdivision. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t dare do it in the streets outside where there&amp;rsquo;s real traffic. That seems like a recipe for being distracted while crossing the road, which CAN LEAD TO DEATH! Granted, the odds of such a disaster are fairly low, but why risk it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe if I still had a regular 2-hour commute (one way) to work, then audiobooks/podcasts would be more appealing while I sit in the back of an FX in Metro Manila traffic. But even then, I think I&amp;rsquo;d rather nap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I make an exception for listening to music of course. Listening to music doesn&amp;rsquo;t take much concentration, and can easily happen as a background task, so that&amp;rsquo;s fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I just haven&amp;rsquo;t found the right podcast to follow? IDK, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried a few. Never could keep it up as a habit. Also, can I subscribe to podcasts using RSS feeds? I think I can, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never tried it. Like, if I find a podcast on Spotify there doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be an RSS option?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;newsletters&#34;&gt;Newsletters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &amp;ldquo;Newsletters&amp;rdquo;, I don&amp;rsquo;t mean those popups that appear on news sites or commercial blogs asking you to subscribe to get updates or such. Those are just spammy marketing BS and I have no interest in such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &amp;ldquo;Newsletters&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m referring to a recent trend in the tech/online world of people moving their writing from websites/blogs to newsletters via platforms such as substack. These have some merit, as it basically involves the type of blog writing I like to consume, except in email newsletter form. There are some such newsletters whose posts I&amp;rsquo;ve read and I do find their content interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s the problem? The problem is I want to treat this type of content the same way I treat blog posts and newspaper editorials - as casual reading that I can pick up and read at my leisure. And (for me at least), casual reading doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong in my email inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an inbox zero policy, and to achieve that I&amp;rsquo;m very strict about what I let in my email inbox. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly limited to actual conversations with people and important notifications. The email inbox is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; where I&amp;rsquo;d like to consume casual reading that I can pick up whenever I&amp;rsquo;d like. Just the idea of leaving them there while having unread markers is annoying. In theory I could filter them to a subfolder and then the unread count would accumulate there, but I don&amp;rsquo;t like unread counts even in my email subfolders!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have nothing against the Substack business model (writers gotta earn a living I guess) and I&amp;rsquo;m sure a lot of people don&amp;rsquo;t mind consuming casual reading content via email, but Substack (and similar platforms) should provide alternate ways to consume their content, preferably RSS feeds. In the meantime I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a service called &lt;a href=&#34;https://kill-the-newsletter.com/&#34;&gt;Kill the Newsletter&lt;/a&gt; to subscribe to a few newsletters I like. It works well enough (though I checked just now and one of the feeds, on a nonsubstack platform, seems to have stopped last June. I just created a new inbox in KTN for it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(It would be even better if the content writers made their content available on their own websites, instead of centralized in a silo like Substack!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, are there any newsletters anyone can recommend that might be relevant to my interests?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>On Mozilla and Firefox
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/on-mozilla-and-firefox/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/on-mozilla-and-firefox/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Mozilla made the tech news recently for laying off a whole lot of people. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2020/08/11/changing-world-changing-mozilla/&#34;&gt;Official statement&lt;/a&gt;). People were alarmed and worried about the future of what is the last major independent browser and the open web, bit it looks like it isn&amp;rsquo;t that bleak. Most of the layoffs were to teams other than those working on Firefox, things like the experimental browser engine Servo, devtools, and MDN. The core Gecko team seems to be unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that these things aren&amp;rsquo;t important. MDN, if you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, is a set of documentation of web standards and browser support, &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/&#34;&gt;available online&lt;/a&gt;, that is one of the best resources for web developers working on cross-platform things. Mozilla no longer funding it&amp;rsquo;s maintenance is a big deal, it means it&amp;rsquo;s less likely to be kept up-to-date, even though community work can still continue. Peter-Paul Koch, writer of &lt;a href=&#34;https://quirksmode.org&#34;&gt;quirksmode.org&lt;/a&gt;, which was the original resource for cross-browser compatibility back in the heyday of the browser wars, wrote an article about Mozilla&amp;rsquo;s problems titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://quirksmode.org/blog/archives/2020/08/the_cult_of_the.html&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Cult of the Free&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; where he argues that it&amp;rsquo;s time to step out of this mentality that all these resources must be maintained for free by &amp;ldquo;the community&amp;rdquo;, but that we as consumers must get used to the idea of paying or donating to support these resources. Expecting &amp;ldquo;the community&amp;rdquo; to step in and maintain these resources &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quirksmode.org/blog/archives/2020/08/i_love_mdn_or_t.html&#34;&gt;also devalues the work of technical writers.&lt;/a&gt; Trying to get more people to support these &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; resources is a good idea, but I worry it goes against the grain of years of internet culture which has conditioned people to expect online content for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of contributing, a while back I had considered looking for open source projects I could contribute to, and preferred projects that I actively use. Given that I&amp;rsquo;d been using Firefox &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/10/firefox-1-0-on-november-9/&#34;&gt;since before version 1.0&lt;/a&gt;, one of the projects I considered was Firefox. I went through the whole rigmarole of &lt;a href=&#34;https://firefox-source-docs.mozilla.org/setup/windows_build.html&#34;&gt;their instructions to set up my machine for the Windows build&lt;/a&gt;, and just the setup process, which involved setting up and checking out code took more than an hour. That was fine for initial setup, but actually building and running Firefox itself took an additional hour or so. Might have been more than that even, it was a while back so I don&amp;rsquo;t clearly remember, but I do remember thinking that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time for these hour-long build times. The whole set up also took up a nontrivial amount of my SSD disk space (imagine how much worse the build time would have been if I had used my non-SSD drive!), which I am always dangerously low on. These 2 factors led me to shelve the idea for the time being; perhaps I could revisit the idea of contributing to Firefox when I upgraded my computer or had more SSD space available. (TBF, I kind of gave up real quick after the first build, maybe the builds get faster on succeeding runs?). So that&amp;rsquo;s my personal &amp;ldquo;contributing-to-Firefox&amp;rdquo; story, for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sheer size of the codebase and the long build times just drive home the point of how much modern browsers are these large complex beasts that are doing so much. They are pretty much an OS of their own since they host a ton of features and web applications and JIT JS and all of that. This means it&amp;rsquo;s really difficult for independent browser efforts to hit feature parity with modern web browsers - even just working with JS and CSS standards, there are so many to implement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drew DeVault laments that &lt;a href=&#34;https://drewdevault.com/2020/08/13/Web-browsers-need-to-stop.html&#34;&gt;Web browsers need to stop&lt;/a&gt; with all these new functionalities and APIs that add scope and complexity, and maybe focus more on performance, efficiency, etc. I do agree - if I was contributing to Firefox, I would want to find a way to reduce the massive memory footprint it always has. I don&amp;rsquo;t even use that many tabs, and I already feel burdened by Firefox&amp;rsquo;s memory footprint. (Pretty sure Chrome is pretty bad in this regard as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why care about Mozilla/Firefox at all? Why not just use Chrome, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, no, Chrome is not necessarily &amp;ldquo;pretty good&amp;rdquo;, given how it props up a surveillance capitalsm engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, even if you didn&amp;rsquo;t dislike Google, having a browser (engine) monoculture is not a good thing. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/old-web/&#34;&gt;got my start in web development&lt;/a&gt; at around the height of Internet Explorer 6&amp;rsquo;s dominance, and I&amp;rsquo;d rather not find my way back there. Granted, one of the issues back then was that IE6 was a stagnant platform that upstarts Firefox and eventually Chrome left behind. No such problem exists now, since Chrome is still in active development and still pushing new web standards forward. And the fact that Chrome is an open-source platform means in theory someone could just fork it if ever Google goes off the rails or such. (And people have already built indie browsers on top of Chrome of course!) But it&amp;rsquo;s still dangerous for a single company and/or codebase to be the sole major implementer of web standards. A single company dictating the future of the web isn&amp;rsquo;t a good thing, and is the very opposite of the idea of an &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side note: Maybe I should try building Chromium too, just for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that&amp;rsquo;s all my ranting for today. In conclusion: reduce your surveillance capitalism footprint and support the open web, use Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-08-16 The Sameyness Report
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-16-the-sameyness-report/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-2020-08-16-the-sameyness-report/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;These weeknotes are coming in late in the day because of reasons. (The reasons being laziness and procrastination.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve been kind of phoning in the weeknotes over the past few weeks, they&amp;rsquo;ve mostly been &amp;ldquo;hey, I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy, so nothing of significance happened, but here are some things I watched/played.&amp;rdquo; Supposedly one of the side effects of writing regular updates is that you tend to look out for more interesting things to do so you have something to write about, even on an unconscious level. In the past few weeks, that has been problematic because (a) as mentioned, I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy with some things, so my excess time is devoted to less mentally taxing things like just watching movies/shows or destress with games; and (b) we are still in the middle of a pandemic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the pandemic, I read this piece recently on the Financial Times: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ft.com/content/32d79c87-1ade-4b63-8d14-7af1a553d963&#34;&gt;We won’t remember much of what we did in the pandemic&lt;/a&gt;, about how the sameyness of our days in quarantine means our brains compress that data since so little of it is meaningful, affecting our perception of time. When 99% of your activities take place in the same environment, in your room during a zoom call, everything just tends to blur together. And I guess that reflected in the weeknotes too! (For that reason, I&amp;rsquo;m switching up the weeknotes format today to be more freeform prose, we&amp;rsquo;ll see if it sticks.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of the pandemic part 2, one thing I have been doing since the pandemic started is writing a regular series of notes, first as &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;one long post that I kept updating every couple of days or so&lt;/a&gt; then later I transitioned to regular weekly update notes, on the same day as these weeknotes. The idea was that in the future I could just browse the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/covid19/&#34;&gt;covid19 tag&lt;/a&gt; on the site and I could recall what things were like during the days of quarantine and the quality of the government response. And this was fine during the start, since things happened and unfolded quickly. But these past few months, the updates have fallen in the quagmire of sameyness as well: I only went out once every 1 or 2 weeks, everything was always getting worse, cases were always going up, government response was always terrible, and so on. One thing the last few months has made clear for me is that the government has no clear plan on controlling this thing and so I am highly pessimistic that things will change anytime soon. For that reason, I&amp;rsquo;m just going to pause on doing the covid19 update notes for now, unless some drastic change happens.(I have no expectation of Russia&amp;rsquo;s vaccine having any effect on our status quo anytime soon!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, so how was my week? I wrapped up the things causing my busy-ness towards the middle of the week, so I expect to be less busy/stressed during the coming weeks. At the very least, I should be able to write on the blog more, and maybe do some work on some of my other side projects. I actually thought about writing some posts already last week but I was like you know what, I&amp;rsquo;ll just relax and watch things and play things and leave the writing to next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching and playing the past week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marvel&amp;rsquo;s Agents of SHIELD had their series finale last Thursday. I enjoyed the first half of this season, but the second half and the finale were just ok, maybe slightly meh. Still, the series finale was pretty good, wrapping things up nicely with a big bow. This series had a lot of haters, I think mostly because of mismatched expectations, because people wanted it to be more directly tied-in to the MCU movies, but that was never going to happen (maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll get that more with the coming Disney+ series). But I like it, it had a lot of fans, and it had a pretty good run. And it had Ghost Rider!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One things I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing a bunch is Amonkhet Remastered, which came out on Magic Arena last Thursday. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing drafts over on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;the twitch channel&lt;/a&gt;, and archiving them to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jsD8jNRlYkw&amp;amp;list=PLmU0vkKslGXg6Pdu3_kaKx5oumTwftUUe&#34;&gt;this playlist on the Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly fun, though I need to play better. Watch me on Twitch/Youtube, or like and subscribe, all that jazz, if you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oh, I also finally finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1293051269129486337/&#34;&gt;Divinity Original Sin 2&lt;/a&gt;! I really dragged out that last act for a few months, but I finally got there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1294146833359364097/&#34;&gt;tried out Fall Guys on PS4&lt;/a&gt; (free on PS+!). It&amp;rsquo;s fun but kind of frustrating, I guess this is why I don&amp;rsquo;t really play these battle royale kind of things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played a little bit Street Fighter x Tekken because of a reddit thread and am once again disappointed that (a) it was such a missed opportunity; and (b) up to now it&amp;rsquo;s still not available on Steam in SEA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so one of the reasons I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing these &amp;ldquo;watching/playing lately&amp;rdquo; posts and segments is because I want to track what I have been watching/playing at any particular point in the past. And maybe I can have like a widget on the site with things like &amp;ldquo;Recently played&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Last movie watched&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;d also want to be able to search/query for things like &amp;ldquo;what year did I watch so-and-so movie?&amp;rdquo; (Helps with trivia quizzes!) I feel like I need to be recording these detail in more of a machine-readable format or a database in order to do those kinds of things. Maybe some kind of Goodreads-like system? It&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;d need to figure out how to implement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, this is already longer than I thought it would be. More things will be posted to the blog (hopefully!) later this week!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-08-09
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-08-09/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-08-09/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Still kind of busy, although there&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of things I hope I can finally wrap up this week, so I can move on to the long list of other things I want to be doing. The world continues to be bleak, so I&amp;rsquo;m still hiding from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/forty-two/&#34;&gt;Forty-two.&lt;/a&gt; I thought about just merging these into a single post for the day, but nah, this seems better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworking the old charity side project still ongoing. I was hoping to finish all the changes last week and next week would be testing and deployment, but stuff got in the way (and estimates may have been a bit off), but the spillover is small and we should still be fine for finishing everything next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lots more SC2 coop this week, mostly in the wee hours to destress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almost impulse-bought a Switch yesterday; a friend&amp;rsquo;s logic and my inexorably large gaming backlog held me back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG Arena: Nothing of significance, but Amonkhet remastered comes out this week so looking forward to that!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actually did a bit better in 1 of the two quizzes we played this week, but I think we had way more fun playing Codenames online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background watching: Jeopardy on Netflix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binged the new Transformers Netflix series, since it was fairly short (six episodes). A very bleak take on the Autobots&amp;rsquo; struggle against the Decepticons on Cybertron, and also a very obvious tie-in to the current War for Cybertron toy line since most of the main characters have toys in that line.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also watched Craig Ferguson&amp;rsquo;s Netflix special Tickle Fight, mainly because I happened to have watch a few of his late night segments on YT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also started watching the last season of Agents of SHIELD, since I&amp;rsquo;m told the season finale is coming up next week. First three episodes seem pretty good for network TV, hopefully I have time for the rest of the (short) season in the next couple of weeks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links: Nothing of note this week. Even though I have read some interesting stuff, I think my link-capturing workflow really needs improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still in a pandemic!&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/covid19-08-09/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2020-08-09 00:00:00&#34;&gt;9 Aug 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Pandemic thoughts and updates, Aug 9 edition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, NCR got sent back into MECQ, a stronger quarantine lockdown. I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually felt the difference, since I&amp;rsquo;m at home most of the time. We went out yesterday for a grocery run, and not much seemed different out there either, still a lot of cars and people out of doors. I don&amp;rsquo;t actually remember what the last MECQ was like, but I kind of assumed things would be closer to how they were at the onset of the lockdowns in March, but this feels still mostly like the GCQ of past weeks. IDK if this 2-week MECQ stretch really serves any purpose except to show the government is trying something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching mass via Facebook again today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As of last night, we are at 126,885 cases (+4226 from the day before, +28653 from last week, huge jump week-on-week), 2,209 deaths (+41 from the day before, +170 from last week, thankfully not as big a jump as from last week), 67,117 recoveries (+287 from the day before, +1852 from last week, a predictably much smaller jump after last week&amp;rsquo;s miraculous &amp;ldquo;mass recoveries&amp;rdquo;). We hit record high daily deaths again over the first few days of the MECQ. We seem to have settled at a much higher average daily rate since then. Luckily, the death rate hasn&amp;rsquo;t gone up that much. We are now #1 in confirmed cases in SEA, overtaking Indonesia. The govt claims nothing to worry about, it&amp;rsquo;s only because we are testing more, but our relatively large positivity rate (around 8.6% as of this writing) implies transmission is outpacing testing? &lt;a href=&#34;https://covid19ph.com/&#34;&gt;Reference.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worldwide, we are at around 19.8 cases (+1.8M from last week, slope holding steady for maybe 3 weeks now?) and almost 730k deaths. Caveat: these numbers are from &lt;a href=&#34;https://edition.cnn.com/interactive/2020/05/world/worldometer-coronavirus-mystery/index.html&#34;&gt;Worldometer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;




            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Forty Two
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/forty-two/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/forty-two/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Forty two is of course the &amp;ldquo;Answer to the Ultimate Question of Life, the Universe, and Everything.&amp;rdquo; (if you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet read the 5-book Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy trilogy, I suggest you do so, you are in for a treat.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason I imagined I would be able to take at least a couple of days off of everything else I&amp;rsquo;m doing to chill and actually craft a well-written, deep, introspective post for the occasion, but alas, various things I&amp;rsquo;m working on and all the usual distractions means I am here in the early morning hours of the day itself typing this out. Likely to just rant a bit here instead of putting out anything coherent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s weird celebrating your birthday in the middle of a worldwide pandemic, when most of the usual celebration trappings are inaccessible. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the reasons why the &lt;a href=&#34;https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/1275013/sinas-other-police-officials-in-mananita-to-face-criminal-case-palace&#34;&gt;birthday mananita debacle&lt;/a&gt; was such a big deal to a lot of people. While these supposed &amp;ldquo;public servants&amp;rdquo; flaunt their privilege, the rest of us are deprived of things like seeing our friends and loved ones in person, celebrating milestones, or even the simple pleasures of eating out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve actually written quite a few of these &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/birthday/&#34;&gt;birthday posts&lt;/a&gt; by now, though not as regularly as I&amp;rsquo;d have liked. I read through a few of them to help me decide what to write for today (didn&amp;rsquo;t really help). My favorite has to be the one with &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/thirty-eight/&#34;&gt;thirty eight lessons I’ve learned through the years&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s for the best, maybe even if I had gotten a few days off I still wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been able to come up with anything satisfying enough. I mean, the point of taking time off for myself was to get away from the world for a bit and be all introspective and to spend time with my own thoughts, but with this pandemic, I might have been doing far too much time doing that already. Perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m not really complaining about the spike in busy-ness I&amp;rsquo;ve had over the past month or so. It&amp;rsquo;s sort of a welcome respite from all the self-reflection this pandemic time has given me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that this is the first birthday after I quit Facebook, I am expecting much, much fewer birthday greetings this year. Interesting how a lot of people are probably dependent now on Facebook to tell them when other people are having birthdays. It is no big loss; the people who are important will remember. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I&amp;rsquo;m not grateful and amazed if someone unexpected should remember. A couple of days ago someone I&amp;rsquo;d only known for less than five years actually remembered to greet me, except the greeting came two days early due to uncertainty about the exact date. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to be remembered, no matter how stoic we pretend to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I almost impulse-bought a Switch yesterday, luckily a friend talked me out of it. Would have made a fine self-birthday gift, but my gaming backlog is still pretty ridiculous as it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit ironic that in last year&amp;rsquo;s post &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/forty-one/&#34;&gt;I complained about an uneventful 365 days&lt;/a&gt; and look what we have now (&lt;em&gt;waves hands around&lt;/em&gt;). I hope I didn&amp;rsquo;t jinx 2020. Next year is a more boring number, maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll have a better year?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-08-02
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-08-02/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/weeknotes-08-02/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Kind of a busy week for me again, so the week kind of passed me by quickly. It&amp;rsquo;s August! In one month it will be (PH) Christmas season! It feels like July went by more quickly than other quarantine months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A bit of consulting work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reworking the old charity side project still ongoing. I was hoping to finish all the changes last week and next week would be testing and deployment, but stuff got in the way (and estimates may have been a bit off), but the spillover is small and we should still be fine for finishing everything next week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starcraft 2 came out with a 10th anniversary patch that had some sweet new features and changes for coop. They added unlockable prestige talents for each of the 18 commanders, each talent alters their gameplay so they play out a bit differently. We had actually been getting a bit bored with SC2 coop and had been playing it less, this patch did a lot to invigorate our enthusiasm for it. We&amp;rsquo;ve been playing it quite a bit to unlock the prestige talents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG Arena: Didn&amp;rsquo;t hit mythic last month, but that&amp;rsquo;s fine. I switched my historic deck to Monored for faster games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only played 1 quiz last week for reasons. Instead, trivia group played some online Codenames (via &lt;a href=&#34;https://codenames.game/&#34;&gt;https://codenames.game/&lt;/a&gt;) on Saturday night, with voice chat over discord. It was a bunch of fun!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s new episodes of Jeopardy on Netflix, so that quickly replaced Family Guy as my background watching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s actually a bunch of new stuff to watch too: Umbrella Academy S2 is out, there&amp;rsquo;s a new Transformers series on Netflix etc. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get around to all of these things someday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some fixes to the trivia app backend, but I can&amp;rsquo;t really get too much into the (other) side projects until I get past my current busyness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet seems to be having some DNS issues this past week. Occasionally can&amp;rsquo;t access various URLs, but is fine on refresh. Problem survived multiple router reboots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right-click button on this gaming mouse I got last year is starting to get less responsive. I only got for $13 in Walmart, but even then it&amp;rsquo;s one of the more expensive mice I&amp;rsquo;ve bought, so I hope it doesn&amp;rsquo;t die too quickly. Maybe I should clean it out?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Couple of somewhat related blog posts resonated with me: &lt;a href=&#34;https://rubenerd.com/why-arent-you-more-serious/&#34;&gt;Why aren’t you more serious?&lt;/a&gt;, asserting the personal blog&amp;rsquo;s right to write about whatever the blogger wants, and not just to focus on specific serious or technical topics; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://om.co/2020/07/30/write-like-a-human/&#34;&gt;Write like a human&lt;/a&gt; is kind of self-explanatory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great follow-up to a previous survey on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pudding.cool/2020/07/song-decay/&#34;&gt;Defining the 90s Music Canon&lt;/a&gt;. Also had an &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/1288899712112717824&#34;&gt;interesting exchange about this with a friend over on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; re:how this might reflect locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IDK, maybe I&amp;rsquo;m getting used to the pandemic. Is this what they mean by &amp;ldquo;new normal&amp;rdquo;? I&amp;rsquo;ll move the pandemic notes to the end of these weekly updates.&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/covid19-08-02/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2020-08-02 00:00:00&#34;&gt;2 Aug 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Pandemic thoughts and updates, Aug 2 edition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We ended July with around 90k active cases. Despite the threat of sending Metro Manila back to ECQ if we breached the 85k mark, the govt did not push through. Over the weekend, this led to a clamor from doctors and other frontliners to have a &amp;ldquo;time out&amp;rdquo; of 2 weeks for the NCR, a temporary quarantine, to give the healthcare system some breathing room. The knee-jerk response from the palace was to say it wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessary, but they quickly flipped their flops and said the IATF would discuss it. Enraging people and doctors, a certain outspoken-on-social-media doctor tried to shame doctors for not being heroic enough, and a certain senator implied that we can&amp;rsquo;t afford it so frontliners just need to work harder and be more passionate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching mass via Facebook again today. Churches have actually been holding limited physical services, but in solidarity with the call for ECQ, they said they will temporarily suspend such services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I went to get some Jollibee takeout last Thursday; apparently they are already allowing limited dine-in customers, that seems unwise, eh. Was anxious the entire time I was waiting for my takeout order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As of last night, we are at 98232 cases (+4963 from the day before, +19820 from last week, huge jump week-on-week), 2039 deaths (+17 from the day before, +142 from last week, moderate jump), 65265 recoveries (+93 from the day before, +39513 (!) from last week, a miraculous jump). We hit record high daily deaths over the past few days, and the huge spike in recoveries is because the DOH decided to do a &amp;ldquo;mass recovery&amp;rdquo; of mild/asymptomatic cases that are already 14 days or older, supposedly in line with WHO guidelines. I can kind of see some logic behind this, but the communication was not handled very well. &lt;a href=&#34;https://covid19ph.com/&#34;&gt;Reference.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worldwide, we are at around 18M cases (+1.8M from last week) and almost 690k deaths. Caveat: these numbers are from &lt;a href=&#34;https://edition.cnn.com/interactive/2020/05/world/worldometer-coronavirus-mystery/index.html&#34;&gt;Worldometer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;




            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-07-26
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-26/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/weeknotes-07-26/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The world:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hm. I was a bit busy this week, so I wasn&amp;rsquo;t paying too much attention, so I don&amp;rsquo;t have too much to rail against today. Well of course, things are still ongoing. There&amp;rsquo;s still the pandemic, fascist police state philosophy continues to rear it&amp;rsquo;s ugly head in the US, PH gov&amp;rsquo;t continues to be dumb, etc., but this week seemed a bit tame comparably.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/covid19-07-26/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2020-07-26 00:00:00&#34;&gt;26 Jul 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Pandemic thoughts and updates, July 26 edition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching mass via Facebook again today. The nearby Church actually holds services, but last I heard it was only 10 people per mass, and need to call ahead of time. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem likely we&amp;rsquo;ll be going anytime soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grocery run yesterday, without incident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;last Thursday I finally &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/1286105826743091201/&#34;&gt;got a haircut&lt;/a&gt; my last one was around New Year&amp;rsquo;s Day, so this was around six and a half months of hair cut off. I didn&amp;rsquo;t go to a barbershop, this was a home service haircut, care of a lady who works at a neighboring salon, who actually came over to do some home care service for my mom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As of last night, we are at 78412 cases (+2019 from the day before, +13108 from last week, slight acceleration week-on-week), 1897 deaths (+20 from the day before, +224 from last week, lower jump than last week), 25752 recoveries (+1278 from the day before, +3685 from last week, much less than last week&amp;rsquo;s jump). The admin claims that if we breach 85k cases by end-July, Metro Manila may go back to NCQ. First, that seems likely to happen so we&amp;rsquo;ll see. Second, it seems a bit unfair and illogical to make Metro Manila&amp;rsquo;s quarantine status dependent on national case numbers, but whatever. &lt;a href=&#34;https://covid19ph.com/&#34;&gt;Reference.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Worldwide, we are at 16.2M cases (+1.8M from last week, slight acceleration) and almost 650k deaths. The US retains a comfortable lead over second placer Brazil. Caveat: these numbers are from &lt;a href=&#34;https://edition.cnn.com/interactive/2020/05/world/worldometer-coronavirus-mystery/index.html&#34;&gt;Worldometer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My stuff:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Busy with rebuilding the UI for the old project. I&amp;rsquo;m having fun with it, so that&amp;rsquo;s something. I think this week went by more quickly for me because of it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final Fantasy VII Remake completed! Review &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/07/ff7r-review/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I played through a couple of Civ6 games, trying out the new civs and game modes from the New Frontier pass. Fun and challenging. Apocalypse mode: it&amp;rsquo;s an insane feeling the first time you see a comet strike take out a city. I was actually streaming the gameplay to a friend on Discord when this happened and we both went &amp;ldquo;Woah!&amp;rdquo; and he said that pushed him to get the DLC as well. Secret societies: Only tried Voidsingers so far; their cultists are great for culture victory since they&amp;rsquo;re a constant source of relics for tourism, and the Old God Monument gives you GW slots for them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG: Still playing a bunch of JumpStart, but also put together Bant Ramp for Historic. Currently at Diamond 4, I&amp;rsquo;ll see if I can grind Mythic for constructed before end of month. Related: I watched Maro&amp;rsquo;s Comic-con stream for Zendikar Rising last night, but left kinda underwhelmed. Set boosters are neat, but I kind of wanted more info/spoilers about the set itself. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to be excited about the set boosters when my MTG involvement is primarily through Arena these days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only played 2 online quizzes this week (the third one didn&amp;rsquo;t fire due to not enough participants). There was a fun Scientists/Inventors round which I could have perfected if I had gone with my gut answer (Rutherford) and not listened to my teammates lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching lately:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a new season of Family Guy on Netflix, so I&amp;rsquo;ve started to watch that in the background while I&amp;rsquo;m working on other things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I watched a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ew.com/events/comic-con/scott-pilgrim-cast-reunion-table-read/&#34;&gt;for-charity cast-reunion live-table-read for Scott Pilgrim vs the World&lt;/a&gt; last week. I enjoyed it so much, I went and rewatched the movie on Netflix as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side projects:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technically, this old project I&amp;rsquo;m revamping used to be a &amp;ldquo;side project&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing of note.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>