<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>books on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/books/</link>
      <description>Recent content in books on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 17:41:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: And Then There Were None by Agatha Chrstie
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/book-review-and-then-there-were-none-by-agatha-chrstie/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 17:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/book-review-and-then-there-were-none-by-agatha-chrstie/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2021/05/orient-express-nile/&#34;&gt;a couple of Hercule Poirot mysteries&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to try an Agatha Christie book from outside that series. I found that &lt;em&gt;And Then There Were None&lt;/em&gt; was one of those commonly appearing on lists of her best works, and the concept intrigued me: Ten people are invited to an island and get trapped there and then murders start to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind of hard to talk about it without spoiling too much (and what I&amp;rsquo;ve said might already have been spoilers!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s one of those things where the whole setup seems super contrived and way too clever for it to ever happen in real life, but the explanation / solution at the end mostly works out and actually makes sense. It was maybe something you could have predicted if you had paid attention to all the little details about the people and their personalities and the actual deaths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a long book. I finished the book in 4 sittings, with the last sitting covering the last half of the book; this is a typical speed for me once a book really gets going, I&amp;rsquo;ll have a hard time putting it down until I&amp;rsquo;m done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying these mysteries, and I find that it&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird that I haven&amp;rsquo;t really read these kinds of mystery novels before. I&amp;rsquo;ve read stuff when I was younger like the Encyclopedia Brown stuff where you&amp;rsquo;re challenged to solve the mystery, etc, but no real mystery novels like this I think. I guess I&amp;rsquo;ve kind of expanded my reading horizons now? That&amp;rsquo;s a good thing!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Reviews: Murder on the Orient Express and Death on the Nile by Agatha Chrstie
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/book-reviews-murder-on-the-orient-express-and-death-on-the-nile-by-agatha-chrstie/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 07:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/book-reviews-murder-on-the-orient-express-and-death-on-the-nile-by-agatha-chrstie/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve not read any Agatha Chrstie, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d rectify that by getting into the Hercule Poirot series of books. To start off I chose &lt;em&gt;Murder on the Orient Express&lt;/em&gt; because &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/watching-lately-jun-jul-2019/&#34;&gt;I watched the 2017 movie a couple of years ago&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Death on the Nile&lt;/em&gt; because it has a movie coming out next year. I figure it would be a good contrast of movie-first vs book first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Took me a bit under a week of leisurely reading to finish &lt;em&gt;Murder on the Orient Express&lt;/em&gt;. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in a rush since I already knew how the mystery turns out. The book wasn&amp;rsquo;t very long, but it was very well structured. A couple of chapters of setup before the crime itself happened, then a chapter each for Poirot to interrogate each of the suspects and then a few more chapters to piece everything together. The book pretty much followed the movie closely, though I think they changed some of the character details for the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Death on the Nile&lt;/em&gt; had a much different pace, although it&amp;rsquo;s about as short as the first one. It feels like the author spent longer on setup, introducing the different characters even before they met Poirot on the trip to the titular Nile. (As opposed to &lt;em&gt;Orient Express&lt;/em&gt; where the entire book narrated only scenes where Poirot was present.) I finished the book in three days; the last day I binged through the last 2/3 of the book once the crime finally happened. It helped that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know the eventual solution (though I had a hunch on who the culprit(s) might be, and the hunch eventually turned out correct), so I was eager to get to the end. I feel like this book gave a better preview of Poriot&amp;rsquo;s investigative abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find myself enjoying the author&amp;rsquo;s writing; the books aren&amp;rsquo;t overly long, and each chapter is usually straightforward, with scenes depicting things that are either red herrings or eventually leading up to the final mystery solution. The books seem like light, leisurely reading, unlike the sci-fi / fantasy epics I&amp;rsquo;m used to. The best comparison I have is to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/hardy-boys/&#34;&gt;the Hardy Boys series&lt;/a&gt; although this series is of course way less juvenile. I can easily send myself reading through a few more of these Poirot books throughout the year. (I didn&amp;rsquo;t follow any recommended reading order, but the books are largely self-contained anyway&amp;hellip; though I know &lt;em&gt;Nile&lt;/em&gt; happens after &lt;em&gt;Orient Express&lt;/em&gt; because Poirot references the prior case.) I should also probably try out some of the author&amp;rsquo;s non-Poirot books as well.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/c72ceb2e3748ccd8611baab1cbfdfe74/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 17:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/c72ceb2e3748ccd8611baab1cbfdfe74/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I finished reading What Matters Now by Seth Godin, a book that is basically a collection of short blog posts by &amp;ldquo;big thinkers&amp;rdquo;, released for free back in 2009. Interestingly, a lot of the ideas presented in the book still feel relevant today. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think it needed a full review post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funniest part for me is that one of the entries is by Jason Fried about how to apologize, advice he certainly could have used during &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/weeknotes-2021-05-09/&#34;&gt;the recent Bandcamp brouhaha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get a copy &lt;a href=&#34;https://seths.blog/2009/12/what-matters-now-get-the-free-ebook/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Snow Crash by Neal Stephenson
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/book-review-snow-crash-by-neal-stephenson/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 02:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/book-review-snow-crash-by-neal-stephenson/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I finished reading &lt;em&gt;Snow Crash&lt;/em&gt; in around three weeks, slightly faster than the other comparable work I&amp;rsquo;ve read this year, which was &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/neuromancer/&#34;&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/a&gt;. Comparable of course only in the sense that they both have some kind of worldwide internet-like network as a central plot point. Otherwise, they are not really that similiar, though the review is made easier by having a base for comparison. Snow Crash is much less cyberpunk than Neuromancer, and maybe takes itself a little less seriously too? I mean, the main character&amp;rsquo;s name is &amp;ldquo;Hiro Protagonist&amp;rdquo;, so that ought to tell you something immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snow Crash was published in 1992, while Neuromancer came out in 1984, so definitely the latter book does take a bit of inspiration from the older one, in terms of cyberspace. The version here in Snow Crash is called &amp;ldquo;Metaverse&amp;rdquo;, and it is actually more akin to a shared virtual reality, much like you were plugged in to a MMORPG such as World of Warcraft. Users of the Metaverse even use goggles to participate, something that only became possible in reality during the last 5 years or so. Hiro in this case is one of the premiere hackers of the metaverse, having contributed a lot to the functionality of the virtual world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is only the second Stephenson book I&amp;rsquo;ve read, after Cryptonomicon &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/11/cryptonomicon/&#34;&gt;waaaay back in 2004&lt;/a&gt;. I was worried that I would encounter the same issues I had with Cryptonomicon here - the general wordiness and the slow pace. Thankfully, Snow Crash turned out to be faster paced and easier to follow than the other book. The plot moves along at a reasonable clip, and revolves almost exclusively around the actions of Hiro and his partner, the Kourier who calls herself Y.T. (for &amp;ldquo;Yours Truly&amp;rdquo;) as they navigate this strange world where the United States has suffered from a severe economic collapse and had to cede parts of California to what are now a bunch of autonomous and sovereign microterritories, many of them belonging to private franchises with colorful names such as &amp;ldquo;Mr Lee&amp;rsquo;s Greater Hong Kong&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;The Mafia&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core of the plot revolves around linguistics, history, archaeology, computer science, and such (unsurprising given the subject matter of Cryptonomicon). It uses this idea that an ancient civilization was able to use language can be used to propagate a &amp;ldquo;virus&amp;rdquo; throughout society by hacking the human brain, in the same way that code can propagate a virus through a computer network. The bad guy in this story is trying to use this concept of a virus derived from an ancient language to control people and create an all-powerful religion with him at the helm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book&amp;rsquo;s title &amp;ldquo;Snow Crash&amp;rdquo; is the name of a digital &amp;ldquo;drug&amp;rdquo; that the bad guy distributes throughout the Metaverse to target hackers. The drug is actually a digital image of random black and white bits (a bit like what a TV/monitor looks like when it loses a signal in those days, literally a crash that looks like snow) that affects hackers&amp;rsquo; brains in a certain way. I guess I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t spoil any more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My one complaint would be the ending felt abrupt, although everything was wrapped up neatly, it all happened mostly outside the purview of our protagonists. I do like it more than Cryptonomicon, which was a later book of his (published in 1999). This one felt easier to grok.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Without Their Permission by Alexis Ohanian
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/without-their-permission-by-alexis-ohanian/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 04:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/without-their-permission-by-alexis-ohanian/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Without Their Permission&lt;/em&gt; is a 2013 book by Reddit cofounder Alexis Ohanian. The central thesis of the book is that modern-day internet breaks down barriers and allows anyone to accomplish great things without having to go through traditional gatekeepers like publishers and such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually read the first part of the book a few years ago, and just resumed reading the book now because I saw in iBooks that it remembered where I had stopped. The first part covered mostly the author&amp;rsquo;s involvement in two successful startups - Reddit and Hipmunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The middle part of the book is dedicated to the central idea that &amp;ldquo;all links are created equal&amp;rdquo; and as long as you make something that other people want and make it accessible on the internet, success is possible. The author extols how the modern internet has made it easier for anyone to start something big, the same way he and his cofounder built Reddit. The funny thing for me is he cites a number of interesting startups that he&amp;rsquo;s invested in, but I&amp;rsquo;ve not heard of most of them, so presumably they didn&amp;rsquo;t actually succeed in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last part of the book covers the then-online community&amp;rsquo;s protests against the SOPA and PIPA bills, lobbyist-fueled IP protection laws that would have stifled the open internet, the precursor of the modern DMCA. While the defeats of SOPA and PIPA were early successes for online freedom, these days there are still other insidious challenges such as surveillance capitalism  and the deliberate spread of online misinformation and conspiracy theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I don&amp;rsquo;t object to this central idea, I feel like it should be tempered with the fact that despite the open internet, success is still much harder than the book might portray it. And despite the waning power of traditional gatekeepers, these days there are online gatekeepers as well that can hinder your success. Online gatekeepers include App Store reviewers, closed platforms like facebook that have unclear moderation policies, censorship from governments, algorithms that decide what to surface to other people, and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s still probably better than the old days, but there are still a lot of challenges on the modern internet. To be fair, the book was released in 2013, which was a lifetime ago on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Reviews: Guards! Guards! and Men at Arms by Terry Pratchett
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/book-reviews-guards-guards-and-men-at-arms-by-terry-pratchett/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 08:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/book-reviews-guards-guards-and-men-at-arms-by-terry-pratchett/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So after reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/neuromancer/&#34;&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/a&gt; last month, I was looking for a bit of lighter fare, so I decided to work on some Discworld books and started with the first book of the City Watch subseries, &lt;em&gt;Guards! Guards!&lt;/em&gt;. I was already quite a bit in when I was like &amp;ldquo;why does all of this seem so familiar? Are Discworld books really so same-y that it feels like I&amp;rsquo;ve read this before?&amp;rdquo; The good news is that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t true, Discworld books aren&amp;rsquo;t super-samey; I have read it before, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/805050532834353152/&#34;&gt;way back in 2016&lt;/a&gt; in fact. And I also found out that I had &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/equal-rites/&#34;&gt;done this in 2016 with another Discworld book as well&lt;/a&gt;! Ok, so I guess that means they are a bit same-y, but on the other hand I am getting better at retention because I actually recognized it this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I went ahead and completed the re-read and proceeded to the next City Watch book, &lt;em&gt;Men at Arms&lt;/em&gt;. And this one was totally new to me, for sure. So, this is a bit of a double review. And maybe a review of the Discworld series as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Guards! Guards!&lt;/em&gt; we get Pratchett&amp;rsquo;s treatment of common fantasy tropes such as dwarves, dragons that can&amp;rsquo;t possibly be flying, and unknown heroes becoming king by slaying evil dragons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have the effrontery to be squeamish, it thought at him. But we were dragons. We were supposed to be cruel, cunning, heartless, and terrible. But this much I can tell you, you ape—the great face pressed even closer, so that Wonse was staring into the pitiless depths of his eyes—we never burned and tortured and ripped one another apart and called it morality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Terry Pratchett, &lt;em&gt;Guards! Guards!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Men at Arms&lt;/em&gt;, Pratchett expands on the cast of the City Watch subseries, explores the guild structure of the city of Ankh Morpork, and expands the lore of races such as dwarves and trolls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take boots, for example. He earned thirty-eight dollars a month plus allowances. A really good pair of leather boots cost fifty dollars. But an affordable pair of boots, which were sort of OK for a season or two and then leaked like hell when the cardboard gave out, cost about ten dollars. Those were the kind of boots Vimes always bought, and wore until the soles were so thin that he could tell where he was in Ankh-Morpork on a foggy night by the feel of the cobbles.
But the thing was that good boots lasted for years and years. A man who could afford fifty dollars had a pair of boots that’d still be keeping his feet dry in ten years’ time, while a poor man who could only afford cheap boots would have spent a hundred dollars on boots in the same time and would still have wet feet.
This was the Captain Samuel Vimes “Boots” theory of socioeconomic unfairness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Terry Pratchett, &lt;em&gt;Men at Arms&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yes, the Discworld books are maybe kind of same-y, but that&amp;rsquo;s kind of a good thing? You usually know what to expect. They&amp;rsquo;re light reading, they&amp;rsquo;re funny in a dry British humor kind of way, and Pratchett likes to attack and parody and deconstruct common fantasy tropes. I like the books, despite their sameyness, although I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll ever be able to work my way through the entire series.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Neuromancer by William Gibson
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/book-review-neuromancer-by-william-gibson/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 02:31:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/book-review-neuromancer-by-william-gibson/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It took me more than three weeks to get through Gibson&amp;rsquo;s influential work Neuromancer, a book that pioneered the cyberpunk genre and even introduced terms like cyberspace, ICE and &amp;ldquo;the matrix&amp;rdquo; into popular lexicon. It&amp;rsquo;s not because the book is bad or anything, it&amp;rsquo;s just that Gibson tends to describe everything very vividly, and almost all of it from the POV of our lead character Case, who is sometimes in the real world, sometimes in cyberspace, and sometimes simply just drunk or high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found myself taking time with each scene to visualize where Case was and what was going on. In later parts of the book, it became even more complicated because Case gained the ability to see the world from the POV of his ally, the cybergirl Molly. So for many chapters the POV would consistently shift between Case in the real world, Case in cyberspace, Case looking through Molly&amp;rsquo;s eyes, and so on. Some of it even takes place in space / low-gravity scenarios, so the perspectives being described can be challenging to imagine. Throw in a lot of high-tech / near-future slang and Rastafarian accents and it can make for a challenging read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made it to the end, somehow, though every step of the way I doubted whether I understood what was really going on. In fact, I had to read a plot summary afterwards to confirm that yes, I did in fact understand the story and I was not being dumb. Hard to tell without spoiling anything, but it&amp;rsquo;s really the sort of thing you&amp;rsquo;d expect from a cyberpunk story anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did enjoy the book, though I suspect I would have liked it more as a movie, as that would have been easier to follow.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Ghost of My Father by Scott Berkun
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/book-review-ghost-of-my-father-by-scott-berkun/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/book-review-ghost-of-my-father-by-scott-berkun/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href=&#34;https://scottberkun.com/the-ghost-of-my-father/&#34;&gt;Ghost of My Father by Scott Berkun&lt;/a&gt; this past week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book isn&amp;rsquo;t my usual fare. It&amp;rsquo;s a memoir about the author&amp;rsquo;s father and their relationship and family life. I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with the author&amp;rsquo;s work, but mostly in the realms of tech, design and public speaking, but this book was largely personal, and mostly talking about strangers I had no real interest in. I think the only reason I have a copy at all is because I was on the author&amp;rsquo;s mailing list and got a review copy of some sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started reading it because I was looking for a new book to pick up, and with the first few pages I was like &amp;ldquo;Oh, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like something for me, I probably won&amp;rsquo;t finish it.&amp;rdquo; but before I knew it, I had finished 40% of the book in one sitting. I consumed mostly as if it was a work of fiction, about strangers and their relationships. Humans like stories after all, and this is a story about people who are only human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author&amp;rsquo;s relationship with his father was strained at best, and it affected the rest of their family as well. I can&amp;rsquo;t personally relate to that, as I have a pretty good relationship with my family. The author&amp;rsquo;s difficult family life provides a window into a kind of human interaction I&amp;rsquo;m not too familiar with. But I do empathize with how it can be difficult to deal with certain people, and how sometimes the people you need closure from the most will simply have no interest in providing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a long book, it was a quick read for me (less than a week). I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have sought out such a book on my own, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad I read it.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Walkaway by Cory Doctorow
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/book-review-walkaway-by-cory-doctorow/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 08:01:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/book-review-walkaway-by-cory-doctorow/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Walkaway-Novel-Cory-Doctorow-ebook/dp/B01FQQ47OC/&#34;&gt;Walkaway&lt;/a&gt; is a novel by blogger Cory Doctorow. It tells the story of a near-future world and a trend of people going &amp;ldquo;walkaway&amp;rdquo;. This term means walking away from what they call &amp;ldquo;default society&amp;rdquo;, characterized by late stage capitalism, massive inequality, ever-present surveillance, and a world controlled by what they call the zottarich, or simply zottas. Not too far from our own present reality of course. Later, the novel also delves into the near-future (?) concept of humans being to upload their consciousness into machines, effectively allowing them to cheat death by running as a &amp;ldquo;brain in a jar&amp;rdquo; on a cluster of computers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going walkaway means giving everything up and deciding to live communally and off the land, as it were. This near-future world makes this possible due to the abundance of materials and equipment that have been left behind or abandoned due to failed cities, institutions or companies. Resources that are presumably being wasted or going unused because of insane things like copyright controls, patents, and so on. Walkaways are shown building entire communities by sending out drones to seek out and gather nearby raw materials and constructing machines like fabricators that can spin out food and clothing, all powered by open source code that is freely shared and improved upon by walkaways worldwide via a highly distributed and decentralized walkaway network. &amp;ldquo;Default&amp;rdquo; society and media portray walkaways as anarchists and terrorists, living on the fringe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot centers upon a small group of twenty-somethings (including one zotta heiress) who initially flirt with the idea of going walkaway, and then decide to jump right in. Under that thin veneer, the novel feels mostly like an opportunity to explore how such an idea could work, and how it could bridge the gap between our current society and an idealized future, post-scarcity and even post-human. That gap is not bridged easily of course. Discoveries in walkaway culture and science such as human mind uploads threaten to overturn the &amp;lsquo;default&amp;rsquo; society and thus draws the ire of the zottas, who send in mercenaries and even armies to disrupt, arrest, and take down walkaways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author is a blogger I&amp;rsquo;ve known about for a while, and his interest in various kinds of technology and possible future applications to help supplant late-stage capitalism are made obvious through the novel. I initially thought it was being a bit too preachy and idealistic about walkaway culture being the right path for humanity. The story argues that there is plenty to go around, and that people shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be coerced to work and should have an abundance mentality, freely helping and giving away to others, something that works in the novel because of the existence of fabricators and the apparent abundance of raw materials, but which I am unsure would be true in the real world. This is why we still have a lot of people arguing against things like UBI and so on. The novel anchors itself from a point where the scarcity issue is mostly addressed, what&amp;rsquo;s left is to overcome the regressive &amp;ldquo;default&amp;rdquo; capitalist systems holding us back from a brighter future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kind of find myself aligned with the author in terms of ideology; I am very much hoping we as a society find a way past the perils of capitalism, but I&amp;rsquo;m not yet so optimisci that it could work. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure whether the story should be classified as a dystopia - it certainly describes a very dystopian status quo, but that status quo is not too far from our current one. And ultimately, despite all the trials and tribulations our walkaway protagonists are subject to, the novel still exudes optimism about humanity&amp;rsquo;s future. So, a hopeful dystopia, a dystopia that can be defeated? A dystopia that is merely a stepping stone towards what the walkaways call &amp;ldquo;the first days of a better nation&amp;quot;

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-1&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The Year Without Pants
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/book-review-the-year-without-pants/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 03:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/book-review-the-year-without-pants/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Year Without Pants&amp;rdquo; is a book by writer Scott Berkun about his time as a team lead at Wordpress.com back in 2010-2012. This book came out in 2013, and the conceit of the book back then was that Wordpress.com, run by Automattic, was a fully remote company, something that was still a rarity at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s weird reading this book in the context of the current pandemic, where remote work is now the norm among tech companies. So one of the things I like about the book is it&amp;rsquo;s kind of a time capsule back to an era when remote work was a novelty and not an everyday part of our modern dystopia. That and the stories about the culture at Automattic and Wordpress, arguably one of the main drivers of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/blogging/&#34;&gt;blogging&lt;/a&gt; phenomenon at its peak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wordpress.com was a force back in the day, and maybe it still is, as Wordpress still powers a good number of sites online I think. I&amp;rsquo;d be eager to read an updated take on what life is like at Automattic/Wordpress.com these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t really recommended the book to anyone who isn&amp;rsquo;t interested in the internet history and the whole tech side of it, but if that&amp;rsquo;s you, it&amp;rsquo;s an entertaining enough read.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The End of Everything by Katie Mack
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/book-review-the-end-of-everything-by-katie-mack/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 11:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/book-review-the-end-of-everything-by-katie-mack/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I finished the book The End of Everything (Astronomically Speaking) by Katie Mack. I got a Kindle copy on sale on Amazon at the top of the year, figured it was a good way to kick off a year of hopefully reading more books. This is a short review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figure it&amp;rsquo;s probably not a spoiler to tell you the book is all about how the universe ends. Or at least, the many possible ways it could end. The book gives a surface-level walkthrough of what we know about the nature, history and future of our universe through the lenses of physics and cosmology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me more than a couple of weeks to get through the book, as each chapter does discuss some challenging topics and I wanted to make sure I mostly got my head around it before continuing. I suspect those with less background in the sciences might have a bit of trouble with the text, but the author tries her best to not be too complicated (which can be challenging given the subject matter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that the text or prose is boring mind you. The author spices things up with a few humorous jabs here and there, although it might depend on your sense of humor. The author&amp;rsquo;s wit reminds me a bit of British-style humor, like in The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to the Galaxy, so YMMV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are able to power through the book, you are rewarded with a fascinating view of the current state of our knowledge of physics and cosmology, of how far we&amp;rsquo;ve come and much we still don&amp;rsquo;t know and how much there is yet to be discovered. Perhaps those who have not much background in science will come away with a deeper understanding of how scientific theories are formed, improved, discarded, iterated upon, and so on. I came away with a better understanding of things like the cosmic background radiation, dark matter, dark energy, and so on. Fascinating stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend the book to anyone with even a passing interest in physics. And even if you didn&amp;rsquo;t have such an interest, you could try it anyway, and maybe that will change.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/book-review-the-end-of-everything-by-katie-mack/end-of-everything_hubcde6db45a4b52971688d0f1eeaf446c_6603555_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Rhythm of War by Sanderson, Brandon
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/rhythm-of-war/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/rhythm-of-war/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Rhythm of War is book four in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s epic fantasy Stormlight Archive series. Goodreads tells me I read the prior book Oathbringer back in Nov 2017, but didn&amp;rsquo;t bother writing a review, so I had to make sure I&amp;rsquo;d write one now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book&amp;rsquo;s launch day kind of caught me a bit unexpectedly so I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother doing a re-read of the previous three books. Which given an epic fantasy series of this scope might have been a mistake, but watch me do it again for book five. No review meant while reading every so often I&amp;rsquo;d stop and be like &amp;ldquo;Who is this character again, and why is she here?&amp;rdquo; Which is to be expected for this kind of thing, probably if GRRM ever manages to bring out Winds of Winter that&amp;rsquo;ll be a thing again. It&amp;rsquo;s a whole big sprawl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got this book on launch day last Nov 17. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/01/words-of-radiance/&#34;&gt;review for the second book Words of Radiance&lt;/a&gt; tells me it took me three weeks to get through it, so I was kind of expecting I might take until 2021 with this one. It only took me a around eight days, with the last third of the book taking me a single read in one long night. So, that says a lot about how good the book is and how the pacing is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a really fun book actually, things are happening, and there&amp;rsquo;s character growth and everything, and I feel like this one touched a lot more on the cosmere stuff. Or maybe I was just notificing more things because no review meant I was reading the wiki more. (Don&amp;rsquo;t worry I managed not to spoil myself!). It&amp;rsquo;s great that Sanderson manages to just put in a lot of stuff and give all of the lead characters significant things to do and character arcs and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s some happenings near the end that turn around some things the characters thought they knew about their history; not as big as the one in Oathbringer, but that&amp;rsquo;s always fun. And some things happen where I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how the next book is going to handle it, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to that. (Trying not to be too spoilery here of course!) At Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s rate, it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be at least 3 years before book 5 comes out, and even after that, the series is expected to have a second 5-book arc, plus there&amp;rsquo;s some side books that I feel like I should read because they introduce some relevant characters (Edgedanger, etc) so there&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of Stormlight Archive to look forward to!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Atomic Habits by James Clear
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/atomic-habits/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 01:02:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/atomic-habits/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Hopefully managing to read at least one book at month this year, kicking it off with &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com/atomic-habits&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits by James Clear&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I forget where I heard of this book, but it&amp;rsquo;s highly recommended and an Amazon best-seller. I followed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jamesclear&#34;&gt;author on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for a while before deciding to buy the book. I read it sporadically through the month. It&amp;rsquo;s not very long - less than 300 pages on the Kindle app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is fairly good and insightful, although I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if there are any ideas I haven&amp;rsquo;t encountered elsewhere (especially if you read a lot of self-improvement stuff). Most of the concepts are easy to arrive at if you sat down to spend like thirty minutes thinking about (&amp;ldquo;Oh, I should make my good habits easier to do!&amp;rdquo; seems kind of obvious in hindsight).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the book shines in tying these ideas together thematically into what the author describes as &amp;ldquo;four laws of behavior change.&amp;rdquo; I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m taking anything away from the book by listing the four laws here as: make it obvious/make it attractive/make it easy/make it satisfying. As is typical with this kind of book, the theme is further supported by citing research, anecdotes, success stories, quotes, tips, and such. While the material in question doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel entirely revolutionary, the presentation is very good and makes it a worthwhile read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had my own share of trouble building new habits in the past of course. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a specific set of good habits to learn/bad habits to unlearn when I started reading, but the book&amp;rsquo;s insights did give me some ideas of how I could restructure some of my daily habits to make things easier for me. And I thought of some new habits during the course of reading and have been keeping them up for a week or so. So, the book has already provided some value for me personally. I hope I can keep it up.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: So Good They Cant Ignore You by Cal Newport
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Aha! I finally managed to finish a book again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of Cal Newport since years ago tangentially due to his Study Hacks blog, which was pretty good at the time. I haven&amp;rsquo;t followed his career too closely, but he&amp;rsquo;s an academic at Georgetown apparently. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t looking for any career advice in particular, but I did have a recommendation for this book from somewhere so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is &lt;em&gt;So Good They Can&amp;rsquo;t Ignore You&lt;/em&gt;, and focuses on what it takes to have a &amp;ldquo;successful career&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite thing about this book is that from the get-go, the author discards something most self-improvement books focus on: passion. The author discards passion as non-essential. A lot of self-improvement books also lay out a bunch of principles and rules and wink at the reader and say something to the effect of &amp;ldquo;You just have to do all of this stuff, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be super successful!&amp;rdquo;, as if all of those rules + a bit of passion are some sort of secret ingredient that allow you to skip past all the hard work necessary to find success. This book doesn&amp;rsquo;t shy away from the concept of hard work. Instead, it embraces it, in the form of what the author calls &amp;ldquo;career capital&amp;rdquo;. Basically, you need to earn enough &amp;ldquo;career capital&amp;rdquo; in order to then exchange that capital for the trappings of a successful career, such as more control over your time. &amp;ldquo;Career capital&amp;rdquo; is what makes you &amp;ldquo;so good they can&amp;rsquo;t ignore you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many books of this type, the ideas are presented as if the author came by them scientific analysis, but really the basis seems to be a series of anecdotal success stories of people whose career paths coincide with the author&amp;rsquo;s central thesis. This is not inherently a bad thing, though it does weaken the foundation of the books claims that it&amp;rsquo;s not backed by a detailed scientific study. But for purposes of laying out his ideas in an entertaining manner, the format is certainly sufficient. The success stories are really the meat of the book, designed to lay out the author&amp;rsquo;s rules and show how they are applicable to real, actual careers. And in most of the success stories, he traces their story for more than a decade of building up &amp;ldquo;career capital&amp;rdquo;, again emphasizing hard work over dreaming of overnight success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally relate to the concept of not being defined by passion and instead working hard to earn &amp;ldquo;career capital&amp;rdquo; and the idea that you can cash that capital in for more control. This mirrors my own career path where I spent more than a decade working for some multinational company, not really specializing in anything in particular and developing a variety of interests before deciding to use that career capital to go freelance and establish more control over my life. What I don&amp;rsquo;t have yet, is the overarching &amp;ldquo;mission&amp;rdquo; described by the author&amp;rsquo;s Rule #4. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a unifying vision driving my life forward, probably a result of my being very &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/unfocused/&#34;&gt;unfocused&lt;/a&gt;. Or perhaps I already have one and it is yet to be clearly articulated? Hmm, we&amp;rsquo;ll see. In any case, I find the book&amp;rsquo;s contents quite relevant to my own career and the ideas presented here will probably be relevant to me personally as I try to crystallize my own plans for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is a relatively short (Kindle version says 276 pages, and a lot of that is notes and links) and a quick read (I finished it piecemeal over 3 days, but could have easily finished in 1). I think I got it on sale a few months ago for around $4, not bad for that price, and a decent pickup for anyone looking to chart a clearer career path.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>My Personal Reading List
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/my-personal-reading-list/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/my-personal-reading-list/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I recently imported my old reviews from Goodreads into this blog as &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/goodreads&#34;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt;. These days I generally prefer just writing my book reviews here anyway, so I will likely stop using Goodreads as a service completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To facilitate tracking of my read/unread books (and perhaps to inspire me to read more, as I really should), I&amp;rsquo;ve published an old file which I&amp;rsquo;ve been using as a sort of &amp;ldquo;to-read&amp;rdquo; list since 2010. I don&amp;rsquo;t restrict myself to reading items from this list, but it serves as a helpful reference should I feel like picking up a new book. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a target for reading them all or anything like that. There are so many items on this list that it&amp;rsquo;s doubtful I will be able to read them all in this lifetime or the next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracking them on the blog is a bit more low-tech than using Goodreads, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s straightforward. Here you go: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/lists/reading&#34;&gt;The Reading List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Utopia for Realists by Rutger Bregman
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/book-review-utopia-for-realists-by-rutger-bregman/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/book-review-utopia-for-realists-by-rutger-bregman/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I forget where I got this book recommendation from, but it did go on sale for Kindle a while back so I got a copy. The full title is &amp;ldquo;Utopia for Realists: How We Can Build the Ideal World&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary: I really like this book, though I think it falls short in providing concrete steps for how to get from where we are to the idealized utopia he presents. Still, in this world of ever-increasing bad news and crises, the optimism of this book is a welcome respite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book covers a number of &amp;ldquo;utopian&amp;rdquo; scenarios worth striving for, namely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;universal basic income&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;shorter work weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;open borders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even before reading a book, I was already a believer in these ideals, well aware of the justifications. But the book covers that and more, providing a history of those ideas and what was tried before and why they failed and why we aren&amp;rsquo;t there yet. The history is particularly interesting, as before this I had no idea how close the US came to implementing something like UBI in the middle of the last century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said, there&amp;rsquo;s very little concrete suggestions as to how to get there though. The author wails a bit about how progressives are stuck trying to protect the status quo instead of pushing forward truly progressive ideals such as these. The book also briefly covers such topics as biases and how difficult it is to push truly progressive ideas forward in the face of those biases. Aside from that, most of the advice seems to be &amp;ldquo;keep on bringing these issues up, their time will come.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a critical eye to these issues leads me deeper into my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/capitalism/&#34;&gt;disagreements with the hyperefficiency of capitalism&lt;/a&gt; because even though with detailed analysis these ideals may tend to hold up in terms of value, it will still be difficult convincing a society to pursue them when said society is focused on profit over all things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably a more detailed discussion of each issue is beyond the scope of this post and each one may even merit multiple additional posts on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, here are some passages/quotes I found myself highlighting from the book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On worrying about what other people think:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On inequality affecting people&amp;rsquo;s self-image (explains a lot about the Philippines):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take bullying. Countries with big disparities in wealth also have more bullying behavior, because there are bigger status differences&amp;hellip; the “psychosocial consequences” are such that people living in unequal societies spend more time worrying about how others see them. This undercuts the quality of relationships (manifested in a distrust of strangers and status anxiety, for example). The resulting stress, in turn, is a major determinant of illness and chronic health problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On why performance-driven societies may not be optimal (i.e. capitalsm&amp;rsquo;s focus on efficiency may not be best):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the writer Kevin Kelly says, “Productivity is for robots. Humans excel at wasting time, experimenting, playing, creating, and exploring.” Governing by numbers is the last resort of a country that no longer knows what it wants, a country with no vision of utopia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On shorter work weeks:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Ford, Kellogg, and Heath had all discovered is that productivity and long work hours do not go hand in hand. In the 1980s, Apple employees sported T-shirts that read, “Working 90 hours a week and loving it!” Later, productivity experts calculated that if they had worked half the hours then the world might have enjoyed the groundbreaking Macintosh computer a year earlier. There are strong indications that in a modern knowledge economy, even forty hours a week is too much. Research suggests that someone who is constantly drawing on their creative abilities can, on average, be productive for no more than six hours a day. It&amp;rsquo;s no coincidence that the world&amp;rsquo;s wealthy countries, those with a large creative class and highly educated populations, have also shaved the most time off their workweeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the cult of busy:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, excessive work and pressure are status symbols. Moaning about too much work is often just a veiled attempt to come across as important and interesting. Time to oneself is sooner equated with unemployment and laziness, certainly in countries where the wealth gap has widened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On &amp;ldquo;bullshit jobs&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bizarrely, it&amp;rsquo;s precisely the jobs that shift money around–creating next to nothing of tangible value–that net the best salaries. It&amp;rsquo;s a fascinating, paradoxical state of affairs. How is it possible that all those agents of prosperity–the teachers, the police officers, the nurses–are paid so poorly, while the unimportant, superfluous, and even destructive shifters do so well?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This one I highlighted because I found it a questionable ideal at best, he offers no explanation for why this should be true:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we restructure education around our new ideals, the job market will happily tag along. Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine we were to incorporate more art, history, and philosophy into the school curriculum. You can bet there will be a lift in demand for artists, historians, and philosophers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On how even smart people are not immune to cognitive dissonance:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart people, concludes the American journalist Ezra Klein, don&amp;rsquo;t use their intellect to obtain the correct answer; they use it to obtain what they want to be the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Never give up!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Solomon Asch made another discovery. A single opposing voice can make all the difference. When just one other person in the group stuck to the truth, the test subjects were more likely to trust the evidence of their own senses. Let this be an encouragement to all those who feel like a lone voice crying out in the wilderness: Keep on building those castles in the sky. Your time will come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On not focusing too much on work:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, Australian writer Bronnie Ware published a book titled The Top Five Regrets of the Dying, about patients she had tended during her nursing career. 2 And guess what? No one said he or she would have liked to pay closer attention to coworkers&amp;rsquo; PowerPoint presentations or to have brain-stormed a little more on disruptive co-creation in the network society. The biggest regret was: &amp;ldquo;I wish I&amp;rsquo;d had the courage to live a life true to myself, not the life others expected of me.&amp;rdquo; Number two: &amp;ldquo;I wish I didn&amp;rsquo;t work so hard.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall a very good read, despite my criticisms, and a lot of his thought appeal to my own ideals personally.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game of Thrones
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/game-of-thrones/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/game-of-thrones/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After a much-maligned eighth and final season, HBO&amp;rsquo;s Game of Thrones is done. Unmarked spoilers follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eighth season was so notoriously bad, we got petitions asking for rewrites. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I explained it to a friend after the notorious episode 5:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not about characters being killed, it&amp;rsquo;s about bad writing because they&amp;rsquo;re cramming. The writers were determined to finish the show in 2 smaller seasons so they&amp;rsquo;re skipping a lot of necessary character development and characters just do stupid things because the plot demands it. The most recent episode (spoilers follow, no apologies) has Dany do something really bad and out of character. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been so bad if they had spent maybe 5-6 episodes building up to it, but there&amp;rsquo;s nothing, she just decided out of nowhere, fuck it, let&amp;rsquo;s do this. The show was already very simplified compared to the books, which had a lot of plot threads and character arcs that never carried over to the show, which is understandable given the volume, and season 8 basically dumbs it down even more so they can hit their target number of episodes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final episode aired today, and I was mostly whelmed. A big meh. It&amp;rsquo;s always challenging to finish in a satisfying manner an epic story with many intersecting character arcs, especially something this popular. You are almost always not going to please everybody. Some endings made sense, some I could see that GRRM was probably planning for all along, some came out of nowhere (Arya the Explorer comes to mind). Like many things about season 8, so much of it feels crammed and unearned. The season might have been better received if they had stretched things out more. As it is, they had to do things like have Tyrion justify Dany&amp;rsquo;s madness in a speech to Jon after the fact, instead of building up to it organically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experiencing the series as a book reader was interesting, since we knew what was going to happen for basically the first five seasons. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;m not the only book reader who was excited to see how TV viewers would react to things like the execution of Ned Stark and the Red Wedding. Once the series overtook the books, we then fell into this weird position of having the show spoil the books. Not that we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t still read the books, but the show leaving out certain elements changes their importance in the books. For example, the absence of the Lady Stoneheart and Young Griff in the shows implied those plot threads were actually irrelevant to the show&amp;rsquo;s ultimate ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think the poor writing in season 8 makes me look forward to the books more, if only to see if and how GRRM is able to deliver a better and more satisfying ending. I think the ending for the Starks is probably what he had in mind all along (or very close to it); in his initial outline for the entire series, it was always about the Starks. Whether he sticks to that plan or pivots after seeing the reactions to the show, we shall see. I read a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dsilvermint/status/1125856091261136896?s=21&#34;&gt;great thread on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; describing GRRM as a &amp;ldquo;pantser&amp;rdquo; kind of writer, i.e. he writes by the seat of his pants, letting the characters and events drive the story forward instead of strictly following an outline. It makes for good narrative, but is probably also why he&amp;rsquo;s taking forever to finish. And we hope he will finish! Maybe someday, when the books are done, we eventually get a better and more faithful remake series (cue the &amp;ldquo;Game of Thrones: Brotherhood&amp;rdquo; jokes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall though, I think history will look kindly on the entire series of Game of Thrones for what it did. It brought epic fantasy to the forefront of pop culture. People talked excitedly about every episode as it came out and speculated about what would happen. Even my dad got into it, even though I often had to explain some bits to him, and he didn&amp;rsquo;t like watching the show without subtitles. They failed to stick the landing, so they don&amp;rsquo;t belong in the same conversation as series like &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;, but there were a lot of epic moments and some very good television in those eight seasons, and the show ultimately deserves its places in the cultural zeitgeist. Because of this show, we are getting other epic fantasies as TV series moving forward. I&amp;rsquo;m most looking forward to Amazon&amp;rsquo;s upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/wheel-of-time-new-spring/&#34;&gt;Wheel of Time&lt;/a&gt; series, hopefully they don&amp;rsquo;t screw it up. (That one would take maybe two decades to finish!)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Wheel of Time: Eye of the World
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/wheel-of-time-eye-of-the-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/wheel-of-time-eye-of-the-world/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Continuing with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/wheel-of-time-new-spring/&#34;&gt;Wheel of Time re-read&lt;/a&gt;! I devoured Eye of the World much more quickly than I expected, finishing the book in less than 3 days. It helps that I had already read it before of course, but I think there&amp;rsquo;s also a part of me that enjoys escaping into this fantasy world when the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/ph-elections-2019-otso-diretso-compromises-lesser-evils/&#34;&gt;real world outlook seems dire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the book shows a lot of Tolkien-esque plot influence, especially near the start: Some kids from a backwater village are visited by a magic user and after some troubles are forced on the run from black riders? Sounds familiar. Not only that, but you can even map the characters somewhat:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emond Field kids -&amp;gt; Hobbits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moiraine -&amp;gt; Gandalf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lan -&amp;gt; Aragorn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thom -&amp;gt; Okay, LoTR didn&amp;rsquo;t have a bard, but he does take the role of sacrificing himself while the kids run&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s even a location called the Mountains of Dhoom, which is a riduclous name!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s fine. I remember back when I read this series the first time I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much patience for Jordan&amp;rsquo;s prose where he describes everything in so many words including the food being eaten, the clothes worn, the crowds, the buildings and so on; I was always hungry for the plot so I tended to skim a lot of the background noise. This time I made more of an effort to appreciate the prose and the settings, since I already knew most of the plot. It is not as boring as I feared it would be, and perhaps my imagination is more enriched because of it. The characters certainly look a bit different in my head now than they did before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the book does take its time. After Shadar Logoth, the party gets split up and it takes them forever to be reunited. It isn&amp;rsquo;t until 85% through the book that everyone gets back together and Moiraine concludes that they have to go visit the titular Eye of the World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Nynaeve and Lan relationship wasn&amp;rsquo;t built up very well either I think. It seems they just were suddenly affectionate near the end, after barely anything more than longing looks and barely any conversations for most of the book. Also, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the WoT TV series if only to learn how to properly pronounce &amp;ldquo;Nynaeve&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book ends with a victory for the good guys. Not THE victory, as some of them think, but it is a victory. But it is also a strange place, as Rand discovers what he can do and decides to leave the group for a while. The next book takes them to Ilian for the Great Hunt I believe, and I seem to recall that it may be a long time before the Emond Fielders are together in the same place again. Onwards!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Wheel of Time: New Spring
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/wheel-of-time-new-spring/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/wheel-of-time-new-spring/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Since I was going to be taking a long trip in a month, I was looking for some books to read on the plane and in airports and whatnot while waiting. I settled on a re-read of Robert Jordan&amp;rsquo;s Wheel of Time series, a pretty good time for it since by next year we may have a TV series from Amazon (hopefully better than Game of Thrones). Side note: Wheel of Time is also why I&amp;rsquo;m not optimistic that GRRM can finish ASoIaF in just two more books - Jordan took forever and died before he could finish WoT and even Sanderson who took over needed an additional three books to finish the saga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I read any of the books - I bought and read the final book &lt;em&gt;A Memory of Light&lt;/em&gt; when it came out, so that was around 2013. That means I followed the series for around two decades - I remember borrowing &lt;em&gt;Eye of the World&lt;/em&gt; from a friend maybe around late high school/early college (circa mid 90s) and quickly going through the books until I was caught up. Wheel of Time was my first real epic fantasy series - I only read Tolkien later on and before that most of my fantasy exposure was limited to TV and movies. I enjoyed the first half of the 14-book series, then got &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/05/wheel-of-time-10-crossroads-of-twilight/&#34;&gt;annoyed by the pacing in the second half&lt;/a&gt;, and was relieved when Sanderson managed to satisfactorily land the plane with &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/41200573244/so-i-finished-reading-a-memory-of-light-today&#34;&gt;Memory of Light&lt;/a&gt;. My annoyance with the later books may have been due to the fact that I had to wait for each one in turn to be released - it will be interesting to see how the series holds up for me now that I can read all the books in succession. I also like to think I&amp;rsquo;ve matured as a reader since then and will be able to appreciate the books differently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also well behind my book reading target for this year, so doing a re-read of a long series gives me a good bump. Also, since the books have been out forever, I&amp;rsquo;m not going to bother to mark spoilers when I&amp;rsquo;m discussing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am however starting with a book I haven&amp;rsquo;t read yet - &lt;em&gt;New Spring&lt;/em&gt; is a prequel novel that I never bothered to read before. The story takes place 20 years before &lt;em&gt;Eye of the World&lt;/em&gt;, so it&amp;rsquo;s a good starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story follows the PoV of two characters introduced in &lt;em&gt;Eye of the World&lt;/em&gt; - Moiraine Damodred, starting out as an Accepted with future Amyrlin Siuan Sanche at the White Tower in Tar Valon, and Lan Mandragoran, fresh off the tail end of the Aiel War and how their paths eventually intersect. Given the two main characters future, we can anticipate that the novel will end with them forming the Warder bond. The book is short - about half as long as &lt;em&gt;Eye of the World&lt;/em&gt; - but as is typical of Robert Jordan, it takes a long time to get there, as most of the first half of the book centers around Moiraine and Siuan navigating the intrigues of the White Tower as the search for The Dragon Reborn begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pace picks up a bit once Moiraine manages to leave the tower and crosses path with Lan and they realize the existence of the Black Ajah searching for the Dragon Reborn. Yes, reading this book before the rest means you are already aware the Black Ajah exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given how at the start of this book Lan is openly disdainful of getting caught in Aes Sedai problems and how tight Moiraine and Lan are by the time of &lt;em&gt;Eye of the World&lt;/em&gt;, I assumed there would be some big life-changing event near the end of the book that would cause him to change his mind and allow the Warder bond, but I was a bit whelmed by how it happened. One would think losing his oldest bondsman to the Black Ajah would Lan more wary of Aes Sedai, but all it took was a quick reminder from Moiraine about the stakes and he easily acquiesed to the bond. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished the book in 3 days (as I said, quite short), but the other books in the series are at least twice as long, and there are 14 more books to go, so I think there should be plently leftover by the time the trip rolls around.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Hardy Boys
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/hardy-boys/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/hardy-boys/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Between the ages of 10-12, my reading diet consisted almost exclusively of the teenage-targetted detective series &lt;em&gt;The Hardy Boys&lt;/em&gt;. For me, the term invokes the names Frank and Joe before the Matt and Jeff of WWE fame. We had a fairly wide collection of the blue-hardcovered books of those days. And I believe I made the effort to read every single book in that particular series, through borrowing and such. I think I was successful, but I can&amp;rsquo;t be sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case , that meant this article piqued my interest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2019/01/reading-hardy-boys-nostalgia-disappointment-racism/581071/&#34;&gt;The Knotty Nostalgia of the Hardy Boys Series&lt;/a&gt;
Why one writer still reads the wildly popular books with a mixture of love and disappointment, 60 years after they were revised to remove racist content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading the series as a child, I never felt any serious racist undertones, probably because the versions I had were already torn down. Or more likely, because as a child I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any real concept of race. Sure, Frank and Joe were depicted as white kids on the book covers, but that meant nothing to this brown kid from Asia, even though I was certainly aware of caucasians and blacks by then. As far as I was concerned, I could have been mixed in with their crowd with no issues. I even remember specifically the Hidden Harbor book mentioned in the article, there were some characters who spoke with a southern accent, I guess they were meant to be black? But I never imagined them in my head as any different from their northern visitors. (There was this one character named Grover who in my head looked like a blue muppet&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our copies of those Hardy Boys books are long gone, but like the article&amp;rsquo;s author I still look back at them with a tinge of nostalgia. I did learn a lot from those books, from vocabulary to American culture to different kinds of hobbies. I think the main charm of the Chet Morton character mentioned in the article is that with every book he always had a new, different hobby, and in that way the teenage readers could learn about some new field or possible area of interest. Later on, we also encountered softbound books of a later Hardy Boys series &lt;em&gt;The Hardy Boys Casefiles&lt;/em&gt;, which was more dark (one of the character&amp;rsquo;s girlfriends got killed), but they lacked the charm, templating or formularity of the old ones, and we never got more than a few books from that series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if these books are still available locally, I don&amp;rsquo;t recall seeing them in bookstores. I think they would still be pretty good reading for young boys these days - the Hardy Boys seem like they&amp;rsquo;d be good role models, they&amp;rsquo;re smart, they do well in school, they&amp;rsquo;re friendly and accepting and they obey the law and perhaps most importantly, they exhibit a sense of curiosity and adventure about the world around them, something many kids these days seem to lose as they grow up.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Quezon City Public Library
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/the-quezon-city-public-library/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/the-quezon-city-public-library/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I pass by the Quezon City Hall every so often, and I&amp;rsquo;ve always been curious about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quezoncitypubliclibrary.org&#34;&gt;QC public library&lt;/a&gt; they have there. It got a bit of press a while back about how it was a nice place to hang out (for a government institution at least), so I had a todo list item about checking it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, last week I did! I passed by on a weekday afternoon about 4pm after running some errands. The library was open until 7pm, so the timing was fine. I went up to the building and the guard asked me what my business was and I said I just wanted to check out the library. He told me that bags weren&amp;rsquo;t allowed inside so I had to go to the baggage counter. Oops, luckily I only had my sling bag and not the full backpack I usually had when carrying a laptop. I left my sling bag at the counter and went inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The space wasn&amp;rsquo;t as large as I thought it would be - the pictures on the website made it seem a bit larger in my imagination. The tables and seats were maybe 75% full, mostly with students and library staff. The main library area was in the first floor. Second floor seemed to be some offices and an outdoor cafe, I didn&amp;rsquo;t explore the second floor too much. I walked around the ground floor rooms for a bit, browsing the shelves. Aside from the main area, there was a separate room specialized for Philippine history and such, a room for kids&amp;rsquo; books, a &amp;ldquo;puppeteers room&amp;rdquo;, and a smaller round room with periodicals and such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a small section for fiction books in the main area; the selection was decent, mostly mainstream titles like Hunger Games, some Robert Ludlum, a few sci-fi/fantasy titles, and so on. For the reference materials, it was about what you&amp;rsquo;d expect from a public library - most of it was dated and donated. The tech/comptuers sections had the sort of obsolete computer books you&amp;rsquo;d find at book sale - like &amp;ldquo;How to use Microsoft Access 95&amp;rdquo;, that kind of thing. There were The World is Flat by Friedman, and Obama&amp;rsquo;s book about hope or such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone showed me how to use one of the computer kiosks to search the library&amp;rsquo;s catalog, and I was told it should be accessible via the website, so that seems fine. If you wanted to know whether they had a particular book, you could just check the website first. Also, the catalog said they had some Thor comics, but they were in the children&amp;rsquo;s corner, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like going in there lol. I also tried connecting my iPad to the local wifi, but the internet wasn&amp;rsquo;t very good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came away not too impressed with the library. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what I was expecting. I guess I was kind of hoping to see if it was a good place to hang out, maybe if I was stranded near city hall due to traffic or waiting around in that area for something. It seems like a fairly good place for students from nearby schools though, especially those with no internet access at home. At least my curiosity was sated and I managed to tick an item off my todo list!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Konmari
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/konmari/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/konmari/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about this Konmari thing. I think it&amp;rsquo;s been around for a while, but got a boost recently due to a Netflix special. I think I agree with it in principle, or at least what I know of it from secondary social media commentary. Minimalism is a worthwhile goal, and so is getting rid of things that do nothing for you other than take up space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people aren&amp;rsquo;t reacting well to the idea of throwing away books though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit 22 Jan: The account has gone private, so the previous embedded tweet is no longer accessible. I&amp;rsquo;m quoting the original text here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do NOT listen to Marie Kondo or Konmari in relation to books. Fill your apartment &amp;amp; world with them. I don’t give a shite if you throw out your knickers and Tupperware but the woman is very misguided about BOOKS. Every human needs a v extensive library not clean, boring shelves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Anakana Schofield (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AnakanaSchofiel&#34;&gt;@AnakanaSchofiel&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jaymelynilao/status/1080957281636835328&#34;&gt;January 3, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s missing the point of decluterring though. The idea is getting rid of things that &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t give you joy&amp;rdquo;, so if having books give you joy, then obviously you keep your books, regardless of whether those books are challenging, difficult, depressing etc. Maybe the point is that you have to be constantly re-evaluating whether the hoarding is a positive spin in your life. (And I say this as someone who has a bunch of books waiting to be read just lying around his room.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this kind of decluttering and minimalism doesn&amp;rsquo;t just apply to possessions though. You should also be looking to give up things like friends, relationships, habits, routines, traditions, and so on, that are no longer net positives or &amp;ldquo;bringing you joy&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s sometimes a bigger picture to look at too. Maybe a specific thing doesn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;bring you joy&amp;rdquo;, but your gradnchildren really like seeing that thing when they visit, and seeing them happy brings you joy, so you keep it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the bigger lesson is to not rely on someone from a Netflix show to tell you how to live your life. It&amp;rsquo;s good to take advice from other people, but everyone has different tastes and different things can bring you joy. You decide what brings you joy.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Form good habits and become their slave
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/form-good-habits-and-become-their-slave/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/form-good-habits-and-become-their-slave/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/suggested-new-years-resolutions/&#34;&gt;New year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions&lt;/a&gt; are hard to maintain, so much so that people will make jokes about opening a gym that only runs during January, since most gym NYRs run out of steam by then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best pieces of advice I&amp;rsquo;ve found regarding acquiring new behaviors comes from the first motivational books I ever read - &lt;em&gt;The Greatest Salesman in the World&lt;/em&gt; by Og Mandino, which for some reason we had a copy of in our house when I was young.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book tells us that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;humans are slaves to habit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bad habits can only be replaced by good habits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, in order to improve your life, you should form good habits and become their slave. So if you have a NYR like &amp;ldquo;quit smoking&amp;rdquo;, you should choose a &amp;ldquo;good habit&amp;rdquo; to replace the &amp;ldquo;bad habit&amp;rdquo; of smoking with. Maybe every time you get an urge to smoke, you pick up a book instead and start reading? Just a suggestion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The rest of Mandino&amp;rsquo;s book consists mostly of recommended self-affirmations, which is the &amp;ldquo;good habit&amp;rdquo; he recommends to improve your life.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Stores
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/book-stores/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 02:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/book-stores/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The other day I was passing through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/the-qc-memorial-circle/&#34;&gt;QC memorial circle&lt;/a&gt; (as is my wont) and I decided to walk around the &lt;em&gt;tiangge&lt;/em&gt;/flea market that&amp;rsquo;s often there. It seemd larger than usual that day, so I figured I should finally take a look. And in the process I remembered what I dislike about local flea markets: 90% of the stalls are selling some form of clothes (which I have no interest in browsing - maybe if these stalls sold something my size for once!) and maybe 9.9% are selling cheap knockoff toys (which &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; interest me if they were free or such) or cellphone accessories. And maybe, on a rare 0.1% occassion, a stall will have something I&amp;rsquo;m interested in browsing: used books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like browsing books for sale. Never mind that I already have too many books to read already. Used book sales are not very common in Metro Manila. I mean, there&amp;rsquo;s the big franchise stores in the mall like National Bookstore or Fully Booked or Powerbooks, but given that I alreayd have too many books to read and how frugal I am, I rarely buy from those stores these days (though I still do browse through them often).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used books sales, especially of the random pop-up kind, are a different matter. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit like treasure hunting in a way, where you&amp;rsquo;re hoping toe be lucky enough to find a bargain (I suppose this is how people who like browsing for clothes feel like at these flea markets).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used book sales aren&amp;rsquo;t very common around here, sadly. There&amp;rsquo;s Book Sale branches in the malls of course, but their selection often isn&amp;rsquo;t very good. Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m picky too! I&amp;rsquo;m usually looking for stuff like science fiction, fantasy, or comics. Or maybe an interesting autobiography or nonfiction book - probably the best purchase I ever made at a Book Sale was getting a copy of &lt;em&gt;The Rock Says&lt;/em&gt;, The Rock&amp;rsquo;s autobiography for cheap (I still have that book around here somewhere).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There also used to be a small used book store called Chapter IX at a small commercial center near where I live. They had a very good selection, a lot of it sci-fi and fantasy. Their prices weren&amp;rsquo;t super cheap though, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t buy much from them. My copy of &lt;em&gt;Dune&lt;/em&gt; came from there. Sadly it isn&amp;rsquo;t there anymore. I think they&amp;rsquo;re mostly just selling books online via Facebook now. Browsing through book pictures online doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel the same as rummaging through stacks of used books - it feels more like intentional buying rather than the browsing I enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s another used book store that I sometimes go to called Bookay-Ukay in Teacher&amp;rsquo;s Village. It&amp;rsquo;s okay - the selection is definitely better than Book Sale. They have some comics and sometimes video game guides too (I like those too!). I think I&amp;rsquo;ve bought at least one pocketbook from them and a couple of comics/guides. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if they&amp;rsquo;re still around - the last time I passed by there it was closed, but they seem to have weird hours so IDK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best used book sale I ever found in the Metro was this pop-up stall that I only saw at the Greenfield market near Shaw Boulevard. This was back when Geekfight was doing regular &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/03/scenes-from-a-quiz-night/&#34;&gt;quiz nights&lt;/a&gt; on Fridays in that area. A number of stalls would be set up there around the Friday night entertainment. Most of the stalls would be food or clothing (as per usual) but there was always at least one stall, sometimes two, selling used books. They both had pretty good selections too, I ended up buying quite a bit from them. I remember buying a couple of Discworld books, some old-school CYOA and &lt;em&gt;Heir to the Empire&lt;/em&gt; (the first Thrawn book) from there. Geekfight stopped doing their quiz nights there after a while though, and since I no longer work in Ortigas, I never really pass anywhere near that area anymore, so I don&amp;rsquo;t know if those used book stalls are still a thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always keep an eye out for book stores, used or not, even when I&amp;rsquo;m travelling in another country. During my first night on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/05/so-i-went-to-hk/&#34;&gt;first trip abroad&lt;/a&gt;, I walked a few blocks around the neighborhood where I was staying and was happy to find a small hole-in-the-wall book store just a couple of streets away. Of course, all the books were in Chinese! During &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/03/europe-trip-2015/&#34;&gt;my Europe trip&lt;/a&gt;, I remember walking along the Seine in Paris and I came along a series of pop-up stalls in some kind of mini-flea market near the river side. Quite a few of them were selling old and/or used books, many of them French, some in English, and I think there were some Asterix comics in Italian I think. I didn&amp;rsquo;t end up buying anything, but it was fun. I also remember finding quite a few used book stores in the Camden Market in London while I was there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, travel tip: you can type &amp;ldquo;book stores near me&amp;rdquo; in Google Maps to see nearby book stores (or any other kind of stores I guess). I do this a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish book stores were more common around here, but I can understand why they aren&amp;rsquo;t too popular. Books often aren&amp;rsquo;t a high priority for the Filipino masses, given all the other challenges in life. I&amp;rsquo;m very lucky to have grown up with parents who not only instilled a love of reading in me, but also had the budget to buy me books all the time. Sadly, these days I don&amp;rsquo;t read too many books anymore (I blame the internet). Hopefully that&amp;rsquo;s something I can correct next year.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Shogun, and the rest of James Clavell&#39;s Asian Saga
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/shogun-and-the-rest-of-james-clavells-asian-saga/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 05:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/shogun-and-the-rest-of-james-clavells-asian-saga/</guid>
            <description>
            
            










&lt;a href=&#34;#7c169b1a268757ed034af1866d963d98-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/shogun-and-the-rest-of-james-clavells-asian-saga/1901150_10152838020443912_1173953250_n1_hu5853308db334f9bcb6abe8d239b5c530_76952_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;7c169b1a268757ed034af1866d963d98-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/shogun-and-the-rest-of-james-clavells-asian-saga/1901150_10152838020443912_1173953250_n1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;1 Nov 2018 5:03am&#34;&gt;1 Nov 2018 5:03am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shogun was the first novel I ever read outside of required school readings and it remains one of favorites to this day after many rereadings. It had it all &amp;ndash; the age of exploration, religious conflict, language barriers, duty, honor, love, betrayal, war, sacrifice, samurai, ninjas, guns, cannons, etc and it still influences my thinking to this day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite quotes from this book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toranaga: &amp;ldquo;Tsukku-san says that the Netherlands were vassals of the Spanish king until just a few years ago. Is that true?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blackthorne: &amp;ldquo;Yes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toranaga: &amp;ldquo;Therefore, the Netherlands – your allies – are in a state of rebellion against their lawful king?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blackthorne: &amp;ldquo;They’re fighting against the Spaniard, yes, but –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toranaga: &amp;ldquo;Isn’t that rebellion? Yes or no?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blackthorne: &amp;ldquo;Yes. But there are mitigating circumstances. Serious miti- &amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toranaga: &amp;ldquo;There are no ‘mitigating circumstances’ when it comes to rebellion against a sovereign lord!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blackthorne: &amp;ldquo;Unless you win.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toranaga looked at him intently. Then laughed uproariously. &amp;ldquo;Yes, Mister Foreigner…you have named _the one _mitigating factor.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I later ended up reading the rest of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Asian_Saga&#34;&gt;Clavell&amp;rsquo;s Asian Saga&lt;/a&gt; (in fact, I believe I still have most of them on my bookshelf), but none of them stuck with me as much as &lt;em&gt;Shogun&lt;/em&gt;. And I just found out there&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a &lt;a href=&#34;https://variety.com/2018/tv/news/fx-alex-garland-devs-limited-series-shogun-1202894554/&#34;&gt;TV adaptation soon&lt;/a&gt;! Hope it&amp;rsquo;s good, looking forward to that one. (I know there was an older TV adaptation before starring Richard Chamberlain and Toshiro Mifune, but I&amp;rsquo;m too lazy to go look for a copy of that.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/shogun-and-the-rest-of-james-clavells-asian-saga/1901150_10152838020443912_1173953250_n1_hu5853308db334f9bcb6abe8d239b5c530_76952_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Masters of Doom by David Kushner
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-masters-of-doom-by-david-kushner/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 01:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-masters-of-doom-by-david-kushner/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a copy of this book for quite a while now, but for some reason only got around to starting on it three days ago. It&amp;rsquo;s not a particularly long book, but I pretty much devoured it in twenty four hours.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#31c9d6ecd9e95ab6056f95bf11438150-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-masters-of-doom-by-david-kushner/doom_screenshot_huaea7d8611a246efb988e49157007cb6b_97425_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mandatory screenshot of old-school Doom&#34; title=&#34;Mandatory screenshot of old-school Doom&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Mandatory screenshot of old-school Doom (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;31c9d6ecd9e95ab6056f95bf11438150-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-masters-of-doom-by-david-kushner/doom_screenshot.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mandatory screenshot of old-school Doom&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;14 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;14 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book traces the paths of the lives of John Romero and John Carmack &amp;ndash; two legends of the software development world that changed PC gaming forever. It&amp;rsquo;s a fantastic read for anyone who grew up playing PC games during the 80s and 90s. It gives us a birds-eye view of what the burgeoning gaming industry was like back then, not just with the technical and business aspects, but a lot of the human aspects as well: there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of drama, conflict, and betrayal to go around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book&amp;rsquo;s narrative does a good job of contrasting the Two Johns: Carmack was a programmer, a technical wizard who pushed the boundaries of game programming where no one else dared go. He was interested purely in the programming and in the creation of virtual worlds and preferred a smaller, leaner, ruthlessly efficient company focused on making the most of his technology. Romero was a gamer first, and an ambitious and competitive one. He was the number one competitor on their own deathmatch games and dreamt of building a gaming empire, living the life of a rock start among the gaming community as the front man of id software. Together their complimentary skill set would take them through a dizzying rise to fame and fortune in the game development world as they blazed new trails, defined new genres, and inspired a new generation of competitors. At the same time, their differences would ultimately cause them to go down different paths &amp;ndash; knowing full well in advance how the story ended for their partnership made me turn the pages quicker as I dreaded the inevitable split.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a gamer since the late eighties, and though I never considered myself particularly good at first-person shooters, I did play most of the games that comprised id software&amp;rsquo;s wonder years &amp;ndash; Wolfenstein 3D, Doom, Doom II, Quake and Quake II. I will freely confess I mostly used the build-in cheat codes to just fool around in most of these games, although I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I finished Quake II&amp;rsquo;s single-player campaign legitimately. We didn&amp;rsquo;t have good internet back then, so the only opportunity I ever had to play Deathmatch back then was split-screen on a console at a friend&amp;rsquo;s house, even then it was helluva fun. Post-Quake II, I never played FPSes much again, though I did enjoy reading about John Romero and Ion Storm and was looking forward to their promised RPG Anachronox and only later heard about what a failure Daikatana turned out to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have this lingering dream of breaking into game development somehow. Though I&amp;rsquo;m not envious of the death march crunch mode periods typically described in the book, I am a bit envious of what a huge advantage it was for geniuses like Carnack and Romero to have been at the right place and time for the nascent games industry to turn them into legends. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;d have had the technical chops to compete with them if I had the same opportunities, but I surely would have given it a go. I consider myself closer in temperament to Carnack than Romero &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;m more interested in the technical side and could probably use some help in the promotion and game design and level design stuff. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ll ever actually get there, but I take solace in this quote from the penultimate chapter of the book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Carmack disdained talk of highfalutin things like legacies but when pressed would allow at least one thought on his own. &#34;In the information age, the barriers just aren’t there,&#34; he said. &#34;The barriers are self-imposed. If you want to set off and go develop some grand new thing, you don’t need millions of dollars of capitalization. You need enough pizza and Diet Coke to stick in your refrigerator, a cheap PC to work on, and the dedication to go through with it. We slept on floors. We waded across rivers.&#34; &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-masters-of-doom-by-david-kushner/doom_screenshot_huaea7d8611a246efb988e49157007cb6b_97425_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Mandatory screenshot of old-school Doom&lt;/p&gt;
    



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The 1-Page Marketing Plan by Allan Dib
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-the-1-page-marketing-plan-by-allan-dib/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 01:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/book-review-the-1-page-marketing-plan-by-allan-dib/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I realise it&amp;rsquo;s a bit weird for me to be reviewing a marketing book, given my self-proclaimed aversion to marketing and sales. A while back I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2018/06/book-review-tribe-of-mentors-by-tim-ferris/&#34;&gt;review for Tim Ferris&amp;rsquo; book Tribe of Mentors&lt;/a&gt; on this blog, and for some reason someone decided to contact me citing this review and asked if I would review this other book and they would give me a complimentary copy. This was something new to me, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try it out! (I guess this a thing I do know. Feel free to send me books on random topics to review!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/1-Page-Marketing-Plan-Customers-Money/dp/1989025013/ref=la_B01B715MGW_1_1?s=books&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1529560817&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;Link to the book on Amazon.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, on to the book: It&amp;rsquo;s relatively short, it only took me a while to get through it because of general busy-ness. Coming from someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much experience in marketing and sales, I think the book gives a decent overview of this space. I have some prior informal knowledge of many of these concepts, but it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have a more structured idea of how the general flow of marketing works. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find a lot of modern marketing techniques distasteful. I&amp;rsquo;m not especially fond of people aggressively push-marketing to me via cold calls or pushing flyers in my face. To the book&amp;rsquo;s credit, it points out that such blind-shotgun techniques are wildly ineffective. And while it doesn&amp;rsquo;t go into too much detail about each particular area, I think having a more solid understanding of modern marketing techniques and mentalities will help me &amp;ldquo;understand the enemy&amp;rdquo; better, so to speak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to the 1-page marketing plan itself: I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough marketing knowledge to say whether it&amp;rsquo;s really an innovation in implementation as the author claims, but it seems like a reasonable checklist for a business to consider when planning out their marketing activities. If I ever manage to talk myself into starting a business, the overview given by this book would certainly be useful. The book itself isn&amp;rsquo;t very expensive, so I think it&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable buy for someone new to the marketing space.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Tribe of Mentors by Tim Ferris
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/06/book-review-tribe-of-mentors-by-tim-ferris/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 01:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/06/book-review-tribe-of-mentors-by-tim-ferris/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This book was on sale on Amazon Kindle a while back, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d give it a whirl. Some years ago I had read one of the author&amp;rsquo;s previous books, &lt;em&gt;The Four Hour Workweek&lt;/em&gt;, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too impressed. It was interesting at least, but a lot of the advice seemed either difficult to apply to my personal situation or involved doing stuff I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really interested in (i.e. sales and marketing and whatnot). But this new book intrigued me &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s a collection of life advice from &amp;ldquo;mentors&amp;rdquo;, basically successful people from a wild variety of fields including entrepreneurs, celebrities, venture capitalists, athletes, chefs, scholars, bloggers, authors, and so on. I&amp;rsquo;m always a sucker for this sort of thing &amp;ndash; even if I don&amp;rsquo;t learn anything myself personally, it&amp;rsquo;s always interesting to learn how other people approach life. Spoilers: I enjoyed the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s some common themes that are often repeated among the different mentors in the book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many recommend some form of meditation, whether it be transcendental or something else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many stress how important it was to them to be able to say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to unnecessary commitments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of them recommend some form of nonconformity and taking the time to find your own path&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some great examples of learning from failures and really makes you think about how we often overreact to failures that later on turn out to be not that big a deal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was often pleasantly surprised by how well-read some of the celebrities turned out to be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each mentor also gives a short list of books they often give out as gifts, and there&amp;rsquo;s a *lot* of interesting books mentioned, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably try to read quite a few of them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also started using this function in the Kindle app which let&amp;rsquo;s me highlight some parts and save them for later. I would send those quotes to Google Keep. (Although to be honest there were a lot I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to note down, mostly because I was lazy.) Here are the ones I did manage to save:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;People think focus means saying yes to the thing you’ve got to focus on. But that’s not what it means at all. It means saying no to the hundred other good ideas that there are. You have to pick carefully. I’m actually as proud of the things we haven’t done as the things I have done. Innovation is saying no to 1,000 things.&amp;rdquo; –Steve Jobs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I say no to nearly everything. I make a lot fewer short-term compromises. I aspire to only work with people who I can work with forever, to invest my time in activities that are a joy unto themselves, and to focus on the extremely long term.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Naval Ravikant, CEO and co-founder of AngelList&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;God will not have his work made manifest by cowards.&amp;quot;—Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Desire is a contract that you make with yourself to be unhappy until you get what you want.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Naval Ravikant, CEO and co-founder of AngelList&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;First, whenever possible, connect with others. Second, with enthusiasm, strive always to create fun and delight for others. And third, lean into each moment and encounter expecting magic—or miracles.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Adam Robinson, educator, freelance author, and US Chess Federation life master&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&amp;ldquo;Too often, I hear people effectively given advice that is consistent with sunk cost fallacies. I certainly heard it a lot. &amp;ldquo;You’ve spent X years learning Y, you can’t just up and leave and now do Z,&amp;rdquo; they say. I think this is flawed advice because it weighs too heavily the time behind you, which can’t be changed, and largely discounts the time&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Peter Attia, Surgeon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&amp;ldquo;Yet change is usually stressful, and after a certain age, most people don’t like to change. When you are 16, your entire life is change, whether you like it or not. Your body is changing, your mind is changing, your relationships are changing—everything is in flux. You are busy inventing yourself. By the time you are 40, you don’t want change. You want stability. But in the twenty-first century, you won’t be able to enjoy that luxury. If you try to hold on to some stable identity, some stable job, some stable worldview, you will be left behind, and the world will fly by you. So people will need to be extremely resilient and emotionally balanced to sail through this never-ending storm, and to deal with very high levels of stress.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Yuval Noah Harari, author of Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&amp;ldquo;So you have no choice but to really get to know yourself better. Know who you are and what you really want from life. This is, of course, the oldest advice in the book: know thyself. But this advice has never been more urgent than in the 21st century. Because now you have competition. Google, Facebook, Amazon, and the government are all relying on big data and machine learning to get to know you better and better. We are not living in the era of hacking computers—we are living in the era of hacking humans. Once the corporations and governments know you better than you know yourself, they could control and manipulate you and you won’t even realize it. So if you want to stay in the game, you have to run faster than Google. Good luck!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Yuval Noah Harari again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I read a book like this it refreshes me a little bit and gives me a better sense of perspective and inspires me to do more things that I want to do and maybe live life a little bit more on my own terms. (Whether I actually execute on that, well that&amp;rsquo;s a different matter all together.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: 11/22/63 by King, Stephen
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/03/11-22-63/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/03/11-22-63/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10644930-11-22-63&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;11/22/63&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1327876792l/10644930._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10644930-11-22-63&#34;&gt;11/22/63&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3389.Stephen_King&#34;&gt;Stephen King&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2345577523&#34;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This was my first Stephen King book outside the Dark Tower series. Before reading the Dark Tower, I had pegged King as a writer of &amp;ldquo;scary&amp;rdquo; books because of his early works, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too interested. This book is none of that. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice, informative, well-written time travel story that wraps up nicely. I actually had no idea it was a time travel story when I started reading (you&amp;rsquo;d think the title would have given that away.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;When reading novels with a compelling plot, I tend to charge forward haphazardly, often skimming sentences and paragraphs to get to what happens next. For this one I often found myself slowing down to appreciate King&amp;rsquo;s prose. He&amp;rsquo;s quite good at writing compelling and descriptive sentences that aren&amp;rsquo;t just direct and simple &amp;ldquo;This happened, then he saw that.&amp;rdquo; etc. I suppose that comes from his prolific experience.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The book had a bit of a weaker middle part where I lingered around for a few months before finally deciding to finish it over the long weekend. I learned a lot about American history and geopolitics around the time of the Cuban missile crisis along the way too.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The Hero of Ages by Sanderson, Brandon
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/the-hero-of-ages/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/the-hero-of-ages/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2767793-the-hero-of-ages&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;The Hero of Ages (Mistborn, #3)&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1480717763l/2767793._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/2767793-the-hero-of-ages&#34;&gt;The Hero of Ages&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38550.Brandon_Sanderson&#34;&gt;Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2109440552&#34;&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It was ok. Some tropes turned around. Kind of frustrating how a lot of stuff just dragged out until the end. The identify of the Hero of Ages pretty much given away early on by the flavor text at the start of each chapter. I finished it in two sittings so that&amp;rsquo;s something
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The Final Empire by Sanderson, Brandon
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/the-final-empire/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/the-final-empire/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68428.The_Final_Empire&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;The Final Empire (Mistborn, #1)&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1480717416l/68428._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68428.The_Final_Empire&#34;&gt;The Final Empire&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38550.Brandon_Sanderson&#34;&gt;Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2104551754&#34;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Great book. The story&amp;rsquo;s pace was a bit slow at first as Sanderson was doing his excellent worldbuilding and introducing us to the magic system in his world (he&amp;rsquo;s good at that sort of thing!), but it picks up about a third of the way through. A lot of the plot twists and character developments are handled very well. The pace proceeds fairly quickly towards the end - I burned through the last third of the book in one night because things were escalating quickly. Looking forward to the other books in the series
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The Well of Ascension by Sanderson, Brandon
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/the-well-of-ascension/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/the-well-of-ascension/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68429.The_Well_of_Ascension&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;The Well of Ascension (Mistborn, #2)&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1480717596l/68429._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/68429.The_Well_of_Ascension&#34;&gt;The Well of Ascension&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38550.Brandon_Sanderson&#34;&gt;Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/2106145410&#34;&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I finished Well of Ascension only two days after finishing The Final Empire. I think I enjoyed it a bit less than the first book - mainly because there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of self-doubt here among the protagonists, a lot of paragraphs of &amp;ldquo;why am i doing this? I&amp;rsquo;m not good enough, etc&amp;rdquo;. The plot also takes longer to solidify. Unlike the first book where they had a very solid objective until the end (the downfall of the Final Empire), the protagonists spend most of this book running in circles trying to figure out what they should do.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That being said, I did read through the book in two days, so I still found it compelling. Sanderson expands upon the worldbuilding, mythos and systems from the first book. The first book already had a theme of hopelessness around it, but the second book goes even darker. And as you can expect for the second book of a trilogy, the ending doesn&amp;rsquo;t leave our heroes or the world in a very good spot. Looking forward to the final book.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The Dance of the Possible: the mostly honest completely irreverent guide to creativity by Berkun, Scott
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/the-dance-of-the-possible/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/the-dance-of-the-possible/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34516374-the-dance-of-the-possible&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;The Dance of the Possible: the mostly honest completely irreverent guide to creativity&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1489031935l/34516374._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34516374-the-dance-of-the-possible&#34;&gt;The Dance of the Possible: the mostly honest completely irreverent guide to creativity&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/105025.Scott_Berkun&#34;&gt;Scott Berkun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1942933254&#34;&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Scott Berkun&amp;rsquo;s latest book is short but pretty sweet. Irreverent and insightful, a great read for anyone looking to jump into creative endeavors!
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Heir to the Empire by Zahn, Timothy
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/heir-to-the-empire/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/heir-to-the-empire/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/216443.Heir_to_the_Empire&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Heir to the Empire (Star Wars: The Thrawn Trilogy, #1)&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1512169411l/216443._SY160_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/216443.Heir_to_the_Empire&#34;&gt;Heir to the Empire&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/12479.Timothy_Zahn&#34;&gt;Timothy Zahn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1941667381&#34;&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I realize that the Thrawn trilogy is no longer canon, what with The Force Awakens and all. But I remember reading an interview with Zahn in Inquest Magazine a lifetime ago and how his trilogy was one of the best parts of the extended universe so when I found a used copy I picked it up. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The story is pretty good, taking place 5 years after Jedi, and explores what happens to the galaxy and the efforts of the Empire remnants to mount a comeback. A far cry from what Disney eventually approved to be the canon storyline of course :)
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: What the Dog Saw and Other Adventures by Gladwell, Malcolm
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/what-the-dog-saw-and-other-adventures/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/what-the-dog-saw-and-other-adventures/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6516450-what-the-dog-saw-and-other-adventures&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;What the Dog Saw and Other Adventures&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1344263875l/6516450._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6516450-what-the-dog-saw-and-other-adventures&#34;&gt;What the Dog Saw and Other Adventures&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/1439.Malcolm_Gladwell&#34;&gt;Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1919268914&#34;&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t even know when I started reading this, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a bookmark in it for maybe three or four years now. It&amp;rsquo;s a collection of Gladwell&amp;rsquo;s articles from the New Yorker, so that&amp;rsquo;s to be expected - not exactly designed to be consumed all in one sitting. The book is Gladwell&amp;rsquo;s usual mix of anecdotes spun into pop psychology and meant to make you ask questions or suggest some insight about this or that. It&amp;rsquo;s entertaining enough to read, even though it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really go into much detail about any one topic.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Trigger Warning: Short Fictions and Disturbances by Gaiman, Neil
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/trigger-warning/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/trigger-warning/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22522808-trigger-warning&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Trigger Warning: Short Fictions and Disturbances&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1415036119l/22522808._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22522808-trigger-warning&#34;&gt;Trigger Warning: Short Fictions and Disturbances&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/1221698.Neil_Gaiman&#34;&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1905365439&#34;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Some of these are creepy af, but this is my second Gaiman short story collection so I mostly knew what to expect. The man is a master at putting together words though. I could only aspire to be so good.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The Hobbit or There and Back Again by Tolkien, J.R.R.
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/the-hobbit-or-there-and-back-again/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/the-hobbit-or-there-and-back-again/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5907.The_Hobbit_or_There_and_Back_Again&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;The Hobbit or There and Back Again&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1546071216l/5907._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/5907.The_Hobbit_or_There_and_Back_Again&#34;&gt;The Hobbit or There and Back Again&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/656983.J_R_R_Tolkien&#34;&gt;J.R.R. Tolkien&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1867502912&#34;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Starting the year off right with some Tolkien. The book is unapologetic about how it drags both unsuspecting Bilbo and the reader down a long adventure that includes a lot of singing and being captured and being almost eaten. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how they managed to stretch it into three movies though, the book isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly long.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The Prince by Machiavelli, Niccolò
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/the-prince/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/the-prince/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28862.The_Prince&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;The Prince&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1390055828l/28862._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28862.The_Prince&#34;&gt;The Prince&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/16201.Niccol_Machiavelli&#34;&gt;Niccolò Machiavelli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1852306030&#34;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This book is so Machiavellian. Somehow appropriate as my last book for 2016.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/805050532834353152/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 14:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/805050532834353152/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;2016 Reading Challenge, 29/52: Guards, Guards by Terry Pratchett&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The Amber Spyglass by Pullman, Philip
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/the-amber-spyglass/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/the-amber-spyglass/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18122.The_Amber_Spyglass&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;The Amber Spyglass (His Dark Materials, #3)&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1329189152l/18122._SY160_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18122.The_Amber_Spyglass&#34;&gt;The Amber Spyglass&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3618.Philip_Pullman&#34;&gt;Philip Pullman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1822050997&#34;&gt;3 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Pros:&lt;br /&gt;- I liked having the bear back&lt;br /&gt;- Diamond-legged creatures with wheels!&lt;br /&gt;- An honest effort to tie up all the loose ends and give each character decent endings&lt;br /&gt;- A decent read, at least&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Cons:&lt;br /&gt;- allegories aren&amp;rsquo;t very subtle&lt;br /&gt;- people get miraculously redeemed, even Mrs Coulter who was such a great villain&lt;br /&gt;- build up of Asriel&amp;rsquo;s awesome plan to take the War to Heaven only to find out he didn&amp;rsquo;t really know what he was doing until he found out he had to somehow help two kids find their pets&lt;br /&gt;- build up of how powerful Metatron was, but then at the end &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The Subtle Knife by Pullman, Philip
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/the-subtle-knife/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/the-subtle-knife/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/119324.The_Subtle_Knife&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;The Subtle Knife (His Dark Materials, #2)&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1505766360l/119324._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/119324.The_Subtle_Knife&#34;&gt;The Subtle Knife&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3618.Philip_Pullman&#34;&gt;Philip Pullman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1820847091&#34;&gt;3 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Well, the knife may be subtle, but the allegories are not. I can see why some religious folk might find the trilogy&amp;rsquo;s themes controversial, but as far as I can see they&amp;rsquo;re still just fantasy stories. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how things ramp up in the last book.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I kind of miss that bear though.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The Omega Men: The End is Here by King, Tom
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/the-omega-men/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/the-omega-men/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25790655-the-omega-men&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;The Omega Men: The End is Here&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1470552239l/25790655._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25790655-the-omega-men&#34;&gt;The Omega Men: The End is Here&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/6423138.Tom_King&#34;&gt;Tom King&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1818612533&#34;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Violent, mysterious, and the story unveils in a great way. Art was terrific too, even if there were some issues with guest artists. Some of the best comic-book space sci-fi I&amp;rsquo;ve read since the Annihilation War
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;I am Terry Goodkind, author of NEST (11/15/2016). AMA&#39; on /r/books at https://reddit.com/r/books/comments/5czenp/i_am_terry_goodkind_author_of_nest_11152016_ama/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/da0q1c0/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 02:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/da0q1c0/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;I am Terry Goodkind, author of NEST (11/15/2016). AMA&amp;#39; on /r/books at https://reddit.com/r/books/comments/5czenp/i_am_terry_goodkind_author_of_nest_11152016_ama/:

            &lt;p&gt;Hello, I hope you find the time to answer my questions :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read the Sword of Truth series (up to Confessor - I have not read any of the later books) perhaps a decade ago. I enjoyed the series for the most part, but I always felt that the first few books were the strongest, and towards the end of the series (starting around Faith of the Fallen) I felt that the characters had become a bit too&amp;hellip;shall we say &amp;ldquo;preachy&amp;rdquo; about their particular worldviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My questions are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you initially plan the series to be so many books?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was it originally your plan to introduce philosophical themes such as Objectivist ideas later on in the books?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which parts of the series would you say are the strongest and you are most proud of?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any technical advice you would give to an aspiring fantasy writer trying to get a book sold?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The Golden Compass by Pullman, Philip
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/10/the-golden-compass/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/10/the-golden-compass/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/119322.The_Golden_Compass&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;The Golden Compass (His Dark Materials, #1)&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1505766203l/119322._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/119322.The_Golden_Compass&#34;&gt;The Golden Compass&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3618.Philip_Pullman&#34;&gt;Philip Pullman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1778115581&#34;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Well, the book started off a bit slow, with the protag meandering about while the author did his worldbuilding and all, but the pace picked up quickly after the first third or so of the book; I finished the rest of it one sitting&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t see anything too Church-controversial yet, though I&amp;rsquo;m told it becomes more obvious by the third book. I like how most of it was told through a child&amp;rsquo;s eyes. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that was the best way to end a first book though&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I kind of want to see the movie, even though I heard it tanked, mostly just to watch the awesome bear duel to the death
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Hyperion by Simmons, Dan
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/hyperion/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/hyperion/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/77566.Hyperion&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Hyperion (Hyperion Cantos, #1)&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1405546838l/77566._SY160_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/77566.Hyperion&#34;&gt;Hyperion&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/2687.Dan_Simmons&#34;&gt;Dan Simmons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1731819576&#34;&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I randomly decided to start reading a new book the other day and picked up Hyperion completely blind. I knew it was sci-fi, but that was about it&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And it turned out to be some really good sci-fi too. Simmons introduces new concepts and the history of his universe and human society quickly and unapologetically. Even the prologue bandies around the terms Hegemony and Ouster with little explanation save what we can glean from context. Most of it is expounded upon and elaborated in the short stories which comprise the majority of the book.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The short stories tell the tales of each of the pilgrims making their way to the far off world of Hyperion to face their death before a time-defying god. It seems that each story follows and develops a different aspect of Hyperion&amp;rsquo;s universe: the first one tells us about religion and space travel and colonisation, the second talks about military life, and so on. My favorite was the scholar&amp;rsquo;s story: although the preceding parts of the story make the ending especially predictable, how he gets there is told incredibly well and you can feel the sadness and despair of his situation&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The disappointing part of the book however was the ending, which seemingly just drops the story like a rock. The last story to be told doesn&amp;rsquo;t even explain why the pilgrim wanted to return to Hyperion, and we do not get the climactic meeting the rest of the book has been leading up to. I understand that the story was actually split into two books, and that I would have to read the succeeding book Fall of Hyperion to get any payoff, but I wish it had been handled better&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In spite of that, I liked it. And maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll pick up the sequel too. Some really good sci-fi and world-building and storytelling with a disappointing ending.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/bi81okkh2ww/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 18:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/bi81okkh2ww/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Could have sworn I also had a copy of Colour of Magic and Lords and Ladies, but these were the only ones I found&amp;hellip; I wonder if I should collect them all lol #discworld&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/bi81okkh2ww/1e5a6967fe3c620fb9c18f703eea7303_hu9b2e44c1f23b3d5d749988d789a9f627_135593_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Equal Rites by Pratchett, Terry
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/equal-rites/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/equal-rites/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34507.Equal_Rites&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Equal Rites (Discworld, #3; Witches, #1)&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1407706800l/34507._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/34507.Equal_Rites&#34;&gt;Equal Rites&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/1654.Terry_Pratchett&#34;&gt;Terry Pratchett&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1724328950&#34;&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I bought a used copy of this book a while back and finally decided to read it, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly long. I&amp;rsquo;d found however, that I&amp;rsquo;d already read it before lol. Anyway, I still managed to read through it a second time, it was pretty good. I like the Discworld books, they&amp;rsquo;re ridiculous, popcorn fantasy reads, and this one was no exception. However I do believe I should now track which ones I&amp;rsquo;ve actually read&amp;hellip;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: The Trading Code by Cam, Jason
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/the-trading-code/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/the-trading-code/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29406076-the-trading-code&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;The Trading Code&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1456991538l/29406076._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/29406076-the-trading-code&#34;&gt;The Trading Code&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/15054424.Jason_Cam&#34;&gt;Jason Cam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1672855581&#34;&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Pretty informative and helpful stuff for beginners to stock trading, although I reckon it will still take time and experience to get the hang of stock trading. I was interested in the math so I&amp;rsquo;m happy that the book discussed the formulas for most of the indicators used (with the exception of the ADX)
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Fragile Things: Short Fictions and Wonders by Gaiman, Neil
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/fragile-things/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/fragile-things/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16788.Fragile_Things&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Fragile Things: Short Fictions and Wonders&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1386924550l/16788._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16788.Fragile_Things&#34;&gt;Fragile Things: Short Fictions and Wonders&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/1221698.Neil_Gaiman&#34;&gt;Neil Gaiman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1672855718&#34;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Some good stuff by Gaiman. Generally what you&amp;rsquo;d expect: ghosts and aliens and magic creatures and strange stories and such. There&amp;rsquo;s an American Gods-related novella at the end.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Epic Legends of the Magic Sword Kings by Holkins, Jerry
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/epic-legends-of-the-magic-sword-kings/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/epic-legends-of-the-magic-sword-kings/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/287109.Epic_Legends_of_the_Magic_Sword_Kings&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Epic Legends of the Magic Sword Kings (Penny Arcade, #2)&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1403199476l/287109._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/287109.Epic_Legends_of_the_Magic_Sword_Kings&#34;&gt;Epic Legends of the Magic Sword Kings&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/166500.Jerry_Holkins&#34;&gt;Jerry Holkins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1672856419&#34;&gt;4 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s fun to look back at how both Penny Arcade and the gaming industry has changed over the years
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>