<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>games on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/games/</link>
      <description>Recent content in games on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 07:19:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Digital Boardgames Review: Root
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/digital-boardgames-review-root/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 07:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/digital-boardgames-review-root/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been regularly playing digital boardgames online on Steam with one of my friend groups, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do reviews of them. This is my fourth such review, and this time I&amp;rsquo;m gonna talk about &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/965580/Root/&#34;&gt;Root&lt;/a&gt;. This is a IRL boardgame by Leder Games with the Steam version published by Dire Wolf Digital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Root is a competitive game themed about multiple factions vying for supremacy in a forest area. Each faction vies for control of clearings, draws cards that provide special abilities or items, and generally tries to stop the others from winning the game, which is done via points. The base game has four different factions to choose from (with the Vagabond faction having three different variants) and each faction plays very differently and scores points differently. So there is a bit of a learning curve to familiarize yourself with all the different factions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cats (Marquis) faction are the like the dominant empire in the area, and they gain points primarily by establishing more buildings, but among the factions they get the fewest actions per turn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The birds (Eyrie) represent an old empire trying to make a comeback; they score points primarily by establishing roosts but they follow a strict set of decrees that govern what they must do each turn. If they fail to obey the decrees, their government goes into turmoil, loses some points and has to start over with a new leader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Woodland Alliance represent plucky rebels aiming to establish their own government. They earn points by spreading sympathizers across the map. Whenever other factions attack them or move troops through sympathizer clearings, they earn more supporters, which can be used to establish bases (which let you recruit warriors) and gain even more supporters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, the Vagabond is a freelance adventurer, wandering around the land digging up treasure for ruins and trading for items. He gets stronger the more items he has, can score points by crafting new items, completing quests, or fighting other factions. He can lend his support or even ally with one of the factions for a coalition victory. The Vagabond has several variants that start with different item sets and each have a unique special action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recently released (on Steam anyway) Riverfolk expansion adds two more factions and three more Vagabond variants to the game, adding replay value and more variation to an already very varied game. Each game lasts around an hour or so, which is totally reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Root is without question the one my regular gaming group has spent the most time playing among the digital boardgames. Not only because it&amp;rsquo;s fun (and we love interfering with whatever the others are planning), but it mostly because it has a feature none of the other games we&amp;rsquo;ve tried have: asynchronous multiplayer games. That means we can start a game and take our turns even while the others are offline, and people can just come and take their turn as they please (within the limit of minimum one turn every three days).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means at the end of our weekly gaming sessions, no matter what we&amp;rsquo;ve played, we usually end with starting a new Root game, that we play throughout the following week. Sometimes we can get two or three games done during the duration of the week, finishing the last game when we start our next weekly gaming session. We&amp;rsquo;ve been playing the game almost continuously since the Steam release in September 2020 and the physical boardgame has at least two other expansions lined up that aren&amp;rsquo;t on Steam yet, so it&amp;rsquo;s very likely that we&amp;rsquo;ll continue to play it for many more months and perhaps years to come.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/digital-boardgames-review-root/20210206231830_1_hu82b45758b8fe844de805b2bef2797491_503727_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/digital-boardgames-review-root/20210314205428_1_hu0497b5492076e39329a70644844e53f6_440608_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/05/digital-boardgames-review-root/20210502005350_1_hu75c9a4d0330488ba854adfb56cb0a1b9_645229_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Digital Boardgames Review: Blood Rage
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/digital-boardgames-review-blood-rage/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 03:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/digital-boardgames-review-blood-rage/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been regularly playing digital boardgames online on Steam with one of my friend groups, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do reviews of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s review is for &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1015930/Blood_Rage_Digital_Edition/&#34;&gt;Blood Rage: Digital Edition&lt;/a&gt;. This is a Norse mythology themed game based on a IRL boardgame. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those &amp;ldquo;place your guys on the map&amp;rdquo; boardgame where each player vies for control of provinces. The game is divided into three ages, and at the end of each age one of the provinces is destroyed as part of ragnarok. The players place units in each of the provinces, which have limited slots for units. During your turn you can choose to pillage a province, and other players can fight you for it if they have units there as well or can send units from adjacent provinces. A successfully pillage earns you a stat boost, and successfully defeating other players earns you glory, which is used to score for victory at the end of the game. The age ends when all the provinces have been pillaged or all the players no longer have any possible actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start of each age the players draft 6 cards that will be available for them to use during the age. These include battle cards (which give you bonuses or abilities when fighting to pillage territories), upgrade cards (which give you either new abilities or new units or monsters to summon, each with special powers), or quests (which give you glory and stat bonuses at the end of the age if you fulfill their conditions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The battle and upgrade cards are mostly themed around the Norse Gods - Odin, Thor, Loki, Frigga, and Tyr. Each god has a different set of effects, and some can change your strategy so that you can win without having to actually win battles. For example, Tyr&amp;rsquo;s battle cards are all about giving you bonuses to combat, but Loki&amp;rsquo;s cards are all about earning you benefits when you lose combats. In many of our games, one of the player ends up being the &amp;ldquo;Loki player&amp;rdquo; who just joins every battle he can trying to gain those Loki bonuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battles are encouraged though; many of the upgrades and quests reward you with more glory for fighting and dying in battle, and having your units destroyed in ragnarok gives glory bonuses as well. At the start of each age, all previously destroyed units are again available for placement, so constantly getting into fights and getting sent to Valhalla can be a strategy as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve also gotten and played two of the expansions DLCs: &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1354120/Blood_Rage_Digital_Edition__Mystics_of_Midgard/&#34;&gt;Mystics of Midgard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1366580/Blood_Rage_Digital_Edition__Gods_of_Asgard/&#34;&gt;Gods of Asgard&lt;/a&gt; (recently released). Mystics add a new unit type that can be drafted, including an annoying unit that can&amp;rsquo;t be killed as long as it has a province to retreat to after battle. The mystics usually end of being high draft picks. Gods of Asgard adds two randomly chosen Norse God figures to the board (among the 5 mentioned above), each one applies special properties to the province where they&amp;rsquo;re in, and they move do a different province after every pillage attempt. For example, Tyr makes it so that battles in the province only count battle cards and not the strength of the involved units; while Frigga makes it so that units in the province cannot die in battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game was a bit buggy when we first got it in mid 2020, since it was just released, but it has steadily improved since then. We played it again recently after some time away and noted many improvements to the UI and quality of life changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is fun; we&amp;rsquo;ve played a reasonable amount of it (I&amp;rsquo;m at around 47 hours as of this writing.) It&amp;rsquo;s the kind of game where it&amp;rsquo;s easy and fun to mess around with what your opponents are doing, especially if you drafted some of the trickier cards. The only bad side would be that the games tend to go long, especially if someone drafted a good Loki deck or the Mystics are around or other such tricks. In our last session, we played 2 games for around 3 hours total.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/digital-boardgames-review-blood-rage/20200705002213_1_hu67d08d6bdd0d768722de48757ad655f8_619065_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/digital-boardgames-review-blood-rage/20200712000905_1_hu60211bd50aa1d756022c62674ab9717e_197990_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game Review: Knightin&#39;
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 04:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A while back, on a whim I purchased this indie game &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/922710/Knightin/&#34;&gt;Knightin&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; on Steam. I forget how I came across it and why I decided to buy, but no regrets. It&amp;rsquo;s a tightly-focused dungeon crawler in the style of original Legend of Zelda/Link to the Past dungeons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each dungeon is a set of rooms you clear one at a time, until you get  to the dungeon boss and beat him. Clearing rooms involves defeating  enemies, solving puzzles, avoiding obstacles and opening chests. It&amp;rsquo;s a  short game, there are only four dungeons to clear each slightly more difficult than the last. There is no plot at all. The game itself openly admits this by painting the thinnest of flavors. You play Sir Lootalot and you want to beat the evil dark lord at the end of the fourth dungeon. For treasure! No princess to save or anything like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I say &amp;ldquo;tightly-focused&amp;rdquo;, I mean that the game is barebones and does only what it says, but it does it very well. I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of how well-designed it is. It&amp;rsquo;s entirely predictable, you know what you&amp;rsquo;re getting into, but each part is executed really well. Each dungeon consists of multiple floors. Each floor has exactly twelve rooms, arranged in the same 3x4 rectangle shape every time. There&amp;rsquo;s a minimap that never changes shape, but maps room paths as you go. The minimap has a nice notation that indicates things like stairs up, stairs down, a merchant, a warp point, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combat is simple and straightforward as well. You don&amp;rsquo;t get a plethora of weapons like Link does in the Zelda series. You start out with a sword (obviously) and later you get access to a wand that lets you shoot fireballs, and those are your only weapons ever. Later you also learn to dash (which hits enemies with the sword), fire dash (which leaves a trail of flames as you dash), and learn a spin attack (a la Link to the Past). You only ever have to remember four buttons: swing sword, shoot wand, dash, and raise shield (and I very rarely use the shield).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obstacles in your way include enemies of course, and the difficulty ramp is great here as well. You start out with enemies that just walk around randomly and they damage you if they bump you. As you progress you meet more complicated foes. Enemies with ranged attacks. Enemies that chase you. Enemies that can move faster. Enemies that can pop out from under your feet. Enemies that can reproduce. And so on. They are always introduced one new enemy at a time so you get to know their shtick before you meet them in more difficult rooms. Rooms can also have obstacles, such as blades that suddenly jut out of the ground, rotating saw blades, pillars that shoot projectiles, and so on, all adding to room difficulty. Some rooms will have a merchant who sells stuff (you get gold from enemy drops), or chests you can open. Everything is pre-placed, no procedural generation here.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#d621fbf9a9ac70145a465c88aca90db5-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/enemies_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_274814_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Later rooms contain multiple enemies of different types and some dungeon mechanisms too.&#34; title=&#34;Later rooms contain multiple enemies of different types and some dungeon mechanisms too.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Later rooms contain multiple enemies of different types and some dungeon mechanisms too. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;d621fbf9a9ac70145a465c88aca90db5-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/enemies.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Later rooms contain multiple enemies of different types and some dungeon mechanisms too.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&#34;&gt;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#5c60eaefaea532db8744b8b2555edad4-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/merchant_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_266631_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Each dungeon has a merchant named Mr Businessmage, he sells healing and various upgrades.&#34; title=&#34;Each dungeon has a merchant named Mr Businessmage, he sells healing and various upgrades.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Each dungeon has a merchant named Mr Businessmage, he sells healing and various upgrades. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;5c60eaefaea532db8744b8b2555edad4-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/merchant.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Each dungeon has a merchant named Mr Businessmage, he sells healing and various upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&#34;&gt;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#417cc9be1594a07faeeea9d035ef8475-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/obstacles_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_274074_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Later floors will have pillars which act as obstacles that you have to unlock to progress.&#34; title=&#34;Later floors will have pillars which act as obstacles that you have to unlock to progress.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Later floors will have pillars which act as obstacles that you have to unlock to progress. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;417cc9be1594a07faeeea9d035ef8475-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/obstacles.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Later floors will have pillars which act as obstacles that you have to unlock to progress.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&#34;&gt;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also some puzzle rooms, which come in two types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;switch rooms, where you need to figure out which switches to turn on to access a chest or unlock a path. These are handled well enough. Although there&amp;rsquo;s no dialog anywhere, hints for the correct switch positions are scattered visually throughout the same floor of the dungeon where they are found. When you encounter a switch room, it&amp;rsquo;s usually just a matter of going back to previous rooms to see what the hints mean.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;block rooms, where you need to push blocks around (only push! no pull!) to get them into the correct positions. I enjoyed the block puzzles more. They are relatively well-designed, and some took me a bit more time than I expected (maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just dumb? Lol)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#8224cb04a6260f2b792a0f75907c4557-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/switch_hints_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_305792_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;An example of a hint for a switch puzzle room, found by moving blocks around.&#34; title=&#34;An example of a hint for a switch puzzle room, found by moving blocks around.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;An example of a hint for a switch puzzle room, found by moving blocks around. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;8224cb04a6260f2b792a0f75907c4557-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/switch_hints.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An example of a hint for a switch puzzle room, found by moving blocks around.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&#34;&gt;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#98b1448dad6c41585b92343a1a6f3f67-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/block_puzzle_hu1f2dd98c9ff3be7f12f615c9c8d56277_336070_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This particular block puzzle gave me some trouble. You have to push the blocks onto the lighted tiles.&#34; title=&#34;This particular block puzzle gave me some trouble. You have to push the blocks onto the lighted tiles.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;This particular block puzzle gave me some trouble. You have to push the blocks onto the lighted tiles. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;98b1448dad6c41585b92343a1a6f3f67-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/block_puzzle.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This particular block puzzle gave me some trouble. You have to push the blocks onto the lighted tiles.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&#34;&gt;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;. Completion in this game is largely straightforward as well. Most of the achievements are geared towards acquiring all the upgrades, opening all chests, and beating all the dungeons. The only two I didn&amp;rsquo;t get (and probably won&amp;rsquo;t bother to) are for doing a speedrun under 90 minutes and for doing a no death run. I tried a couple of post-game runs, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure I can do both of those after some number of tries, but I think I&amp;rsquo;m way too lazy for that. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave it installed and maybe someday I&amp;rsquo;ll get around to it.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#1394a46888e9f689dcc126a7335f3eb1-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/achievements_hu225459d6feb8400b5b3b99c1ac215ed9_174374_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;So close.&#34; title=&#34;So close.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;So close. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;1394a46888e9f689dcc126a7335f3eb1-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/achievements.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So close.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&#34;&gt;24 Feb 2021 4:41am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall&lt;/strong&gt;: A very tight, focused, well-designed and quick indie game experience (my total play time so far is less than 3 hours). It&amp;rsquo;s relatively cheap on Steam too. It&amp;rsquo;s not super groundbreaking or anything, but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it for a couple of hours of entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/achievements_hu225459d6feb8400b5b3b99c1ac215ed9_174374_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;So close.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/block_puzzle_hu1f2dd98c9ff3be7f12f615c9c8d56277_336070_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;This particular block puzzle gave me some trouble. You have to push the blocks onto the lighted tiles.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/enemies_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_274814_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Later rooms contain multiple enemies of different types and some dungeon mechanisms too.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/merchant_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_266631_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Each dungeon has a merchant named Mr Businessmage, he sells healing and various upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/obstacles_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_274074_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Later floors will have pillars which act as obstacles that you have to unlock to progress.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/game-review-knightin/switch_hints_hu9d22806621fe1d1ad4285aeb12c27adf_305792_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;An example of a hint for a switch puzzle room, found by moving blocks around.&lt;/p&gt;
    



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Digital Boardgames Review: Scythe
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-scythe/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 07:09:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-scythe/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been regularly playing digital boardgames online on Steam with one of my friend groups, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do reviews of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second review is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/718560/Scythe_Digital_Edition/&#34;&gt;Scythe: Digital Edition&lt;/a&gt;. Scythe is a competitive game where you play one of seven factions in an alternate history post-war Eastern Europe. Players vie to control territories, hire workers, build mechs, accumulate resources, accomplish secret objectives, and other such goals. Accomplishing secret objectives, winning combats or maximizing one of the several metrics (workers, money, popularity, military power, recruits, structures, mechs, etc) earns you stars, and the game ends when at least one player has six stars. Having six stars doesn&amp;rsquo;t guarantee victory, as points are then tallied up depending on various factors including stars, territories, money, popularity, and so on. Having separate victory and end conditions creates a bit of tension and a balancing act between progressing stars and earning points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Players play as one of seven available factions, each with preset locations on the board. The board is preset and consists of hex tiles, each with different movement limitations and resources that can be produced. The board also has &amp;ldquo;encounters&amp;rdquo; on certain tiles, basically roleplaying opportunities where you get the choice of an action to take, typically trading one type of resource for another, usually a good deal, if you can pay the costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The board is fixed, but each player is randomly assigned a mat that determines the actions available during their turn. The mat is split into top actions (produce, move, bolster, trade) each paired with one of the available bottom actions (upgrade, deploy mech, recruit, build structure). During your turn, you may play one top action followed by the corresponding bottom action, and you cannot do the same action pair on successive turns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weird action structure makes the game challenging. Typically, the top actions generate resources, while the bottom actions consume them to advance your goals. If you get a mat with pairings that are poor for your particular situation, it may take a while for you to get into a regular rhythm of production to actually get anything done. Other players can also interfere with you by sending their character and/or mechs to attack or harass your territory or workers. I usually find that I need to plan ahead 2-3 turns to accomplish a simple goal like building a mech. Beyond the 3-turn window, who knows what the board looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combat is kind of straightforward - you can attack a hex with one or two combat units, and up to two combat units will defend it. Each side can spend up to 7 military power, plus play one combat card per unit on their side, each card adds 2-5 to your total. The attacker wins all ties, favoring aggressors. Due to the way military power and combat cards are accumulated, it&amp;rsquo;s risky to initiate combat unless you have at least 14 military power (this ensures you have a fighting chance against a counterattack). Furthermore, each faction can only gain up to 2 stars from winning combats, so you want to make them count. In our games, we find that typically the winning faction will use two combats to try to earn 2 stars in one turn and end the game, and often those will be the only combats that happen in the entire game. Not sure if we are playing this optimally!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games tend to go at least an hour long, roughly 20 or so turns in our experience. Because of the game&amp;rsquo;s pacing and action structure, you can have games where it feels like I haven&amp;rsquo;t accomplished much by then. Usually this creates a bit of snowball effect as well - the player who gets his act together earlier will tend to pull ahead and be difficult to catch up to. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/ComebackMechanic&#34;&gt;comeback mechanism&lt;/a&gt; we&amp;rsquo;re missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The display is literally just the actual board, and the camera can be a bit finicky sometimes. In my last game I accidentally rotated the view and took a minute to figure out how to get it back. The UI is also fairly sparse and a lot of information or options can be hidden in the weirdest places. Like, figuring out where your faction is allowed to cross rivers can be challenging for new players. I&amp;rsquo;ve attached some screenshots to this post, but they&amp;rsquo;re nothing special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably just relevant to my playgroup, but because of the slow pace, we tend to play a second metagame on top of the endgame scoring, where we consider the player who has spent the least amount of time on his turns (as seen via the turn clock) as &amp;ldquo;winning by time&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the digital board games we&amp;rsquo;ve played, this is the one where we have the least amount of playtime. Unsurprising given how slow the pace is and how difficult it is. For this reason, I think it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to recommend to any boardgame newbies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-scythe/20210220223716_1_hua872809a2f8536b39dff7422d14bd553_386462_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-scythe/20210220224938_1_hua872809a2f8536b39dff7422d14bd553_333187_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-scythe/20210220232853_1_hu165c50b18f1565768a5dbf7205c829d0_351856_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Digital Boardgames Review: Sentinels of the Multiverse
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-sentinels-of-the-multiverse/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 07:34:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-sentinels-of-the-multiverse/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Over the past couple of years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been regularly playing digital boardgames online on Steam with one of my friend groups, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do reviews of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one is &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/337150/Sentinels_of_the_Multiverse/&#34;&gt;Sentinels of the Multiverse&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;ve played the IRL boardgame of it before during one of our sporadic in-person meetups. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, it&amp;rsquo;s a comics-themed coop game where up to 4 people play as a group of heroes to beat a villain (basically comic book shenanigans).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a large variety of heroes available to play, each with unique abilities and play styles. Some of them are straightforward and some are super complicated and fiddly to play. The villains you have to beat vary from super simple to really difficult, with advanced variants for even more challenge. The game also provides a &amp;ldquo;weekly one-shot&amp;rdquo; challenge which provides a fixed scenario/villain and set of heroes to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve played a lot of games of Sentinels, and probably only won something like 60-70% of them. Each game takes around an hour or so, maybe more if it was super difficult. Usually we lose when we choose some combination of random heroes just to try them out then get beaten terribly by the villain. Then we go on a revenge run using one of the simpler heroes like Legacy or Tachyon (or we just put in a healer like Dr Medico).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital version has the advantage that it automates a lot of the ability triggers and checks that the boardgame requires, which would usually be a lot of work. On the other hand, it has a UX disadvantage for those scenarios where an ability triggers multiple times and you want to make the same decision every time. In the real board game, you can just handwave it off by saying &amp;ldquo;Ok, we choose X is every time&amp;rdquo;, but in the digital version you have to click through every confirmation dialog every time.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#9b343c2c14c495c5a8dd6b1afec25ba2-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-sentinels-of-the-multiverse/sentinels_hu55ebca5d49dfa13d3a35dca65e2ada62_322159_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;9b343c2c14c495c5a8dd6b1afec25ba2-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-sentinels-of-the-multiverse/sentinels.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;15 Feb 2021 7:34am&#34;&gt;15 Feb 2021 7:34am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game&amp;rsquo;s aesthetic is very much classic comic books, even multiplayer games are joined by entering a code in the format of a comic book issue like &amp;ldquo;Justice Comics #153&amp;rdquo;. The art isn&amp;rsquo;t the most elaborate and could be better; in fact, they are planning a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.polygon.com/2021/1/27/22250963/sentinels-of-the-multiverse-definitive-kickstarter-street-date-price&#34;&gt;Definitive Edition of the boardgame&lt;/a&gt; that has even better art that is closer to the old-school comic book aesthetic. It looks like a signficant upgrade, so I expect if they ever release a digital version of the new version it would be a completely new game on Steam. Our group has enjoyed our Sentinels games though, so I fully expect we will be getting the new Steam version when it does come out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/digital-boardgames-review-sentinels-of-the-multiverse/sentinels_hu55ebca5d49dfa13d3a35dca65e2ada62_322159_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1349796416042856448/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 19:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1349796416042856448/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Finally finished #FireEmblem #ThreeHouses, or one run at least! Doing the other two might take a while!   #NintendoSwitch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, I could have gotten a much better screenshot from the ending I suppose, but I&amp;rsquo;m too lazy to go back and get one lol&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/01/1349796416042856448/1_1349796416042856448_Ertwr_MVcAAopN5_hu20f035f322dcaa791106724dc8453daf_125479_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game Review: Super Mario Odyssey
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After playing through &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/mario-3d-all-stars/&#34;&gt;Super Mario 3D All Stars in October&lt;/a&gt;, I borrowed a copy of Super Mario Odyssey for the Nintendo Switch from my brother and played through it for most of November. Odyssey was the main reason I actually got a Switch; I played through a few worlds at a friends house during a single session and loved it, so I had been meaning to get the console just for Odyssey alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game deviates a bit from the formula established by Mario 64, Sunshine and Galaxy; Instead of a single hub that leads to small mission worlds, there are a number of different kingdoms, each of which have different residents. The plot is standard Mario fare; Bowser kidnaps Peach because he wants to marry her against her will (and apparently there&amp;rsquo;s nothing she can do about it?! You can say no girl!) You visit each kingdom in turn as you chase Bowser across the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each kingdom is a self-contained &amp;ldquo;open world&amp;rdquo; where there are many challenges you can complete to advance the story. Completing challenges earns you Power Moons (the analogue to 64/Galaxy&amp;rsquo;s stars and Sunshine&amp;rsquo;s shines) which ostensibly power your ship, the Odyssey. Examples of the Kingdoms are the Metro Kingdom featuring New Donk City, whose mayor is the girl you rescued from Donkey Kong so long ago; the Woodland Kingdom is populated by flower-growing robots; the residents of the Seaside Kingdom are slugs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  




&lt;a href=&#34;#0e296a63e8c5317e383ba1adf72d06a3-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/new-donk-city_hud58de80b5c48a33903c4e78adf89972c_330126_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;It&amp;#39;s so weird when you&amp;#39;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&#34; title=&#34;It&amp;#39;s so weird when you&amp;#39;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so weird when you&amp;rsquo;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;0e296a63e8c5317e383ba1adf72d06a3-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/new-donk-city.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s so weird when you&amp;#39;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#e484a0deecbc15a71ffd6173d9c64579-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/woodland_hu39148852bfe8193ef55eed0344c3d387_349647_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;This is the woodland kingdom&#34; title=&#34;This is the woodland kingdom&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;This is the woodland kingdom (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;e484a0deecbc15a71ffd6173d9c64579-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/woodland.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is the woodland kingdom&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#84526be5a48128edac1b70b29da91719-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/beach_hucc1160ff1649688cbfe46fb4ddd33ef0_299952_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&#34; title=&#34;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Mario wearing a parka at the beach (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;84526be5a48128edac1b70b29da91719-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/beach.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually finished the main story after around a week of play. It&amp;rsquo;s fairly straightforward, not especially challenging.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#7ba08eb041f1571ff133f4ee17ae133b-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/credits_hub108851206b98ce5466a0d64971ceaa1_272556_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&#34; title=&#34;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;7ba08eb041f1571ff133f4ee17ae133b-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/credits.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is however, a lot of post-game and completion stuff to do, that took me another couple of weeks and change. Odyssey&amp;rsquo;s completion revolves around collecting a rather large number of Power Moons. A good chunk of them are only available after beating the main story, though I did try to get as many as I could even before beating Bowser. And some worlds like Peach&amp;rsquo;s Mushroom Kingdom and the more challenging Dark Side/Darker Side of the Moon are available only in the post-game.&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#313a380fa8b81e6d69b10f94691c3c60-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/mushroom-kingdom_hu0d6d184ea89cff2c96204967b79d565d_305312_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&#34; title=&#34;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;313a380fa8b81e6d69b10f94691c3c60-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/mushroom-kingdom.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite parts of the game are these segments where Mario becomes a 2D Mario and you have to play 2d Mario stages in 8-bit style, they appear in the open world as murals, often hidden, and they&amp;rsquo;re really nice throwbacks. They even made 8-bit versions of each Mario costume!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completion is a real challenge. There are much more difficult platforming challenges involved, and some moons like the Koopa racing ones will require you to master advanced moves and jumps to beat them. There&amp;rsquo;s also a whole lot of minigames to complete, moons hidden using art-based clues, and a whole lot of collectibles (including hats and costumes for Mario) that you can purchase from stores using coins and regional currency that you collect. I played most of the game in handheld mode, but there are some moons that are easier to get using motion controls, which requires you detach the joycons, so that&amp;rsquo;s something I sometimes had to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  




&lt;a href=&#34;#afa7f811401cc0b4aa2ed14482ff2296-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/clue_hu5c03d63d75cc02a67f36228a0ae744c9_163462_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;There&amp;#39;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&#34; title=&#34;There&amp;#39;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;afa7f811401cc0b4aa2ed14482ff2296-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/clue.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#8743a48562a1c5ef53ff66112e0af0d2-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/space-koopa_hu5a04ad347ee2589302cf1ada3c228395_130058_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mario doesn&amp;#39;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&#34; title=&#34;Mario doesn&amp;#39;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Mario doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;8743a48562a1c5ef53ff66112e0af0d2-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/space-koopa.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Mario doesn&amp;#39;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#cf3c150025add34858ebdc88dd0872a9-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/hats_hu0fc2897e727a2efd79695b17b87b2564_246730_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Maybe there&amp;#39;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&#34; title=&#34;Maybe there&amp;#39;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team? (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;cf3c150025add34858ebdc88dd0872a9-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/hats.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Maybe there&amp;#39;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get all but 7 of the unique 880 collectible moons. The 7 I missed were 5 for minigames (100 jumps in jump rope, 100 volleys in beach volleyball, and 3 bound bowl races) and 2 stage moons (for Breakdown Road in Dark Side). While none of these seem impossible to do, they all seem like they require much more patience than I am willing to give, so I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with this completion rate for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;







  




&lt;a href=&#34;#97e0ebef995f25880cec449204a6d666-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/874-moons_huac9045153cdd9a41641854a98f87ad17_219394_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;It&amp;#39;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&#34; title=&#34;It&amp;#39;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason. (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;97e0ebef995f25880cec449204a6d666-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/874-moons.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;









  




&lt;a href=&#34;#3116ac381049afd75bad589d6cc5a45d-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/thank-you_hu7f88aae91c13a4ffff71119166449a0c_73671_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&#34; title=&#34;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;3116ac381049afd75bad589d6cc5a45d-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/thank-you.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;2 Dec 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only complaint is that at some point I found going for completion to be super tedious, especially with those last few moons. 880 moons is a ridiculous number, compare that to a paltry 240 stars in Galaxy. This might be a case of there just being too much stuff? I realize this is a weird thing to complain about. Overall it&amp;rsquo;s still a fun and engaging game, though I&amp;rsquo;m waffling over whether this one or Galaxy is the better game. (I probably still like Super Mario 3D World over either though!)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/874-moons_huac9045153cdd9a41641854a98f87ad17_219394_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;amp;rsquo;s 874 because I bought an extra moon at the stores for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/beach_hucc1160ff1649688cbfe46fb4ddd33ef0_299952_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Mario wearing a parka at the beach&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/clue_hu5c03d63d75cc02a67f36228a0ae744c9_163462_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;There&amp;amp;rsquo;s a lot of these weird art clues that you can use to get bonus moons&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/credits_hub108851206b98ce5466a0d64971ceaa1_272556_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;The timestamp on this image tells me I finished the game Nov 7th&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/hats_hu0fc2897e727a2efd79695b17b87b2564_246730_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Maybe there&amp;amp;rsquo;s a big Team Fortress fan on the team?&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/mushroom-kingdom_hu0d6d184ea89cff2c96204967b79d565d_305312_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;After you finish the game you get to relax in the mushroom kingdoom.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/new-donk-city_hud58de80b5c48a33903c4e78adf89972c_330126_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;amp;rsquo;s so weird when you&amp;amp;rsquo;re in this city, as every else has more human proportions&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/space-koopa_hu5a04ad347ee2589302cf1ada3c228395_130058_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Mario doesn&amp;amp;rsquo;t need to wear a helmet on the moon, but this Koopa does&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/thank-you_hu7f88aae91c13a4ffff71119166449a0c_73671_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;You get a THANK YOU for finishing the Darker Side challenge&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/game-review-super-mario-odyssey/woodland_hu39148852bfe8193ef55eed0344c3d387_349647_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;This is the woodland kingdom&lt;/p&gt;
    



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 16:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I finished #LinksAwakening ! #NintendoSwitch&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/1_1322214646221205504_EllzNqXUYAEQpTF_hufca77d7143b0e88fd60778ab186248a8_79498_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/2_1322214646221205504_EllzNqRU0AEZguo_hu27c06787f10c878c0a516d8a14943077_104101_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/3_1322214646221205504_EllzNqcUcAExjPY_hu72bde3e146d4d6d5669e55ee0f8aeff1_105527_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1322214646221205504/4_1322214646221205504_EllzNp0VgAAJ9cF_hue2dfce44e2adc13f7c83ee6471e19c2d_41706_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game Review: Super Mario 3d All-stars
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/mario-3d-all-stars/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 06:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/mario-3d-all-stars/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/nintendo-switch/&#34;&gt;got a Nintendo Switch last month&lt;/a&gt;. One of the first games I had gotten for the system was the recently released Super Mario 3d All-Stars. I had really been wanting to play Super Mario Odyssey instead, but my brother had a copy of that game that I could borrow later, so I decided to get 3dAS first, as I had never really played the 3 games on the collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly played the 2d Mario games prior to this, with the exception of 3d Land (3DS) and 3d World (WiiU), although both of those games were closer in style to the the 2d mario games than to the games in this collection. The three games here share the same style of having a hub-like world from which you visit other worlds to accomplish missions to get stars/shines. The other worlds have multiple &amp;ldquo;episodes&amp;rdquo; so you have to replay each of them a bunch of times (doing different things each time) to get all the stars/shines available in those worlds. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a clever world to save on level design resources - each world is essentially multiple stages sharing the same maps and objects and so on. It can also mean the player might get tired of repeating the same worlds over and over, but the hub system means they can visit other worlds for a while if that happens. As you gather stars/shines, you unlock more areas of the hub world and thus more worlds/stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Super Mario 64&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t optimistic about SM64 going in. I played a little bit of it on the DS when it was released there, didn&amp;rsquo;t really enjoy it. Released in 1996, I know it&amp;rsquo;s regarded as a classic and revolutionized 3d platforming in its day, but for me it hasn&amp;rsquo;t really aged very well. My problems with the title are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poor camera handling. You don&amp;rsquo;t have smooth right-stick control of the camera (since the N64 did not have a right analog stick), and the camera angles are often limited in how you can rotate them around. There&amp;rsquo;s a button to toggle the camera from Lakitu perspective to Mario perspective, which is annoying for me since I don&amp;rsquo;t find the over-the-shoulder Mario perspective useful, and I accidentally keep hitting the toggle button. There is a setting to disable the Mario perspective altogether (such that the toggle button now fixes the camera to a given position instead), but the setting resets every time you load your game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even when the camera is in Lakitu mode, it will often turn or rotate far too quickly for my taste, and for me this means if I play the game for around an hour or so I start getting dizzy, and this is the main dealbreaker for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I find it quite difficult to control Mario in this game as well. His normal movement is to run, not to walk, so a simple flick of the left analog stick moves him farther than I&amp;rsquo;d like, and the same goes for his jumps. I think it&amp;rsquo;s because this was their first 3d game, so they hadn&amp;rsquo;t really calibrated yet what would be a good walk/run speed and jump distance. Adding to that, some actions like turning Mario in a new direction combined with jumping can cause him to jump in a different direction/distance, it&amp;rsquo;s something to get used to. You don&amp;rsquo;t have much jump control once you are in mid-air either. So for difficult platforming segments, I often found it challenging to position Mario for precise jumps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many of the worlds/stages are also quite frustrating. You will be dying quite often. This is unsurprising for a Mario game, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that many of the sequences are a bit long so it can be annoying to re-do them. Combined with the finnicky controls and the often weird camera angles, it can cause unnecessary frustration. Even worse, when you die, you are not just kicked back to the start of the stage, but most of the time you are kicked out of the stage altogether and back to the hub world. A minor inconvenience, but it still means additional friction in the try-fail-retry cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of try-fail-retry, a lot of the missions really require you to spend multiple lives dying and trying again. This isn&amp;rsquo;t unexpected, but a lot of them can be extremely challenging. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking in particular of that one mission where you have to race a penguin down a twisty icy slope, where veering off the slope means death. Trying to get to the end of the icy slope is bad enough - it&amp;rsquo;s going to take you a lot of trial and error to do so - but then you have to make sure you get there ahead of the penguin too. I feel like a lot of the more challenging missions carry over some of the &amp;ldquo;Nintendo hard&amp;rdquo; mentality from the NES/SNES generation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t managed to even finish SM64 yet, so I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are a lot more challenging stages ahead. As of this writing, my progress stands at a pitiful 17 stars obtained (out of a possible 120). The dizziness due to the camera is the main problem for me. I may try to come back to it later, but for now there are better games to play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Super Mario Sunshine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released in 2002 for the GameCube, Sunshine is the mainline Mario I&amp;rsquo;ve never even tried before. I later found out that Sunshine is considered one of the most difficult 3d Mario games to date. I will tend to disagree; I think the average SM64 stage is more difficult than Super Mario Sunshine, given that I was actually able to beat Sunshine. I will concede that 120-shine completion is probably very difficult for Sunshine though, but more on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunshine provides some improvements over SM64:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most significant upgrade is graphically. It&amp;rsquo;s a huge jump over SM64&amp;rsquo;s blocky polygons, and Mario&amp;rsquo;s appearance here is already pretty close to his latest modern appearances.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still find walk/run controls a bit slippery, but there is significant improvement in jump control since this game gives you FLUDD (the water jetstream firing thing), which has hover functionality making it easier to make difficult jumps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsurprisingly, the most challenging parts of the game are the &amp;ldquo;secret&amp;rdquo; platforming stages where Mario is denied the use of FLUDD. These secrets usually have to be accessed at a certain point in the composite worlds. Although these secret stages are difficult, the blow is kind of softened by two things: if you die, you are returned to the start of the secret stage (instead of kicked out to the containing/hub world); and most of the stages will have one or more 1-ups available, with one easily available near the start of the stage. You&amp;rsquo;re still going to need to grind a lot to finish these secret stages, but at least you&amp;rsquo;re not likely to run out of lives doing so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also most of the game&amp;rsquo;s worlds and settings are a lot more fun in terms of ambience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, I did manage &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1314224120490389504/&#34;&gt;to beat Super Mario Sunshine a couple of weeks ago&lt;/a&gt;. I finished with around 77 shines (out of a possible 120). I may eventually come back to it for completion, although that looks challenging. The main challenge would probably be completing the blue coins in each world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Super Mario Galaxy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally released in 2007, Galaxy is easily the best game in this collection. I tried playing this back when I first got a WiiU (by borrowing the game and a couple of WiiMotes from a friend). At the time I wasn&amp;rsquo;t thrilled with the WiiMote control scheme, especially with having to use the WiiMote as an imprecise pointer, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t get far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m obviously much happier with the Switch version. In handheld mode, you use touch controls on the screen to do the pointer stuff (like to collect star bits), which is much easier and more precise than using the WiiMote (or pointing the joycon in TV mode), so that&amp;rsquo;s my preferred mode of playing the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some stages that require motion controls, where I find I need to switch to TV control. Examples are the ones where you have to control a Mario riding a rolling ball, or Mario riding a manta ray surfing along a water track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game itself is very beautiful and significantly easier (or at least, less frustrating) than the first two games. You don&amp;rsquo;t have FLUDD this time, but Mario gets a spin jump that gives him additional jump control. And longer stages now have checkpoints in between so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to start over from the beginning if you die. Many of the stages are fun to play and do a lot of innovative things like playing around with gravity and such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still some challenging stages. Two of them specifically come to mind: The first one is Galaxy&amp;rsquo;s Greatest Wave, which is one of the aforementioned ray-surfing stages. The race course is very twisty and challening, and if you take each turn too fast or don&amp;rsquo;t turn just the right amount, you&amp;rsquo;re going to be falling off. There are a number of 1-ups along the course, and I managed to get to 99 lives in trying to finish the course. My personal estimate is that I probably re-did the course at least a hundred times. The second one that comes to mind is Luigi&amp;rsquo;s Purple Coins, a stage only available after beating the game the first time. It&amp;rsquo;s a stage where you have to be constantly jumping across disappearing platforms while collecting purple coins all within a time limit. It took me a lot less tries than the ray-surfing one, but each try was exhausting since you&amp;rsquo;re jumping all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I wish they would have done for this port was add more button support for the menus, instead of having to use tap/motion control for many of them (such as when retrying a level).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1317023064555548672/&#34;&gt;finished Galaxy for the first time&lt;/a&gt; last week, and completed the bonus Purple coin missions a few days later. That makes it the first game of this trilogy where &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/10/1318238520251621377/&#34;&gt;I hit the goal of 120 stars&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike the first two games though, Galaxy has an additional &amp;ldquo;second quest&amp;rdquo;, an additional 120 stars to be earned while playing as Luigi. Again, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably come back to this at another time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Switch is a great console for these games, since I can easily pick it up at any time and play a couple of stages in handheld mode. I was worried whether this purchase would be worth it, since to be honest I&amp;rsquo;m getting a bit old and am not as good as the platforming stuff as I used to be. Platforming in 3d only adds an additional level of difficulty for me personally. But overall, it was a good purchase. I somehow managed to beat two of the games, and it was nice to see how the 3d Mario games evolve through the years. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad they didn&amp;rsquo;t include Galaxy 2, which by all accounts is as good as Galaxy was. My fingers and wrists are tired from all the jumping though, so maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll put down the Switch for a few days before I get started with Odyssey.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Late Game Review: Uncharted 4: A Thief&#39;s End
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 09:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I finished Uncharted 4: A Thief&amp;rsquo;s End yesterday, and I felt like making a post about it, since I had a bunch of screenshots. Late game review because the game came out in 2016. I think I got it from PS+? Certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t pay for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first played the original Uncharted trilogy back in 2010-2011, but I found out just now while writing this post that I never finished Uncharted 3 (started yes, apparently), so that explains why some story elements seemed unfamiliar in the 4th game. (I think I may have also gotten the trilogy remaster via PS+, so maybe I should play the 3rd game too? Maybe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually have to thank the Uncharted series for getting my into this kind of single player adventure game in the first place. After Uncharted, I played some kinda similar games like Infamous, Tomb Raider etc, I was never that into the genre before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main complaint with the series is the sheer suspension of disbelief it requires to imagine a person like Nathan Drake could exist: basically a human at peak physical ability, able to fearlessly leap off high cliffs and cling onto walls with unbelievable grip and upper body strength, barely ever getting tired, while at the same time good enough at gunplay to go up against armies of battle-hardened mercenaries and come out on top. Oh, and he has an intimate knowledge of archaeology and is also able to find ancient lost treasures and cities all the time apparently. And also he&amp;rsquo;s pretty good at sketching. It&amp;rsquo;s fine, after all what are video games but power fantasies right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncharted 4 gives us a deeper look at Nathan Drake&amp;rsquo;s background and how he grew up to be like this, and we find out that not only is he this human at the peak of physical ability, he also has a brother who, despite 15 years rotting away in some backwater prison, is also at peak physical ability and also has all the rest of Nathan&amp;rsquo;s abilities (except the sketching though). (Cue Star Wars prequel meme &amp;ldquo;This is getting out of hand, now there are two of them!&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from that minor complaint, the games are pretty great though. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, the games are highly linear and story-driven, consisting of set pieces and sequences that are either platforming/exploratory (figure out how to get from point A to point B) or combat/stealth vs the aforementioned armies of battle-hardened mercenaries. Oh, and there&amp;rsquo;s the occasional puzzle too. Uncharted 4 adds some new elements such as letting you drive a car (4 wheel drive) around in what seems like an open world (it really isn&amp;rsquo;t), but it&amp;rsquo;s still mostly the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a big action game player, so I dislike the combat parts and I die a lot there. You can see in one of the screenshots later that my shooting accuracy rate was like 49%. For this reason, I&amp;rsquo;m not inclined to go for achievement completion on this one (or any of the Uncharted games for that matter), since there are many combat-related and difficulty-related trophies, and even one that requires me to finish the game with like a 70% accuracy rate. Good luck with that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dying a lot isn&amp;rsquo;t a problem, as the game is very forgiving. There are a generous number of checkpoints, and there&amp;rsquo;s really no penalty for dying too much. (Again, you can see in the stats screenshot that I failed checkpoints 105 times.) It&amp;rsquo;s kind of unavoidable with on-rails games like these - there are plenty of spots where if you don&amp;rsquo;t climb or run or jump in just the exact way the game wants, you&amp;rsquo;ll die and fail the checkpoint. It&amp;rsquo;s not super frustrating since you never really have to repeat too much, but it&amp;rsquo;s that kind of game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I guess Nathan Drake is famous now, because people know about his discoveries from the first 3 games, but I feel like he should be richer than he is portrayed. Not that he&amp;rsquo;s poor, but surely he got away with a few valuable trinkets here and there during his adventures right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Story-wise it feels like they planned this to be Nathan Drake&amp;rsquo;s final run, given the epilogue, but who knows? I mean in their universe, Sully is pretty old but he still also does ridiculous stunts with the rest of the gang. And they did introduce some new characters, so it&amp;rsquo;s not far-fetched there&amp;rsquo;ll be another Uncharted game later on, possibly with someone else as the lead?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, game is pretty good, play it if you can, happy to have ticked it off the backlog! Have some screenshots:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200819161627_hue6c3d46fad30247253f2f08750550326_281237_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200819164051_hu46b1ea91c7bf31829b8523e65817aed1_284669_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200819171018_hu3cbaffc4a9258d8ccdc9fe76ff5ef790_353542_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200820145613_hu403aa6f2b7883be608292b34d31f0541_228256_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200820161032_hue6f0fc6e9cab95271fa5e49312e151f2_213537_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200821005232_hu77a464efa196223d535d5d166edbd702_249841_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824132714_hu393eb55f5daa77aa9578e357f0d401ab_256211_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824134711_hu60f27add9b976eaa32a0786b0fafffc3_359095_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824141635_hud98938188e653e52bd358edaf3726a73_235308_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824141841_hucb6379a5c5ac429b1d02a79d5e9bb792_219355_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824150416_hud82d76a20e0c21ff6f033155e898b0db_286617_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200824153812_hu5c87c70b5272ab6a51e76853fd77ce96_516803_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200902155328_huc18a971ba541a72d57dc6c5d98f39d47_471881_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200902160409_hu9a09840b91ff174991e32f7dea81452a_328014_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200903175039_hu3c2c7a92b0c11ba087adae7a561ba05a_189250_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200904175427_hucb32ea5bdc2fb02d76116f411fec83b6_250565_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200907153040_hu32ec07853396cc30d7bf98038969beb3_483247_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200907154245_hu6d68b18cefb9e51e808b08e5061bdd28_382391_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200907160038_hu4b332f6f1c50aa46c7ba742bd2bd28af_353812_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200908161345_hu5166799124c3a256c98bdb0c7f9f6e6e_269790_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200908163738_hu06619873d0347acf0d171102042ab812_261645_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150307_hufe632e9a13baf3e08bccb13204b3cdd9_47663_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150314_hu1ba1ae46a319d73a2e0edad4107da04e_244973_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150318_hubbb4574ac2bcf446e9289a64bdadae3a_308505_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150405_hu9ff76feff73fe703f85ed92600715c00_113648_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150418_hu05256f8c3514656b4b5432360c346062_112211_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150432_hua574e1f093b45b31822fd1746cdf0fbb_113862_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/uncharted4/Uncharted%204_%20A%20Thief%E2%80%99s%20End%E2%84%A2_20200909150504_hu10f0f7c57b129ddae527f21ecafb9522_115195_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/1301222471568297984/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 18:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/1301222471568297984/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Just finished Disco Elysium. This game is fantastic&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/1301222471568297984/1_1301222471568297984_Eg7e4IYUcAADWW0_hua76e0710e968f976ea23893f5cda1dc5_127116_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/1301222471568297984/EhARAQzUcAAbS0b_hu8d807c74dc2b2922ede02aa05f7147b0_457106_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1293051269129486337/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 05:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1293051269129486337/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Finally finished Divinity Original Sin 2. Not sure if I should do a review since due to character choices and party comp, I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve only scratched the surface of the content, and it might take a couple more runs to alleviate that. But it&amp;rsquo;s a great turn-based RPG!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/08/1293051269129486337/1_1293051269129486337_EfHW_5QU4AA6u6i_hu56e1ca3720402fa985d25e6aa86fe8d8_125161_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Late Game Review: Tales of Berseria
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;For the past month, most of my gaming time was spent on the Steam version of Tales of Berseria, which I got from a Humble Monthly Bundle back in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary: One of the best entries in the Tales series. Has fun combat, a great cast, a darker story and a really good aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the Tales series of games, ever since Phantasia on the SNES and Destiny on the PS1, and I take the opportunity to play them whenever they come out for a console I actually have. I&amp;rsquo;m especially a fan of how their real-time battle engine has evolved over the years, and version in the Berseria may be one of my favorites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The combat balance is slightly tilted in favor of the heroine Velvet, but the rest of the party members are reasonably fun to play as well and each have their roles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I played majority of the first run on Hard difficulty, I think I dropped to Moderate a couple of times in the bonus dungeon, just to get things over with. Hard difficulty had a reasonable balance: if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t paying attention to random encounters, there was a nontrivial chance I could just die. (And I did, more than once!). You have to look out for Risky Encounters (back attacks!) or Dangerous Encounters (when you trigger more than one mob groups at the same time), as both those encounters give the mobs serious advantages. And then, there&amp;rsquo;s the Dire Foes, boss-type mobs with invincible minions that show up unannounced at the end of battle if you&amp;rsquo;re doing too well in a certain area. They&amp;rsquo;re great for farming grade later on, but the first few times I encountered one led to a game over due to me being unprepared. As you can tell, I like a bit of challenge in my random encounters, I like that if I&amp;rsquo;m not focused, I might die. For the second achievement-focused run, I played all of it on the highest difficulty (Chaos), though that was blunted by the XP boosts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the game&amp;rsquo;s cel-shaded aesthetic as well. I took a whole bunch of screenshots, you can see them later in this post!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the story is a bit atypical of Tales games where you&amp;rsquo;re usually some chosen hero out to save the world. In this case you start out more as a villain/anti-hero and are out for revenge in a Count of Monte Cristo kind of way. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely darkier/edgier than most Tales games, although there are still light-hearted moments along the way. You spend most of the story as fugitives opposing the dominant authority of the era. The rest of your party members are mostly in the same boat: rogues and escaped criminals and pirates and rebels and whatnot. It&amp;rsquo;s a refreshing change of pace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Berseria also acts as long-ago prequel for Tales of Zestiria, though the world map is mostly different (due to certain in-game events vastly changing geography at the end of Berseria), it was fun to revisit that world and remember how everything lines up with what happened in Zestiria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did two runs for the achievement completion. Total playtime came out to 119 hours, which seems like a lot, but for comparison, when I finished &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/01/690206344666750976/&#34;&gt;Tales of Zestiria back in 2016&lt;/a&gt;, my playtime clocked in at a whopping 472 hours (where did I find the time?!?), so Berseria actually took a lot less time. Tales games typically have a lot of super-grindy achievements, Berseria had some, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as bad as it usually was, I would guess my overall grinding specifically for achievements took less than ten hours total.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Happy to see Milla and Jude appear as cameo characters in this one, as Xillia was one of my favorite ones, and Milla may be my favorite character design in the Tales series overall. (They&amp;rsquo;re in a bunch of screenshots below!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the screenshots below, you can see that I had everyone wear Normin suits for the second run lol. I like how the Tales series has introduced cosmetics with the advent of 3d models. It&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable as DLC, since they&amp;rsquo;re not really essential, but they can also be fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what RPG I&amp;rsquo;m playing next - FF7R is coming out in April, and I already have it preordered; there might not be time to squeeze in another long one in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screenshots follow!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200119133747_1_hu1d2c80cc970471dace658b6ac2a41bb2_464824_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200119141136_1_hu4e005adfa1d1a91371c21c04df199980_319970_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200119142026_1_hu874f80eba19d8121efebb5c17e91851a_229363_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200119142305_1_hu581c9bba1e090b1cbd9c0d7028b589f0_190344_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200120203302_1_huff86b701f5770e6b23036fa0064aed9a_336105_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200120203432_1_hucf5fed4689bb210726056b5737286ee5_332179_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200120211659_1_hua80a8c243bbec4fa0702a4b9bcb930b0_293737_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200121150954_1_hu8d15ee1786434bff44d8dec98f68f171_504460_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200121152406_1_hu2ac909e448aaa2099febd666442d1672_211524_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200122173436_1_huf34c93c8dbff552a3686338b4e9e1eac_310639_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200123120108_1_hu513f1f74d7bc4a517e49c78db2433c56_375612_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200123120813_1_huf96a45fd5a873897e6c7c19f9f8d6b73_209115_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200124133522_1_hu8a11f3ac32bfa1b16baa02e0c03913c3_255082_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200125054927_1_hud0f68d0003d54cbff3dfc0d0d6c00212_285321_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200125145624_1_hue08f724f98722f60aa26e5b8d60e74cb_189828_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200125151108_1_hu9280f92a0fa67087b83ad78dd8802d84_352763_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200128070656_1_hu7511a5faf1eace5d2540a587048008a0_450370_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200130174531_1_hu508c3c03615bf6c694cf9c1d7dd51cd3_202440_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200130174719_1_hud781dd899493dd7b8d8e5d8673d8f413_303122_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200130181715_1_huc94043054c5b2f8940dd9e496b953ce4_329295_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200130182133_1_hu8089eb8ad2da63bc119f423d2e9428f7_239972_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200203203222_1_huebc408151ab625a3e6d00e692b819db8_264282_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200206082547_1_hu02ef7e1a110e77d5ab3cc033407efbbb_240360_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200206083707_1_hu602687dc5f92c2d7cc1158f3d81c201c_241323_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200206083843_1_hu18f587825f469555a810eaed8d7b091f_218543_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200206084107_1_hu91eb4f6c8808412b83706cf205eb881f_263405_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200206161636_1_hub67820f2cf24900ef628ec6cbed3271a_243381_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200207140147_1_hu2058801b3329a1257660ace75f66c9f0_235785_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200207150124_1_hu54d8cdc74906ace82acb09821eaca35b_203560_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200207172509_1_hu37c039e72fe6fd144d986d7197bb29d2_199705_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200208194905_1_hu32738891796ffbe37944b8817c45b3a8_442551_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200208201042_1_hu8cde7d1aefbc40310adea6c2930164dd_392629_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200212132521_1_hu2e0215a511bd01d3cf90705b9d6612f0_286051_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200214075418_1_huc1c3d29f7772b36a2e8d9811bb85171e_293868_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200214080236_1_hu2fac34c18e5b4754337e0d5ea4ab26bc_268254_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200214203948_1_huec88b2380f1465a248799e9519e3f765_296667_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200221133346_1_hu33a05d867b94303cea4c2f9333fde8fa_255716_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200221133458_1_hud30b746e6f7995ed434882dae57f76c6_314165_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200223175232_1_hua4ddf96d598c04ab883798f881180a8f_215855_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200223212154_1_hudc7ed94fab9faf19ebbb2b61a71ff891_332582_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200223213931_1_hu82c5c68c6ca0c391a5f583215426a868_230201_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200223233424_1_hu9d19d52c85e14aa3e905b2aad2aee917_640561_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200223234151_1_hu3390985eb6407167b8071a70b1acbdf0_463312_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200229034647_1_huf7ed2fbd5345ec82c9f1f082927e872b_282992_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/20200301155038_1_hu3e816b3922058584d99d90c5b6dc4081_292905_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/tales-of-berseria/steam_hu72697dad1b69a28909d5d9bc3290c7bb_666314_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: The Outer Worlds
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I bought the Outer Worlds &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/b4op_a_h17a/&#34;&gt;earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;, mainly because I had been without both my graphics card and my PS4 for a bit and I kind of wanted to play a relatively new game. I got the PS4 version because I hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet replaced my video card at the time and besides, the game was not available on Steam. I guess minor spoilers follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary: A reasonable Fallout-esque RPG from the makers of Fallout: New Vegas. It&amp;rsquo;s not as expansive or quite as nonlinear as their previous games, but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty serviceable and there&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable amount of stuff to do. A decent purchase, though I chafe at buying games at full $60 price these days lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;setting is a far future corporate dystopia in a remote human colony. Or at least, a caricature of a corporate dystopia. Your main enemies are evil corporations, which appeals to my recent disdain for capitalism. There are no intelligent alien races to interact with, but plently of wild animals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the space map shows something like 6-7 inhabited planets in the cluster, but you really only interact with 3-4 of them so that&amp;rsquo;s disappointing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there are some gorgeous environments on those planets though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;feels a bit like Fallout, with the general aesthetic hewing closely to Fallout&amp;rsquo;s 40s/50s vibe. Even the loading screens and movie advertisements are throwbacks to monster flicks from that era.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also feels a bit like Mass Effect, mainly with you getting a ship and the shuffling between worlds and the companion system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would say the companions are not as fleshed out as the Mass Effect ones though. Some of them are a lot less fleshed out than others. One of them is basically just a cleaning robot that you stuck a gun to, and he has no further storyline. Also, tbere is no companion romance option, but completing companion questlines unlocks an extra perk for them (though this isn&amp;rsquo;t clearly indicated when it happens, you have to check their status screen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phineas Welles gives a strong Rick Sanchez vibe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t a true open world, more like a forest of smaller open world areas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are a lot of quests to do, at least at the start, and they do a good job of putting the other quests in your path so that you naturally feel like you&amp;rsquo;re running into them. Towards the last third of the game, new quests seem to taper off though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actually, by the last third of the game, everything felt a bit same-y. I was definitely less enthused to play towards the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combat especially doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much variation. Either enemies run at you with melee weapons or shoot at you from afar etc. I wish I used a more sniper-rifle style with scoped hunting rifles, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t. There is a version of VATS (which only you can use so somehow its a superpower), but it&amp;rsquo;s more like a bullet time effect to help you aim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like the voice acting, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty decent, although as always it&amp;rsquo;s noticeable when multiple NPCs have the same VA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Load time between areas can be a bit horrendous, sometimes as long as 1-2 minutes, or does it only feel that way?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It feels like you earn a lot of money, but there isn&amp;rsquo;t really anything to spend it on. There&amp;rsquo;s no reason to buy anything from shops, you&amp;rsquo;ll get more than you ever need just from looting and picking up stuff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a respec machine on your ship, which is cool, since it means you can commit skill points without too much fear of screwing up. However, I never really felt the need to respec during my run. I did respec after finishing the game to do some achievements though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Level cap is 30. I did all the quests I could and I got to the cap before the point of no return, so that was annoying. I even went with nonviolent solutions a lot of the time, so if you were one of those guys who like to kill all the enemies instead, you&amp;rsquo;ll hit the level cap even earlier. You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to max a lot of skills. I like to be a &amp;ldquo;jack of all trades&amp;rdquo; kind of guy, so my skill distribution was fairly spread out and I was only able to max one skill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For some reason, the game has a plethora of consumable items. I suspect these are mainly to support the hardest difficulty (supernova), as on normal difficulty there was never any reason to use a consumable other than the standard &amp;ldquo;Heal X HP&amp;rdquo; item.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished the game yesteday, on normal difficulty. I actually started out on hard, but then, surprise, I had a hard time at the start. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be too stressed so I downgraded to medium for the rest of the run. I got the &amp;ldquo;good ending&amp;rdquo;, that is to say, the one where you &amp;ldquo;defeat&amp;rdquo; the corporate master class, such as they are. Normal difficulty is relatively stress-free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually want to go for 100% achievement completion, but this game had one that requires finishing on the highest difficulty, so that&amp;rsquo;s another run altogether. Presumably the second run would be much faster since I don&amp;rsquo;t have to do everything any more. I might get around to it someday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Screenshots follow!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191109171057_hu663911b70b599acb7dd198baad5634c6_454848_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191109171134_hu14460175ab9ae97c97ea443584b227b3_484835_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191109173940_hu932b1a776ae595da714c3d7295c6e1e7_356657_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191109175703_hu8ace86fdd648c1669655d5d96d533940_374896_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191109184407_hua2f7a771f97cd431e24e9a1dcb1acacb_230578_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191111095932_hu9845485e4e91ab77d5d0f79879d111ad_480484_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191111120508_hu9c31d2e12f3be6f643c41f7ec1fe0a77_236016_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191113135554_hu754cf09587d3ba5fff2970042949cd95_448388_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191114154024_hu3aae469688cad8acbabb23e4b6997cce_558086_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191115072134_hu7b373da2ffc62c7bcd253f78e499759b_509298_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191115083418_hu3564a94a499bcd16ee2e85eb131662cb_237712_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191115083933_hu8386a5886f9414a7e5d7f87af0b48321_419345_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191115090658_huc07df1a213adb0e17bc21feb79350fa5_322282_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191115203007_hued757f342709b6500649990f3a4735ac_489036_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191116112318_hud03d118e39fedb4b21900583a17de55e_587006_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191116113510_hubf261a83ab84e6950eb2700cf2daccba_284411_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191116213022_hufaaed7f1ba876af49468c5e2e9045199_228224_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191118160138_hua0f77c4f5de9b90567778da64a5906cf_200045_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191118161506_hu0ff18eddf89513573915c98db0cabace_230999_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191118163846_huee2155bb180d28214542ae4f698b7197_199251_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191119113909_hu436b725e52a12b1acd50b2f4f77ada8e_239969_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191119113929_huca52c3ab6ceb988c0bc883e29b7e93cb_502125_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191119172857_huc8dd2d2403a377c6363af479644b90f7_238307_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191120115503_hu90f0737629bc8dba5534c81c30b2e51e_261000_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191120122947_huca04fbb95b6167d2a05e76ef2e88bcd2_227799_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191120123338_hufa7cb37de4198bde3fb4802790017038_278669_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191120124351_hu1cebe49681508d34b841969428f1dab7_458665_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191120130229_hu6da4c1bd287c8b8b943d806a407a8431_404136_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191120131209_hu5682342c930fd4b453d4f5f1836d3f35_441576_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191122154310_hufe2f23568001ea38905fe484ba673ca7_637229_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191122155947_hu3c820036788856129a5fe4119f3a9cf3_225428_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191122162411_hud3692ddcfe015eabded72b3dbd9721a7_183723_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123114645_hu2276e9dd957e0d52ed0cd34950b07e27_231153_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123115759_hu08fb87ae3957848d04e4a9b830694bc3_461115_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123123630_hubc1f3809512569f1495c841924215bfd_484421_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123124235_hub9db9276f37e4552a625f46c995145d9_419966_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123182832_hu72c1e309067c92702a5925f4d96d3c41_214556_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123185642_hufa739780ca0ffd14f8668638758ba816_462145_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123195521_hu24d3c88812df506f00fd67a5ba758049_463457_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123201044_hu1b288dee1672b7712c67d4710b524a29_297596_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191123210637_hu4266b9819f8cc7d34d0879f6bfe393ea_196410_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125073019_hude301703c3fa9d4566ba172969c22ce2_401104_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125073338_hu772253fce186037a95c081e999c113f8_223083_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125081214_huca414546823899a4cf4a11a71cab8eef_548485_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125145910_hu85f8334fde878031c87851aab935b58a_206279_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125151654_hu9a198a09c8e52cc3996353b8dc8e83db_289349_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125152306_hu8b8f8a12a5a772cbd1e79d456ef202fa_407402_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125152847_hua75e5dfe1f1c2426960be6c856d826bf_385317_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125153218_hu0c68d568336e6733e21f1387015b7d45_375720_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125155836_hu0da743e185f522f908cf1daa51404b78_579717_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125161516_hud308931bbe9fec99c21a397811bf8936_368844_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/outer-worlds/The%20Outer%20Worlds_20191125162751_hu6e65543f24f8914de84fdd63e2c1f298_271572_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Zero Time Dilemma
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;With the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/rip-ps-vita/&#34;&gt;PS Vita recently being discontinued by Sony&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to work on reducing my Vita backlog a bit. One of the games I&amp;rsquo;d been meaning to play for a while now was Zero Time Dilemma, the third game in the Nonary Games trilogy. I&amp;rsquo;ve only previously played the 2nd game in the series, Virtue&amp;rsquo;s Last Reward, which is a bit appropriate given how the events in these games often unfold nonlinearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#eec3f3dcaf74c2aba71bfe2db6d3e39e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/ztd-phi_hu2d16a9ba67469bfb9806d424cff0a232_107631_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;eec3f3dcaf74c2aba71bfe2db6d3e39e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/ztd-phi.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;20 Mar 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;20 Mar 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ZTD is pretty good, but the story is understandably complex, given how it builds off a series of games that already involved espers and time travel and multiple timelines and cults and world pandemics and so on. It didn&amp;rsquo;t help that it&amp;rsquo;s been 4-5 years since I played VLR, and that game already had an overly complex plot so I can barely remember the details from that game as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it&amp;rsquo;s a story-based series, the gameplay largely consists of two parts: (a) escape rooms; and (b) decision-making. The escape rooms part are entertaining enough, nothing too difficult, but satisfying enough to solve everything. The decision-making part is used to unlock branching timelines, and the path to the &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; endings is determined by your ability to find the correct decisions to unlock the correct events. Not all decisions are binary or multiple-choice; some of the more important ones require text or numeric input, making it impossible to guess them. At multiple points, you will need to reference information learned from other branches of history (don&amp;rsquo;t worry, there is a story reason for why this happens).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Took me a couple of weeks of playing sporadically to finish the game. I enjoyed the game enough to spend a couple of late nights to finish it once I got really going. I will shamefully admit I did get stuck in one place and in my impatience I googled my way past it. Still, a platinum is a platinum:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#464ea2382226fa4e0d255676200af297-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/ztd-platinum_hud697a1a6556e2713bcac2e1fabb23b1f_93213_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;464ea2382226fa4e0d255676200af297-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/ztd-platinum.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;20 Mar 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;20 Mar 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, given how old the first game is, it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely I&amp;rsquo;m going to get to complete the trilogy. There&amp;rsquo;s still a couple of other Vita games I want to play as well (notably, I&amp;rsquo;m still in the middle of a 3-year old Tales of Hearts R run), so maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get around to those&amp;hellip; someday!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/ztd-phi_hu2d16a9ba67469bfb9806d424cff0a232_107631_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/zero-time-dilemma/ztd-platinum_hud697a1a6556e2713bcac2e1fabb23b1f_93213_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game Review: Hollow Knight
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-hollow-knight/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-hollow-knight/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Back in 2017 during a Steam Sale, I was trying to choose a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metroidvania&#34;&gt;Metroidvania&lt;/a&gt; to play. My choices came down to either Ori and the Blind Forest or Hollow Knight. My impression that was that Ori had the more challenging platforming, while Hollow Knight had the more challenging combat. I chose Ori at that time, and I enjoyed that game. Last October, Hollow Knight was in a Humble Monthly, and I decided to go for it. I played it for just about a month since January, and my impressions remain the same, but I now think that while Ori had a better visual presentation, Hollow Knight is the superior game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not taking anything away from Hollow Knight&amp;rsquo;s aesthetic mind you, it&amp;rsquo;s a perfectly gorgeous game. It&amp;rsquo;s just that I remember enjoying Ori&amp;rsquo;s visuals more. Here&amp;rsquo;s a couple of screens!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#f1cccfcb17d9c84c586406c490fb463b-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-hollow-knight/hollowknight-1_hu03a46052c2db41f0589e0a33529a0bdf_196370_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;f1cccfcb17d9c84c586406c490fb463b-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-hollow-knight/hollowknight-1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;16 Feb 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;16 Feb 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#1073c52a955cb3a5b062d5f3b6230717-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-hollow-knight/hollowknight-2_huc974cf01ba4dd9ebd56121af5b622b13_252794_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;1073c52a955cb3a5b062d5f3b6230717-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-hollow-knight/hollowknight-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;16 Feb 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;16 Feb 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ori had a few more challenging platforming bits, but some areas in Hollow Knight provide a significant challenge as well (looking at you White Palace!). Movement in Hollow Knight also felt a lot more fun and fluid - it was great dashing and double jumping and wall jumping across the screens once I had full mobility. Hollow Knight has a stronger combat focus, and some of the fights can get very challenging indeed (as of this writing I have yet to complete the Trial of the Fool).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The progression in Hollow Knight is also less linear than Ori - which can be a bit of a double-edged sword. While the freedom to roam is nice, it can also lead to some frustrating moments when you find a path that looks like you &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be able to do it with a bit tighter platforming, but it turns out you should just wait for some other ability to unlock before going for it. I feel like there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more stuff to hunt down for completionists too. I finished the game at 105% completion. Post-launch DLC pushed the maximum up to 112%, but I doubt I&amp;rsquo;ll be bothering to do most of the other stuff, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty satisfied with the game as-is. I did manage to hit all three main endings somehow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#ee97af99d43d89918d192d8596599111-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-hollow-knight/hollowknight-completion_huc7fa2882b90ca055653b4781c4bacd3e_443146_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;ee97af99d43d89918d192d8596599111-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-hollow-knight/hollowknight-completion.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;16 Feb 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;16 Feb 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Ori, not gonna go for achievement completion on this one. Some of the challenges are a bit too much for me. It&amp;rsquo;s actually surprising to me how I can still play and enjoy action games like this, given how terrible my reflexes are nowadays, but Metroidvanias have a special place in my gaming heart for some reason and somehow I am able to muddle through. With deaths. Many, many deaths. I finished Ori with 900+ deaths. Hollow Knight doesn&amp;rsquo;t track this statistic (thankfully?), but I probably got close to that number in Hollow Knight too. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably wait a while before picking another one up again though, maybe let my slow reflexes relax for a while with some turn-based games instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Coincidentally, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pFAknD_9U7c&#34;&gt;sequel for Hollow Knight&lt;/a&gt; was just announced! IDK if I&amp;rsquo;d play it - I haven&amp;rsquo;t played yet the sequels to the last two Metroidvanias I played (Guacamelee and Ori and the Blind Forest), somehow a completely new experience seems better for me.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-hollow-knight/hollowknight-1_hu03a46052c2db41f0589e0a33529a0bdf_196370_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-hollow-knight/hollowknight-2_huc974cf01ba4dd9ebd56121af5b622b13_252794_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-hollow-knight/hollowknight-completion_huc7fa2882b90ca055653b4781c4bacd3e_443146_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game Review: Slay the Spire
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-slay-the-spire/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-slay-the-spire/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I picked up Slay the Spire during the last (Winter) Steam Sale, not really knowing what I was getting into. I had heard some good things, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know much other than it was a roguelite where I had to go through a dungeon. But it was cheap so I took the dive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised to find that not only was it a roguelite, it was also a deckbuilding game! I love deckbuilding games, they often generate a significant amount of variance that translates to fun, and pairing that mechanic with a roguelite meant each run would be pretty interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in Slay the Spire, you choose a character from three choices, each of which have a different set of powers and cards. You go through the dungeons, one room at a time. Each room might have an enemy, a treasure or a random event. The map for the entire dungeon act is available ahead of time, so you can plot your route as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#1c94092f8f4b7ae78ac2c2ef706b0caa-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-slay-the-spire/slaythespire_hu35bffa5482582b07d5d679f7c3d03273_358404_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;1c94092f8f4b7ae78ac2c2ef706b0caa-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-slay-the-spire/slaythespire.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Feb 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;2 Feb 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your character is equipped with a deck of cards that includes attacks and blocks and powers. Along the way you can add new cards to your deck by defeating enemies or opening chests or buying from merchants and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three available characters to play (as of now), and they offer pretty different play styles. There&amp;rsquo;s the Ironclad, who&amp;rsquo;s kind of a straightforward attack and block kind of guy. There&amp;rsquo;s the Silent, a rogue who prefers chaining multiple attacks or using poison. And there&amp;rsquo;s the Defect, who summons persistent orbs that perform various functions. The dungeon proceeds the same way for each class, but they have different card sets to choose from so battles often play out differently, and each character has different builds you can lean towards to increase your odds of a successful run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battles proceed in a turn-based manner. You draw some number of cards from your deck and each turn, and play as many as your energy allows. The unique thing about Slay the Spire is that during your turn, you can see each enemy&amp;rsquo;s intent. That is, you can see what the enemy will do next turn, more or less, via an icon over their head (see image).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#aafaacd2db44b2628a0dce0eb63cb6a4-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-slay-the-spire/slaythespireintent_hu4b75871302203df90c0b1fcd01f05aff_410558_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;aafaacd2db44b2628a0dce0eb63cb6a4-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-slay-the-spire/slaythespireintent.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;2 Feb 2019 5:56am&#34;&gt;2 Feb 2019 5:56am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the enemy plans to attack, there&amp;rsquo;s an icon over their head indicating how much damage and how many attacks they&amp;rsquo;re going to do. If they&amp;rsquo;re going to block, there&amp;rsquo;s a shield icon. And there&amp;rsquo;s icon for if they are going to do buffs or debuffs. In a sense the game gives you perfect information about what the enemies are going to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means every turn is sort of a mini-puzzle: what are the cards I need to play to minimize the amount of damage I take (always your priority, since taking too much damage endangers your run) or should I try to avoid debuffs or can I maybe already beat the enemy this turn?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all plays out in the framework of the spire, the dungeon you&amp;rsquo;re trying to conquer, with the map being randomly generated rooms. Every room presents choices: which card to add to your deck? Which card to remove? Should I risk some HP to gain a relic? And so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s all very fun, and quite challenging. It can also be frustrating, but since the game gives you near perfect information (you even know at the start of a floor which among a set of bosses you are going to be facing at the end of the floor), any deaths are always at least partly your fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tend to wait until I&amp;rsquo;ve &amp;ldquo;completed&amp;rdquo; games before I review them, and for Slay the Spire I did manage to finish a run with each class at least once. But I&amp;rsquo;ve only scratched the surface, there&amp;rsquo;s a ton of content beyond that. I haven&amp;rsquo;t even gotten the &amp;ldquo;true ending&amp;rdquo; yet, which only becomes available after beating the game once with each class, as the &amp;ldquo;true ending&amp;rdquo; boss is quite difficult. And even beyond that there&amp;rsquo;s special cards to unlock, daily challenges with different parameters, and even an endless mode I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried yet. I also hear that the devs are very diligent and add content on a regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slay the Spire recently went &amp;ldquo;live&amp;rdquo; and left Early Access, just last month, and they&amp;rsquo;re planning for a Switch port too. The one disadvantage of the game for me is that each run takes a considerable amount of time (You can actually quit at any time during a run and resume it later, but I always feel compelled to finish each run in one sitting), and I have a lot of other games to play. I&amp;rsquo;ll still probably revisit the Spire from time to time, but frankly trying to &amp;ldquo;complete&amp;rdquo; the game, Steam achievements and all, seems like a huge task, given the large amount of variance in the game, but maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get there someday.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-slay-the-spire/slaythespire_hu35bffa5482582b07d5d679f7c3d03273_358404_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/game-review-slay-the-spire/slaythespireintent_hu4b75871302203df90c0b1fcd01f05aff_410558_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Game Review: Marvel&#39;s Spider-Man for PS4
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/game-review-marvels-spider-man-for-ps4/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 02:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/game-review-marvels-spider-man-for-ps4/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Finally had the time to play &lt;em&gt;Marvel&amp;rsquo;s Spider-Man for PS4&lt;/em&gt;. Took just a little under two weeks from start to Platinum. Maybe mild, unmarked spoilers somewhere in this review, be warned!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall: the game was amazing and spectacular and fun, especially for a big comic book fan like me, well worth the buy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mechanics: Combat felt a bit weird to me at first, mainly because I was expecting it to be closer to Arkham-style combat, and I kept trying to use Spider-Man&amp;rsquo;s Circle Dodge the same way I use Batman&amp;rsquo;s Triangle counter, and that got me clocked by the first boss of the game (Kingpin) a few times. Spider-man&amp;rsquo;s Dodge doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow you to cancel out of existing animations like Batman&amp;rsquo;s counter, so I really needed to unlearn that instinct. Once you get a hang of it, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good, but feels a lot more chaotic than Arkham style combat. Arkham combat felt a lot more rhythmic where you just tap commands out and point at the baddie you want to hit. Here it feels like you have to be jumping all the time and swinging across the air and moving the camera around to look for objects to throw at enemies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mechanics: Web-swinging around Manhattan also felt weird at first. Sometimes the command to web swing would be unresponsive, which I would later realize would be because I was at a height that was too high to find surfaces to swing from. Once you get the hang of it, it feels very smooth and fun and you&amp;rsquo;re zipping around Manhattan like a boss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story: Peter Parker in this universe is reminiscent of old-school Peter Parker who&amp;rsquo;s always late to things and always behind on his rent. The early parts have him getting evicted from his apartment (classic Parker!) and looking for a place to crash. (Although after that point, it&amp;rsquo;s never mentioned where he&amp;rsquo;s sleeping, if he is at all.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story: Spider-man here is however, a well-known public figure, a veteran of super-heroing who even gets some assistance from law enforcement primarily in the form of Captain Yuri Watanabe. He&amp;rsquo;s been webslinging around long enough to build a stable of villains who are constantly referenced about being held in the Raft.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mechanics: There&amp;rsquo;s actually a lot to do around the city. Not really collectibles, but more like different kinds of challenges and missions. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of crimes to stop that you&amp;rsquo;ll hear on police bands as you&amp;rsquo;re web-swinging around. More difficult crimes and missions unlock as the story progresses, and they all come with optional objectives (such as perform X type of special move, etc) that give you bonus rewards. There&amp;rsquo;s also stealth missions reminiscent of Arkham&amp;rsquo;s predator modes, pigeon chasing, research missions that have you doing all sorts of weird tasks, and so on. Missions typically reward you with some form of tokens, which are used to unlock suits, gadgets and upgrades. This Spider-Man has a lot of gadgets, making him closer to a Batman figure in this universe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story: In this universe, J. Jonah Jameson is retired from his days at the Daily Bugle and instead hosts an internet radio show where as can be expected, he&amp;rsquo;s always castigating Spider-Man. His broadcasts come in as you&amp;rsquo;re swinging around the city, and Jonah will often comment on things you&amp;rsquo;ve recently done or missions recently accomplished. I especially like it when one of the missions had you doing something ridiculous like intentionally swinging through smog and Jonah makes wild speculations about what the hell you were smoking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mechanics: The suit selection in the game is fairly good, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of suits available and you unlock more as you level up (you need to purchase them with tokens). You can change costumes at any time, and most cutscenes will show Spider-Man wearing whatever suit you have on at the time, which can be sometimes hilarious. I&amp;rsquo;m severaly disappointed at the lack of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://vignette.wikia.nocookie.net/spiderman/images/6/69/F0ab528486904cef1297397514b73ef9.jpg/revision/latest?cb=20120721011355&#34;&gt;Fantastic Four Amazing Bag-Man costume&lt;/a&gt; though. My favorite costume from this game is the classic comic book costume (screenshots below), I really like how well it&amp;rsquo;s animated so smoothly and gives such a cartoony vibe. I would totally play an entire game rendered in this fashion. It&amp;rsquo;s also hilarious when this costume is used in cutscenes!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/KcHOHTc.png&#34; alt=&#34;My favorite costume!&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/4KOBWj0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Why won&amp;rsquo;t you take me seriously MJ?!?&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imgur.com/XyiqRIW.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Those guns won&amp;rsquo;t work on me, I&amp;rsquo;m a cartoon!&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mystery: I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why, but the distance scaling in this game is super-off. In-game measurements tell me Manhattan island is about 4 km from top to bottom, which feels really small. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manhattan&#34;&gt;Wikipedia entry&lt;/a&gt; says Manhattan is almost 60 sq km, but in-game it can&amp;rsquo;t be more than 10 sq km. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why it would be like this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story/Mechanics: You don&amp;rsquo;t get to play as Peter Parker/Spider-Man all the time, there&amp;rsquo;s also a few missions you have to play out as one of two side characters. One of them is the lovable spunky red-headed Mary Jane Watson, who in this universe is not a supermodel actress, but rather has a more Lois-Lane like role as an investigative reported for the Daily Bugle. That means she gets herself into all sorts of troublesome situations where she has to sneak around enemies in order to escape. She&amp;rsquo;s no damsel in distress here, I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure if Peter ever rescues her directly. I like this MJ iteration, she has a lot more spunk. The other side character you get to play at is young Miles Morales, who enter&amp;rsquo;s Peter&amp;rsquo;s life somewhere in the 2nd act of the story. Miles parts consist of sneaking around as well, although he has a different toolset than MJ, mainly consisting of a hacking app that lets him create distractions to bypass guards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story: One of the best things in this game&amp;rsquo;s story is the mentorship relationship between Peter Parker and Otto Octavius, although if you know comics, you have a pretty good idea of where this is headed. Unlike the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/07/movies-spiderman-2/&#34;&gt;2nd Tobey movie&lt;/a&gt;, the game gives their relationship sufficient time to develop before you start to see signs of trouble. The fall itself is well-executed and heavily foreshadowed and Peter has only himself to blame when he finds out he helped turn his mentor into an insane mechanical octopus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Story: The overall story had some twists and some surprises in the ending itself. At the heart of all the problems facing Spider-Man this time around is the incumbent Mayor Norman Osborn, but who never actually turns into a green villain himself. The game&amp;rsquo;s ending heavily hints at a 2nd outing, so they&amp;rsquo;re probably saving Norman for later. Wise decision as well, Spider-Man has a deep bench of villains to pull from, and many of the classic ones haven&amp;rsquo;t been hinted at yet in this game. Aside from the Goblin, the 2nd game could very well introduce us to the Lizard, Sandman, Mysterio, and maybe even Venom among others!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After getting the platinum, I was tempted to purchase the &amp;ldquo;City That Never Sleeps&amp;rdquo; DLCs as well for additional content, but I decided to hold off for now. My experience already feels &amp;ldquo;complete&amp;rdquo; and just right anyway, and adding more missions might be too repetitive. Maybe if it goes on sale sometime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stan Lee (RIP) also had a small cameo in this game. For me it&amp;rsquo;s bittersweet that I got the platinum a couple of days after his death; I consider the game to be a fitting tribute to his life&amp;rsquo;s work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is tradition, here&amp;rsquo;s a screendump, awash with in-game spoilers! (Mainly because I chose to include the automatic screenshots that came with each Trophy unlock). You can see during the later parts I was using the comic costume almost exclusively!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;a/GXG9Qb5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;//imgur.com/GXG9Qb5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Late Game Review -- Ni No Kuni: Wrath of the White Witch (2013)
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/late-game-review-ni-no-kuni-wrath-of-the-white-witch-2013/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 01:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/late-game-review-ni-no-kuni-wrath-of-the-white-witch-2013/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(&amp;ldquo;Late Game Review&amp;rdquo; because I&amp;rsquo;m trying to play through games on my ridiculously old backlog, so these games are pretty old)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got my digital PS3 copy of &lt;em&gt;Ni No Kuni&lt;/em&gt; during some kind of PSN sale a while back for like $10 and seeing as how the sequel came out recently, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d better finish the first game before my rarely-used PS3 decides to die on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the game was great and I enjoyed it enough to go for the platinum (post-game was a bit grindy though):&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#ed40962d3c92d7f644de56616ab1d035-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/late-game-review-ni-no-kuni-wrath-of-the-white-witch-2013/DopmwwhUcAMCTak.jpg-large_hu00624a9d56d0f06fdbe8477345c3c7f9_109019_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;ed40962d3c92d7f644de56616ab1d035-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/late-game-review-ni-no-kuni-wrath-of-the-white-witch-2013/DopmwwhUcAMCTak.jpg-large.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;13 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;13 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visually, it&amp;rsquo;s a very pretty game, animated Ghibli-style. The combat system is basically Pokemon. So yes, it&amp;rsquo;s Ghibli+Pokemon. Pokemon in this game are called &amp;ldquo;familiars&amp;rdquo; and each party member can have up to 3 familiars ready to fight in battle. The party members can fight directly as well, but most of the time it&amp;rsquo;s a better idea to let your familiars go at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, the grindiest part of the post-game was collecting all the familiars. Ok, not all of them, the achievement only required 250 different species captured, but that&amp;rsquo;s a helluva lot. During the normal main game run, I only captured a bit less than 100 different species. It was made more grindy by the fact that there&amp;rsquo;s no mechanism for trying to capture the familiars (i.e. pokeballs), you basically just have to beat them in battle and whenever you beat one, there&amp;rsquo;s like a 2-8% chance that you will get an opportunity to recruit it. Thankfully, you can shortcut the grind a bit by collecting the lower level ones and using metamorphoses (basically pokemon evolutions) to get the higher level ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story feels like it&amp;rsquo;s targeted towards children, so it has a kind of fairy tale feel, and the world is very bright and cheerful (mostly) and there&amp;rsquo;s things like a kingdom where the king is a giant cat, and so on. Not that the plot is simple mind you &amp;ndash; there&amp;rsquo;s quite a bit or parallel worlds, a tiny bit of time travel, and a few plot twists thrown in (although you might have seen them coming).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite part of the game has to be all the puns. Many of the familiars have some sort of pun involved in their name, like there&amp;rsquo;s a dog familiar called &amp;ldquo;Ruffian&amp;rdquo;; there&amp;rsquo;s an egg-shaped familiar with a pharoah mask called &amp;ldquo;Eggyptian&amp;rdquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s a cat thief familiar called &amp;ldquo;Purrloiner&amp;rdquo;, who evolves into a &amp;ldquo;Cutpurrse&amp;rdquo;, and can then evolve into another form which you can fight on the seas called a &amp;ldquo;Puss in Boats&amp;rdquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s a sheep familiar called &amp;ldquo;Baatender&amp;rdquo; who can evolve into a &amp;ldquo;Baabarian&amp;rdquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s a familiar that wears a turban and he&amp;rsquo;s called a &amp;ldquo;Turbandit&amp;rdquo;, and he has higher forms called &amp;ldquo;Turban Myth&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Turban Legend&amp;rdquo;. Okay, I&amp;rsquo;ll stop before I enumerate them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a few other systems familiar to JRPG players &amp;ndash; crafting, a casino, farming enemies for drops, bounty hunts, errand boards and so on on. Oh and some nonsense about fixing people&amp;rsquo;s hearts by finding people willing to contribute attributes like confidence and kindness and whatnot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all a very fun game and something I&amp;rsquo;m glad to have gotten off my backlog! Not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll have time to play the second game though, maybe in another five years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;__&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/late-game-review-ni-no-kuni-wrath-of-the-white-witch-2013/DopmwwhUcAMCTak.jpg-large_hu00624a9d56d0f06fdbe8477345c3c7f9_109019_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/08/1030779233100947456/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 11:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/08/1030779233100947456/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Thanks to the free promo on Humble, I played through Orwell today. Story-focused game about gov surveillance, very well done&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/03/974999316036136960/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 13:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/03/974999316036136960/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Finally finished Twilight Princess HD, which I started back in January. All hearts, 51/60 Poes, 37/50 stamps. With this, the only console Zeldas I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished are Zelda 2 (which I have on 3DS) and Skyward Sword (maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll give up on this as I dislike the Wiimote lol)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/03/974999316036136960/974999316036136960-DYfkskXU8AAySbW_hu102672888267efd5672dbf7c22521875_150667_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/03/974999316036136960/974999316036136960-DYfksktU0AArliz_hu4adb702490a46dc27233514607a9d249_70222_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/956354182767820805/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 02:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/956354182767820805/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Finished Tomb Raider. Not gonna go for achievement completion since there&amp;rsquo;s multiplayer stuff. 100% collectibles is good enough!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/956354182767820805/956354182767820805-DUWm_MbU0AAfN1j_hu5b51e7b215e1c38110a4b6a42a385441_50217_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/949318192073121792/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 16:34:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/949318192073121792/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This game was amazing #PS4share&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Life is Strange)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/949318192073121792/949318192073121792-DSyn3M6VQAEe72U_hu4ea4e82720724847be61ce025ca1db98_66533_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/12/bduzgkaacpp/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 04:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/12/bduzgkaacpp/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Managed to beat the game before the new year came in. 109/120 shrines. #zelda #botw&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/12/bduzgkaacpp/0667cf590638726efcf14ed750d4a963_hu20b3b3df45e9a5bff5bfd9c9b73565c7_57608_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/924546017281785859/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 07:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/10/924546017281785859/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Im like 90% through Kingdom Hearts 2 Final Mix and I have no idea whats going on&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Persona 5 (You Never Saw It Coming)
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 01:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My first Persona game was Persona 4 Golden on the Vita &amp;ndash; a fantastic game. After that I dived into Persona 3 Portable and eventually the spin-off games Persona 4 Arena (and Ultimax) and Persona Q on 3DS. So it was no surprise that one of the game releases I was most looking forward to this yearwould be the next numbered game in the series: Persona 5 on the Playstation 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like P4G before it, the focus is on the school life of a young man forced into a new environment, interspersed with some good old JRPG dungeon crawling. You meet a ragtag group of misfits and somehow band together to save all of Japanese society from itself. Or something to that extent. This is just an excuse to dump some screens of P5, so let&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;#resources&#34;&gt;get that out of the way&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JRPG side streamlines a lot of the problems from P4G: the main story dungeons are hand-built JRPG style dungeons and there are save points in between to make dying not so much of a pain. Even on normal difficulty, I still managed to die a few times &amp;ndash; notably to those Angel enemies that tend to suicide when low on life. Andthey brought back Persona negotiation! I didn&amp;rsquo;t appreciate this too much in&lt;em&gt;Shin Megami Tensei IV&lt;/em&gt; as it felt a bit obtuse there, but here the Persona&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;personality&amp;rdquo; is shown which makes it easier to figure out the &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be leading a team of thieves there&amp;rsquo;s also a bit of a &amp;ldquo;stealth system&amp;rdquo; while dungeon crawling.It&amp;rsquo;s not a very deep stealth system, basically just hide behind corners and ambush enemies to gain battle advantage. The only problem is that the camera and the controls don&amp;rsquo;t always agree with your stealth plans, and sometimes the wrong button press can lead you to disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Phantom Thieves story is okay, although most of the plot is telegraphed ahead of time. I kind of liked P4G&amp;rsquo;s big murder mystery where you had to figure out who among your confidants was a big ol bad guy. Here in P5, it&amp;rsquo;s painfully obvious who sold you out, even if you hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed his &amp;ldquo;mistake&amp;rdquo; early on. That being said, there is a surprise twist near the end that caught me by surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to P4G, Persona 5 comes out at the height of social media, so while I like the P4G&amp;rsquo;s battle theme a bit better, P5&amp;rsquo;s battle music has managed to become a meme of its own:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WUWQFnC2zqU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must&amp;rsquo;ve seen this video at least 50 times now due to some of my friends (you know who you are).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I dislike about the Persona series is thatbecause of the time management aspect of the game, a lot of things are missable. Since I tend to play RPGs without any guides or walkthroughs the first time around, it&amp;rsquo;s problematic for me. This means that on my first run through I missed completing the Confidants/Social Links, even though when I started the run I told myself I&amp;rsquo;d prioritize them over other activities. Definitely need a second run for the platinum. (Of course, I have yet to platinum P4G either due to a mistake I made during the second run~)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion:Despite (or maybe because of?) it&amp;rsquo;s ridiculousness, Persona 5 is a great game. Story is tight, and the dungeon crawling has been streamlined a lot. That being said, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not a game for everyone, mostly because of the style. If you dislike Japanese stuff or anime or anything turn-based, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not for you. Go play Call of Duty or something. For everyone else, enjoy one of the year&amp;rsquo;s best JRPGs (sorry FF15!)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5-2_hu921f21792efe6df58cfdd76cc74be3f8_1295752_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;This game is educational, I didn&amp;amp;rsquo;t actually know this before.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5-3_huc3882e386c7a8a1fe1199c9823a3a394_1622367_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;That&amp;amp;rsquo;s totally his canon name in the lore.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5-4_hu36baa77a2b24d7d4993bb9d0138d9738_2108521_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Some of them are&amp;amp;hellip;  stranger than the others&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5-5_hud41f742dfb241d068ac375adca4bcf5e_270706_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;Your teammates have the utmost respect for you as team leader.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5-6_huce6524213e574f1aa1ba9f56e1737e15_2730189_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5-7_huef1bbf1d2db0431d96dfa605ad8d6cf4_2009996_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;When dungeon crawling, you can summon mighty persona in battle! They&amp;amp;rsquo;re like Pokemon, only way more phallic.&lt;/p&gt;
    



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/review-persona-5-you-never-saw-it-coming/p5_huab9f56f516e8a2df605d7d86f58b39c8_656798_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;

    



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/04/10155494022193912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 00:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/04/10155494022193912/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After 3 years, I finally finished Persona Q, just in time for Persona 5 release week. Pwede ko na isoli ung game lol&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/04/10155494022193912/_hu27f7dc34c9db8fd2b063f3fba6be9864_116555_7c1aef14c12bc8420e6b749b1535e23f.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Final Fantasy XV
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 01:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;With The FFXIII trilogy not being particularly well-received and FFXIV being an MMO, Final Fantasy XV has been a long awaited as the next mainline single-player game in the much-acclaimed series. This review will have minor spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#f692e95e95045baba65eb48bee33bc04-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/mxS7hvb_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_229769_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;f692e95e95045baba65eb48bee33bc04-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/mxS7hvb.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Mar 2017 1:30am&#34;&gt;18 Mar 2017 1:30am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Story&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FFXV follows the story of Noctis, prince of Lucis and his band of brothers (okay they&amp;rsquo;re not really brothers, but they might as well be). They&amp;rsquo;re supposed to be on a road trip to get Noctis married, but things happen along the way and eventuallythey haveto figure out how to liberate their homeland from The Evil Empire. That&amp;rsquo;s the backstory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story as presented in the game has a few problems. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of significant back story and goings-on that happen off-camera:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s botha feature-length movie (Kingsglaive) and a six-episode anime (Brotherhood) that expounds on the four main characters&amp;rsquo; backgrounds and how the current political situation got to where it is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s supposedly a whole effort by minor characters like Cor to organize a resistance against the Empire, but we&amp;rsquo;re never really exposed to it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s Lunafreya, Noctis&amp;rsquo; betrothed, who goes off and does her own stuff to try to undermine the Empire and supposedly help Noctis, but for most of the game it&amp;rsquo;s never really explained what exactly she&amp;rsquo;s doing orhow it&amp;rsquo;s relevant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of your friends, Gladio, goes off on a short sidequest of his own and vanishes for a while, and it&amp;rsquo;s never explained WTH that was about. Presumably it will be covered in a future DLC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anotherproblem is that Noctis and the gang spend most of the gamesort of lollygagging around enjoying their road trip without much sense of urgency. Understandably they wanted to present an open world this time (since much of the criticism of FFXIII was for its linearity), but the problem is that the open world is filled with a lot of frivolous things that don&amp;rsquo;t seem particularly urgent given the fate of the world being at stake. I mean, the party spends a lot of time camping out, cooking food, fishing, taking pictures, driving around looking for auto parts, and so on. The sense of urgency is not apparent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose the lack of urgency is an acceptable trade-off for the open world, but even for the supposed main story quests in the earlier chapters, it&amp;rsquo;s not immediately clear how they serve to help you overcome the Empire. I feel like there should have been more story quests related to helping establish a resistance and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The later chapters narrow down the open world significantly, and the second half of the game takes place outside the main continent where there is significantly less freedom to explore. It feels a bit like they spent a lot of their design budget on the open world half and so just restricted the second half to the meaty story parts. Reminds me a bit of Xenogears disc 2!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the chapters near the end was also executed very poorly. To establish a sense of tension,most of the systems you had been relying on throughout the game are taken away from you. While this would have been okay for a short segment, the chapter goes on a bit too long and ends up being far too tedious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did find myself surprised by events leading up to the final chapter, although I felt like it was another wasted opportunity. The final chapter gives us a glimpse at a different version of the open world but never really let us see most of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ending itself was bittersweet (and easily trolled haha), but I found it an acceptable ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#789f63e586a9f7d449e790cce4b79cef-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/RTcRL3u_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_226845_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;789f63e586a9f7d449e790cce4b79cef-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/RTcRL3u.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Mar 2017 1:30am&#34;&gt;18 Mar 2017 1:30am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I found the main cast of Noctis, Ignis, Gladio and Prompto tohave engaging personalities, they don&amp;rsquo;t really have much backstory in-game (most of the character backstories are in Brotherhood). In fact, later on, a startling revelation is made about one of them and none of them really bat an eye at all. It was in the sense of &amp;ldquo;hey, we don&amp;rsquo;t care about that, we&amp;rsquo;re your friends,&amp;rdquo; but it still felt like something that should have been explored further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interaction among the group is great though. They regularly banter and tease each other even during combat. It really felt like they were a group of long-time friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Combat**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an old-school FF fan, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first to admit I miss ye olde active time battle. FFXV&amp;rsquo;s battles take place entirely in real-time, with the player controlling Noctis and the other characters controlled by AI. The AI control goes about as well as you could expect, they do fine against weak enemies but against tougher battles you find yourself constantly having to help them with potions or other items. You can command them to do special attacks when available, and they will participate in combo attacks when possible, but for the most part it&amp;rsquo;s just Noctis warping and striking.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#d82d2b78eee302311886bbe6f8f6f938-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/iEmsTOE_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_259480_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;d82d2b78eee302311886bbe6f8f6f938-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/iEmsTOE.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Mar 2017 1:30am&#34;&gt;18 Mar 2017 1:30am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combat is fluid and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of movement and jumping around and looking for opportunities to strike from behind. Early on you arediscouraged from wandering around at night as the enemies might be too high level, but the combat system is set up such that most tough battles can be overcome simply by having enough recovery items around. I only got a game over once, early in the game when didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I was doing and I tried wandering at night and promptly got squashed by an iron giant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Open World&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The open world gives the party a lot to do. There&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;hunts&amp;rdquo; dished out by people in diners (basically quests to go kill a specific bunch of monsters) and other side quests given out by various characters. There&amp;rsquo;s a fishing minigame, because apparently it&amp;rsquo;s a hobby of Noctis. The fishing minigame is okay, except Ididn&amp;rsquo;t have the patience to try to get the most difficult fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s the photos and the food porn. A lot of pandering to themodern-day youths here, I&amp;rsquo;m surprised instagram hasn&amp;rsquo;t been invented in their world. Cooking is Ignis&amp;rsquo; specialty, and the game renders each dish really well, sometimes enough to make you hungry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the photos are the specialty of Prompto. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those things that feels really frivolous in the game. Every time you camp you can browse pictures that Prompto has taken so you can save them for later viewing. A later patch provided a photo mode that you can control directly. There&amp;rsquo;s an entire reddit thread about how players have snappedmore pics for this game than for their own vacations!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m no exception. Exporting a lot of photos is a pain though, as there is no batch export option in-game. Attached to this post are a sampling of the photos I got (a bunch of them are from achievements).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achievements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of achievements, I was a touch disappointed with FFXV&amp;rsquo;s achievement set. I got the Platinum trophy, but I felt like it was a bit too easy, as there was still a lot of things to do in the game outside of the achievements. I don&amp;rsquo;t wantannoying grindy achievements, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want them to be too easy and &amp;ldquo;no challenge&amp;rdquo; either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other stuff&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had this weird Chocobo carnival DLC that somehow takes place in another timeline or something LOL. IDK how it works.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#3aabd71a1b71d255ee347f24d74b93e4-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/2Uj1VM3_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_317363_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;3aabd71a1b71d255ee347f24d74b93e4-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/2Uj1VM3.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Mar 2017 1:30am&#34;&gt;18 Mar 2017 1:30am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that the more action-oriented combat system is indicative of where SE plans to take the series moving forward, there&amp;rsquo;s still a significant amount of nostalgia in the game for old-schoolers to appreciate. Callouts range from Prompto humming the classic victory fanfare after the battle to 2d sprites in the store menus jumping up in down to indicatewhich characters can equip each item. Classic FF beasties like the Malboro still make an appearance (and are still a pain to fight!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weirdest thing overall has to be the Cup Noodles thing! They had some sort of tie-up with Nissin and Cup Noodles is one of themeals your party can have in the game and Gladio is obsessed with them. Later on you even get a quest to try to find a way to improve on Cup Noodles and it ends with the characters saying there&amp;rsquo;s really no beating the original since it has a perfect mix of ingredients already. I feel like the VA&amp;rsquo;s really enjoyed doing those lines haha.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#9d5e0d0709c77d00dff936e3bc6bc7f3-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/MDiYsIS_hu6811b2db0627b9aac12c8e31820f335e_380065_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;9d5e0d0709c77d00dff936e3bc6bc7f3-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/MDiYsIS.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Mar 2017 1:30am&#34;&gt;18 Mar 2017 1:30am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I had a bunch of complaints and nitpicks but to be honest, I enjoyed the game. There was a lot of gameplay, some seriously though battles and some annoying dungeons that took forever, but I finished most of it and got the platinum in under a month. Nowadays for an RPG that&amp;rsquo;s very quick for me, an indication of how much I liked the game. There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch more content planned for it, including DLC story packs for each of the other main characters, and high-end boss fights and what not. Not sure if I&amp;rsquo;d still play those since there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more RPGs on the horizon (2017 is a good year for RPG gamers.) But if Final Fantasy XV is the next step for the series moving forward, I find it acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/0bVhWhs_hudfa9d7fffb1e1e6c958f37a5a2dcdff6_322785_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/10DdYOe_huc3e453cefa3b365c6cd3734b9f92c44e_416608_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/1M8VFHi_huf18601d42f925b06d811bd40db719de8_260128_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/1SHfpfc_hu7c2b2cec7352ec5dc2d133639a90b860_433222_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/2Uj1VM3_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_317363_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/2aDSI3X_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_358696_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/443CKHF_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_196571_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/4IQc7Iy_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_175087_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/4qOXkcq_huc6aa658716464d401f5e52113faaf39b_394548_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/4sk2UWK_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_304347_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/4ynj89K_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_107942_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/5pv7ukv_hu69ec9e0b231ad9dbdecae64de30fcc1f_291264_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/6LMNWiN_huffcae6b2e7c9d3a3702d1a83e4ba1521_304037_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/6gsGmVv_hua670061b1e1e83b9d3a975a3d73e5160_259532_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/7TPTQHF_hu3e2e73c0f6aa0fc75ed6a29a66368dc4_168855_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/8IlQcvf_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_260625_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/8aeubIb_hu4f3ef8cf936c02f1b06ccc4cc9a2f2ac_129812_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/BuFeIOe_hue9a4a7955192896e8bfc1c588fea865c_409307_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/EXfkOPl_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_140783_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/EiHAGdS_hu4ed2e25e4e204d63c2feeb87859ca705_252203_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/EinlegF_hu5fce119acaec87c08c8969e2f47005ad_359249_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/FDwZOh2_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_176791_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/GKJRdHh_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_329014_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/HQbFnWb_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_335049_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/Ha9fLNe_hua38133944e41faec37872c4fc61c4cb9_158755_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/HgqgjwT_hu5fce119acaec87c08c8969e2f47005ad_377874_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/HpBWfyY_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_248723_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/Htstf4J_hu882ff366eea2a6b449c870a6ad0be508_456737_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/IZm6rmQ_hu3083ecbcb53ff532a4cf142d7c2f7452_525362_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/ImtNek9_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_242809_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/Ip6dkqE_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_213298_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/KLtvFNv_hucf5fa36909f98529e45d560fb14732b1_155528_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/KS9A7dt_hucf877bab2c7fdd26d43b3b9c794cdf4b_641675_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/KkLR6HY_hufe8e6cc0b04cc213f5057f7fdd9870e9_415889_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/LND32FQ_hue2b8c0675fccb971fbd4290dab46e93e_585651_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/MDiYsIS_hu6811b2db0627b9aac12c8e31820f335e_380065_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/MDmGfoA_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_246040_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/MYlTlfj_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_123294_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/OU0uAkz_hue40a9aa0e06a76fd06c25e2d0f644694_460301_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/P4w7XxI_hub08404c79cc124be68d303c3a7128556_532669_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/PkPKwvj_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_168131_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/QMcm7Lu_hu10d83d77710fae593f133b1fde0b9b87_264805_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/Qa9U2hR_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_306622_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/R64QBrx_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_121879_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/R6UmqlC_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_284049_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/RTcRL3u_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_226845_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/RnKg7vd_hu5fce119acaec87c08c8969e2f47005ad_377014_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/S5Ha66P_hucfe88dd878163610e7abcd2deddd5b56_350324_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/SAG5MdW_huf0caecc8939d1d4d456d283c9d2b2a8d_443191_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/TUqZiRo_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_329550_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/UmoRKSF_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_218814_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/VKZtMTK_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_370857_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/VxSolik_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_325144_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/WOPT8yl_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_153950_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/Wi0188A_hufb20b767390cefbfa2e7272082484c19_511412_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/X0wtwB6_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_230544_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/X98v3Ze_hu6787aeb01591750615dacae73e4ae7bb_408764_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/XTji6gb_hu73306f1908da2ec25044991e3ea3ebd9_213770_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/YHTUek0_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_223020_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/ZK4RkhN_hudf9f6120103b3ea22e31712b2f8451d7_417840_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/d430q2O_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_190346_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/dBUlanb_hu0755e81eeecbfd85cfaab35d1b379fab_223865_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/eEZ5diJ_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_249746_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/efHl5YE_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_231361_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/efMypwx_hu5fce119acaec87c08c8969e2f47005ad_356048_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/fLVm8yB_hu5cac18cbc24c77ec9d5bd6c0b85382fd_333870_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/hBFz8lQ_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_181449_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/iEmsTOE_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_259480_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/iL2AMei_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_176304_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/iUOPyjX_hu468bd2830625154a1c1a747d0585912f_140926_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/ilhK2zs_hu5c56ff6982c1a753ce5271f38f9f66a3_192231_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/j9MZ9pp_hu3d67570a2eb7e3d0ade5d868d0bb948a_159301_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/jLlvjHP_hu77f3bc94b91811f4f4285a4a284b4150_156367_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/jbKBeDX_hu953cd59c930eb0dfbf403f8106234786_214321_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/k4dGiZe_hucde7f5d271b773c89fafec4a6b1688b8_272605_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/krKPSin_huc7dda0f026eb6bf46bcdc7f8be664f8c_147928_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/lkj6Xvc_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_370778_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/mNPlX42_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_351350_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/mVzTx59_hu2685e1807bec3db6e1f9c3b2074182c5_189661_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/mxS7hvb_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_229769_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/nlqtp3y_hu6ed40d20b60b9c88d6ba26aa6a7dff2f_257251_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/nwfypLG_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_44017_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/o8BvjdG_hue388f5ebbca4f26e66f75fcdb3755f10_345947_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/o9Duqtc_hua77bcbefb89715b9bcb148bb719af1c1_365820_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/oJqKI95_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_238157_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/oqi9vBB_hu3319bad5616b44f3c489c3c0bac24d5f_381839_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/pDCgiIf_hu919ae8affde0477efbbb5f2f9219cdfc_374587_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/pGAkIAV_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_274720_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/pHZnD4C_hue7f3461db719abd5576ecdcb489e0daa_152253_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/pSHBvLh_hu7bfc026132f08f41ab14326f368278b4_296301_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/pcDc010_hua09bf63abe4305623160cf810db640d5_239196_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/pedbhss_huab4534aabed47dd40b87e6dab70c77d9_400259_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/pi4Srw8_hu1b8262ae41340c9a1c5d731cb8c445ff_383151_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/q8BoSEz_hu01e8fa7770d90d58a1f049e04c132e3a_166248_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/reDgmEb_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_320455_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/rtJJ0Na_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_165850_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/sW2cPDI_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_300376_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/sgupq0B_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_180641_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/tCdSwwF_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_295709_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/tPp0axo_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_181524_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/u4PbwGU_hucfb8ff740e112f79051e75497a5a887e_150361_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/ut2O7YQ_hu8fc58172997e147059c0d27f19cfb8e8_322053_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/vCFNTYX_hu4c0dfac8d51d2ff3a6dd990bcaabeb12_260258_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/xLmAlzI_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_289948_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/xcY5Qup_hu81dd8589e7a862263b0570256c0762af_264435_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/xo3RVNn_hu45148047e5f4cc45650c0ec043516b24_178240_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/yEWfyNB_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_228518_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/review-final-fantasy-xv/zPDgrCK_hu255f50146e4af4e11739e93a6fe4223b_239088_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/841428616068001792/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 23:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/841428616068001792/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I might be done with Stardew Valley. Game was great, but getting the last few achievements would be too grindy for me&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/841428616068001792/C61axoHV4AEEukD_hu6b4bef66b7c34b8896c590392857d8a6_51404_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Duelyst
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 01:30:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/hearthstone-vs-mtg/&#34;&gt;Hearthstone&lt;/a&gt;, I tried out a couple of other digital CCGs:&lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/429680/&#34;&gt;Spellweaver&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://store.steampowered.com/app/531640/&#34;&gt;Eternal&lt;/a&gt;, but neither one hooked me. The one I enjoyed the most and did pick up to play regularly was &lt;a href=&#34;https://duelyst.com/&#34;&gt;Duelyst&lt;/a&gt;. So this review is written from the perspective of someone who has played both Magic the Gathering (MTG) and Hearthstone (HS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hearthstone, Spellweaver and Eternal played like digital MTG with some advantages, as I outlined in the HS post linked above. Duelyst keeps many of the same elements and advantages, but adds an extra dimension. Besidesbeing a card game, Duelyst is also a board game.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#45dce95b50f9d04ecee469edc104a35d-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20161015104936_1_hu28345954637ff43c1f8b238adc065a50_415978_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;45dce95b50f9d04ecee469edc104a35d-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20161015104936_1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Feb 2017 1:30am&#34;&gt;18 Feb 2017 1:30am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Board game&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a game of Duelyst your General (the analogue to Hearthstone&amp;rsquo;s hero) and his minions are played into a 95 board. Minions can only be summoned on empty spaces adjacent to one of your units. During your turn, each unit can either: attack an adjacentenemy; or move up to two spaces, then attack an adjacent enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a board and unit movement greatly enhances the &amp;ldquo;positioning matters&amp;rdquo; mechanicas compared to Hearthstone. In HS, it only mattered whether minions were adjacent, to the left or to the right.In Duelyst, you can position minions to prevent enemies from reaching your General, or to restrictenemies from moving completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means a number of spells and abilities care about positioning too. Eachof the available Generals has a Bloodborn spell (BBS), the equivalent of Hearthstone&amp;rsquo;s Hero Power. One of the Generals has a BBS which allows her to deal damage to all enemy units in the same column as the opposing General. This means you have to be careful where you place your minions whenever her BBS is active! There are spells that affect a small area (22 or 33 and so on). There are spells that care about adjacency (&amp;ldquo;Destroy target minion that is not nearby any general&amp;rdquo;). And so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Factions and Generals&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hearthstone has different heroes, and each hero has a different card pool available. By contrast, Duelyst has factions and Generals. Each faction has its own card pool, and of course there is a global or &amp;ldquo;neutral&amp;rdquo; card pool as well. Each faction also has two Generals, each of which has a different BBS. The factions and Generals encourage a lot of different playstyles.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#7893d4dff4403b69eaab48e91d493637-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20170216154217_1_hu2712e8d2214bb80d8b8cbb3f52aa2fad_388288_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;7893d4dff4403b69eaab48e91d493637-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20170216154217_1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Feb 2017 1:30am&#34;&gt;18 Feb 2017 1:30am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some factions like the Songhai are more focused on spell-based damage and backstabs. The Lyonar focus on cheap, efficient creatures. Vetruvian has obelisks that can generate temporary minions. Abyssian focuses on swarm tactics and shadow creep. The Vanar rely on placement and trickery. My favorite General, the Magmar Vaath, likes to go toe-to-toe with the enemy General and&lt;strong&gt;punch him in the face!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keywords&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, manyof Duelyst keywords care about positioning, and thushave no meaningful equivalent in either MTG or HS. Namely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Airdrop&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; minions with Airdrop can be summoned anywhere on the board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backstab&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; this unit deals extra damage when attacking from behind (yes, even facing matters!) and doesn&amp;rsquo;t receive a counterattack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blast&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; attack hits all enemies in the same row or column&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flying&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; may move anywhere on the battlefield&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frenzy&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; normal attacks hit ALL adjacent enemies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infiltrate&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash;gains bonus effect if its on the enemy&amp;rsquo;s starting side of the board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Provoke**&amp;ndash; somewhat likeHS&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Taunt. A&lt;/strong&gt;djacent enemies cannot move and&lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; attack a Provoke unit if there is onenearby&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ranged&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; can attack from anywhere on theboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shadow Creep&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; this is a modifier that can be added to board tiles. An enemy standing on Shadow Creep takes 1 damage at the end of the Shadow Creep owner&amp;rsquo;s turn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Zeal**&amp;ndash; gains bonus effect as long as it&amp;rsquo;s nextto the General&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duelyst also has a number of keywords that are analogous to abilities in MTG and HS.&lt;strong&gt;Rush&lt;/strong&gt; is the same asMTG&amp;rsquo;s**Haste**and HS&amp;rsquo;s&lt;strong&gt;Charge&lt;/strong&gt;.**Opening Gambit**and&lt;strong&gt;Dying Wish&lt;/strong&gt; are the same as HS&amp;rsquo;s&lt;strong&gt;Battlecry&lt;/strong&gt; and**Deathrattle.**(I worry that at some point new cardgames will run out of names for &amp;ldquo;enters the field&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;leaves the field&amp;rdquo;.) And so on &amp;ndash; no need to cover everything here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skill Level, Competitive Play and F2P&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The added dimension of positioning means that Duelyst is strictly more skill-based than HS.This is obvious if you note that there are a lot more choices for where to place minions. Hearthstone is also more reliant on RNG than Duelyst is, although I can&amp;rsquo;t say that will hold for the future. I enjoy some level of RNG as it creates variance, but the randomness means a higher chance of losing due to bad luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find competitive play onthe ranked ladders for both Duelyst and Hearthstone to be about the same. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying either meta is healthy, but as I see it there are more viable decks in Duelyst ladder as compared to HS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;ve already spent a bunch of money in MTG, I don&amp;rsquo;t like spending money on digital card games. So for both HS and Duelyst, Iam strictly free-to-play (F2P). Both games offer similar monetization models (pay money for booster packs/cosmetics) but Iwas able to get further up the ladder in competitive Duelyst.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#b2f9e96959d46d69b74fdfb70152125d-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20170131192316_1_hub7a52f37225406efe877da2275b8d6f8_162003_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;b2f9e96959d46d69b74fdfb70152125d-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20170131192316_1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;18 Feb 2017 1:30am&#34;&gt;18 Feb 2017 1:30am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my first full month (December), I was already able toget to Duelyst&amp;rsquo;s Gold Division. This should be similar to around rank 10 in HS. After a lot (and I mean&lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt;) of grinding from Diamond rank, I managed to hit the S-Rank Division last month. This is the equivalent of HS&amp;rsquo;s Legend rank. The highest rank I ever got in HS was around rank 6 or 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I think Duelyst is more skill-based than HS, why did I find it easier to get to S-Rank than HS&amp;rsquo;s Legend rank? Two reasons come to mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I found Duelyst games more fun&lt;/strong&gt;. This means I was playing Duelyston a daily basis since it started. At the start, I played regularly becauseI wanted to get Steam Achievement completion. But I found myself enjoying the game and continuing to play even after that. There are also a lotmore variance in decks being played on theDuelyst ladder. By comparison, HS ladder seemed to be almost 50% the one best deck (used to be Midrange Shaman, nowadays Pirate Aggro&amp;hellip; ) while the other 50% are trying to beat it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It was easier to get the powerful cards and build the tier one decks in Duelyst&lt;/strong&gt;. The pricing of packs is about the same (100 gold), but on averageI could earn around 100-150 gold per day from Duelyst&amp;rsquo;s quests, compared to 40-60 for HS. The drop rates for Legendaries (highest rarity in both games) is higher in Duelyst as well.Unlike HS, Legendaries in Duelyst are not restricted to one per deck, you can play as many as three. This meant you need more of them, which annoyed me at first. But I think that&amp;rsquo;s counterbalanced by the higher drop rate. For comparison, I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing HS for more than a year and have only gotten two premium (golden) Legendaries. Three months into Duelyst and I&amp;rsquo;ve opened the same amount of premium (prismatic) Legendaries. (Well, this comparison may be skewed since I open more Duelyst packs due to the increased gold rate.) Another factor was the Bloodborn expansion, which you could complete byplaying enough to grind 3900 gold. That expansion came out in December, and I completed the set early in January. This set gave me access to manyuseful cards that were important in the meta. This allowed me to build a tier one deck and reach S-Rank in January. Even after that deck was nerfed, I was also easily able to shift to another tier one deck from another faction. In HS, I still haven&amp;rsquo;t found a new competitive deck after Midrange Shaman.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Future&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I told myself I would stop playing Duelyst after I completed the Steam Achievements. Then I said I would stop playing after I got to S-Rank. But I&amp;rsquo;m still playing it now. By comparison, I now launchHS once or twice a week, and I don&amp;rsquo;t clear the quests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duelyst is still a young game &amp;ndash; the second expansion just came out last December. So in the future it may yet be plagued with the problems Hearthstone currently has. The developers have shown themselves to be responsive in nerfing problematic cards and shaking up the meta though. Whether they are able to keep this up remains to be seen. In the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;m willing to keep playing as long as the game is still enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20161015104936_1_hu28345954637ff43c1f8b238adc065a50_415978_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20170131192316_1_hub7a52f37225406efe877da2275b8d6f8_162003_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/review-duelyst/20170216154217_1_hu2712e8d2214bb80d8b8cbb3f52aa2fad_388288_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/10155237324233912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 06:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/10155237324233912/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I also finished Persona 3 Portable today (been playing it on and off since Feb 2015). I figured I should clear it off my backlog before P5 next year. Didnt manage a completionist run though&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/10155237324233912/_hud8d014f8dcbe391825028c8955ce3bf9_56580_7db3b294b67d572afc01a075312a6c28.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Xenoblade Chronicles X
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:44:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Just in time for the end of the year, I finally finished Xenoblade Chronicles X, which I started playing around the first week of August (5 months!), with 120+ hours of game time. The game doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the best graphics (WiiU, etc), but I really like how it looks and how the world is built and all the different environments and the weird and sometimes absurdly large beasts.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#772e3d8e953038cedb88d1392c9c7c02-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/18%20-%20KnpoEd3_hu0252cf28de3e1cfead0a956e3cceba9e_486468_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;772e3d8e953038cedb88d1392c9c7c02-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/18%20-%20KnpoEd3.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;30 Dec 2016 12:44am&#34;&gt;30 Dec 2016 12:44am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a whole lot of stuff to do in-game. It plays mostly like a single-player MMO, with party members that act on their own and most skills on a cooldown. There&amp;rsquo;s a ridiculous number of quests and items to grind for, I&amp;rsquo;m even tempted to still continue with the post-game content (if only I didn&amp;rsquo;t have FFXV waiting for me!), as I&amp;rsquo;m only at around 70% completion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story was okay, at many points well-told and hitting a lot of emotional highs (although some of the characters felt a bit over-acted). The ending was&amp;hellip;  well, kind of sequel-baiting. A mixture of disappointment and confusion and hope haha. I don&amp;rsquo;t imagine that they&amp;rsquo;ll have a sequel set in the same universe/timeline, so it felt a bit likethey made up a ridiculous explanation that would attempt to explain some of the nonsense that happens in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attached some screenshots from the game!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/1%20-%200Voqh4q_hu074e443f75385669f189485722f04e89_440730_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/10%20-%20j4pRFbO_hua73d9b77aff9aa54fe3ff34c69caf81c_493101_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/11%20-%204Bg7Vdn_hu1d630624f41d3eb90370368010fc11ef_480878_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/12%20-%20a5EWLsX_hu695ce3e55552ebd859ebfe9c651458ea_490913_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/13%20-%201RrW3np_hucc73b3a284730bb160e18423969c3559_438709_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/14%20-%20oz2ZTXV_hu86ff6a09b7bae82f9e7579d300f019e4_418034_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/15%20-%20aLsNJ89_hu8110a64e359c37ce46aeb417b6b6beeb_486931_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/16%20-%20Hu7Ytkj_hu9a3c68f0e24f3161038f1edacc2e1b02_435859_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/17%20-%20AfeboMQ_hudf0b484fe162c32a3b2fc19c6c931dc4_449343_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/18%20-%20KnpoEd3_hu0252cf28de3e1cfead0a956e3cceba9e_486468_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/19%20-%20iGcpkLe_hu5036fa07aa27ebf89bf80cb2d2b0b95e_468189_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/2%20-%20VSXcLdQ_hu1832cfde9b48974035003d36c8a4326f_447516_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/20%20-%207706H2A_hu414ffaee9b39b8068d2cb5a11553e488_503413_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/21%20-%20RhzS6JS_hu7fb31ddb8cba9fda362433bacd61835b_476000_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/22%20-%20VSRrIxr_hu2e9d3e2a9701c402938193f7c76d044f_487841_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/23%20-%20MUxGd8c_huc9cf7a8d4ea1736c1a21a1f319c45086_457185_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/24%20-%20f9A0xxK_hu17e59a31ab347292113940a2f4a09c93_449197_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/25%20-%20GgEMlQY_hu2dfd8d678b5157f833acdb32cdad614f_454703_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/26%20-%20M6l0eQA_hu58ef3ce3c23d65ea0ec3d763665040cd_490968_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/3%20-%20Fga6tNf_hude5eebabaa108cf0205bf7b916aad099_309489_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/4%20-%20q9D59F0_hud3df224773c385bfaaea49ffb5dd98d8_408525_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/5%20-%20SNNQ3ho_hue54b74196722269b910dc47280bc8c42_419239_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/6%20-%20DHdX9OQ_hu2c134cc8a2e2097549dc747882eb8b1b_454373_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/7%20-%20rDpA7Xv_hue61c6322d6dcb44c046cd10ae2432850_309753_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/8%20-%20sGRLWI7_hu88c917557a70e81064fe4cd5d3fb7ec7_420002_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/review-xenoblade-chronicles-x/9%20-%20FwS94TG_hu9c362c87977f2b60da3ea6083befbdc4_474750_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/10154443128298912/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 13:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/10154443128298912/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So I managed to &amp;ldquo;platinum&amp;rdquo; Rocket League on Steam (all nonDLC achievements) despite not being very good at it. Goes to show how easy it is to get into, but I guess I&amp;rsquo;m done with the game for now&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/10154443128298912/_hudee6665b3f99a2b613fd1db34ce2109e_48716_7c6fff76c7860612c151a46b22d367ec.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/02/10154348659503912/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 08:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/02/10154348659503912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Finally finished Wind Waker HD, great game. Didn&amp;rsquo;t bother with the completion, there&amp;rsquo;s just too much other stuff to do. If the game had achievements, I&amp;rsquo;d think about it lol&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/10/8laqfkmoj3/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2015 10:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/10/8laqfkmoj3/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Platinum chasing to destress #psvita #danganronpa&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/10/8laqfkmoj3/e2a976099ae15bacfaddc006baf0a828_huc5b4c86d82d6535c6daf42707d14ca8d_79651_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/11/10153371179008912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2014 16:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/11/10153371179008912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Dragon Age: Inquisition spoiler-free review: First off, the game is vast. There&amp;rsquo;s a ridiculous amount of quests, collectibles and stuff to do. Exploring feels a bit like Kingdom of Amalur where you can&amp;rsquo;t go far without encountering something to pick up or bad guys to fight. The fighting is a bit more arcade-y than Origins (I did not play DA2 so I cannot compare); I only really switch to Tactical view when fights get tough, the action mode is good enough maybe 60-70% of the time. A real time-sink, this one.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/11/528700287406469120/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/11/528700287406469120/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;First ps4 platinum #PS4share&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/11/528700287406469120/528700287406469120-B1ZSHCzCMAAG2h0_hua29a7a2d50fc6e6a249a802fa1df87ed_83401_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/04/10152879455218912-0/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 01:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/04/10152879455218912-0/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Finally! Pwede na mag move on lol&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/04/10152879455218912-0/_hu724be130d2136efe5cfd2a3576efc429_64902_9dde647b842c394d3704028cfebfd5a2.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/07/353690869481738241/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 01:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/07/353690869481738241/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Just finished The Last of Us. Fantastic game, great story and some great action sequences, but that ending&amp;hellip;and that lying liar!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/02/305358880874057728/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 16:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/02/305358880874057728/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;That borderlands 2 final boss was intense and chaotic&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/10/258215576680407041/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 14:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/10/258215576680407041/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I just finished Borderlands today. Borderlands ONE. Relevant xkcd: &lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/606/&#34;&gt;https://xkcd.com/606/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/09/249794730370686976/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 08:57:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/09/249794730370686976/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;I might be enjoying Tactics Ogre: Let Us Cling Together (on PSP) a bit too much.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/04/188971847163977728/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 12:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/04/188971847163977728/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Finished Planescape Torment! Fantastic game, despite being 13 years old.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2011/12/148286730351550469/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2011 06:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2011/12/148286730351550469/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Just finished Bastion. Such a beautiful, fantastic game&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2011/07/97231680342986753/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 09:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2011/07/97231680342986753/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Finished Fallout: New Vegas ~ Still a lot to do in the Mojave though&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/12/16438210175434752/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2010 10:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/12/16438210175434752/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Finally finished Infamous! Now for the other 200 games on my backlog.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>[Step by step modding-Guide]: Turn Baldur&#39;s Gate and its sequel into ...
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/09/step-by-step-modding-guide-turn-baldur-s-gate-and-its-sequel-into/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 10:51:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/09/step-by-step-modding-guide-turn-baldur-s-gate-and-its-sequel-into/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via delicious:
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/gaming/comments/cebua/step_by_step_moddingguide_turn_baldurs_gate_and/&#34;&gt;[Step by step modding-Guide]: Turn Baldur&amp;#39;s Gate and its sequel into ...&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/07/19811340486/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 08:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/07/19811340486/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Finished the Wings of Liberty campaign! Secret mission was exciting.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/04/11808025555/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 05:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/04/11808025555/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;finally finished final fantasy xiii&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Collectible Card Game Headquarters  View forum - ManaLink 2.0
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/03/collectible-card-game-headquarters-view-forum-manalink-2-0/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 22:48:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/03/collectible-card-game-headquarters-view-forum-manalink-2-0/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via delicious:
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slightlymagic.net/forum/viewforum.php?f=25&#34;&gt;Collectible Card Game Headquarters  View forum - ManaLink 2.0&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>