<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>philosophy on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/tags/philosophy/</link>
      <description>Recent content in philosophy on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Equal Protections
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2020/05/equal-protections/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2020/05/equal-protections/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralistic.net/2020/05/25/mafia-logic/#mafia-logic&#34;&gt;recent post on Cory Doctorow&amp;rsquo;s pluralistic blog&lt;/a&gt; had a really good take on the general worldview of &amp;ldquo;the right&amp;rdquo;, describing it as &amp;ldquo;mafia logic&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m going to quote a huge chunk of it here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This follows perfectly from the second definition. The purpose of the law is to protect the rightful rulers, so the law can&amp;rsquo;t – by definition – punish them. And it is &amp;ldquo;mafia logic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holbo was talking about Michael Gove – a UK Tory Minister – excusing his the Prime Minister&amp;rsquo;s advisor Dominick Cummings repeatedly breaking the quarantine rules that Cummings is responsible for creating and enforcing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it could apply equally well to Trump&amp;rsquo;s pardons for his crooked henchmen, or the legions of Karens who think the cops should come and bust some Black kid&amp;rsquo;s head for selling lemonade without a license, while ignoring their own anti-vax playground quarantine-breaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pure Blue Lives Matter logic: the law should protect cops from Black people, but not Black people from cops. It should punish Black people who break the law, but protect cops who break the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a meaningful difference between reactionary and progressive, left and right. It&amp;rsquo;s the difference of property rights vs human rights – whether you exact the right to hoard while others starve, or the right not to starve while others hoard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the difference between pluralism and elitism: whether you think some of us were born to be ruled over, or whether you think we should have a government selected by its people to serve those people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the difference of equal protections and duties under the law, as opposed to impunity for the powerful and the legalized oppression of the powerless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This resonates with me a lot because &amp;ldquo;equal protections under the law&amp;rdquo; may be a pretty big ask in this country when individual citizens find it difficult to apply judgement equally to both those they support and those they don&amp;rsquo;t. Double standards abound, both for the government and many of the citizens. There are a lot of people in this country who support the people in power blindly because of some form of tribalism; they chose this person so they feel they have to support them no matter what, no matter how incompetent, no matter how blatant the abuses are, and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s a weird case of trying to justify a purchase after the fact, even if it turned out to be horrible, out of some sense of pride, maybe? People hate being wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of someone I used to know who was an avid supporter of a particular candidate during the 2016 elections. Whenever he would fail to convince us of the merits of his candidate (or be unable to answer our concerns about his human rights record, etc), he would simply say &amp;ldquo;you guys just don&amp;rsquo;t trust him&amp;rdquo;. Which is a really weird thing to say because why trust any politician based on anything other than his track record and what he says or does? It always felt like he had already decided to trust this candidate and that nothing else mattered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like so many people in this country are so used to our politicians taking advantage of them that they have become hostage to this form of &amp;ldquo;rule&amp;rdquo;: ordinary people are subject to the harshness of the law, while for those in power, the law must be &amp;ldquo;tempered with compassion&amp;rdquo;. Being progressive and believing in pluralism in this country requires that we challenge those norms wherever we can, that we hold the powerful to account, regardless of political affiliation. It can be challenging to get people to look beyond their tribalistic nature, but it&amp;rsquo;s something we need to figure out if we are to survive and evolve as a truly democratic &amp;ldquo;rule of law&amp;rdquo; society and not devolve into some kind of right-wing populist authoritarian &amp;ldquo;rule of men&amp;rdquo; wasteland (if we aren&amp;rsquo;t already there yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going back to the Doctorow quote (which I&amp;rsquo;ve already strayed from a bit&amp;hellip; the last few paragraphs turned out a little ranty about the state of the country, but I&amp;rsquo;ve actually already rewritten it a couple of times to be&amp;hellip; less ranty I guess?), this model of how &amp;ldquo;the right&amp;rdquo; thinks can be a useful tool when engaging in debate or discussion with others (something I am less inclined to do these days). The two sides of this model are mostly incompatible, thus when discussing with anyone you can ask yourself (or them directly) which side of that divide they lie on. (I don&amp;rsquo;t imagine anyone would say out loud they believe people in power deserve special treatment, because that sounds absurd. Or evil. But that might just be the leftist perspective in me.) Whether they agree with you or not, at the very least it gives you a model in which to frame further discussion, or even to decide whether further discussion would even be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer 1: Doctorow is of course primarily left-leaning, hence his bias towards these definitions. It would be interesting to see what the equivalent definitions would be on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer 2: Every individual is slightly different. I use &amp;ldquo;the right&amp;rdquo; in quotes here to indicate that the generalizations are describing a significant subset of people who might consider themselves &amp;ldquo;right-wing&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;conservative&amp;rdquo; or whatnot. I use this label more for this particular way of thinking rather than a political alignment. (And I dislike labelling people anyway, as much as possible.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Social Media, High School Reunion Anxiety, and Envy
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/09/social-media-hsra-envy/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/09/social-media-hsra-envy/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The following article made the rounds recently: &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshcsimmons.com/2019/09/10/i-quit-social-media-for-a-year-and-nothing-magical-happened/&#34;&gt;I Quit Social Media for a Year and Nothing Magical Happened&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting enough not only on its own, but also for the discussion generated around any piece about qutting social media. I will admit I&amp;rsquo;ve been flirting with the idea myself, but that&amp;rsquo;s a topic for another day. Of particular interest to me at the moment is this comment about the article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20934675&#34;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest issue with social media is less that it&amp;rsquo;s distracting (IMO not necessarily an unhealthy thing) but that it has, for me, more than anything else seemed to make all aspects of my life a competition with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Instagram, you&amp;rsquo;re competing with others on who has the happiest life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On LinkedIn, you&amp;rsquo;re competing with others on who has the steepest career trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even on Twitter, perhaps more acutely in certain jobs or industries, it seems like you&amp;rsquo;re competing with other in gaining professional influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It creates a lot of anxiety that stems from a feeling like you&amp;rsquo;re constantly on the verge of falling behind others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plenty of scholars/thinkers/philosophers have said something to the effect of focusing on just being a better version of you. Social media enables the exact opposite i.e. forcing you to constantly evaluate how you compare to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminds me of my previous post &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2018/11/comparison-is-the-thief-of-joy/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Comparison is the Thief of Joy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. This kind of mindset is applicable to real life as well as social media, though I do agree that social media tends to exacerbate the problem. If you are the type of person who has this mindset, then yes it&amp;rsquo;s probably a good idea to reduce/control/filter your social media usage accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I generally don&amp;rsquo;t suffer from this problem, mainly because I outgrew comparing myself to other people a long time ago, but also because I tend to aggressively filter my social media channels so that I&amp;rsquo;m only seeing content from people that are of interest to me. I wonder sometimes about those people who whine that Twitter is so toxic or some such complaint. Don&amp;rsquo;t they know they control the kind of people who appear in their feed? Why are they following toxic people? (I understand that this may be more of a problem that is difficult to control once you get to higher follower counts, but hey that&amp;rsquo;s the price you pay I guess.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat related: Our 25th high school reunion is coming up next year, and this early our batch has a thread about High School Reunion Anxity (HSRA). Here are some excellent words from a batchmate that I thought were good to share (removing some stuff specific to this person and the batch, since the post was to a private group. Will happily cite the original poster if she requests it):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re not alone. It&amp;rsquo;s common to feel a lot of anxiety about attending a high school reunion. Our 25th at that. Kasi ohmaygad ganyan na ba tayong katanda?!
&amp;hellip;
The second common barrier to attending is HSRA. Mostly because you might feel your life didn&amp;rsquo;t turn out the way you wanted and that other batchmates have done so much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So 2a - your life didn&amp;rsquo;t turn out the way you wanted. You know what? My life didn&amp;rsquo;t turn out the way I wanted. &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m willing to bet nobody&amp;rsquo;s life turned out exactly the way they planned. And that&amp;rsquo;s OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2b - other batchmates have done better. OK so please for your own mental and emotional health do NOT compare other people&amp;rsquo;s external stuff (visible on Facebook, Instagram, etc) to your internal stuff. That&amp;rsquo;s illogical and bad science. Also will drive you crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Marketplace Ethics
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/08/marketplace-ethics/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/08/marketplace-ethics/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I brought up among one of my friend groups this Reddit thread where the poster says they were able to buy hundreds of dollars worth of &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/tags/magic-the-gathering/&#34;&gt;Magic&lt;/a&gt; cards from a garage sale for around $70. (Not gonna link to the original thread because it might seem like I&amp;rsquo;m shaming the OP.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that there&amp;rsquo;s anything bad with such &amp;ldquo;garage sale finds&amp;rdquo;, as it were. These things are posted every so often on subreddits especially those dedicated to some sort of collectible. I mentioned that while I would be very excited to find something like this in the wild, I might have an attack of conscience because I&amp;rsquo;m potentially cheating someone out of fair market value and taking advantage of their ignorance. I&amp;rsquo;m probably more likely to feel this way if I was dealing with a seller personally (like at a garage sale), rather than some entity indirectly (like at a big store for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, my ethical dilemma is only for the scenario where there is an information imbalance - where I as the buyer have information about the product&amp;rsquo;s fair market value that the seller is not aware of. If the seller knew full well the actual value of what he&amp;rsquo;s selling and he still sells at that price, then I will gladly buy it cheap with no concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-is-why-im-not-a-salesman&#34;&gt;This is why I&amp;rsquo;m not a salesman&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such a case, the way to assuage my ethical concerns would be to bring up the possible imbalance. Something along the lines of &amp;ldquo;I think you&amp;rsquo;re selling this for much less than what it&amp;rsquo;s worth!&amp;rdquo;, and if he nods and still wants to sell at that price anyway, then both of you complete the transaction happily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friend O commented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think people have a kind of &amp;ldquo;code of ethics&amp;rdquo; that applies to marketplaces&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that&amp;rsquo;s a bit different from everyday ethics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;just like how doctors/lawyers/priests have a code of ethics specific to their contexts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the idea is that participants in the marketplace should assume that everyone else is doing their due dilligence when it comes to price/quality research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I guess I can satisfy my concerns as well by telling myself that &amp;ldquo;Caveat Emptor&amp;rdquo; applies in the opposite direction as well, so &amp;ldquo;Caveat Venditor&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hold-yourself-to-a-higher-standard&#34;&gt;Hold yourself to a higher standard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am only presenting an ethical dilemma here as it applies to myself when I am the buyer in the above scenario, or otherwise the one with information advantage in the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been on the receiving end of bad trades before of course, numerous times. Such often happens when I foolishly decide to participate in a transaction without doing the necessary research, so I guess Caveat Venditor is accurate. I don&amp;rsquo;t lay blame on the other party for taking advantage of my ignorance either; after a bad trade I will most likely blame myself. Therefore, I don&amp;rsquo;t expect other people I am transacting with to treat me as fairly as I want to treat other people should I have the advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friend J pointed out that holding myself to a higher standard like this can be considered a bit elitist since it&amp;rsquo;s like considering yourself &amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo; than others. I think of it more like managing expectations of other people. Other people don&amp;rsquo;t have the same life experiences and values as I do, so some things are more important for me than for them. I would of course love it if everyone was conditioned to treat everyone else fairly in this manner - society would be much the better for it, but I understand the reality of human wants and needs enough to know that&amp;rsquo;s a pipe dream at best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;all-in-theory&#34;&gt;All in theory&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, all of this is untested, because I haven&amp;rsquo;t been lucky enough to find a deal like I originally described. Maybe when I&amp;rsquo;m there at that point in time all my ethical questions give way to impulse or greed and I&amp;rsquo;m already at home gleefully counting my winnings before the dilemma comes to mind. But I like to think thought experiments like these help to flesh out one&amp;rsquo;s thought processes so that when the time comes, one is more likely to behave appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Justice vs Vengeance
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/04/justice-vs-vengeance/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/04/justice-vs-vengeance/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;https://np.reddit.com/r/politics/comments/b87waa/the_supreme_courts_conservatives_just_legalized/ejwf8j5/&#34;&gt;/u/haveanicedayreddit on reddit&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very fact that our nation&amp;rsquo;s highest court is weighing in on the amount of cruelty we can inflict upon those we put to death suggests we&amp;rsquo;ve taken a wrong turn. And yet the very subject invites some to ask why we should even care about the feelings of rapists or murderers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s why we need to care. We need to care because our justice system demands it. Regardless of where we stand on the appropriateness of a death penalty, we must agree that the administration of any punishment must be done in the absence of passion or cruelty. Whether we&amp;rsquo;re putting someone to death, locking them up for shoplifting, interrogating them in a criminal case or holding them while we determine their legal residency status, we must be adamant in our commitment to do so in a way that&amp;rsquo;s free from resentment or rage… or amusement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this so important? It is important because when we allow anger and apathy to seep into our justice system we begin to do unjust things. We keep prisoners in tents whose temperatures reach 114 degrees. We lock them in solitary confinement and laugh as we watch them die of a seizure. We surround them at a traffic stop and kick them in the stomach and face while they lay handcuffed and helpless. We end up with a Supreme Court justice who erupts in a blind rage when his fitness is questioned. We end up with a president who admonishes police not to &amp;ldquo;go so easy&amp;rdquo; on suspects when apprehending them, a president who leads cheers of &amp;ldquo;lock them up&amp;rdquo; whenever he brings up a political opponent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We lose our way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very existence of a criminal justice system is an agreement where the public allows its government to suspend – or even eliminate – some of the rights outlined in our constitution. In doing so we expect our government to exercise this power with the utmost care and respect, even for those accused or convicted of the most serious offenses. Because to do otherwise invites vengeance into our system. Vengeance and justice cannot coexist; one will always replace the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of how in our country, there are politicians advocating for the death penalty in response to the supposed drug menace, when there has generally been &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2014/04/30/theres-still-no-evidence-that-executions-deter-criminals/?utm_term=.55ee4ef75738&#34;&gt;no evidence to show the death penalty deters crime&lt;/a&gt;. The last time we had the death penalty, only one convict was ever executed, the country did not have the stomach for it. I imagine (based only on the perceived behavior of our politicos) that those advocating for the death penalty do not really have deterrence in mind, but rather punishment - they wish to cruelly punish the offender to satisfy the bloodlust of the populace. i.e. Vengeance, not justice.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Capitalism
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2018/10/capitalism/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 01:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2018/10/capitalism/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;In fourth year HS, we had an Economics subject, and back then I was fascinated with the idea of free market capitalism &amp;ndash; the free market, the invisible hand, the law of supply and demand, and the idea that through competition we are forced to adapt and become better and more efficient in order to survive. Capitalism mirrored the law of nature: the strong will survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, I am much less enamored with the idea of capitalism. Not that I disbelieve that it makes us more efficient, but that ruthless efficiency has a cost. Like the law of nature that it mirrors, capitalism ensures that the strong survive, but the corollary is also true: the weak will die and be consumed by the strong. Humans are a societal species, which means we are supposed to be stronger together. But capitalism, optimized towards the pursuit of profit, often times can force us to sacrifice the greater good in favor of individual interests. Corporations especially, will often act as soulless entities whose mandate is above all to pursue profits in the name of the stockholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the societal ills in the world today can be directly traced to the ruthless efficiency in pursuit of profit, the prime example being environmental issues like climate change and pollution: governments don&amp;rsquo;t want to enact stronger controls because it will cut into corporations&amp;rsquo; bottom lines, and politicians don&amp;rsquo;t want to piss off corporations that they rely on for donations. Capitalism&amp;rsquo;s ruthless efficiency has brought us to a world of wage inequality, banks too large to fail, and large monolithic companies that are virtual monopolies due to network effect. It&amp;rsquo;s a system that reinforces the rich and powerful (the strong survive) while the masses suffer in silence (the weak will die)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergence of large monolithic corporations wielding monopoly powers is especially challenging, and is a natural consequence of &amp;ldquo;the strong survive&amp;rdquo;. As the rich get richer, they can use the accumulated power and money to defeat any further competition that dares to challenge them. Thus they are able to resist becoming more efficient in favor of simply using their leadership status as a blunt instrument. You can see this in the tech industry with virtual monopolies such as Google (search), Facebook (social networking), Amazon (sales, cloud hosting); realistically they can only be challenged by companies of similar scale, there is no space for smaller guys to move into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still think capitalism can be a force for good, and that efficiency is still something to strive for. But I also now believe that this efficiency should be tempered by a corresponding collectivism, whether enforced by states  (through regulation or subsidies or welfare programs) or by some other mechanism. The idea of something like universal basic income is promising, but under a purely free market system, I don&amp;rsquo;t see how it could work. It is hopefully not too late for us to find a way to navigate our society to a post-scarcity Star Trek-like future, where humans are able to dedicate themselves to scientific and artistic pursuits without worrying about survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(If this sounds like a rant with no proposed answers, it is. This post and others like are just me sounding off on how my thinking and philosophical leanings have changed throughout the years, so that I may consider where it can lead me to. Feel free to debate me in the comments.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>