<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Opinions on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/opinions/</link>
      <description>Recent content in Opinions on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/opinions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Speaking truth to power
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/speaking-truth-to-power/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/speaking-truth-to-power/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;According to Wikipedia, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speaking_truth_to_power&#34;&gt;Speaking truth to power&lt;/a&gt; is a non-violent political tactic, employed by dissidents against the received wisdom or propaganda of governments they regard as oppressive, authoritarian or an ideocracy. I always had the general sense of it before, but not that it was specifically for use against oppressive or authoritarian governments. It is believed the phrase has origins in a Quaker pamphlet published in 1955.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reminded of this phrase today and looked it up because it seems relevant again recently, at least in the Philippines. Recently Maria Ressa, the head of the online news site Rappler, was arrested at dusk (so no bail could be set), on charges of cyberlibel, for an online article published before cyberlibel became a crime. Ostensibly, the state&amp;rsquo;s rationale is that there was a minor edit to the article after the cyberlibel law was passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m struggling to think of any instance where a state authority arrested journalists without the intent to silence criticism. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying there aren&amp;rsquo;t any - there probably are - but probably such instances don&amp;rsquo;t get much publicity precisely because they are normal functions of the state. For this instance, it feels very much as just the next step in targetted harassment against those who, as they say, speak truth to power. I remember one of the pork barrel senators saying during the launch of his senatorial campaign that he was the victim of &amp;ldquo;selective justice&amp;rdquo; (which is weird because it still implies he was guilty, just that other people were guilty too). I&amp;rsquo;m hoping in some interview someone has the balls to ask the senatorial candidates whether they think Trillianes or Ressa have been victims of &amp;ldquo;selective justice&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro-admin partisans of course will just say &amp;ldquo;rule of law&amp;rdquo; etc, which they like to do when someone they dislike is being targetted, but not when say, suspected criminals are killed by vigilantes or under suspicious circumstances by the police. Most probably in their heart of hearts they know exactly what is going on here, and they either approve of it wholeheartedly or view it as a necessary compromise in their pursuit of what they believe to be good for the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to avoid being too political in this blog, maybe sticking with the occasional rant or election-related personal leanings post. But with the climate these days, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that&amp;rsquo;s resposible. Those of us who are able to speak out on our platforms, no matter how small, don&amp;rsquo;t we have a responsibility to speak truth to power?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Companies banned because of their governments
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/companies-banned-because-of-their-governments/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/companies-banned-because-of-their-governments/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;In late 2017, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-USA-cyber-kaspersky/trump-signs-into-law-u-s-government-ban-on-kaspersky-lab-software-idUSKBN1E62V4&#34;&gt;US moved to ban Kaspersky antivirus from use by federal agencies&lt;/a&gt;, because of suspected influence from the Russian government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late 2018, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2018/12/countries-banning-huawei-181206130850129.html&#34;&gt;the US and other countries have either banned or are considering banning the Chinese tech giant Huawei and its telecoms products&lt;/a&gt;, for security reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both companies are under scrutiny for their perceived ties to their governments, both of which happen to have authoritarian leanings. From a certain POV, the bannings may be unfair, as they are &amp;ldquo;preventive&amp;rdquo; in nature, i.e. punishment is given preemptively before any offence is discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to me because it shows that being under the sway of an authoritarian leadership can be considered a competitive disadvantage in the international marketplace. Trust in the Russian and Chinese governments is low (internationally), which affects the corporations working out of those states. While they may not be doing anything nefarious now, the fact that these states &lt;em&gt;can possibly&lt;/em&gt; influence these companies is already a considerable risk, especially for government&amp;rsquo;s mission-critical systems given the geopolitical history and past behavior of those states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even here in the Philippines, there is some level of mistrust against the entry of the supposed third telco, which is a consortium of which China Telecom is a part, mainly for security concerns as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, this distrust should not be limited to Russia and China. For example, the US also has a history of requesting information from tech companies like Facebook, Google, Twitter, and so on. So in theory these US-based companies should not be trusted with communication platforms, etc. The difference is that the US-based companies have a stronger history of independence from the US government. They also regularly release &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.engadget.com/2017/12/18/facebooks-government-data-requests-continue-to-rise/&#34;&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; about how the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnet.com/news/google-reports-all-time-high-of-government-data-requests/&#34;&gt;US and other governments request data&lt;/a&gt; from them. These are exercises to build trust from the consumer base, to emphasize their independence from any one state authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kaspersky ban was a relatively small deal, I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure if it affected Kaspersky at all. But the Huawei (and potentially ZTE as well) ban would be more important as Huawei is a very large telecoms company currently. It will be interesting to see how they move forward - will they take actions to assert their independence from the Chinese state and improve international trust? Or will they double down and have China resort to diplomatic pressure?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>On Trump and Zuckerberg
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/on-trump-and-zuckerberg/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 02:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/on-trump-and-zuckerberg/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Donald Trump and Mark Zuckerberg are different people in vastly different positions, but I find it interesting the uncanny parallels their stories have taken them through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many non-Americans, I&amp;rsquo;m acutely aware of the shenanigans of Donald Trump, the current US president. It would be a fascinating story, if only it weren&amp;rsquo;t so bad for the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His character arc is of someone who rose to the level of this own incompetence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before becoming president, he was basically the worst kind of businessman - a sleazy con man/grifter always looking out for ways to scam other people to further his own interests. A snake oil salesman who somehow stumbled into becoming president of the most powerful country on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who knows why he ran for president? Maybe the Russians goaded him into it. Maybe he thought it was good for his businesses. Maybe he thought he could profit off campaign contributions. The most unlikely reason seems to be that he believes he could do good for his country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now he finds himself in a very challenging position, the pressures and problems which could be understand by very few other people in the world. His position is now subject to increased legal scrutiny that could threaten him, his family, and even his con man businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many tech guys, I&amp;rsquo;m also acutely aware of the problems besetting Mark Zuckerberg and his super-dominant social network Facebook, mostly problems of his own making. Again, it would be a fascinating story, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t so bad for the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like Trump, he seems to have risen to the level of his own incompetence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He started this software company when he was still in college and somehow it grew and snowballed until he was in charge of the most powerful communication platform on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t start out with noble intentions, calling his users &amp;ldquo;dumbfucks&amp;rdquo; and everything, so it&amp;rsquo;s no surprise he and his company made a lot of stumbles along the way, many of them only coming out just now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He surely had no idea that his proposed advertising business model and his mission of connecting the world would lead to fake news, Russian collusion, and numerous privacy problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His position as head of Facebook leads to pressures and problems which could be understand by very few other people in the world. And now he finds himself under increased legal scrutiny that could threaten his business model, his company, and even his legacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someday (perhaps soon), Trump and Zuckerberg will be held to account for their failings. Until then, the world is being moved by men who were completely unprepared for their positions and are basically making it up as they go along. (Of course, many, many people are making it up as they go along&amp;hellip;). I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if there any lessons to be learned from these observations, but maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just a stark reminder that a man&amp;rsquo;s reach cannot exceed his grasp.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Great Filter
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/the-great-filter/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 01:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/the-great-filter/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Sorry, a bit more doom and gloom this time: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2018/dec/03/david-attenborough-collapse-civilisation-on-horizon-un-climate-summit&#34;&gt;David Attenborough: collapse of civilisation is on the horizon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was visiting at a friend&amp;rsquo;s house recently and our discussion turned to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/the-sky-is-falling/&#34;&gt;the impending doom threatening the world&lt;/a&gt;. While I hold out a tiny bit of hope that maybe somehow human society and/or science will find a way to save us, he was not so optimistic. He reads and writes a lot of speculative fiction and his view is that we are inevitably headed towards an era of land scarcity and resulting wars due to climate changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you imagine, some thousands of years down the line, some spacefaring alien race chances upon the remains of our sorry civilization and discover all this discussion of our civilization&amp;rsquo;s impending collapse and they&amp;rsquo;re trying to figure out why our civilization fell apart in spite of having sufficient foreknowledge of the upcoming disaster, and they&amp;rsquo;re incredulous that we simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered because it was too inconvenient!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would humanity still be able to find a way out of this corner we&amp;rsquo;ve painted our way into? Recent signs are not encouraging. We know there is upcoming disaster and yet any adjustment on our part must come at great economic or political costs that we are unable to pay. Climate change is a far-away risk for most people who struggle with everyday problems. Consider the case of Macron&amp;rsquo;s France, which was recently &lt;a href=&#34;https://edition.cnn.com/2018/12/05/europe/france-yellow-vest-protests-intl/index.html&#34;&gt;forced by protests to withdraw a fuel tax&lt;/a&gt; that was intended to reduce the country&amp;rsquo;s climate impact. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.channelnewsasia.com/news/world/trump-attacks-paris-climate-agreement-cites-france-protests-11014022&#34;&gt;Trump uses this event to justify the US withdrawal from the Paris climate treaty&lt;/a&gt;. The US clings to its climate-destroying industries like coal in a bid to save jobs. Companies refuse to be regulated because it would be too expensive. And so it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This inability to come together and bypass individual interests and work towards a common good may very well be what is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Filter&#34;&gt;the great filter&lt;/a&gt;, and it is in front of us, leading to a high probability of self-destruction. Inequality, itself a result of unbridled individualism, makes it much harder for us to come together as well. Capitalism, in spite of its propensity for ruthless efficiency, is not very good at managing a communal property like our planet (or the internet, etc). By endearing ourself to capitalism during the 20th century, we may have chosen a path of doom for our civilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this actually made me rethink authoritarianism. Our cultural embrace of freedoms make it difficult to force people to swallow bitter pills needed for our civilization to survive. What if the path to sustainable collective survival lies in the private sector made ruthlessly efficient by capitalism, yet tempered by an authoritarian state that manages the common good? What if China was right all along? They are certainly more committed to battling climate change at the moment, compared to the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t advocate any shift towards authoritarianism or fascism of course, but it might be time to consider surrendering some of our individual freedoms and ambitions for the greater good. Inequality needs to be addressed too, some level of socialism might be necessary, such that the burden may be shouldered more by the elites who have taken most of the benefits from the planet anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I think I already have a very low carbon footprint, compared to the average middle class person. I try not to travel too much (even within the city), and I don&amp;rsquo;t drive a car. But the weight of these decisions isn&amp;rsquo;t on us ordinary citizens, especially the developing world. There is very little we can do individually. The onus is on the leadership especially of the more advanced nations, to take the bold steps necessary to reduce inequality and emissions, and on the elite, to participate in the redistribution of wealth and to make sacrifices for the greater good. For the rest of us, all we can do is raise our voices in protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sound like I&amp;rsquo;m calling for some kind of revolution, but I&amp;rsquo;m merely thinking out loud. I&amp;rsquo;m worried for what is to come. For my generation, things will probably be fine. But if nothing is done, the next 2 or 3 generations might be looking at living vastly more difficult lives. I realize this post seems really pessimistic (same for the prior one), which seems a bit off-brand for me. Maybe if we&amp;rsquo;re lucky, I&amp;rsquo;m totally wrong and within the next 5-10 years some kind of solution emerges, and I&amp;rsquo;ll look back at this post and laugh at how silly I was to be worried, but given the nature of humans and society it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to be optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Paradox of Tolerance
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/the-paradox-of-tolerance/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 05:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/the-paradox-of-tolerance/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;When I was young, I was a fan of Voltaire’s famous quote &amp;ldquo;I disapprove of what you say, but I will defend to the death your right to say it.&amp;rdquo;. Today, in the face of a world where hatemongers and the intolerant are able to use modern communication technologies to more easily spread their views, I realize that things may not be so black and white. Like so many beliefs I held when I was young, I now find myself of the opinion that instead of absolute tolerance (which may not even be possible), there is some semblance of intolerance that may be needed to keep to the ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter Karl Popper’s Paradox of Tolerance:&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://preview.redd.it/uedawtfzqbgz.jpg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=fd2456eb7ee01f3eef7db8bb7adf91e7076e988a&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or if you want to read his actual text from &lt;em&gt;The Open Society and Its Enemies:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &#34;Unlimited tolerance must lead to the disappearance of tolerance. If we extend unlimited tolerance even to those who are intolerant, if we are not prepared to defend a tolerant society against the onslaught of the intolerant, then the tolerant will be destroyed, and tolerance with them. In this formulation, I do not imply, for instance, that we should always suppress the utterance of intolerant philosophies; as long as we can counter them by rational argument and keep them in check by public opinion, suppression would certainly be most unwise. But we should claim the right to suppress them if necessary even by force; for it may easily turn out that they are not prepared to meet us on the level of rational argument, but begin by denouncing all argument; they may forbid their followers to listen to rational argument, because it is deceptive, and teach them to answer arguments by the use of their fists or pistols. We should therefore claim, in the name of tolerance, the right not to tolerate the intolerant. We should claim that any movement preaching intolerance places itself outside the law, and we should consider incitement to intolerance and persecution as criminal, in the same way as we should consider incitement to murder, or to kidnapping, or to the revival of the slave trade, as criminal.&#34;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another article about it that I like is this Medium post titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://extranewsfeed.com/tolerance-is-not-a-moral-precept-1af7007d6376&#34;&gt;Tolerance is not a Moral Precept&lt;/a&gt;. From this post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tolerance is not a moral absolute; it is a peace treaty.&lt;/strong&gt;Tolerance is a social norm because it allows different people to live side-by-side without being at each other’s throats. It means that we accept that people may be different from us, in their customs, in their behavior, in their dress, in their sex lives, and that if this doesn’t directly affect our lives, it is none of our business. But the model of a peace treaty differs from the model of a moral precept in one simple way: the protection of a peace treaty only extends to those willing to abide by its terms. It is an agreement to live in peace, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; an agreement to be peaceful no matter the conduct of others. A peace treaty is not a suicide pact.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet another essay, the work Nassim Taleb (author of &lt;em&gt;The Black Swan)&lt;/em&gt;, asserts that &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/incerto/the-most-intolerant-wins-the-dictatorship-of-the-small-minority-3f1f83ce4e15&#34;&gt;intolerant minorities can easily take over a majority&lt;/a&gt;, if not controlled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;We can answer these points using the minority rule. Yes, an intolerant minority can control and destroy democracy. Actually, as we saw, it &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; eventually destroy our world.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Popper still advocates maximum tolerance as long as the intolerant can be held in check, but he assumes there is a limit beyond which such is no longer viable. Society will need to find the proper balance.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The sky is falling
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/the-sky-is-falling/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 05:03:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/the-sky-is-falling/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of doom and gloom and bad news in the world these days, giving us ordinary folk little reason to be optimistic. Examples include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we are almost certainly too late to prevent climate change at all and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.minnpost.com/earth-journal/2018/10/new-outlook-on-global-warming-best-prepare-for-social-collapse-and-soon/?fbclid=IwAR2OR1lTChzd3eAnEl9nnlCpgDr9GhvUKxNrCd5JNXShQK9Uj8EMCbKPvhM&#34;&gt;social collapse is now an actual possibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump has begun taking steps to walk back a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www3.nhk.or.jp/nhkworld/en/news/20181021_80/&#34;&gt;nuclear arms control treaty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;increasing trends of nationalism and populism threatening to walk back the gains of globalisation (i.e. Brexit) and diversity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elon Musk warns us of the existential threat of artificial intelligence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;locally, some friends of mine are largely pessimistic about the future of Philippine society as it seems that we are falling further into the trap of autocratic leanings and dynasty-driven patronage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if things are looking so bad because we are coming from a period of relative peace and expansion of liberal democracy the past few decades (not saying things are perfect, but at least we haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten into any world wars recently). Maybe some of the societal and cultural problems highlighted above may be nothing more than society trying to find a new equilibrium in an age of political correctness and social justice. Climate change is of course, a game changing problem that we as a society seem to be unable to face or control. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to think of myself as an optimist, but even I am increasingly wary of where our world and my country are heading. I am slightly comforted by the words of an American novelist, which I heard from the recent season of Daredevil:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &#34;Life is to be lived, not controlled; and humanity is won by continuing to play in face of certain defeat.&#34;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&amp;ndash; Ralph Ellison&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have to hold out hope that humanity and society can adapt and survive these crises, that we have not come all this way simply to lose to our own hubris.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Change and Risk and Governments
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/change-and-risk-and-governments/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 05:03:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/change-and-risk-and-governments/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Systemic change is difficult. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about software projects/systems, but there are a lot of parallels with societal systems too, like governments or states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been in large projects with hundreds of thousands of LOC where a lot of the code was painful to read and full of code smells and so on. It happens over time as projects get maintained by different developers and teams or different enhancements or changes are made. It becomes more difficult/costly for new developers to work on the project as things are brittle and may easily fall apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also had the dubious pleasure of living under a system of government heavily burdened by corruption and inefficiency and patronage and nepotism and inequality and a bunch of other problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Will Be Tempted To Throw Everything Out And Start Over&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such situations, you will often find yourself fed up. You will be tempted to throw everything away and start over and rebuild everything from scratch. You wonder who made all of these past decisions that have resulted in such a terrible system and what the heck were they thinking?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, you can&amp;rsquo;t just throw everything away. People still need to eat, and the system users still need to do their work. You can instead do some kind of system-wide one-time big-time change. But the problem with that is&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Change Is Risk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More often than not, the existing system works. Or at least, it works well enough that the system isn&amp;rsquo;t totally unusable. The software system&amp;rsquo;s users can still perform the needed functions, albeit maybe with some number of bugs. The state&amp;rsquo;s citizens can still mostly survive and there aren&amp;rsquo;t riots on the streets or people dying of mass starvation or anything like that. Life is hard, but there is life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking to change things means some level of risk, and of course some level of cost. There are several possible outcomes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change happens and things become better. Hooray! The change was worth it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change happens but things remain the same. Uhh, why did we spend all that time and effort for the change then?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change happens but things actually get worse. This is the worst of all worlds. We wasted time and money and energy and things got worse! Why didn&amp;rsquo;t anyone warn us this could happen!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often we can&amp;rsquo;t predict with any certainty which outcome will happen. We can make educated guesses, by comparing to past experiences or other people&amp;rsquo;s experiences. **But each software project is unique. **This is kind of a blessing since it means it&amp;rsquo;s hard for programmers to run out of work. But it&amp;rsquo;s also more of a curse since it means we can only reuse small parts from other projects with no guarantee that the entire whole will work cohesively together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Countries/states/governments are unique too. Each people has their own geography, culture and history and unique problems arising from such. And to make matters worse, countries are made up of people, and most people will have differing opinions on which things are better and which things are worse. This makes it much more difficult to form a consensus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;****Granted that change is risk. But sometimes we have to take those risks anyway. We have to decide whether the risk is worth the possible upside vs the potential downside.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Superhero shows being political
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/superhero-shows-being-political/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 05:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/superhero-shows-being-political/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Comic books and superheroes have always tended to skew towards liberal philosophies, given how writers and artists tend to support ideals like individualism and free expression. So it&amp;rsquo;s not surprising that the derivative shows tend to lean the same way. Not only do many of the shows promote diversity, but many are becoming overtly political as well. Some recent examples. (Spoilers for current seasons of Supergirl, Legends of Tomorrow and Daredevil follow)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The current season 4 of Supergirl seems to be focusing on anti-alien sentiment, a thinly-veiled allegory towards the anti-immigration movement propagated in far right &amp;ldquo;nationalist&amp;rdquo; circles. Similar to real-life, hatemongers are portrayed riling up crowds frustrated with losing jobs and threats to law and order due to the presence of &amp;ldquo;aliens&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The pilot episode of Legends of Tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s season 4 includes a short segment where one of the characters visits her mother, a Muslim immigrant in the US, and wishes she could warn her to move to Canada before &amp;ldquo;this country turns against her.&amp;rdquo; Do the Legends know about things to come? (Of course, during the previous season, the showrunners &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2017/aug/4/dcs-legends-of-tomorrow-producer-admits-muslim-cha/&#34;&gt;admitted that the Muslim character in question was introduced precisely as a response to Trump&amp;rsquo;s election&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally, in the fantastic Daredevil season 3, Wilson&amp;rsquo;s Fisk&amp;rsquo;s being billeted in the &amp;ldquo;Presidential Hotel&amp;rdquo; and his calling out his supposed crimes as politically-motivated &amp;ldquo;fake news&amp;rdquo; reminds a lot of people of the current American president. If that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough, &lt;a href=&#34;http://boundingintocomics.com/2018/10/18/daredevil-season-3-showrunner-compares-wilson-fisk-to-donald-trump/&#34;&gt;even the showrunner compares the Kingpin to Trump&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though it&amp;rsquo;s not a completely new thing I&amp;rsquo;m glad the showrunners are willing to make their political opinions known. This, despite the existence the so-called ComicsGate movement among a minority of superhero fans, which is a self-described revolt against &amp;ldquo;liberalism&amp;rdquo;. I wonder if these ComicsGate people also hate the TV shows?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Suggested additions to HS curriculum
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/suggested-additions-to-hs-curriculum/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/suggested-additions-to-hs-curriculum/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I have no plans of running for elective office (though it is a running joke among some of my circles), but if I were, one of the problems I would focus on would be education. As such, I have a list of suggested additions to the High School curriculum here in the Philippines. (The first version of this list was in an FB post I wrote during the 2016 campaign period, in response to people clamoring for better Martial Law education. I have since made additions and added some notes. )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planninbasic logic and reasoning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;different types of fallacies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to do basic research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;critical analysis of history &amp;ndash; not just the rote memorization of dates and names common in most schools, but the students should be encouraged to analyze why things happened the way they did&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to judge whether something is likely to be true &amp;ndash; not sure if this is possible, humans are quite bad at making judgements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to judge whether a source is reliable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to to identify satire and/or sarcasm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basic concepts of statistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to articulate your arguments well (I think the Eng/Fil subject in HS curriculum covers only literature and not any sort of communication skill)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how to debate and argue without taking things personally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planning, decision making and time management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basic concepts of economics (including how taxes work, inflation, GDP, mortgages, loans, etc &amp;ndash; we had an economics subject in 4th year HS, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know if that&amp;rsquo;s standard and it was mostly theory and not on day-to-day applications)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basic concepts of investments and financial advice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ethics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;proper usage of memes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when it is appropriate to post spoilers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, the challenge here is that many of these topics are easily &amp;ldquo;testable&amp;rdquo;, i.e. it means the teacher will have to work harder with individual students to make sure they are understanding the concepts. If we turn these topics into simply rote memorization classes, then they would be useless anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure the lack of critical thinking/analysis and other life skills in education curricula isn&amp;rsquo;t a problem unique to our country, but as a developing nation I think it&amp;rsquo;s an important aspect that we can&amp;rsquo;t afford to skimp on if we want to accelerate our development. The information age requires more than factory workers and rote memorization skills, it requires a well-educated citizenry with creativity and thinking out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Capitalism
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/capitalism/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 01:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/capitalism/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;In fourth year HS, we had an Economics subject, and back then I was fascinated with the idea of free market capitalism &amp;ndash; the free market, the invisible hand, the law of supply and demand, and the idea that through competition we are forced to adapt and become better and more efficient in order to survive. Capitalism mirrored the law of nature: the strong will survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, I am much less enamored with the idea of capitalism. Not that I disbelieve that it makes us more efficient, but that ruthless efficiency has a cost. Like the law of nature that it mirrors, capitalism ensures that the strong survive, but the corollary is also true: the weak will die and be consumed by the strong. Humans are a societal species, which means we are supposed to be stronger together. But capitalism, optimized towards the pursuit of profit, often times can force us to sacrifice the greater good in favor of individual interests. Corporations especially, will often act as soulless entities whose mandate is above all to pursue profits in the name of the stockholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the societal ills in the world today can be directly traced to the ruthless efficiency in pursuit of profit, the prime example being environmental issues like climate change and pollution: governments don&amp;rsquo;t want to enact stronger controls because it will cut into corporations&amp;rsquo; bottom lines, and politicians don&amp;rsquo;t want to piss off corporations that they rely on for donations. Capitalism&amp;rsquo;s ruthless efficiency has brought us to a world of wage inequality, banks too large to fail, and large monolithic companies that are virtual monopolies due to network effect. It&amp;rsquo;s a system that reinforces the rich and powerful (the strong survive) while the masses suffer in silence (the weak will die)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergence of large monolithic corporations wielding monopoly powers is especially challenging, and is a natural consequence of &amp;ldquo;the strong survive&amp;rdquo;. As the rich get richer, they can use the accumulated power and money to defeat any further competition that dares to challenge them. Thus they are able to resist becoming more efficient in favor of simply using their leadership status as a blunt instrument. You can see this in the tech industry with virtual monopolies such as Google (search), Facebook (social networking), Amazon (sales, cloud hosting); realistically they can only be challenged by companies of similar scale, there is no space for smaller guys to move into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still think capitalism can be a force for good, and that efficiency is still something to strive for. But I also now believe that this efficiency should be tempered by a corresponding collectivism, whether enforced by states  (through regulation or subsidies or welfare programs) or by some other mechanism. The idea of something like universal basic income is promising, but under a purely free market system, I don&amp;rsquo;t see how it could work. It is hopefully not too late for us to find a way to navigate our society to a post-scarcity Star Trek-like future, where humans are able to dedicate themselves to scientific and artistic pursuits without worrying about survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(If this sounds like a rant with no proposed answers, it is. This post and others like are just me sounding off on how my thinking and philosophical leanings have changed throughout the years, so that I may consider where it can lead me to. Feel free to debate me in the comments.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The perils of hyperpartisanship
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/the-perils-of-hyperpartisanship/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 01:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/the-perils-of-hyperpartisanship/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A few days ago I read this great &lt;a href=&#34;https://np.reddit.com/r/europe/comments/9mcuy2/viral_manspreading_video_is_staged_kremlin/e7e10n2/&#34;&gt;Reddit comment about how increasing hyperpartisanship makes it easier to influence the entire population&lt;/a&gt;. Quoting the relevant part:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;Once you&#39;ve done that, you have a population that&#39;s easier to manipulate. You have, say, 30% that&#39;s 100% sure on both ends, and probably another 15% on both ends that are 80% sure, and a remaining 10% that could go both ways. The more you do this, the more the 15% will be set in stone.&lt;br /&gt;Then, the fun begins with manipulating the 10%. You know where they live (through facebook), you know how they think (Cambridge Analytica), so you can target &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt;, and only &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt;. Not only can you target this particular group, but by knowing how the electoral system works, you can target only a few people, in a few swing states.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US is already in this hyperpartisan state, as evidenced by how the &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1049048025073512448.html&#34;&gt;GOP rhetoric often has them itching for civil war&lt;/a&gt;. This is kind of mirrored in the more extreme online views of some pro-admin people here in the PH, with admin propaganda minions demonizing anyone who opposes the president and some literally calling for opposition to be jailed or even killed. I don&amp;rsquo;t think the PH has gotten as bad as the US in terms of hyperpartisanship though, mainly because (a) political parties in the Philippines are a joke; (b) Majority of Filipinos distrust politicians in general (hence the popular term &amp;ldquo;trapo&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s just that they still vote for them even knowing how they are); and (c) Filipino politicians&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a friend who has given up on being moderate or centrist, he says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;br /&gt;The past couple of years have taught me that politics really is like Game of Thrones. Moderation and compromise is weak. If you get complacent, if you let your foot off their throat, they&#39;ll destroy you, so you need to be willing to do all that dirty stuff right back.&lt;br /&gt;In the US the other side is racists, misogynists and rich old white ppl. In the Philippines the other side LITERALLY HAS DEATH SQUADS.&lt;br /&gt;Progressives can never let up on the gas. They can never stop and say &#34;this is enough,&#34; because if you do, the gains it took decades to work toward can be undone just like that.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure he knows I disagree with this position &amp;ndash; I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in fighting dirty (but I do believe in calling out those who do). I&amp;rsquo;m not advocating we adhere to the Spaceballs quote &amp;ldquo;Evil will always triumph because good is dumb,&amp;rdquo; but rather I would prefer people find a way to rise above this hyperpartisanship and find better ways to resolve differences. Somehow, there&amp;rsquo;s still part of a &amp;ldquo;Lawful Good&amp;rdquo; idealist in me, despite the best efforts of this terrible world. Maybe this will be the death of me when fascists start trampling over the rest of us.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>What is education for?
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/what-is-education-for/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 01:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/what-is-education-for/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I recently watched this TedX talk by Seth Godin about the purpose of school/education: &lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-embed-youtube wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-has-aspect-ratio wp-embed-aspect-16-9&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;wp-block-embed__wrapper&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&#34;1040&#34; height=&#34;585&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/sXpbONjV1Jc?feature=oembed&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; encrypted-media&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;One of the best points I agree with from the talk is that majority of our educational system is geared towards generating graduates who are obedient. We teach students from a young age to follow rules and answer roll calls. We teach them standard prescribed solutions. We teach them how to take exams and how to find the right answers. Even school culture among students teaches kids to conform or be ostracized. Our school systems are optimized for generating employees for industry &amp;ndash; and in the old days industry meant factory workers, who knew just enough to get on an assembly line and put things together. Even today, we are told that the purpose of education is that we need it in order to get a good job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Locally, this talk became even more relevant when the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cnnphilippines.com/news/2018/10/04/Protest-rally-student-activists-UP-state-universities-PNP-Albayalde.html&#34;&gt;Director General of the Philippine National Police questioned why state scholars &amp;ldquo;go against the government&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. This is a common line found in the comments section of news articles as well whenever students from universities would participate in protest actions against the government. As if by virtue of the government providing for the education of its citizens (as is their responsibility), the students now owe the government an unquestioning obedience and should turn a blind eye to any of the government&amp;rsquo;s abuses. (This line of thinking seems to be primarily prominent during the current administration though &amp;ndash; I didn&amp;rsquo;t really notice people commenting this way during previous admins despite the fact that students have *always* tended to be more activist).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this is working as intended. The purpose of the state sponsoring education shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be in order to create obedient, unquestioning citizens. It should be to create citizens that are more discerning and analytical and able to make intelligent and informed decisions about the country&amp;rsquo;s future. And we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be educating people simply so they can find good jobs (although that&amp;rsquo;s part of the reason as well), we should also be educating them because an educated citizenry leads to a better society. (And when I say educated here, I assume there is an ethics component involved as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student activism isn&amp;rsquo;t a bug, it&amp;rsquo;s a feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Of course, I&amp;rsquo;m not advocating that all students should be required to be activists, just that we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t consider universities producing some percentage of students as activists as a problem.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Boxes
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/boxes/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 01:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/boxes/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;We put people into boxes because it is convenient. It&amp;rsquo;s easier for our mental model of the world to say to yourself things like &amp;ldquo;This guy works with computers, maybe he can tell me how to fix my printer.&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;This person is from [school] and they are very arrogant.&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re from [country]? You guys do [that country&amp;rsquo;s thing] right?&amp;rdquo; or  &amp;ldquo;This person is a supporter of [politician] so he must support all the things that politician does, even the things I hate.&amp;rdquo; Or in the modern world, there are even worse stereotypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boxes and stereotypes are convenient because it means we don&amp;rsquo;t need to relearn our reactions and opinions when presented with a new person. We simply choose a convenient box to put them in and then we convince ourselves we are treating them appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the real world is not so discrete. The real world is a lot more granular, a lot more nuanced. While it is inconvenient for your mental model, people will usually not fit exactly into any of your preconceived boxes. Or they may fit in multiple boxes. Or maybe none at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time you put a person into a box, you discredit her by some amount. In your mind, you shave off some of who he is a person so that he better fits your box. And for many instances, maybe that&amp;rsquo;s okay. Maybe you don&amp;rsquo;t have any significant interaction with that person, and the simpler mental model is sufficient. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to understand the character nuances of every grocery store cashier for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But beyond that, in order to pursue any kind of meaningful interaction with another person, that is insufficient. We must be willing to set aside whatever box you have put a person into and be willing to understand all those little bits we set aside. Those nuances characterize and define the individual, not whatever box we have put him into.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>War
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/war/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 01:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/02/war/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;As of today, our country (The #Blessed Republic of the Philippines) is already at war with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Illegal gambling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communist rebels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other things we might consider declaring war on (in no particular order):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poverty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ignorance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Misinformation (sorry, &amp;ldquo;Alternative facts&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abusive government officials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traffic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rights abuses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pollution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High power rates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Political dynasties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poor quality of local cinema offerings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Politicians putting their names everywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet trolls and bullies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of critical thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redundancy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overtime without overtime pay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Government officials blatantly lying or pulling statistics out of thin air&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slow and expensive internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The MRT breaking down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cruelty to animals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poor quality of local anti-piracy ads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jejespeak&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SMS spam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typhoons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taxis that don&amp;rsquo;t give exact change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;War&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Irony&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoilers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pineapples on pizza&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poor grammar and/or spelling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hashtags&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hypocrisy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-level marketing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working at &amp;ldquo;Edi sa puso mo&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redundancy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low effort blog posts that start out serious but end up trying a bit too hard to be funny&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who don&amp;rsquo;t understand sarcasm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who stand in malls and shove fliers in your face&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commenting on posts without reading the actual article&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lists that end abruptly at weird numbers so you&amp;rsquo;re not sure if there&amp;rsquo;s more or what&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>12 Signs You Should Think About Leaving Your Job
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/12-signs-you-should-think-about-leaving-your-job/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 01:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/12-signs-you-should-think-about-leaving-your-job/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Signs you think about leaving your current job:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The company culture has changed in ways you don&amp;rsquo;t like or recognize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are no longer proud of the work you do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are always feeling tired, even when you just got to work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You more easily notice your coworkers&amp;rsquo; screwups and are more easily annoyed at them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You feel unappreciated for the work you do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You feel like the company doesn&amp;rsquo;t listen to your inputs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many of your close friends in the company are unhappy and want to leave or are already leaving or have already left&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You no longer trust your boss to make good decisions about the company&amp;rsquo;s future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are always looking for more free time to pursue other pursuits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday and you&amp;rsquo;re already looking forward to Friday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You hate your commute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You start reading articles about signs you should think about leaving your job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people feel trapped in their current job. They feel that they will be unable to find better or at least similar work and will rather stay than risk it. It&amp;rsquo;s a false sense of &amp;ldquo;job security&amp;rdquo; vs fear. It might be true that you have no good options. But if you&amp;rsquo;re not looking at all, it&amp;rsquo;s 100% surely true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t find better options, the act of looking for them helps you through some sort of catharsis. It confirms if you really have no choice but to stay. It helps you understand your place in the job market and what you can do to improve your position and maybe open up more options later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom line: if you&amp;rsquo;re unhappy in any way (as indicated by any of the signs above), you should at least be looking. Otherwise you are doing yourself a disservice.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Notes on Decision Making
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/notes-on-decision-making/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 01:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/notes-on-decision-making/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At my old job I used to have this group of coworkers I had Friday lunch outs with. Inevitably, every Friday around noon someone would message the others asking &amp;ldquo;where are we eating?&amp;rdquo;. Now, there are a lot of good places to eat around the area and we&amp;rsquo;ve all been working there a while so most of the time we don&amp;rsquo;t care where we eat and we&amp;rsquo;d say we&amp;rsquo;ll decide when we get to the elevators. We get to the elevators but we&amp;rsquo;re still not sure where to eat. So we take the elevators down and we&amp;rsquo;ll figure it out downstairs. What often happened is that we ended up walking around, wasting time and eventually just choosing a place at random. It was a weird sort of decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decision making can be tough, especially for big, complicated decisions that need to be evaluated on multiple axes. Buying a house, choosing a new job, and yes, even where to have lunch, these are all examples of possibly tough decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, you are able to put forth a set of requirements for your decisions and then you check which among the available options best fulfills the requirements. Sometimes that approach is insufficient. It can be because you are lacking information or have too much information or have too many choices or none of the choices are acceptable or you are unable to properly evaluate the trade-offs between different criteria, or maybe even that your subconscious has a set of &amp;ldquo;secret&amp;rdquo; requirements that you are unable to formalize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some notes I&amp;rsquo;ve kept on decision-making:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spending too much time on decision-making is a cost. Be aware if there is a time limit to your decision making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For most things, decision-making should be quick and easy. Minimize decision making for unimportant (read: low cost or low impact) stuff. For example, remembering passwords. Either use an app or a scheme so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to decide or try to remember what the password for each site is. &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t sweat the small stuff.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to use your guts or emotions to make an initial decision, then validate if it&amp;rsquo;s okay using more empirical criteria. If your emotions don&amp;rsquo;t lead anywhere, measure and use data, pros/cons to determine best course of action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the difference between an acceptable choice and the best choice. It may be easier to settle merely for a choice which is acceptable rather than spending extra time to try to find the best choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;Not making a choice is also a choice. Sometimes not all the choices will satisfy your standard or requirements. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget that abstaining or deciding not to do anything can also be a valid choice.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you’re having trouble choosing between some options, that means they are mostly within an acceptable range for you (if any of the options was flat out unacceptable you would have rejected them on the spot). In that case, just choose one at random (literally roll a dice if you can’t decide) and go. If it turns out later that it wasn’t the best choice, figure out if there was any information that would have helped you, take note of it for next time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be careful when making big purchases. Even if you have already made a decision, you may want to delay it a bit for really big amounts to give your subconscious some time to ponder it. (This is really more about money management than decision making&amp;hellip;  but I had it in this list so here you go)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: 400;&#34;&gt;In moments of self-doubt, ask other people for advise. It can be friends and family or even random strangers on the internet.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to the lunch out story. Some years later, a different lunch group (that I was occasionally a part of) thought of a better approach: they set up an automated email that got sent out to the members around 11:30am. The program would choose at random one of the nearby places to eat, making the decision for the group. If anyone objected to the randomly selected choice, they bore the responsibility for providing the new choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is too short to waste on poor decision making.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Online Discussions, Opposing Views, and Street Fighter
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/online-discussions-opposing-views-and-street-fighter/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 01:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/online-discussions-opposing-views-and-street-fighter/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you know the enemy and know yourself, you need not fear the result of a hundred battles. If you know yourself but not the enemy, for every victory gained you will also suffer a defeat. If you know neither the enemy nor yourself, you will succumb in every battle.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;― Sun Tzu, The Art of War&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading a forum thread recently about learning competitive Street Fighter. The poster was using a particular character (his &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo;) and asking how he could learn to counter the attack strings of other characters. The answers from more experienced players were pretty much what I would have expected: you had to dedicate specific time and effort to each matchup you wanted to study. That meant going into training mode, looking at the opposing character&amp;rsquo;s attack strings and seeing where he could interrupt them or the proper way to answer them. It meant a lot of hard work too, since fighting games typically have a lot of characters. So reaching the top tiers meant understanding each opposing character in and out, knowing their strengths and weaknesses and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it not only applies to competition, but also to any scenario where there is an opposing party or point of view. In order to make any progress or improvement, it is necessary to understand where the other side is coming from and study their motivations. Sadly, in online debates it often turns into the equivalent of a shouting match where everyone just screams out their POV hoping to brute force their opponent into some kind of &amp;ldquo;submission&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to Street Fighter: When picking up a new fighting game, I typically try to sample all the available characters until I find one whose fighting style I like and am comfortable playing as &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; (hint: it&amp;rsquo;s often Ryu lol).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same way, in any online discussion it&amp;rsquo;s important to expose yourself to a variety of opinions, and not limit your discussions only to people with similar views. Political discussion online can get toxic so it becomes tempting to block out those views that you disagree with, but this tends to create an echo chamber effect. It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to keep a healthy amount of opposing views on your feeds. Although where you draw the line is of course your own decision; Personally I try to avoid blocking any friends and have not yet had occasion to do so, although I do block any sites that tend to promote misinformation or stuff like racism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike competition, the goal of an online discussion (especially for sensitive topics like politics) isn&amp;rsquo;t really winning. Discussion should lead to some sort of progress or learning, or in the worst case, &amp;ldquo;agreeing to disagree&amp;rdquo;. But regardless of the outcome, understanding opposing points of view should give you valuable insights into your own views, and maybe even convince you to reconsider them.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Thoughts on Authoritarianism vs Democracy
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/thoughts-on-authoritarianism-vs-democracy/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 01:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/thoughts-on-authoritarianism-vs-democracy/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Democracy is the worst form of government, except for all the others.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;― Winston S. Churchill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the current world political climate, it seems that in many instances democracy and the related values (equality, human rights, and so on) are increasingly taking a back seat to populism and increasingly authoritarian leaderships. One sometimes has to consider whether authoritarian states would in fact be more effective in this day and age. After all, China&amp;rsquo;s ascension as a world power shows that even authoritarian states are able to achieve great gains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The allure of authoritarianism is understandable for anyone who&amp;rsquo;s been exposed to problematic democracies: progress is often held back by countless deliberations, committee meetings, legislative mills, and various other processes that mean elected officials are able to accomplish very little until it&amp;rsquo;s time again for them to think about the next election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authoritarian state on the other hand has the advantage of being able to push a singular vision, since it has concentrated power unto itself, it can set aside any dissent and other discussion, put its foot down and say &amp;ldquo;this is what we&amp;rsquo;re doing, let&amp;rsquo;s do it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it might also seem to be easier on an individual level? You just have to trust your leadership (since you probably don&amp;rsquo;t have a choice) and not think too hard about things other than what&amp;rsquo;s going on in your own life. This is probably also why authoritarian states are more likely to try to get away with rights violations and such &amp;ndash; people are more concerned with their own survival and their own lives and not too worry too much about the things the state is doing to &amp;ldquo;other people&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The risk of course of such a single-minded &amp;ldquo;getting things done&amp;rdquo; attitude is: you might not be doing the right thing. When the state has concentrated power unto itself, there is a tendency to promote only those ideas and projects and whatnot that adhere to the state&amp;rsquo;s singular vision. Another problem is that anyone who dissents or holds different values than the authoritarian state&amp;rsquo;s singular vision can be labelled or vilified as enemies of progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authoritarian states also have the tendency to set aside values commonly held in democratic states: freedom of expression and religion, human rights and equality, and so on, if they are seen to hinder progress. I guess you have to consider whether as a society, you are willing to sacrifice these values in the name of getting things done. And it&amp;rsquo;s sad when you find that many of your countrymen don&amp;rsquo;t consider democratic values all that important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Democracy on the other hand, due to the nature of (in theory) every voice being given value, has a stronger tendency towards a diversity of ideas, so that more options are considered and thus theoretically better decisions are made. This mirrors the natural world, where genetic diversity allows a species to more easily thrive and adapt to changing circumstances. In the same way, we hope that by encouraging debate and dissent democracies are better able to adapt to the challenges the world presents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authoritarianism is great when you have leadership that you can trust to make good and wise decisions for the betterment of all. But humans are weak and fallible beings prone to faults such as arrogance, pride, greed, and so forth, so more likely than not the leadership in an authoritarian state cannot be trusted. While the same can be said of democracies (since in the real world there are no perfect democracies), at least in democracies we have a greater chance of being able to change the state of affairs to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New Year&#39;s Checklist
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/new-years-checklist/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 05:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/new-years-checklist/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;In no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greet your loved ones and friends and anyone else you hold dear. Maybe even those you disagree with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ponder why people give so much significance to the transition between an arbitrarily-chosen pair of 24 hour periods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take stock and reflect on the past year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about what you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn this year or how you want to improve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Count your blessings for the past year and be grateful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change your passwords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy a new toothbrush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a New Year&amp;rsquo;s joke (&amp;ldquo;My New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolution is 1440×900!&amp;quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a target of how many books you&amp;rsquo;ll read in 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose the first book to read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throw away a few things you no longer need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of where you will travel to in 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out what movies are coming out this year and which ones you want to watch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audit your financials &amp;ndash; where is your money going, how much do you owe, how much are you earning, where should you invest, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make another New Year&amp;rsquo;s joke (&amp;ldquo;I haven&amp;rsquo;t taken a bath since last year!&amp;quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick up your keyboard and shake out all the grime that&amp;rsquo;s gathered there over the past year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of projects you want to do in 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose something from the past year that you&amp;rsquo;re going to stop watching or doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat your favorite food. Or ice cream. Ice cream is great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember that there&amp;rsquo;s a new episode of Sherlock today (well January 1 in the UK)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get rid of 2016 calendars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list for the new year!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Decluttering
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/decluttering/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 01:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/decluttering/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I traditionally try to save some time on the week between Christmas and New Year&amp;rsquo;s Day to do some cleaning up and decluttering of my stuff. One would assume that having more time meant I would be better able to organize my stuff and all that, but one would be wrong. My room still has stacks of books, toys, Magic cards and other stuff in random places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe I just have too much OCD that I want everything to be neat and organized, but I&amp;rsquo;m not industrious enough to make it happen. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are people a lot more cluttered than me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the start of the year, I told myself I should throw out/get rid of/dispose of at least one thing a day. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those relatively easy things to do I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do we keep around all this old stuff we don&amp;rsquo;t need?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of it may be from a mentality of scarcity &amp;ndash; we don&amp;rsquo;t want to throw away stuff for fear of finding out that we may need it later. But reasonably, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t used a thing in years, maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll never use it and even if you had need of one, how difficult would it be to find one again? Some kind of pack rat mentality. I know a few of my friends who would be very familiar with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other things we keep around for some sort of nostalgia or as keepsakes of other people and faraway places. That&amp;rsquo;s fine I suppose, but maybe one shouldn&amp;rsquo;t put too much value in things that don&amp;rsquo;t actually have them. Case in point: I have a bunch of rocks here from different countries I visited in Europe, haha. Pictures, letters, and other personal keepsakes one might consider digitizing and storing in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a cluttered space has a cost, one that&amp;rsquo;s difficult to ascertain or quantify. Not only do things look messy, but things are harder to find when you need them most. There&amp;rsquo;s also a strange satisfaction that comes from achieving a fine, organized space (before it all falls back into chaos of course.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Are you willing to accept criticism?
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/are-you-willing-to-accept-criticism/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 01:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/are-you-willing-to-accept-criticism/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;If a friend found out your work was horrible, would you want to know? Or would your feelings be hurt?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your coworkers think you&amp;rsquo;re doing something wrong, would you prefer that they keep quiet or that they call you out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a leader, do you prefer to have sycophants who sing your praises or people who are willing to tell you that you have no clothes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your ego more important than doing a good job or self-improvement?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But what if the guy is just being an asshole who hates me and wants to discredit me?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not someone is an asshole is independent of whether or not his criticism is valid. You can call him out for being an asshole if you want, but you owe it to yourself to consider if any criticism given to you is valid and something you can act on regardless of whether the messenger is an asshole or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are afraid that having your mistakes called out will be damaging to you, consider how damaging it will be if you keep doing those mistakes and develop a reputation for them.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Wizard&#39;s First Rule and Demagoguery
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/wizards-first-rule/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 01:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/wizards-first-rule/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The series was a bit formulaic, and towards the end really preachy toward&amp;rsquo;s the authors personal philosophies, but Terry Goodkind&amp;rsquo;s Sword of Truth series always comes back to me because it codified one of life&amp;rsquo;s most important truths:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wizard&amp;rsquo;s First Rule: &amp;ldquo;People are stupid. They will believe a lie because they want to believe it&amp;rsquo;s true, or because they are afraid it might be true.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you&amp;rsquo;re stupid or I&amp;rsquo;m stupid, just that collectively, we&amp;rsquo;re kind of dumb. Put another way by another wise character in popular culture, from the film Men in Black:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kay: A person is smart. &lt;strong&gt;People are dumb&lt;/strong&gt;, panicky dangerous animals and you know it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what makes it so easy for demagogues from Hitler to McCarthy to Trump to certain local politicians to stir up support: create a boogeyman that people fear, and people will willingly believe your lies as long as you tell them what they want to hear (under the guise of &amp;ldquo;telling it as it is&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, a demagogue doesn&amp;rsquo;t even have to be consistent in what he says: he can say one thing at first (&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;our anti-crime drive is doing well, crime is down&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;) to project one image and a contradicting thing later on (&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is a state of lawlessness, we should consider harsher methods.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;) depending on how his goals change and what the particular audience wants to hear. It has the added benefit of making anyone who reports on it look bad and inciting conflict (because people never agree on what the demagogue means!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Wizard&amp;rsquo;s First Rule is a saddening fact of human nature, we should take heart in the fact that despite humans being stupid and often being caught in the same traps, tyrants still fall and progress is eventually made and we somehow manage to muddle through and humanity survives long enough for the next crisis. (Although Trump&amp;rsquo;s climate change denial could seriously test that last part.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Bad news
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/bad-news/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 01:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/bad-news/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Recent events both in my country and abroad, both of wide importance and personal importance, have made the past week or so difficult. Bad news and bad events have no master or timing, they do not consider giving us a break, they come and go as they please no matter how bad the situation already is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fully understand why many people choose to withdraw from daily news or shut it out altogether or even just avoid social media completely. Hearing the bad news can be disheartening, and it comes at us even when there is work to be done or words to be written or deadlines to be met. We have no choice but to soldier on, to slog through the bad news and do our work anyway. It is the world we live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To withdraw from this world and hide away from all the darkness is understandable, if only for a short time. But all the bad things in the world won&amp;rsquo;t go away simply because we refuse to see them. At some point we have to come back to it and voice our objections and engage in discussion and reach out to other people and ask what we can do to help turn the tide. It is not a burden we simply leave other people to bear, it is on our shoulders collectively to try to make the world a better place, if only a little bit at a time, if only by saying &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think these things are good, and here&amp;rsquo;s why&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop for us because it makes us sad. The work that needs to be still needs to be done. We move forward, one step at a time.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Whatever Doesn&#39;t Kill You Only Makes You Stronger
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/whatever-doesnt-kill-you-only-makes-you-stronger/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 01:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/whatever-doesnt-kill-you-only-makes-you-stronger/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a very rare, privileged group of people for whom everything in life goes well and they experience great success all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You and I are not part of that group (most likely). Like the vast majority of other people, sometimes our lives are good and sometimes our lives are bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes life can feel cruel or unfair or exhausting. In those times it&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget the times when life was good and to wallow in your misery. And I guess to some extent humans need a bit of that wallowing time, but try not to linger there too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have to take the good and the bad life gives you and make what you can of it. Whatever failures or trials you suffer, learn from them and move on. Let the low points forge you into a sharper sword. Whatever doesn&amp;rsquo;t kill you only makes you stronger&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Introspection and Self-Awareness
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/10/introspection-and-self-awareness/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 01:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/10/introspection-and-self-awareness/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Sometimes I write something and at the end I find that it upsets me. Or I think about something I haven&amp;rsquo;t thought about in a long time just before I sleep, then I have a nightmare about it and it saddens me to think that my subconscious still hasn&amp;rsquo;t let go of it after all this time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a good thing though, right? One of the purpose of writing and introspection is to become more attuned to your inner thoughts and emotions, to better understand and work with your own self. I try to have this self-awareness that I&amp;rsquo;m sure not many people bother with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just yesterday, a friend asked me why I tracked a certain thing that I do. I told him that I track a lot of things because memory is poor and fragile. I track the restaurants I go to, the shows I watch, the books I read, the games I play, the things I spend money on, how much I sleep, etc. Maybe I should add &amp;ldquo;how I feel&amp;rdquo; to that list too&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introspection and self-awareness is a fine line to walk. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to be so absorbed in yourself that you get bogged down in overthinking. Yet everyone needs some level of self-awareness in their life &amp;ndash; if only to be able to identify when their own prejudices, fears, or other emotions are starting to affect daily decisions&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Large Projects and Losing Focus
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/10/large-projects-and-losing-focus/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 01:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/10/large-projects-and-losing-focus/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m kind of a serial project starter. I&amp;rsquo;m sure it&amp;rsquo;s a very common thing. I&amp;rsquo;ll often have random ideas for projects I could do, big or small. I&amp;rsquo;d have a dozen of them percolating in my head at any one time. And somewhere between four to five dozen scattered down in various documents, notepads and what not, waiting to be explored. (I literally have two such small post-it notes with 5 such items in front of me right now)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These projects range from the small (programming: small scripts to automate some stuff I do regularly; sketches: quick sketches I want to do; writing: blog posts, short stories;) to the rather large and time-consuming (game development ideas, complicated data analysis ideas, novel ideas, some major reorganization/sorting of stuff, and so on). Unfortunately, starting new projects is rarely fruitful unless you actually finish those projects. And I rarely finish the larger projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think about what it takes for me to get one of the largest projects to completion. At which stages do I typically falter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically it starts with an idea. Something cool I could do. Or make. Or write. At this stage there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of optimism. I&amp;rsquo;m probably in love with the idea. If it&amp;rsquo;s a big enough idea, I might even think it&amp;rsquo;ll make me famous. Or earn me a lot of money. Or win me a nobel prize. Or all of those!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea enough to start on it immediately, I&amp;rsquo;ll add it to one of my lists that hopefully I manage to get back to sometime within the next century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I do like the idea enough, I&amp;rsquo;ll move on to some form of brainstorming. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll let the idea run around in my head for a couple of nights. Typically I&amp;rsquo;ll run the idea through some people I trust and would have a similar interest in the area. Then maybe draw up a short idea document outlining some of the details I&amp;rsquo;ve already imagined, to be expanded or reduced later as needed. If it&amp;rsquo;s a writing thing, I start to think in broad strokes: what the setting is, who the protag is, where I imagine him to be ending etc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I pretty much have an idea of what I want to do. The next step is to study what I need to execute. If it&amp;rsquo;s a programming or game development project, I look into what tools I&amp;rsquo;ll need or programming techniques I need to learn. I might need to access or scrape some sort of data source for analysis so I&amp;rsquo;ll start looking for sources&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I would try to get started. For programming stuff I might make a small prototype already. If it&amp;rsquo;s a writing thing, I might write a scene or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the first tranche of work, I&amp;rsquo;m going to assess how much farther I need to go. And typically this is where many of the projects will drop off. At this point I become aware of the size and scope of what I plan to do. I would look at the sheer amount of work needed to bring the project to conclusion, and it can be disheartening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I start out optimistic, thinking about the exciting, cool stuff I get to try out, amazing scenes I want to write, interesting gameplay mechanics I thought of, and so on. But once I get past that I start to realize that finishing the job will require a lot of drudgework too. That means a lot of small, annoying, menial tasks that I&amp;rsquo;ll put off and won&amp;rsquo;t want to do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read a lot of self-improvement and &amp;ldquo;getting things done&amp;rdquo; sort of stuff, so I know all the usual advice: break down the big tasks into small tasks, take one step at a time, and so on. The problem is usually lack of focus. Since at this point there&amp;rsquo;s a lull in my interest towards the project, it&amp;rsquo;s an opportune time for some other idea to come along and distract me. Or maybe some shiny new video game or book starts taking up my time. Or some other random distraction that takes my time away. Then I&amp;rsquo;m too lazy to pick it up again, and the vicious cycle repeats with the next big project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smaller projects are fine &amp;ndash; the ones that only take me a few hours or a day to do. It&amp;rsquo;s the bigger ones that are the problem. I mostly know where I have to improve &amp;ndash; I have to be able to focus and commit my time. Eliminate distractions. Stay on track. And so on. Someday I&amp;rsquo;ll get it right&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Appearances and Diplomacy
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/10/appearances-and-diplomacy/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 01:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/10/appearances-and-diplomacy/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;(A bit of Philippine politics in this post, if that sort of thing bothers you)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently as the whole world watched one of our political leaders display his expected lack of diplomatic finesse on the global stage, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but think about how in my younger days there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance I might have approved of his frank, straight-talking, shoot-from-the-hip brand of diplomacy. I have a bit of a reputation myself for preferring to speak frankly and directly instead of dancing around the issues, although these days I understand the wisdom of adapting to the situation as needed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my youth I was the sort of person who disdained those who prioritized form over substance. For this reason I disliked protocol and ritual and dress codes and formalities and all that. I imagine that IT people are notorious for preferring casual dress and disliking suits. I proudly enjoyed games with dated graphics when other people would fawn over the latest Crysis or whatever. I felt that anyone who prioritized appearances was somehow shallow and that one should focus more on the functional and practical. This is somewhat related to my views on &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/lying-and-salesmanship/&#34;&gt;lying and salesmanship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I got older though, I began to appreciate that sometimes appearances can matter too. Formalities and rituals can have meaning, especially when other people value them. And sometimes you have to dress up, either to impress people, or to fit in with the situation. These are concessions one has to make in order to be member of society. As Sheldon Cooper would say, &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s the social convention&amp;rdquo;. I guess I consider learning to navigate society&amp;rsquo;s social conventions is part of being a mature adult&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is part of why the current leadership&amp;rsquo;s lack of diplomacy is so annoying for me personally. It smacks of immaturity. Reacting to criticism with cussing and swearing and dredging up century-old mistakes and calling other people gay, these are behaviors I&amp;rsquo;d (sadly) expect from a 10 year old on XBox Live, not the leader of a sovereign nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And supporters will say at least he&amp;rsquo;s honest and direct and real. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;m honest and direct and real (ask anyone!) and I don&amp;rsquo;t go around swearing at people just because they point out my faults. There&amp;rsquo;s no reason to antagonize people just because they don&amp;rsquo;t agree with you. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to disagree and still be diplomatic. Not even the leadership of North Korea talks like that. Well, I could talk my head off politics if given the chance, so I&amp;rsquo;ll just abruptly end this post here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Lying and Salesmanship
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/lying-and-salesmanship/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 01:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/lying-and-salesmanship/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;http://waitbutwhy.com/table/when-is-it-okay-to-lie&#34;&gt;recent post on Wait But Why&lt;/a&gt; had me thinking about lying.&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#156762f0f0b6c5bc30c13dd9e7093048-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/lying-and-salesmanship/lying_hu5e2a1ce206cfbe1292a2aa426385ba8c_223279_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;156762f0f0b6c5bc30c13dd9e7093048-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/lying-and-salesmanship/lying.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;27 Sep 2016 1:30am&#34;&gt;27 Sep 2016 1:30am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people will scoff if I say I don&amp;rsquo;t lie. They&amp;rsquo;re not wrong. I once spun a tall tale about a childhood rival I had visited in the province who challenged me to a swimming contest to explain &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/11/my-eyeglasses-belong-to-the-sea/&#34;&gt;why I had lost my glasses to the sea&lt;/a&gt;. The lie was so good, I got a follow-up question about it a year later and was so surprised I just blurted out that my rival died in accident before finally admitting to the fib&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I will intentionally lie often only for fun or mischief, or in the rare case, to protect someone or avoid some problem or injustice. Even for that last scenario I will try to avoid it as much as possible. I am more likely to stay quiet or avoid discussion or maybe even stretch the truth a bit to &amp;ldquo;technically correct&amp;rdquo;, but I try to avoid any outright falsehoods unless absolutely necessary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this same reason, I kind of have the same aversion to any form of salesmanship, although I am occasionally told that I am good at writing copy. At work I was sometimes asked to write some response to questions in a tender that would be less than honest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We don&amp;rsquo;t have this feature, how should I respond?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just say we have it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But we don&amp;rsquo;t. How about I just write that this feature will be available?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the use of optimistic future tense to stretch the truth a bit. At one point a higher-up even told me that all the other suppliers do that to, as if that justifies it. Being asked to outright be dishonest was stressful for me at best so I later on learned to avoid such tasks altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand that not all salesmanship is dishonest and that not all salesmen are scammers looking to sell snake oil. But we basically live in a world that is caveat emptor don&amp;rsquo;t we? I feel like those salesmen who are honestly just extolling the virtues of their wares are the exception rather than the norm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recognize the need for salesmanship as a skill in everyday life, although younger me would have scoffed at that idea, believing that things should be judged solely on their merits. But merits aren&amp;rsquo;t always obvious, and you still need some level of presentation and good communication skills to push your ideas and merits forward.  I&amp;rsquo;m fine with that I guess, as long as we try to keep things honest.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/lying-and-salesmanship/lying_hu5e2a1ce206cfbe1292a2aa426385ba8c_223279_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Speak Up
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/speak-up/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2016 01:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/speak-up/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Asians, and maybe Filipinos more specifically, have this cultural bias towards trying to avoid conflict. So often there will be people who don&amp;rsquo;t like to speak up when they think something is wrong, either just tolerating it or hoping someone else will take it up. A software dev in another company once told me that he felt like he was complaining so much that he was looking like a bad guy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is of course, a bad attitude to have. If no one speaks up about the problems we see, how would we ever improve? Someone has to do it, it might as well be you. And often there will be benefits too to speaking up, for one thing you might get credit for raising something no one else has thought of. As they say, the squeaky wheel gets the grease&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, you should of course pick your battles. Don&amp;rsquo;t complain too much about the little things, but be sure to raise your voice when there&amp;rsquo;s an important battle to be fought. This will give you a reputation such that when you do raise something, people will pay attention. Having a balanced approach is a lot more helpful than complaining about every little thing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, and of course if someone is doing something wrong, try not to be combative but be a bit diplomatic. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to offend anyone, you just want to do things the right way. And question the action instead of the person so that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a personal attack. &amp;ldquo;Hey, is that really how it should be done?&amp;rdquo; will be received better than &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s not how to do it, you idiot!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to be unreasonable every so often. As George Bernard Shaw famously said &amp;ldquo;The reasonable man adapts himself to the world; the unreasonable one persists in trying to adapt the world to himself. Therefore all progress depends on the unreasonable man.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Random Thoughts on Time
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/random-thoughts-on-time/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 01:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/random-thoughts-on-time/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I remember having a discussion with a friend a few years back where I made the following list to emphasize a point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8-9 hours at work (possibly more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7-8 hours of sleep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-4 hours commuting in Metro Manila&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 hours for meals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That leaves you between 1-4 hours for all forms of recreation including exercise, sports, TV, derping around on the internet, hanging out with friends, and so on. On any given day if you needed to work overtime or run errands, you&amp;rsquo;re probably saying goodbye to any recreation time on that day. And if you have kids to take care of, that&amp;rsquo;s basically all days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days I&amp;rsquo;ve found that even if you&amp;rsquo;re not working most days, it&amp;rsquo;s easy enough to feel like there&amp;rsquo;s not enough time for all the things you want to do. Or maybe that&amp;rsquo;s just me because there&amp;rsquo;s a whole lot of things I want to be able to do. I want to be able to learn, read, write, watch, draw, create, play, work on my side projects, argue with people on the internet, and so on. I don&amp;rsquo;t understand people who say they have too much free time and they get bored, I feel like those people just don&amp;rsquo;t have enough things they want to do. The difference between work and leisure is that when you&amp;rsquo;re  at work, you look for enough tasks to fill your required hours, while for leisure you like for enough hours to do the things you want to do&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started working I always had this idea that it was a ridiculous notion that we had to give up so much of our time to work so that in theory we could be comfortable in some foggy unknown future. You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t sacrifice today to enjoy tomorrow, what&amp;rsquo;s the point? Your hour today is the same amount of time as your hour tomorrow. I get that sometimes you have to sacrifice some time today for some sort of multiplicative effect it may theoretically have on the future (i.e. doing something today for 1 hour may earn you multiple hours in the future), but you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t sacrifice so much that you are no longer able to enjoy and appreciate the present (if you have that luxury of course)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get the same amount of time (24 hours) every day as everyone else though. That&amp;rsquo;s the same amount of time as Einstein or Bill Gates or Barack Obama or whatever other random successful person you want to cite. It&amp;rsquo;s the ultimate equalizer. Other people accomplish so much with the same amount of time, so why can&amp;rsquo;t we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supposedly it&amp;rsquo;s all about setting your priorities and focusing on what&amp;rsquo;s important. Unfortunately focus has always been a problem of mine since I like to dabble in a wide variety of things. I look at the list of things I want to do and I tell myself I have to decide to sacrifice some of these so that the others can get done. Focus only on what matters. What if everything matters?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People will say you should cut back on TV or playing video games if you want to get stuff done, that these things are a waste of time. But as John Lennon said &amp;ldquo;Time you enjoy wasting is not wasted time&amp;rdquo;. If doing these things is what you want to do, you should go for it, just be aware of what you&amp;rsquo;re sacrificing in exchange&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that some time within this century attitudes of people towards work and time will begin to change. That the idea of working 40-50 hour days being a normal thing will start to fade away. (Or maybe I am being too optimistic). Until that time comes, we all need to consciously manage our time and priorities in order to cope&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Things We Learn In School
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/the-things-we-learn-in-school/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 01:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/the-things-we-learn-in-school/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re young and in school memorizing math formulas or history dates or whatnot, all of it seems so silly and you wonder if you&amp;rsquo;re really going to be using all of this knowledge in real life. However, the intent of a general education program isn&amp;rsquo;t specifically to give you knowledge that will be useful to you in the future (although it may turn out to be so)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stuff school teaches you &amp;ndash; literature, mathematics, art, history, science, and so on &amp;ndash; are intended to give you a broad enough base from which you can freely choose the direction you want to go in life. This means that as you specialize, many of these subjects may become &amp;ldquo;irrelevant&amp;rdquo; to you, but having this broad base of knowledge gives you a better foundation in life. Knowledge from unrelated fields can often give useful insight into your own specialized field&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, the most useful stuff you learn from school isn’t the stuff that’s in the lectures or in the textbooks. School is supposed to teach you about more than formulas and history dates too. But it&amp;rsquo;s a problem that most of the time, formal education doesn&amp;rsquo;t deliver the lessons well enough. Math shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be about memorizing formulas or equations, but about developing analytical and problem solving skills. History should be about appreciating how changes affect people and societies, not about memorizing dates. Science should be about appreciating how nature works and developing scientific curiosity. And so on. But because these things are difficult to teach and test for, formal education usually focuses on facts and figures and formulas and all these things that appear in exams. It&amp;rsquo;s up to the student (or his mentors encourage him) to apply himself further&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still many more holes in formal education. There are memes about how you learn not so useful stuff like &amp;ldquo;mitochondria is the powerhouse of the cell&amp;rdquo; instead of real-world useful things like how to manage your finance or how to do your taxes. And for sure we need more of those practical things taught to students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most important things you learn from school are in the methods of learning and working well with others. School teaches how to apply yourself, how to study and pick up new material, how to listen to other people, how to determine which knowledge is useful to learn, how to discern truth from fiction, how to work within a set of rules, how to manage your time, how to deal with schedules and deadlines, how to work well with other people, how to deal with difficult people, and so on. In short, the most important lessons school teaches you are about how to deal with the real world&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>We Must Speak
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/we-must-speak/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 01:18:40 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/we-must-speak/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;If you follow me on Facebook or &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/roytang&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ll know I have a tendency to be pretty vocal about any problems I have with our country&amp;rsquo;s erstwhile leadership. But for the most part I&amp;rsquo;ve restricted it to those channels and have tried to avoid posting about current events in the country on this blog (outside of my personal choices for the election), but I feel that now more than ever those of us who can speak out have a responsibility to do so whenever we can, for several reasons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2016.villageidiotsavant.com/2016/08/19/232-sanity-survival-strategies-for-the-next-six-years/&#34;&gt;Village Idiot Savant&lt;/a&gt; says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Third, write. But don’t write as you would for the consumption of social media, write instead to keep a record of these times. Write in long form, write reflections, write your frustrations, write with big words, write even if it appears you are rambling. Write with Art and with Irony. Because we will eventually emerge from this period of madness, hopefully to a season of sanity, and we will need to look back and remember, and if needed, to indict. Write because it will someday be history.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last part resonated with me. &amp;ldquo;Write because it will someday be history.&amp;rdquo; It reminds me of where we are currently with the Marcos legacy, with an entire generation having been brainwashed to believe that Marcos was actually a hero and a positive influence on this country, all because in the intervening years since the EDSA revolution we (and by we I mean we the people, not just the government) grew complacent and believed that exile was sufficient and that we would not have to worry again about such a dark time in our society to come back and haunt us again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet here we are again on a road, perhaps even a slippery slope, towards a dark future. Marcos is again being glorified, and the state is once again extending its reach with the similar excuse of &amp;ldquo;peace and order&amp;rdquo;. We do not yet know where this path ultimately leads, perhaps it won&amp;rsquo;t be the darkness many of us can foresee, perhaps we as a society are able to turn away from the brink before it is too late. There are those who believe it is already too late, that we are already in the darkest timeline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if our country falls under a shroud of darkness, like the darkness of Martial Law it will also eventually pass and hopefully we emerge on the other side stronger and wiser as a country. In the hopes of that light beyond the darkness, we must write. We must take our voices and speak out against what ills we see. It often feels futile, with many of our countrymen already having surrendered their wills to the violence. Many are unwilling to listen, many treat the current leadership as if they are infallible demigods who could do no wrong. Maybe there is really no one listening and you are but a lone voice crying in the wilderness. It is not for them that we need to write, but for those of us who still hope for a better future. And for those in the future to recognize and learn from the mistakes of our time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must write and speak, while we still can. We don&amp;rsquo;t know whether we will still be able to speak up tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, we should write to spite those who would silence us for our opposition. For many of the administration&amp;rsquo;s supporters, anyone who speaks out is an open target for harassment and accusations most vile, as one of Rappler&amp;rsquo;s correspondents recently found out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Chastising Duterte is not mutually exclusive with supporting De Lima. But to the trolls, insult the president = &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/FXfg0wigJ3&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/FXfg0wigJ3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Natashya Gutierrez (@natashya_g) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/natashya_g/status/766531070116278272?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;August 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;I can appreciate those of my friends who limit themselves to &amp;ldquo;like&amp;quot;s on the posts of those who speak up, or who limit their support to private discussions. Not everyone has the liberty to speak up. Not everyone can afford to sacrifice time nor ego to the possibility of a horde of online trolls pouncing on you. Not everyone can afford to be stressed out over this. Not everyone has the temperament to be willing to offend other people or risk losing friendships. All the more reason for those of us who are able to speak up to keep on going and to persist in the face of overwhelming ignorance and hypocrisy. The ones who cannot afford to speak, we speak for them too&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I didn&amp;rsquo;t write about this too much on this blog is that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want this channel to become about politics. But it feels like so much more than just politics now. Despite what some fanatics may have you believe, we do not voice opposition simply because we believe in another camp or because we want to destroy the current administration. We voice opposition because we want the best for our country, and we believe that these issues &amp;ndash; the continuing demonization of human rights and due process, encouragement of a culture of killing and violence, intellectual dishonesty and willful ignorance, and so on &amp;ndash; are issues worth raising up and discussing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sure I have friends and family who are tired of me bringing up such subjects. At least one person has unfriended me already without explanation, although circumstances dictate it was about &amp;ldquo;politics&amp;rdquo;. For my friends and family, I apologize. If you are tired of me speaking up, please trust that I am tired too&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Review: Stranger Things
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/review-stranger-things/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 01:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/review-stranger-things/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/38/Stranger_Things_logo.png&#34; width=&#34;728&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Stranger Things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s true, it&amp;rsquo;s great. I thought it might be overhyped, but it&amp;rsquo;s not. And I can see why people find it hard to explain without spoiling things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about strange things happening in a small town. Creepy things. It&amp;rsquo;s a mystery. It&amp;rsquo;s suspense. It&amp;rsquo;s not a jump-scare sort of thing if you&amp;rsquo;re not into that. Well, there&amp;rsquo;s maybe a little bit of jump scares. The best description I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s about as scary as an X-Files or Doctor Who episode. So if that&amp;rsquo;s not too scary for you, you&amp;rsquo;ll be fine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s about a child who goes missing in a small town (not a spoiler) and the succeeding events. It&amp;rsquo;s about the mother searching for her son. It&amp;rsquo;s about a group of kids trying to solve a mystery. It&amp;rsquo;s about a small-town police chief in over his head. It&amp;rsquo;s about the 80s. It&amp;rsquo;s about kids in the 80s, music in the 80s, school in the 80s, small American towns in the 80s. It&amp;rsquo;s about outcasts and bullies and first times and trying to fit in and how they all deal with these stranger things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like Stephen King wrote an episode of X-Files and it was directed by Stephen Spielberg starring the cast of Stand By Me. The acting is great too, especially the kids&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe minor spoilers follow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of told in that weird True Detective way, with perspectives jumping around a lot among the ensemble cast. Past and present scenes are interspersed with only context to rely on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It keeps you hooked. I wanted to watch only a couple of episodes at first but ended up awake past three AM at episode six. I finished it the net morning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love how the mystery unfolds to different parties and separately they uncover parts of it and they all come together in the end to force a resolution. I love how the characters overcome their horror-movie tropes. I love all the 80s references and the geeky references&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was satisfied with how it ended and all came together. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what to expect for a second season though&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Motivation vs Discipline
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/motivation-vs-discipline/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 01:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/motivation-vs-discipline/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Motivation is a fickle mistress. It comes and it goes. It&amp;rsquo;s easily distracted. It can vanish in a blink of an eye. When it&amp;rsquo;s there, it&amp;rsquo;s great, but when it&amp;rsquo;s not you don&amp;rsquo;t get anything done and you don&amp;rsquo;t feel terrible. Motivation is based on the principle that you need a certain emotion or state of mind to get things done. Motivation is burst damage, you can get a lot done but you don&amp;rsquo;t know when it&amp;rsquo;s gonna come out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discipline is a harsh mistress. Discipline means doing things no matter what. It means you do what you need to do even if you&amp;rsquo;re uninspired, or tired, or exhausted. It means you gather all the mental blocks and the excuses and the urge to go do something else, and you power through all of these and do what you needed to do in spite of all of these. Discipline means that your goals are independent of emotional whims, that they need to get done no matter how you&amp;rsquo;re feeling. Discipline is DPS, it&amp;rsquo;s constant work that can get boring, but it will surely get the job done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; I need more discipline.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Promise of Social Media
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/the-promise-of-social-media/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 01:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/the-promise-of-social-media/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;When blogging and social media started to explode in popularity, it held a great promise: it would give a voice to the masses. Where previously there were gatekeepers in traditional media channels who controlled whose opinions could be published or broadcast, the internet meant that anyone with an internet connection could publish and voice out their thoughts and people would be all smart and there would be lots of intelligent discussion and it would be great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that did kind of happen &amp;ndash; there was now a wealth of information and opinions and discussions online &amp;ndash; but people being people there was a lot of silly, frivolous stuff too. Memes, jokes, 4chan, and all that. And that was all fine and great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there was some dark stuff too. Spammers and scammers and whatnot trying to take advantage of people. And more recently with all the political activity it seemed like it had come to a head. Lies, damn lies and propaganda. It had always been happening before, but now the scales were larger and the stakes were higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of discussing opposing points of view, people joined social media groups  supporting one side or another, discussions giving way to echo chambers and crowds castigating people who didn&amp;rsquo;t share their views. Online trolls were paid to harass opposing personalities and reinforce their benefactor&amp;rsquo;s propaganda. Outright false information was spread using social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it was our fault too. We seek out those opinions that feed our biases and don&amp;rsquo;t bother questioning their veracity. Many times we don&amp;rsquo;t even bother reading past the clickbait headlines and make judgments without all the information because who has time for all that context right? Many acted like fanatics where their side could do no wrong and the other side were demons who could do no right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine, disgusted with the outright lies and propaganda of the opposing camps, has started censoring comments he disagrees with on his posts. I felt that stifling discussion was counterproductive, but he insisted that in this new era, a wide variety of approaches was necessary, with both moderates maintaining balanced views and encouraging discussion; and fanatics pushing aggressively to counter the opposing propaganda. Perhaps it was true, but it lessened my hopes that we would be able to raise the standard of online discussion to a higher level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started writing this post the original title was &amp;ldquo;The Unfulfilled Promise of Social Media&amp;rdquo;, but I realized the adjective there wasn&amp;rsquo;t appropriate. If anything, the promise of democratized discussion has been completely fulfilled &amp;ndash; I had just forgotten that democracy did not necessarily mean people would be smarter or more enlightened. Just like in real-life we are vulnerable to charlatans and demagogues and lies and propaganda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the more reason we need to be vigilant with what we read, share, comment and post online. We need to give adequate consideration to opposing points of view, to weigh the facts against speculation. We need to learn and apply critical thinking, and to teach other people to do so. We should strive to elevate discussions to higher levels (although it can often be tiring to do so!). It is an ongoing struggle for me to improve and be critical of my own thinking, but I believe it to be a worthy cause.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Evolution of Society
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/evolution-of-society/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 01:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/evolution-of-society/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I found this draft blog post that I had written back in 2010. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why I never published it, though it does end on a dire note and seems a bit incomplete. Perhaps I had some further thoughts percolating in my brain back then that never came forward. I am also not sure if I wrote this before reading about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Filter&#34;&gt;The Great Filter&lt;/a&gt;. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d just publish it now without further comment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about all the stupid things humans do, and the fact that there are still so many stupid humans about, and because of the stupid things human do like not focusing on education, we are creating even more stupid humans. It seemed to me like some sort of failure of evolution that we have not yet got it through our thick skulls how important stuff like education and critical thinking are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at some level, we&amp;rsquo;re experiencing a different form of evolution, one that is applied to our society as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider that in some other part of the universe, maybe at a nearby star or somewhere so far we have no way to imagine the distance, there probably exists an earthlike-planet. Maybe it has differences in terrain or weather, but for the most part it has seas and oceans, continents and archipelagos and glacial poles and all that jazz that makes earth interesting. And maybe on this other earth, life has evolved similar to the way it has here. Maybe some species are different, maybe some survived there that did not survive here, but for the most part there are plants and animals and insects and fungi and of course, there are humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course these humans won&amp;rsquo;t be exactly like us. Maybe they were spawned in different weather conditions, making the dominant skin tones different. Maybe they evolved slightly better or slightly worse eyesight or sense of smell. Maybe their superstitions were slightly different. Though in most ways this other human society on this other earth is similar with our own, all the slight differences are going to add up and the fate of their society may be vastly different with our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe because of their different superstitions, they are unable to survive massive plagues and disease in their middle ages. Maybe because of their differences they are unable to resist the temptation to devolve into thermonuclear war. Maybe they lack focus on technological advances and are unable to bridge the gap to the stars before their ever-growing population outgrows the resources their earth provides for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the nature of humans on this other earth is close to what we have here &amp;ndash; selfish, bickering, superstitious, xenophobic then the odds of these humans able to evolve past their world and into the stars is pretty low.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Continuous Learning
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/continuous-learning/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 01:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/continuous-learning/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;During my adult life, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to learn or at least expose myself to one new skill or programming language every year. For example, over the past year or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying, dabbling, or trying out the following: game development using Unity, technical analysis of stocks, Spanish, driving a car, and even some simple cooking! I&amp;rsquo;ve also been regularly practicing to improve my skills in writing and sketching. I probably even forgot a few things I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to learn. I also have a backlog of programming languages and frameworks I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to learn and/or try out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There can be a tendency for some people, especially those tired of formal education, to fall into the trap of thinking that once they become adults they no longer need to learn new things or improve their skills, but an attitude towards continuous learning and improvement pushes us towards more fulfilling lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are even certain professions such as software development or medicine where you pretty much have to keep up with the latest trends or new technologies in order to maintain your skill set. But even outside of such professions, a lifetime of learning can be enriching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s literally too. Learning and exposing yourself to new things is a process of growth and discovery that can lead you to better career options and be more financially rewarding. Scott Adams (creator of Dilbert) gave some advice that &lt;a href=&#34;http://dilbertblog.typepad.com/the_dilbert_blog/2007/07/career-advice.html&#34;&gt;you can make yourself more valuable by combining two or more skills&lt;/a&gt;. The more skills you learn, the more likely you are to find a combination of skills that gives you the edge towards financial success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At work, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been happy to take on tasks that required me to learn new frameworks or programming languages. Without an attitude towards continuous learning, your skills will stagnate. You&amp;rsquo;ll be working on the same sort of tasks again and again, leading to boredom and unhappiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the possible financial rewards, continuous learning has a few other soft benefits. It keeps you mentally sharp and healthy even as you grow older. It can help you meet new people. It can give you new conversation topics with your friends. It builds your confidence and leads to trying even more new things. It helps you look at things and situations with fresh eyes or different angles. And it means you&amp;rsquo;re almost never bored!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have kids, it sets an example for them that learning is a good thing and definitely you should be trying to instill the same example in them. Encourage their curiosity and facilitate their learning whenever they show interest in something, especially outside of school, to reinforce the idea that learning isn&amp;rsquo;t something that can only happen in the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be exhausting sometimes to be trying to keep up with everything and learn new things all the time, but you owe it to yourself (and perhaps even to the world!) to continuously try to be a better person.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Everyone is Biased
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/everyone-is-biased/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 01:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/everyone-is-biased/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grammar note: &amp;ldquo;Biased&amp;rdquo; is an adjective. &amp;ldquo;Bias&amp;rdquo; is a noun. It is not appropriate to say that a person or an entity &amp;ldquo;is bias&amp;rdquo;. Unless you are talking to like a prejudice elemental or something (takes note of that for hypothetical hipster RPG)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a (long-winded) discussion during the recent election period, someone told me that I &amp;ldquo;obviously had a bias&amp;rdquo; and my answer was &amp;ldquo;Of course I do! Everyone does!&amp;rdquo; People have different histories and backgrounds which means for any given topic they are likely to start from different points. These biases are perfectly okay and healthy and they&amp;rsquo;re called opinions. (Cue quote about opinions being like assholes). Example: I&amp;rsquo;m not in favor of the death penalty therefore I&amp;rsquo;m biased against candidates that want to promote it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although we are all entitled to our own opinions, many times we are called upon to make objective judgments. Common examples are jury trials, elections, or when you&amp;rsquo;re a judge in some contest. During these instances we have to be careful to weigh our own biases and opinions objectively to make sure we are giving a fair judgment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you do need to note is when you become subject to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_bias&#34;&gt;cognitive biases&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; unconscious, automatic influences on human judgment and decision making that reliably produce reasoning errors. &lt;strong&gt;Be wary of your own cognitive biases&lt;/strong&gt; and try to mitigate or compensate for them in your reasoning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research has also shown that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cmu.edu/news/stories/archives/2015/june/bias-blind-spot.html&#34;&gt;people have a bias blind spot&lt;/a&gt;. This means &lt;strong&gt;we think we are less biased than other people&lt;/strong&gt;. This is why it is important to &lt;strong&gt;examine your own arguments&lt;/strong&gt; from time to time to see whether you are subject to any of the known cognitive biases. When there is a need to be objective, we need to be extra critical of our own arguments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, it is simply a matter of shifting your perspective: think about how a situation looks to people with an opposing point of view to balance out your own views. A sure sign of bias is that you are only aware of the positives of your own point of view and the negatives in others&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-width=&#34;550&#34; data-dnt=&#34;true&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;
    Common Evidence of Bias: Your candidate is the best, and you can find absolutely nothing good to say about other candidates.
  &lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Neil deGrasse Tyson (@neiltyson) 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/neiltyson/status/741361923061653504?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;June 10, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Chastising Duterte is not mutually exclusive with supporting De Lima. But to the trolls, insult the president = &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/FXfg0wigJ3&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/FXfg0wigJ3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Natashya Gutierrez (@natashya_g) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/natashya_g/status/766531070116278272?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;August 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Another tip: **Do not listen only to people who have the same opinion as you do. **If you only expose yourself to people who think along the same lines, you are enabling the same set of biases until they become subconscious. This traps you in an echo chamber of people constantly reinforcing the same ideas. A friend and I recently were discussing how certain people react poorly to differing opinions and theorized that maybe that person grew up surrounded by people who enabled his biases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead,** seek out different opinions. **Continuing from the death penalty example above, I don&amp;rsquo;t shut out discussion from friends who I know to be pro-death penalty. I still read their threads and try to understand their point of view. Listening to a wide variety of different opinions will tend to cancel out your biases with time and will lead towards more objective thinking. For example, when conducting a performance assessment of a team member (something I&amp;rsquo;ve done often for the past decade or so!), I tend to get other people&amp;rsquo;s opinions first to contrast with my own, and will often ask someone else whether I might be biased in certain situations. The risk of personal bias is mitigated by sourcing different opinions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, we probably can&amp;rsquo;t completely eliminate our own biases, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we stop trying to be more objective in our thoughts and discussions and decisions&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Immortality
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/immortality/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 22:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/immortality/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do you know what&amp;rsquo;s there, waiting beyond that beach? &lt;em&gt;Immortality&lt;/em&gt;! &lt;em&gt;Take it! It&amp;rsquo;s yours&lt;/em&gt;!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Achilles, Troy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each person has a different view of what their life&amp;rsquo;s purpose is, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found more often than not it relates to some form of immortality. Usually that means leaving something behind, some trace of yourself so that the world remembers you, something that says &amp;ldquo;I was here, I existed.&amp;rdquo; For many people that means offspring, for others it may mean some other legacy: children taught, people helped, ideas expounded, inventions created, companies founded, and so on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind actual immortality. Who knows, it may still happen in our lifetime. Medical science may yet find a way to extend our lifespans or even permanently remove aging (at which point we really need to expand beyond this planet). Or maybe we manage to survive until the singularity and live on as artificial constructs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Literature and popular culture often portray immortality as some sort of curse. Sometimes a literal curse, as in vampires or highlanders needing to cut each other&amp;rsquo;s heads off. More often the implied of curse of eternal solitude &amp;ndash; Superman is often taunted by writers with the idea that everyone he loves will eventually grow old and die, and other immortals are often portrayed as not wanting to burden themselves with short-lived human connections&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What interests me the most about the idea of immortality is the idea that we as a species have so much to look forward to. (Assuming we manage to bypass &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Filter&#34;&gt;The Great Filter&lt;/a&gt; and avoid screwing things up for ourselves of course.) Even just the coming decades hold a lot of promise, with advances in space exploration, artificial intelligence, autonomous vehicles, and so on that may very well expand the horizons of the human experience. And who knows, immortality may actually help George R.R. Martin finish the &lt;em&gt;Song of Ice and Fire&lt;/em&gt; series!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be immortal if only to be able to see where we are going and what comes next. The future, it comes. Perhaps sooner than many of us expect&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Debating On The Internet
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/debating-on-the-internet/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 00:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/debating-on-the-internet/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Relevant XKCD:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/386/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/duty_calls.png&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;330&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I have this inexplicable urge to argue with people. With recent events I&amp;rsquo;ve found myself getting into more discussions, debates and otherwise friendly arguments online. The quality of these interactions hasn&amp;rsquo;t always been the best, and many times I feel like I should have stopped engaging sooner or maybe not participated at all. I&amp;rsquo;ve considered some points to help me decide in the future whether to bother engaging other people online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I&amp;rsquo;ve always been both used to and biased in favor of vibrant and open debate and discussion. And I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say many of my closest friends are of the same temperament. But one thing I&amp;rsquo;ve learned is that &lt;strong&gt;many people don&amp;rsquo;t like their views being criticized&lt;/strong&gt;. For some people, posting on the internet is putting themselves out there and risking being criticized (as if receiving criticism were a bad thing in and of itself!). I do think that more people voicing their opinions can only be a good thing, so maybe we can try not to be so aggressive when we know the person doesn&amp;rsquo;t like criticism or isn&amp;rsquo;t used to an open debate. &amp;quot; I understand that you believe that, although have you considered the studies that say &amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;&lt;figure id=&#34;attachment_1222&#34; style=&#34;width: 836px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;








  




&lt;a href=&#34;#f8dff1d9da1ba1bb035397e7cc6d0c49-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/debating-on-the-internet/discussion_hu1e6b6f008ac53ad78a5c7d9e861c8940_109375_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;(Image cribbed from a friend)&#34; title=&#34;(Image cribbed from a friend)&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;(Image cribbed from a friend) (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;f8dff1d9da1ba1bb035397e7cc6d0c49-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/debating-on-the-internet/discussion.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;(Image cribbed from a friend)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;24 May 2016 12:30am&#34;&gt;24 May 2016 12:30am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accept that you are not going to &amp;ldquo;win&amp;rdquo; any debate.&lt;/strong&gt; From experience, it is very rare to win a debate on the internet. At best you are going to agree to disagree, or maybe find common ground to agree on and move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try to phrase your replies in the form of questions,&lt;/strong&gt; they are softer and will seem less like an attack. &amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t there evidence of claim X?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;What credentials does expert Y have?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t you think this violate the principles of Z?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try to see what the other person is looking for.&lt;/strong&gt; Many people online aren&amp;rsquo;t looking for debate or discussion, they simply want to air their view for others to consider or maybe look for some validation. It can be difficult, sometimes people can pretend to be open to discussion but really just want to reinforce their own views. It&amp;rsquo;s easiest if you already know the person. For example, if the person has a history of not believing easily-verifiable facts, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s better not to engage at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Know what you are looking for. **Typically, there&amp;rsquo;s one of three things I want out of a discussion: (a) I want to gather more information to help in my own decision-making; or (b) I want to point out misinformation or logical problems; or (c) I want to present my own point of view for others to consider. If you&amp;rsquo;ve already met your goals, you can safely consider tapping out &amp;ldquo;I just wanted to say that I think X is a better choice. Take that as you will&amp;rdquo;. Of course sometimes there&amp;rsquo;s a fourth thing I want: just to engage in a lively discussion 😀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid attacking the other person&lt;/strong&gt;, even when he/she is obviously being a bloody idiot. Bloody idiots can have opinions too after all. It should be possible to point out logical flaws or misinformation without taking things personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**If you are aiming to convince others to change their position, you should be willing to change yours as well. **Not only is it more sincere, it&amp;rsquo;s also fair. It will make your own arguments more compelling if you can show a willingness to question your own assumptions as well. That being said, you probably only need to employ this if the other people are willing to change their positions too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**Don&amp;rsquo;t take things personally, and don&amp;rsquo;t respond to criticism in anger. **If someone says something like your work is cringeworthy, instead of taking offense maybe you can ask the person to elaborate &amp;ldquo;Which parts did you find problematic and why?&amp;rdquo; If the person is not willing to discuss in detail, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s no longer productive to continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know when to tap out of a discussion.&lt;/strong&gt; You have to learn to recognize when other people are (a) not willing to consider other points of view; or (b) not looking for a debate or discussion or pros and cons. It will usually become obvious once they reply one or two times (sometimes it will be bloody obvious when they say something like &amp;ldquo;I believe in X no matter what&amp;rdquo;). Unless you are really enjoying the debate (which I am sometimes wont to do!), it&amp;rsquo;s probably not productive anymore to continue discussion. In that case, it&amp;rsquo;s probably better to just agree to disagree and move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m probably still going to occasionally dive into a debate just to be a devil&amp;rsquo;s advocate or even just for fun though, but hopefully these guidelines help me (and maybe even you!) recognize when it&amp;rsquo;s unproductive to engage and just to move on.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/debating-on-the-internet/discussion_hu1e6b6f008ac53ad78a5c7d9e861c8940_109375_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;

    
    &lt;p&gt;(Image cribbed from a friend)&lt;/p&gt;
    



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Marcos and Historical Revisionism
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/marcos-and-historical-revisionism/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 07:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/05/marcos-and-historical-revisionism/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to keep telling people that Ferdinand Marcos was a terrible president and that the Martial Law he imposed was terrible for the country. Imagine if a significant percentage of German citizens kept insisting that Hitler was a great man and the more sensible Germans had to keep trying to educate them on why that wasn&amp;rsquo;t true and why World War II was a terrible idea and that they wanted to elect Hitler&amp;rsquo;s descendant to a position of national prominence. That&amp;rsquo;s where we are right now with all these Filipinos supporting Marcos. (Why yes, I did open a blog post immediately with Godwin&amp;rsquo;s Law, thankyouverymuch)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have nothing personally against Bongbong Marcos, and I make no judgments on his personal track record and qualifications as a public servant. My main issue with him is that he is promoting historical revisionism of the sort that holocaust deniers are proud of. By insisting that his father was a great President and that Martial Law was actually good for the country is to demand that we unlearn the lessons of the past. Sure, the Aquinos and the succeeding administrations weren&amp;rsquo;t exactly the best either and had their faults too, but that&amp;rsquo;s beside the point. The crimes and excesses of the Marcos regime are well-documented and even international bodies have rendered verdicts against them. To deny these truths is to fool ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do believe that at some point we need to move on from this issue. But I believe that in order to move on, there is one thing needed most of all: the truth. A friend recently asked: if Bongbong apologizes for his father&amp;rsquo;s sins and for Martial Law, would I accept that apology and move on? My answer, verbatim: &amp;ldquo;For me it&amp;rsquo;s acknowledging the sins of the father, returning the money, and telling all about the crimes of the marcos regime, including what they know about the forced disappearances and torture, the staged ambush that started martial law, the crony deals, the assassination of Ninoy, the cheating during the snap elections, etc.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I write this, I believe the Vice Presidential election results are too close to call. But regardless of whether BBM wins or not, the very fact that at least 13 million voters chose to accept his brand of historical revisionism should be a source of national shame.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>PHVote: Choosing your 2013 Senators and Party List
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/05/phvote-choosing-your-2013-senators-and-party-list/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 13:09:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/05/phvote-choosing-your-2013-senators-and-party-list/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of this post is regarding my own opinion and who I plan to vote for. If you want to do your own research (I highly recommend it), here are some links to get you started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mggphilippines.com/category/candidate-info/&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 13px;&#34;&gt;Movement for Good Governance briefers on Senatorial candidates&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rappler.com/nation/politics/elections-2013/data/candidates/senator?limitstart=0&#34;&gt;Rappler Senatorial profiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would also Google &amp;ldquo;rappler [candidate name] interview&amp;rdquo; for the interview article for each candidate (too many to list here)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Nlyo6P6MoOvdrrBCj533U-CZ3rzQWNaHtweq8_EyASU/edit&#34;&gt;link to a Google doc of my own notes on each candidate&lt;/a&gt;, which I used as basis for recommendations below. (I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to clutter up the blog post with details)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of people have asked me to recommend who they should vote; while I prefer that they do their own research I don&amp;rsquo;t mind giving suggestions. Here are my recommendations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strongly recommended:&lt;/strong&gt; Jun Magsaysay, Risa Hontiveros, Teddy Casino&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to vote for:&lt;/strong&gt; Legarda, Escudero, Pimentel, Madrigal, Zubiri, Hagedorn, Poe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to vote for the following if you don&amp;rsquo;t mind them being members of or associated with political dynasties:&lt;/strong&gt; Cayetano, Gordon, Angara, Ejercito, Aquino&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to vote for the following if you don&amp;rsquo;t mind their strong association with religious groups:&lt;/strong&gt; Delos Reyes, Villanueva&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definitely DO NOT VOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; Honasan, Trillianes, Maceda, Mitos Magsaysay, Villar, Enrile, Binay, Cojuangco&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s okay to vote for&amp;rdquo; groups, just use your own preferences, i.e. if you don&amp;rsquo;t like Erap you probably won&amp;rsquo;t vote for JV Ejercito.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Ticket&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following will most likely be the 12 I will vote on Monday (barring something ridiculous happening):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jun Magsaysay (Team PNoy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risa Hontiveros (Team PNoy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teddy Casino (Independent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legarda (Team PNoy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Escudero (Team PNoy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pimentel (Team PNoy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Madrigal (Team PNoy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zubiri (UNA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hagedorn (Independent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gordon (UNA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Angara (Team PNoy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aquino (Team PNoy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand that the choices aren&amp;rsquo;t perfect (I&amp;rsquo;m not too fond of some of them&amp;hellip; ), but we have a limited selection of viable candidates and I&amp;rsquo;d rather fill up all 12 slots to at least have an infinitesimally small chance that the candidates I don&amp;rsquo;t want don&amp;rsquo;t get in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**What about the Party List?**There are really too many Party Lists to evaluate. Just don&amp;rsquo;t vote for some ridiculous group; look for a group with a strong advocacy and track record. My personal preference is for &lt;strong&gt;#95 AGHAM Party List&lt;/strong&gt;, because SCIENCE! Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://agham.org.ph/category/legislation/&#34;&gt;a list of legislation they&amp;rsquo;ve supported&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the last post from me before the elections on Monday (I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be ranting more &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang&#34;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;). If you have a chance to vote go out and do so, but be sure to do so wisely; it&amp;rsquo;s your privilege and an expression of what you want for this country. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope that the surveys are wrong and the voting public miraculously smartens up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: The original recommendations list missed out Grace Poe. Also added a short note on imperfect choices.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Even more ramblings about the elections
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/05/even-more-ramblings-about-the-elections/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 14:36:26 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/05/even-more-ramblings-about-the-elections/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to blame the poor, the masses for voting into power devious politicians, the corrupt, those with no track record, political dynasties based on money, survey results, name recognition or who has the most giveaways. But take a look at the number of decisions that have to be made when you go vote in an election (let&amp;rsquo;s say it&amp;rsquo;s also a presidential election so that we have a complete view):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to choose a president out of maybe 6-8 candidates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to choose a vice president out of maybe 6-8 candidates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to choose 12 senators from a pool of 20-30 or more candidates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to choose a congressman from maybe 4-6 candidates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to choose a governor (I&amp;rsquo;m from Metro Manila, we don&amp;rsquo;t have a guvnor so I&amp;rsquo;m just guessing here) from maybe 3-5 candidates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to choose a mayor from maybe 3-5 candidates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to choose a vice mayor from maybe 3-5 candidates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to choose god knows how many councilors (I seriously have no idea, is it 6?) from who knows how many candidates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to choose a party-list from over a hundred choices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to &amp;ldquo;vote wisely&amp;rdquo;, for each of those choices, you&amp;rsquo;d need to have some idea of who they are, what their background is, what their advocacies are, what their stand is on the issues, what bills they have pushed/sponsored/passed (if they had previous legislative experience), etc. For all of those candidates! I live a comfortable life and have a reasonable amount of free time and even I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do that! Not to mention that unlike me, a very, very large percentage of the voting population don&amp;rsquo;t have easily available internet access so that they can do their own research on candidates&amp;rsquo; backgrounds. They&amp;rsquo;re not on Facebook all the time reading about Nancy&amp;rsquo;s shenanigans or how Jack Enrile doesn&amp;rsquo;t want you to look closely at a murder rap in his history. They&amp;rsquo;re too busy with more mundane everyday concerns like how to earn money, where they&amp;rsquo;re going to get food to feed their large families, etc. They just don&amp;rsquo;t have the time, inclination or opportunity to soak up all the relevant information that would let them make an informed choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what do they do, they do what any regular, sane person does when faced with an overwhelming amount of information, they use filters. But their filters are silly things like survey results (&amp;ldquo;Other people think this candidate is okay, so I guess I can vote for him&amp;rdquo;), celebrity endorsements (it&amp;rsquo;s sad that former Sen. Jun Magsaysay only got a bump in survey results when he got Sir Chief to endorse him) or worse things like bribery, vote buying through giveaways, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What am I saying, what am I talking about? All this time I&amp;rsquo;ve been harping about how voter education is important, but how it&amp;rsquo;s delivered needs to be thought about. We can&amp;rsquo;t just flood people with information, they&amp;rsquo;re just going to be overwhelmed and the silly yet simpler things like inane political ads are going to win out. We need to, I dunno, find a way to provide better, easier filters for people. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how, I&amp;rsquo;m not that smart. Not yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But Roy,&amp;rdquo; I can hear you objecting already, &amp;ldquo;elections are serious business deciding the future of our country! It&amp;rsquo;s important, and they should take it seriously and think very hard about their choices!&amp;rdquo; You&amp;rsquo;re absolutely right that it&amp;rsquo;s important, but the problem is that for a vast majority of poor people, they have a lot of other more important, more urgent things to worry about. Elections affect what happens to our country three, five, ten years down the road, but a lot of people have trouble figuring out how they&amp;rsquo;re going to get through the next day. The feedback loop for getting results from elections is just too long for people to take it seriously. Now, we can suggest that maybe, just maybe, we can just ask those people not to vote if they&amp;rsquo;re not going to take it seriously? Maybe, but that&amp;rsquo;s hardly enforceable in any reasonable way. And you&amp;rsquo;re going to get accused of being anti-democracy or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;It has been said that democracy is the worst form of government except all the others that have been tried.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; William Churchill.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a solution, I&amp;rsquo;m just rambling. Maybe this is really how it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to work, democracy? We live with what the people choose, even if they&amp;rsquo;re bad choices. Democracy is very effective at a small scale (&amp;ldquo;Guys let&amp;rsquo;s vote on where we should have dinner!&amp;quot;) but I feel like the logistics of it all gets way way more difficult as we scale up to the level of an entire country. Maybe smarter people than me have proposed solutions, I dunno, comment and give me links if you know of them. Who are the best democracies in the world and how do they get away with it? Certainly not the United States with their two-party system and their lobbyists and what not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although now that I think about it, it might help if we reduce the number of choices that would need to be made. The simplest changes are to have president/VP be voted in together, same for mayor/vice mayor, and to have regional senators instead of national so that each person only needs to choose one senator (this has the pleasant side effect of reducing the amount of money needed to win a senate seat). I have no solution for party-list, I&amp;rsquo;d rather have it be removed if no solution can be found&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we need to start thinking about these things even outside of the electoral cycle (probably a bit hypocritical of me, I only post about election stuff during the election season). Going about ways to improve the next elections need to start as soon as the last elections end. Sometimes I feel like the Comelec has crammed a lot of stuff into the past year or so (registration, source code audits, rulings on party-lists, etc.) Why can&amp;rsquo;t we ask candidates to register 3 years before the election? That way voters have a lot more time to become familiar with them and the candidates are forced to flesh out long-term plans instead of making excuses that they don&amp;rsquo;t have time for debates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, I complain a lot, but I&amp;rsquo;m still going to vote. I&amp;rsquo;m not one of those people who complains but won&amp;rsquo;t vote. We should vote because (a) it&amp;rsquo;s our responsibility and (b) it&amp;rsquo;s an expression of what we as individuals desire to have in leaders of our country. And it&amp;rsquo;s probably our responsibility to vote wisely too, though I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that&amp;rsquo;s a rule encoded somewhere, the Comelec certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t emphasize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure of which senators I&amp;rsquo;ll be voting for, most of my slots are up in the air (although there are many candidates I&amp;rsquo;m surely NOT voting for). I&amp;rsquo;ll probably finalize my choices the weekend before the elections, and as has been my tradition, I will post my choices in this space. I&amp;rsquo;m registered in a different district than where I&amp;rsquo;m currently residing so I don&amp;rsquo;t vote for congressman and councilors, so my only choices this time around are the 12 senators and mayor/vice mayor of QC.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Nancy and the Elections: A Fictional Dialogue
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/04/nancy-and-the-elections-a-fictional-dialogue/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 14:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/04/nancy-and-the-elections-a-fictional-dialogue/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;People who follow me on Facebook or Twitter know that I&amp;rsquo;ve been recently made a number of anti-Nancy Binay posts. For a while now I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to write a blog post about that and several other election-related thoughts. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to present these thoughts it as a fictional chat between made-up characters. Totally fictional characters. Any resemblance to actual people living or dead = pure coincidence. &lt;em style=&#34;font-size: smaller; color: gray;&#34;&gt;(Although if you must try to imagine these characters, you can imagine jaeger as a dashing idealist, in-in as a cynical pragmatist, ORYLY as a carefree vagabond and Scrappy coco as someone who just wandered into the wrong room.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2 c9&#34;&gt;10:04:04&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3 c9&#34;&gt; * Scrappy coco will Nancy Binay win?&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:04:18&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; it is likely&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:04:28&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3 c12&#34;&gt;tzia_n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; will you rage?&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:04:32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; yes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:04:33&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; not really&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:04:45&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; i don&#39;t mind, idiots need representation too&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:08:03&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34; style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34; style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt; tsaka bat hate na hate mo si nancy binay over the other candidates? what makes her extra stupid?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:08:20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; nauna sya e&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:08:24&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; i dont hate her&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:08:27&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; but she&#39;s arrogant&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:08:33&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; ok lang kasi yung walang experience&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:08:44&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34; style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34; style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt; as long as you acknowledge it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:09:02&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; and talk about how you plan to surpass it&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:09:09&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; but she doesn&#39;t talk about anything&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:09:19&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; her ads are just literal motherhood statements&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:09:32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; and may arrogance kasi, especially from the father&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:09:39&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; na qualified daw sya simply because anak nya&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:10:00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; ic ic&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:10:14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; pero yung unang commercial pa lang nainis na ko&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:10:21&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; sya ata yung unang nagcommercial&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:10:26&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; before pa nung campaign period&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:10:38&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; di ba si villar?&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:10:44&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; buti na lang wala kaming tv&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:10:48&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; lol&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:10:53&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; ok lang naman ung nagdecide ka magrun for senator kahit walang experience, kahit sino naman pwede mangarap&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:11:31&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; actually, almost all the political ads are annoying&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:11:43&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; una ko lang napanood ung kay nancy so she&#39;s been annoying the longest time&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:12:12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; lol isa pa yung kay Enrile&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:12:14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; lel&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:12:24&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; annoying song&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:12:30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; plus annoying gesture&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:12:38&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; annoying tagline&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:13:14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; annoying everything&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:13:23&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; enrile daming pera&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:13:45&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; he doesn&#39;t look trustworthy as well. maski si jpe shady din actually yung past.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:14:09&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; i can feel some littlefinger vibes from jpe, sr. actually since before pa&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:14:48&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34; style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34; style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt; daming flipflopping ni sr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:17:34&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34; style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34; style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt; im really annoyed with the fact na dynasty na ang lumalabas pero sasabihin lng nila &#34;let the people decide&#34;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:17:59&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; #randomrant&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:18:53&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; that&#39;s not really a problem&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:19:00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; kasi ung people talaga ung problem&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:19:17&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; yeah in a way, people din may kasalanan&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:19:20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; if only we could somehow leverage the power of the information age&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:19:22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; the dynasty restriction is just a hack to attempt to minimize the problem&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:19:30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; yeah&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:20:30&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; dapat may some sort of viral facebook meme&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:20:46&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; like &#34;change your profile pic to this icon if you&#39;re going to vote intelligently&#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:20:49&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; lol i dunno&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:21:04&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; ahahaha&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:21:07&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; marami namang smart people sa pilipinas, someone needs to figure something like this out&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:21:07&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; also binay is arrogant when she said in a statement that sth like ayaw nya makipagdebate, kitakits na lng sa senate floor&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:21:09&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; and what will that do?&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:21:28&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; in-in at the very least raise awareness&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:21:39&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; and baka may peer pressure&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:21:49&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; sabagay nagawan nga ng TRO yung cybercrime bill&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:21:51&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; not just the profile pic thing&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:21:57&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; dapat may some sort of manifesto&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:22:02&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; from just changing our profile pics to black&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:22:45&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; well, most of the internet is already against nancy lol&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:23:13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; the problem is really the loads of people who are easily fooled by the going around and shaking hands, cheap giveaways, mababaw na commercials&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:23:42&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; *easily swayed&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:24:45&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; oh, and one should talk to people&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:24:47&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; on the street&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:24:53&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; taxi drivers, jeepney drivers&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:25:06&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; not necessarily to convince them of anything&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:25:11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; but just to get them thinking&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:25:44&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; i say this but i dont really do it. may risk of getting into a politically heated debate with a man who could get you killed if he gets careless&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:25:57&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; hehe&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:26:22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3 c13&#34;&gt;&gt; ‹jaeger› but just to get them thinking &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt;&lt;- and maybe convince them to talk to other people too. parang pyramiding&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:26:24&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; but does it help when you do it at that scale?&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:26:34&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; ah, try to get a meme going&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:26:36&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; that&#39;s where the pyramiding comes in!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:27:00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; kasi you need to make it virulent&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:27:09&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; catchy songs are virulent&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:27:09&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; kaya nga kelangan maraming tao ang gumagawa&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:27:12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; it cant just be me&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:27:20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; oh man, have you seen the comelec ads&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:27:26&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; about ung mga bawal na election practices&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:27:33&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; grabe ang obvious na low budget lol&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:27:39&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3 c13&#34;&gt;&gt; ‹jaeger› the problem is really the loads of people who are easily fooled by the going around and shaking hands, cheap giveaways, mababaw na commercials &gt;&gt; nahh they&#39;re easily swayed by the MOOLAH&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:27:40&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; I haven&#39;t turned on the TV since forever&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:27:56&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3 c7&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; and the intelligent people are not registered&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:27:57&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; si mr bawal!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:28:06&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; ibang issue pa yung vote buying&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:28:09&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; that&#39;s because the really intelligent thing is to sway other people&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:28:15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3 c10&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; not to vote intelligently yourself&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:28:19&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; pero unti-unti rin yun magtuturn if people start thinking&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:29:07&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; yeah, but isn&#39;t that the riddle of the century?&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:30:47&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; what do you mean?&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:30:55&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; i was thinking of writing a blog post about all of this&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:31:03&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; but now i think i&#39;ll just paste this chat log lol&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:31:12&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; it covers most of the things i was thinking about&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:31:39&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; probably cut the part about enrile (libel lolz)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:32:11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; making people start thinking is hard&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:32:23&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; well, doing it at a scale that matters&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:32:42&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; if it was easy, it would already be done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:32:47&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; anything worth doing is hard&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:33:06&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; yeah, I mean you&#39;ve come back to the same problem that everyone came across before&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:33:08&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; other people!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:33:53&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3 c11&#34;&gt;derp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3 c13&#34;&gt;&gt; ‹in-in› and the intelligent people are not registered &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt;&lt;-- woohoo! I&#39;m intelligent!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:34:05&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; we just need more ideas. there are lots of smart people that could be helping -- social scientists, psychologists, behavioral scientists, etc. -- who might be able to come up with ways to more easily propagate stuff like this&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2 c9&#34;&gt;10:35:22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3 c9&#34;&gt; * ORYLY they&#39;re working for advertising companies and the campaign management&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:36:54&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; voter education is important, but practically no one is talking about it though&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:37:15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34; style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34; style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt; should the media?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:37:16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; not even self-professed reformists&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:37:16&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; funds, yeah&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:38:08&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34; style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34; style=&#34;color: #000000;&#34;&gt; feeling ko delikado kasi to talk about voter education kasi you might offend the masses? I dunno&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:38:53&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; is that it?&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:38:56&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; sounds like a neutral topic&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:39:01&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; maybe because it&#39;s a boring topic&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:39:33&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; well that too&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:39:41&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; it&#39;s not like candidates actually talk about issues!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:39:50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c7 c3&#34;&gt;in-in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; offend the masses?&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:39:53&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; well sometimes they do, but not when their audience is the masses&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:40:14&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; maybe the important things just have to be framed correctly?&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:40:28&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; framed interestingly, I mean&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:41:00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; framed &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3 c9&#34;&gt;scandalously&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:41:00&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; framed with MONEY&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:41:01&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; jk&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:41:07&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; ooh scandalously haha&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:41:32&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; may scandal video talking about voting wisely&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:41:52&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; lel&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:41:56&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; or or or&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:42:13&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; kris aquino complaining about her ex husband not voting wisely&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:42:34&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; may iyak iyak pa&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:42:43&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; fund it&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:42:47&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; err&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:42:50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; crowdfund it&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:42:54&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; grassroots&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:42:55&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c10 c3&#34;&gt;ORYLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; yeaaaah&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:42:56&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; lol kickstarter&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2 c9&#34;&gt;10:43:27&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3 c9&#34;&gt; * ORYLY poof for social change&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:44:06&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c8 c3&#34;&gt;Scrappy coco&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; or or or Janine Tugonon breaking up with BF on Kris TV for not voting wisely&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:44:07&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; ok i guess that&#39;s enough material&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;c4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;c2&#34;&gt;10:44:10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;‹&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;jaeger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c0&#34;&gt;›&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c3&#34;&gt; lol&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>CJ Corona Impeached
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/05/cj-corona-impeached/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 13:51:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/05/cj-corona-impeached/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Time for some Monday morning quarterbacking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I Am Not A Lawyer. I&amp;rsquo;m just a guy with opinions. And you know what they say about opinions&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the Philippine Senate has impeached the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court by a vote of 20 to 3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve generally kept silent about the CJ trial, mainly because I know people who are rabidly pro-Corona and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like getting into an argument with someone who&amp;rsquo;s obviously biased (I&amp;rsquo;m sorry my friends, we are going to have to agree to disagree now). Not to say I dislike him either. I&amp;rsquo;ve never met the man, I don&amp;rsquo;t personally know anything about his family. All I know is what I&amp;rsquo;ve heard reported in the news, media, etc. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to hold my judgment until the end of the trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First: yes, the prosecution was terrible. Rushed impeachment complaint, bringing charges that are near-impossible to prove (&amp;ldquo;bias&amp;rdquo;? =/) fishing expeditions, &amp;ldquo;evidence&amp;rdquo; mysteriously appearing given by &amp;ldquo;unknown sources&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s all kinds of shady. To be honest, if the defense had rested their case right after the prosecution finished, they might have gotten a better outcome than this, maybe even won, who knows. The prosecution had next to nothing before the defense made their presentation. All they had were dollar accounts inaccessible to them, and the properties being declared with market value rather than acquisition cost. The defense made so many mistakes, it&amp;rsquo;s facepalm-worthy. Calling a hostile witness to the stand without knowing what she would bring, calling irrelevant witnesses, arguing that the foreign currency act restricted Corona himself from disclosing the dollar accounts; Cuevas (or whoever pushed for it) should be disbarred for even arguing that last one. They really had only one thing they had to explain, the co-mingled funds in the peso account issue. And even that they weren&amp;rsquo;t able to explain, with nothing to back up Corona&amp;rsquo;s explanation: no bank documents, no paper trail, none of the family members testifying that some of the funds were there, nothing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only things Corona brought with his testimony were ad hominem attacks, appeals to sympathy, appeals to authority and drama. While I don&amp;rsquo;t care if those arguments are presented to the media or via press conferences I couldn&amp;rsquo;t care less, but for the chief justice himself, the head of the judiciary, to be making such arguments in a quasi-legal proceeding? It boggles the mind, to be claiming that the prosecution is bringing forth charges without evidence, when your arguments consist of a conspiracy theory involving an unrelated agrarian reform case and the state of mind of your grandchild. Ugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I was already leaning against the CJ the moment he accepted the midnight appointment from Gloria Arroyo. That was a terrible, terrible thing to do. You can say that technically it was legal and the Supreme Court upheld it but whatever. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe that we should be supportive of public servants just because they adhere to the minimum standards set by the law. I believe that with public office being a public trust, public servants should be held to a higher standard than ordinary citizens, even more so those who hold the highest positions in our land. Higher standards of integrity and delicadeza. Public servants should be like caesar&amp;rsquo;s wife: beyond any suspicion.  To accept that midnight appointment, while ruled to be technically legal, while it could not be proven to be for the benefit of GMA, was a terribly unethical decision for someone who should be the epitome of legal ethics. It would have been so easy to say &amp;ldquo;No, this is not right, I will not accept this nomination, I will not degrade the position of Chief Justice&amp;rdquo; and thus to end his career honorably (possibly even be chosen as the CJ at a later date). But pride, ambition, loyalty, whatever, he still chose to accept it, and it led to his downfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interpretation of the FCBD act and the SALN law to his benefit is another example, an indicator of a preference of adhering to the letter of the law rather than the spirit of the law; of placing more importance to a law whose purpose was to encourage dollar savings than to a law that promotes transparency and good government. Is that the sort of shining example we want to give to the judiciary, that they should be placing their personal interests above those of the country?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And rushing out of the trial, claiming a low blood sugar attack, conveniently right after he dramatically calls for waivers from his &amp;ldquo;political opponents&amp;rdquo;, then coming back in a wheelchair looking dazed to try to get sympathy (what, there were no sugar sources anywhere in the senate building?). There&amp;rsquo;s no way to disprove the claim or to show it was staged (even though he had time to shake hands with some people on his way out of the courtroom), but you have to wonder if the CJ himself would allow that sort of shenanigans if he was presiding over the court. Not a very good example either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were very few real winners in this trial, but a clear one has to be the Senate President Juan Ponce Enrile. Despite all the incompetence of the related parties, he did the best job he could, presiding over a very fair trial, calling it straight down the middle down to the very end. Respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, time for a lesson in bad arguments (mostly for internet commenters): &amp;ldquo;Let he who is without sin cast the first stone&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; this is a logical fallacy called &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tu_quoque&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tu quoque&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, a form of ad hominem. While this is great for bibilical parables, probably not the best argument to cite for legal proceedings. Sure, a whole lot of the accusers themselves are probably corrupt or misdeclaring their SALNs or whatever. Impeach them too. Impeach them all if we have to. (Fortunately for the president, incompetence is not an impeachable offense&amp;hellip; yet.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s my 2 cents. Now can we move on? We still have to prepare for the next circus, it&amp;rsquo;s coming in May 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>On Working
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/06/on-working/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 16:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/06/on-working/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write about why I quit a perfectly good job I had at &lt;a href=&#34;http://azeus.com&#34;&gt;Azeus&lt;/a&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s been hard to articulate the reasons, in the same way I found it hard to explain to people why I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel a corporate &amp;ldquo;9 to 5&amp;rdquo; was entirely necessary at this point. Then I read a blog post today &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.two-shay.com/articles/why-i-quit-a-six-figure-job&#34;&gt;Why I Quit A Six Figure Job&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; which I found to express/coincide with my thoughts pretty well on the upsides and downsides of having a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started working in 2003 I was young and inexperienced and had no idea what sort of things should be planned out in life. For the first four years of my stay there I worked hard, the job was awesome, I was working with terrific people, I was learning a lot and the paycheck was great. Somewhere around late 2006 I completed my first largish project as technical lead and I felt we had pulled it off quite well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to three years later (2009). For some reason, it felt like time went by really quickly and the period of rapid growth that I experienced during the first half of my stay had slowed down into a more gradual pace. Though I was still improving and learning new things, it was nowhere near the level as when I first started. I felt like I was pretty much in the same place I was in 2006, in terms of technical skill, responsibilities, etc. (Well, of course my paycheck got better&amp;hellip; ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the hardest part to explain, at that time I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand it very well myself, but basically there is a trap that anyone working a &amp;ldquo;9 to 5&amp;rdquo; job easily falls into. That trap is complacency. It&amp;rsquo;s a trap fueled by the easy money of the regular paycheck. By then I would often find myself just &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=phone%20it%20in&#34;&gt;phoning it in&lt;/a&gt;. Successive days would pass by where I&amp;rsquo;m just going through the motions of waking up, slogging through the commute, doing whatever needs to be done, sleeping through the bus ride home and hoping the weekend comes sooner. And whenever I tried to look down the line, imagining what the job would be like three or four years later, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see it being any different than what it was right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure a lot of people (probably 95% of people or more) would have been perfectly happy where I was with a good job and a steady paycheck. But I&amp;rsquo;m a greedy bastard, I want more in life than other people are willing to settle for. I felt like if I stayed where I was, somehow the story of my life would be over, as I already knew how the future would go if I stayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I forced the change. I resigned from my job and took the leap into an uncertain future. I still don&amp;rsquo;t know where I&amp;rsquo;m going, and I&amp;rsquo;m still currently unemployed, but I know I have a lot of options. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any big commitments (not gonna be married anytime soon) and I have enough of a safety net to last me a few years, so I&amp;rsquo;m in no hurry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post already went on for longer than I intended, so I&amp;rsquo;ll leave other questions such as &amp;ldquo;What are you doing now that you&amp;rsquo;re a bum?&amp;rdquo; (I get asked this a lot) or &amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t it stupid to quit your job without a plan?&amp;rdquo; for future discussions. If you found my reasons interesting though, you may want to read &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=1451175&#34;&gt;the discussion thread on Hacker News about Xavier Shay&amp;rsquo;s post&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s quite interesting.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Casual Fridays?
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/06/casual-fridays/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 13:05:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2009/06/casual-fridays/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the scenario: Last Sunday in the early morning, there was a fire in our office building, which hit some power stuff in the basement. So yesterday (Monday), the whole building was running on generators without air conditioning. Last night, we were notified that the power was back in the building, but just in case, we should come in to work in casual clothes (&amp;ldquo;dress down&amp;rdquo;), normally reserved for casual Fridays/Saturdays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, this got me thinking: what&amp;rsquo;s the rationale here? Do we get to dress down because it might be hot? There was like a week long period during summer that the building air conditioners were 50% malfunctioning; it was pretty hot then too, so that&amp;rsquo;s probably not the reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question is: why do we have a regular office dress code (ours is &amp;ldquo;smart casual&amp;rdquo;) and a different dress code on arbitrary days (&amp;ldquo;casual Fridays&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;when the air conditioning breaks down&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;if we have bowling in the afternoon&amp;rdquo;)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, why do we have office dress codes at all? The easiest answer to think of is that management wants us to &amp;ldquo;look professional&amp;rdquo;. While I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily agree with that (especially at my work since we aren&amp;rsquo;t usually meeting with clients or anything that remotely requires being impressive), I will stipulate that there are certain benefits of having everyone in the company wearing a certain level of attire; it can provide a certain sort of ambiance that makes people feel more professional and thus conducive to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, given that, why do we have dress-down days? Does it imply that during those days it&amp;rsquo;s okay to be &amp;ldquo;less professional&amp;rdquo;, or to work less? If not, then why aren&amp;rsquo;t we allowed to dress casually all the time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, I would prefer to be allowed to wear whatever I want; wearing comfortable clothes is a lot more conducive to work for me than &amp;ldquo;looking professional&amp;rdquo;. But again, I will stipulate that not everyone may think this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you think, dear reader? Dress-down days: yay or nay?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Predictions on the Evolution of Language, Part 1
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/11/predictions-on-the-evolution-of-language-part-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 06:48:38 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/11/predictions-on-the-evolution-of-language-part-1/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I predict that eventually, &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;won&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;can&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rdquo; and the like will eventually become their own words, dropping that weird apostrophe they have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few decades after this happens, some people will wonder what &amp;ldquo;wan&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rdquo; used to stand for.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Programmer, engineer, scientist, critic, gamer, dreamer, and kid-at-heart.
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/02/programmer-engineer-scientist-critic-gamer-dreamer-and-kid-at-heart/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2006 01:02:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/02/programmer-engineer-scientist-critic-gamer-dreamer-and-kid-at-heart/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I remembered that I haven&amp;rsquo;t written an About page yet. This post will go there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/profile/1694272&#34;&gt;Blogger profile &lt;/a&gt;describes me as a &amp;ldquo;Programmer, engineer, scientist, critic, gamer, dreamer, and kid-at-heart.&amp;rdquo; Let&amp;rsquo;s break that down, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmer : Since January of 2003 I&amp;rsquo;ve been working as a software developer for the RP office of a Hong Kong-based company. I&amp;rsquo;m no Computer Science graduate, but I did manage to fake it well enough to pass the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jitse.org/&#34;&gt;JITSE &lt;/a&gt;certification exams. I code because I find that I&amp;rsquo;m fairly good at it. This is my day job, and I&amp;rsquo;m luckier than most, because I actually _enjoy _my day job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineer : I&amp;rsquo;m an Engineer by education, having completed a degree in Electronics and Communications Engineering from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.upd.edu.ph/&#34;&gt;University&lt;/a&gt;. I passed the ECE board exams in 2002, but have never practiced as an Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientist : Does having a Bachelor in Science degree allow me to consider myself a scientist? What about graduating from the premiere science high school in the country? A naturally geeky curiousity that tends to overanalyze everything?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critic : No wait, that last one from &amp;ldquo;Scientist&amp;rdquo; goes here. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m only somewhat of a critic. Or maybe what I really meant at the time was that I enjoy criticizing things. 😀&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gamer : Well, just by reading this blog you know I&amp;rsquo;m into games. Card games, board games, console games, computer games, psychological games, you name it. Regarding electronic gaming, I started with the Atari 5600 that my parents bought in the US, and only during the PS2 era have I started to slow down. At one point or another I have been addicted every major genre: strategy, RPG, action, FPS, puzzle, whatever. Well, except for Dance Dance Revolution and the like. I&amp;rsquo;m really sucky at that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dreamer : I dream of a lot of things, and not only when I sleep. There are a lot of things I want to do, and more things I want to be. Off the top of my head, I want to be a published game developer, a published writer and world-famous. And those are just the three most probable ones :p&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kid-at-heart : I guess you have to be a kid-at-heart to dream the dreams that I do. I really want to expound on this, and the &amp;ldquo;Dreamer&amp;rdquo; part, but I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that would entail entirely separate entries. 😀&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>On the Mohammed Cartoons Issue
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/02/on-the-mohammed-cartoons-issue/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2006 07:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/02/on-the-mohammed-cartoons-issue/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The response of the western world to the recent backlash against published cartoon depictions of mohammed could be described as the unavoidable result of two completely distinct cultures clashing against each other. On one hand, Islam dictates that any such depiction of the prophet Mohammed are considered as blasphemy; on the other hand, Western media views it as a free speech issue; since every other religion in the world tolerates media lampooning, why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Islam? Arguably, other faiths also have a certain threshold of tolerance for religious mockery beyond which they would mercilessly tear down whatever publication dared to print it. The only difference is that the threshold for Islam is a lot easier to break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are dying now, from riots against Danish embassies in protest of the actions of the Denmark papers. Western-cultured individuals would question why any intelligent human being would rail against a government for the actions of its&amp;rsquo; media outlets. But these radicals are the sort that don&amp;rsquo;t understand the virtues of the free press. The sheer number of Muslims reacting violently is a testament as to how many of the freedoms that we in the Western-oriented world take for granted can be considered as unimaginable in some cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The frightening thing is that with all the tension between the Western world and Islam right now, these small things are the sort that could be used as an excuse to trigger a third world war. And someone may have even &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.neandernews.com/?p=54&#34;&gt;added fuel to the fire on purpose.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>