<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>stormlight archive on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/stormlight-archive/</link>
      <description>Recent content in stormlight archive on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/stormlight-archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Rhythm of War by Sanderson, Brandon
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/rhythm-of-war/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/12/rhythm-of-war/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Rhythm of War is book four in Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s epic fantasy Stormlight Archive series. Goodreads tells me I read the prior book Oathbringer back in Nov 2017, but didn&amp;rsquo;t bother writing a review, so I had to make sure I&amp;rsquo;d write one now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book&amp;rsquo;s launch day kind of caught me a bit unexpectedly so I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother doing a re-read of the previous three books. Which given an epic fantasy series of this scope might have been a mistake, but watch me do it again for book five. No review meant while reading every so often I&amp;rsquo;d stop and be like &amp;ldquo;Who is this character again, and why is she here?&amp;rdquo; Which is to be expected for this kind of thing, probably if GRRM ever manages to bring out Winds of Winter that&amp;rsquo;ll be a thing again. It&amp;rsquo;s a whole big sprawl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got this book on launch day last Nov 17. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/01/words-of-radiance/&#34;&gt;review for the second book Words of Radiance&lt;/a&gt; tells me it took me three weeks to get through it, so I was kind of expecting I might take until 2021 with this one. It only took me a around eight days, with the last third of the book taking me a single read in one long night. So, that says a lot about how good the book is and how the pacing is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a really fun book actually, things are happening, and there&amp;rsquo;s character growth and everything, and I feel like this one touched a lot more on the cosmere stuff. Or maybe I was just notificing more things because no review meant I was reading the wiki more. (Don&amp;rsquo;t worry I managed not to spoil myself!). It&amp;rsquo;s great that Sanderson manages to just put in a lot of stuff and give all of the lead characters significant things to do and character arcs and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s some happenings near the end that turn around some things the characters thought they knew about their history; not as big as the one in Oathbringer, but that&amp;rsquo;s always fun. And some things happen where I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how the next book is going to handle it, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to that. (Trying not to be too spoilery here of course!) At Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s rate, it&amp;rsquo;s gonna be at least 3 years before book 5 comes out, and even after that, the series is expected to have a second 5-book arc, plus there&amp;rsquo;s some side books that I feel like I should read because they introduce some relevant characters (Edgedanger, etc) so there&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of Stormlight Archive to look forward to!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Words of Radiance by Sanderson, Brandon
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/01/words-of-radiance/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/01/words-of-radiance/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17332218-words-of-radiance&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Words of Radiance (The Stormlight Archive, #2)&#34; src=&#34;https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1507307927l/17332218._SX98_.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17332218-words-of-radiance&#34;&gt;Words of Radiance&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/38550.Brandon_Sanderson&#34;&gt;Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1537966035&#34;&gt;5 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The first book I read for 2016 was Words of Radiance by Brandon Sanderson second book of the Stormlight Archive. It&amp;rsquo;s a huge book, and the first half took me more or less three weeks to slog through (I started it in late December), but by the time I got to the middle of the book, a lot of exciting things were happening and my pace improved considerably. I finished the second half of the book in around 2-3 days. The great thing is that the book resolves a lot of the dangling plot lines from Way of Kings, rewarding the reader with serious payoffs for the stories of Kaladin and Dalinar and a deeper look at Shallan&amp;rsquo;s back story. The first half builds up to a second half full of great action sequences that the reader is anticipating. Interspersed with Kaladin and the Kholin family&amp;rsquo;s action is Shallan&amp;rsquo;s back story and her dangerous forays into studies and investigations that dig up even more plot lines left to be resolved for later books. Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s world-building is again top notch as he introduces us into new exotic locales in this world and constructs an interesting mythology around the spren and the Parshendi. The book ends on a satisfying note at the same time leaving some threads hanging and the greater plot looming on the horizon. It&amp;rsquo;s too bad the next book isn&amp;rsquo;t scheduled until 2017
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/18436248-roy-tang&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>