<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>watching lately on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately/</link>
      <description>Recent content in watching lately on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:13:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Reviews: Casino Royale, Gunpowder Milkshake, The Long Halloween, Masters of the Universe Revelation
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-casino-royale-gunpowder-milkshake-the-long-halloween-masters-of-the-universe-revelation/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 11:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-casino-royale-gunpowder-milkshake-the-long-halloween-masters-of-the-universe-revelation/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve watched lately. Spoilers for Gunpowder Milkshake and MotU: Revelation are marked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;casino-royale-2006&#34;&gt;Casino Royale (2006)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 21, and the first for Daniel Craig. The final era in this James Bond run, looking forward to it. Casino Royale is new to me, but I&amp;rsquo;ve seen two of Craig&amp;rsquo;s Bond films, so I have an idea of what to expect: a more serious and much less campy James Bond, grim and determined. The tone here is much closer to Dalton&amp;rsquo;s two films than any of the other runs. Since it&amp;rsquo;s kind of a reboot, it takes place early in Bond&amp;rsquo;s career, in fact he earns his double-O status right in the cold open. Craig&amp;rsquo;s Bond is younger, brasher, more vulnerable, and a bit more prone to mistakes, like letting himself getting caught on camera assassinating a prisoner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme song here is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YnzgdBAKyJo&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;You Know My Name&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by Chris Cornell of SoundGarden fame. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit more alternative than recent theme songs; I like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judi Dench is back as M, the only actor carried over from previous incarnations. We don&amp;rsquo;t get any of the usual support staff like Moneypenny or Q. Bond spends most of the first half of the film alone in the field, and the second half supported by treasury agent Vesper Lynd (played by Eva Green). Mads Mikkelsen plays the protagonist, terrorist financier Le Chiffre, who Bond challenges to a high-stakes poker game at the titular Casino Royale. Also making an appearance is an old Bond ally, CIA&amp;rsquo;s Felix Leiter, who we last saw mauled by a shark in Dalton&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/4e93006d466cb2f6a53325cba8e27b63/&#34;&gt;License to Kill&lt;/a&gt;. (He has been recast as a black man for the modern age of James Bond.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plot is reasonable and action-packed. Daniel Craig probably feels the least &amp;ldquo;Bond-like&amp;rdquo; compared to what his predecessors have established for the role, but his Bond is pretty good and is portrayed as relentless and unstoppable, in spite of his mistakes. The on-foot chase scene in Madagascar near the start of the film is great, especially all the crane shots. Le Chiffre seems a bit incompetent for a villain. The final third of the movie (after the poker game) plays out a bit strangely, for a while I was like &amp;ldquo;What the heck is going on?&amp;rdquo; There is a betrayal in the end that I didn&amp;rsquo;t see coming, which erased any doubt in my mind whether I had actually watched this one in the theaters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to the rest of Craig&amp;rsquo;s run!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gunpowder-milkshake-2021&#34;&gt;Gunpowder Milkshake (2021)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We watched this during our Saturday online gaming session watch-along. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have high expectations for the film, as I thought it was kind of an ultraviolent grim John-Wick style thing and I didn&amp;rsquo;t really think Karen Gillan and Lena Headey would be good to lead that kind of movie. It does turn out to be ultraviolent, but not super grim, and in fact maybe even a little goofy. There are some great action sequences and fight scenes here, but as soon as I saw that 
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    Karen Gillan was going to have a fight scene in the doctor&amp;rsquo;s office with her arms all floppy from anesthesia
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
, I was like, ok this movie is already worth watching. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a very deep, complicated plot or anything, but overall a decent popcorn watch. A fun, ultraviolent, very bloody, very much not for kids movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;batman-the-long-halloween-2021&#34;&gt;Batman: The Long Halloween (2021)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a 2-part entry to the DC Universe animated movie line, an adaptation of the famous comic of the same name by Jeph Loeb and Tim Sale. The story covers an early year of Batman&amp;rsquo;s career as he works with Captain Jim Gordon and then-district attorney Harvey Dent to face both the Gotham mob and a serial killer that kills once a month, on the holidays. The film mostly covers the same story beats as the comic (which I had to review because it&amp;rsquo;s been probably more than a decade since I read it!), with a bit of a twist towards the end of the first part that changes the eventual ending in the second part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t help but compare this storyline to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/07/movies-the-dark-knight/&#34;&gt;The Dark Knight (2008)&lt;/a&gt; as it covers some of the same elements: organized crime in Gotham and the origin of Two-Face among others. In fact I believe the comic book was one of the inspirations for Nolan&amp;rsquo;s eventual plot for TDK. I would guess that TDK changes were largely due to the need to focus on The Joker, who is more of a minor villain The Long Halloween, and I can&amp;rsquo;t help but imagine what if Nolan had chosen to stay more faithful to TLH storyline, what kind of movie could we have gotten?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this particular animated version is pretty good, mostly faithful to the source material, and I like the animation style here. Jensen Ackles is a serviceable Batman voice, and Troy Baker is a pretty good Joker; for a moment I wondered if it was Mark Hamill in the role. Part one was released back in June, and part two just last week, so I only watched both parts today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the next DCU animated movie project is &lt;strong&gt;Injustice&lt;/strong&gt;, based on the game series of the same name, also looking forward to that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;masters-of-the-universe-revelation-season-1-part-1&#34;&gt;Masters of the Universe: Revelation (season 1 part 1)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also watched this during Saturday&amp;rsquo;s watch-along. This one is a bit controversial, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write about it even though technically the season is only halfway through. The controversy is because the show&amp;rsquo;s plot mostly focuses around Teela and a quest she undergoes after the events of the first episode: 
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    He-Man and Skeletor are presumed dead in a battle and Teela leaves the service of King Randor out of anger over having Adam&amp;rsquo;s secret withheld from her for so long.
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voice work is pretty good; we immediately recognized Lena Headey&amp;rsquo;s voice as Evil-Lyn, and Mark Hamill as Skeletor is unmistakeable. We didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize Sarah Michelle Gellar as Teela though! The storyline so far is okay, though not super original. It kind of felt like a typical JRPG party-gathering and going on a quest thing, really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of old fans didn&amp;rsquo;t like the focus being taken away from He-Man and focusing on a female character, which many imagined as purely a diversity play. I feel like it&amp;rsquo;s much too early to judge the season overall, since it&amp;rsquo;s only halfway through, but even then, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong about focusing on some other characters, as the show is explicitly titled &amp;ldquo;Masters of the Universe&amp;rdquo; without the &amp;ldquo;He-Man and the&amp;hellip; &amp;quot; prefix. It&amp;rsquo;s probably best to see where Kevin Smith takes us for the eventual second part (for which we have no release date yet).&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reviews: Die Another Day, Army of the Dead, Valerian, Superstore, Omelas
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-die-another-day-army-of-the-dead-valerian-superstore-omelas/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 02:37:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-die-another-day-army-of-the-dead-valerian-superstore-omelas/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I used to do these &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Watching Lately&amp;rdquo; posts&lt;/a&gt; to talk about movies/tv/books I&amp;rsquo;d recently consumed, but for a while I folded up the reviews into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/weeknotes&#34;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; and sometimes via short &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes&#34;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; but the reviews have been getting longer so I guess I&amp;rsquo;m bring the &amp;ldquo;Watching Lately&amp;rdquo; tag and series of posts back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;die-another-day-2002&#34;&gt;Die Another Day (2002)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 20 and Brosnan&amp;rsquo;s final appearance. The main question for me going in was: have I actually watched this before in the theatre? My memory says no, but this movie does have the ice palace scene I originally thought was in World is Not Enough. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember any of the other plot details though. I think I would have if I had seen it before, because I actually really liked the film and think it&amp;rsquo;s the best of the Brosnan run. I mean, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even remember the betrayal towards the end, and that took me by surprise this time. The likely explanation seems to be that I had caught the later parts of the film on cable tv which is why I remember the ice palace thing, so I will consider this NOT a rewatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I read up on it after watching, apparently this film had a mixed reception, but I liked it. It has the campiness of the earlier films, and some good throwbacks and references, as it&amp;rsquo;s the 40th anniversary of the film. I mean, I agree the invisible car was a bit silly, but maybe about as much as everyday use of a jetpack (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/03/c6152994fa5ddf4b9c3302bcddfdd699/&#34;&gt;Thunderball&lt;/a&gt;) or going into space (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/06/cbb6135fa20b48a488982eccc7df76ce/&#34;&gt;Moonraker&lt;/a&gt;). There&amp;rsquo;s also an actual honest-to-goodness sword fight here that goes on quite a bit, first with fencing swords and later with actual swords. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just that I really enjoy swordfights lol. I also liked the car vs car battle later on in the movie; Bond has not had to face anyone with the same level of fancy car gadgets before, so it was fun. Also, the villain plot was to use something akin to C&amp;amp;C&amp;rsquo;s ion cannon! A space laser! I really would have remembered that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked the opening theme performed by Madonna, but didn&amp;rsquo;t actually recognize her in the cameo. This is the first film without Desmond Llewelyn as Q, as he had passed away the year before release. John Cleese is an adequate replacement, but this is also his final appearance in the role. This movie was also apparently Rosamund Pike&amp;rsquo;s first film. Hally Berry is ok as a Bond girl, nothing too exceptional. Her character was quite competent at first but then got captured (twice) in the second half. I believe this film is also the first time Bond has faced a North Korean villain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I think a fitting end to the Brosnan run and as a 40th anniversary celebration of the series. The campiness is fine, especially since the upcoming Daniel Craig era would be much more serious and gritty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;army-of-the-dead-2021&#34;&gt;Army of the Dead (2021)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watched this yesterday, mostly as background while I did other things, so not paying 100% attention I guess. I remembered reading that Tig Notaro (who plays the helicopter pilot) was never on set with the other actors (due to covid or something I guess) so every time she would be in a scene I&amp;rsquo;d mentally note how she&amp;rsquo;s not shown together with the others or was possible just edited into the shot. I really led with that lol, it&amp;rsquo;s what was foremost on my mind while watching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a reasonable action movie and zombie/heist flick, if not a bit predictable. I liked that safecracker guy, he really had a passion for his work, too bad he died. I actually thought more of their team would survive, but maybe I just haven&amp;rsquo;t seen enough zombie flicks. There&amp;rsquo;s an obvious setup at the end for a possible sequel, but Batista won&amp;rsquo;t be coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;valerian-and-the-city-of-a-thousand-planets-2017&#34;&gt;Valerian and the City of a Thousand Planets (2017)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ended up watching a second movie later in the day. I had been meaning to watch this for a while as it looked good. It&amp;rsquo;s an ok sci-fi movie to watch, but not a must-see as the plot is kind of predictable / cookie clutter, and there&amp;rsquo;s this one sequence in the middle which felt unnecessary and was just an excuse to get Cara Delevingne in a dress. Visuals are super pretty though, all the space stuff and the special effects and the City of a Thousand Planets all look great. The main guy Valerian fights waaaay too well, so that needs a bit of suspension of disbelief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only learned after watching that this movie was actually a French production directed by Luc Besson (of &lt;em&gt;Fifth Element&lt;/em&gt; fame), and was based on a French comic called &lt;em&gt;Valerian and Laureline&lt;/em&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s right, the comic actually had Laureline on equal billing with Valerian but noooo, the movie had to be titled for Valerian only. Actually, the comic seems more interesting from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Val%C3%A9rian_and_Laureline&#34;&gt;the wikipedia description&lt;/a&gt; as it seems to be more time-travel focused (Laureline is actually supposed to be from 11th-century France), but the movie doesn&amp;rsquo;t really give us much background on either of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this movie got mixed reviews and was a flop, so a follow-up in the same universe seems unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;superstore-season-5&#34;&gt;Superstore season 5&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I binged the first four seasons of Superstore on Prime Video &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/09/weeknotes-09-13/&#34;&gt;back in 2020&lt;/a&gt;, and over the weekend I saw the fifth season was already up, so I had it as my background watching for most of the weekend and actually finished it already by Monday. Season 5 is pretty much more of the same flavor, though there are a bit more Filipino references (which I always enjoy) since there&amp;rsquo;s a stronger focus on the character Matteo, who in the last season was arrested by ICE because he was an illegal immigrant from the Philippines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-ones-who-walk-away-from-omelas-by-ursula-k-le-guin&#34;&gt;The Ones Who Walk Away From Omelas by Ursula K. Le Guin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone gave me a copy of this because I mentioned I&amp;rsquo;d never read any Le Guin before. It&amp;rsquo;s super short but quite thought-provoking, making you think about what costs any possible utopia could have. But I also think the ending is projecting a bit of optimism, in that no matter what darkness you discover, there&amp;rsquo;s always the option of just walking away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure whether to log this in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/lists/media/books/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;books read list&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; category, given that it&amp;rsquo;s not really a book and the length is actually barely a short story, but hey it&amp;rsquo;s my list, I&amp;rsquo;ll do what I want. It did make me want to seek out other Le Guin works, I&amp;rsquo;ll see what I can find.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reviews: The World is Not Enough, Barry season 1, Loki
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-the-world-is-not-enough-barry-season-1-loki/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 10:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/07/reviews-the-world-is-not-enough-barry-season-1-loki/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Warning: Spoilers for the just-ended season of Loki at the end of this. I have &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2021/07/1415238174377340930/&#34;&gt;a spoiler-free review&lt;/a&gt; of that if you&amp;rsquo;d like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-world-is-not-enough-1999&#34;&gt;The World Is Not Enough (1999)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bond film no. 19 and Brosnan&amp;rsquo;s third. Pretty sure I saw this in the theaters when it came out, but for the life of me could not recall any of the plot details at all. Turns out it was because the plot was a bit unnecessarily convoluted. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to tell straight away that Sophie Marceau is on the bad guy side, given her henchmen, so that was no surprise. Renard was a bit boring, revenge yada yada, bullet in my head, etc. The master plan here, originally misdirected as terrorism, turns out to just be financial all along. What assured me that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t insane and that I did see it in theaters was that as soon as I saw Denise Richards name in the opening credits I remember she played a nuclear physicist in this one. Probably the weakest of the Brosnan ones so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have a scene of Brosnan in some kind of ice building (?) in my random access memory, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t here so I think that&amp;rsquo;s a sign that I may have actually seen his next and last Bond film &lt;strong&gt;Die Another Day&lt;/strong&gt; before and just blocked out any memory of it for some reason. We&amp;rsquo;ll find out next week I suppose!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;barry-season-1&#34;&gt;Barry (season 1)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this late last week, and the season is only eight episodes but I only finished last night because each episode is a bit stressful to watch. Stressful in the sense that you pretty much expect that bad things are going to keep happening and that things are just going to get tougher for the protagonist. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit like Breaking Bad, where the protag just keeps getting into deeper and deeper trouble, but where Walter White started to revel in his notoriety, Barry just wants out, but he can&amp;rsquo;t get a break, and keeps on finding himself forced to do bad things. It&amp;rsquo;s very good, but also very dark. The season ends in a surprisingly satisfactory manner while still setting up possible follow-up storylines. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit tempted to just stop there and be happy with the show as it is and not continue to the second season as the show might actually get worse, we&amp;rsquo;ll see how long I hold it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;loki-season-1&#34;&gt;Loki (season 1)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season finale ended earlier today. As noted above, there is a spoiler-free review:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;On 
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;/2021/07/1415238174377340930/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;time datetime=&amp;quot;2021-07-14 09:14:09&amp;quot;&amp;gt;14 Jul 2021 9:14am&amp;lt;/time&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
I wrote:
&amp;lt;blockquote&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;#Loki spoiler-free review:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;overall plot was fine, if not predictable, given what we knew about mcu phase 4 going in&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;weak pacing and writing in most episodes; could have easily been a two hour movie instead of six one hour episodes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;good watch for mcu fans because of the larger phase 4 implications, but much weaker as a standalone series&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;/blockquote&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think overall, the plot of Loki delving into the truth behind the TVA and eventually causing the return of the multiverse was entirely predictable given the series&amp;rsquo; premise and what we knew of the larger MCU even before the series aired. The whole thing is even telegraphed completely in the first episode: removing the TVA means multiversal war; we are told the stakes from the very beginning and nothing really changes in that regard even up to the final episode and the reveal of who was actually behind the TVA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of the whole &amp;ldquo;reveal a new character and info dump his background in the last episode&amp;rdquo; treatment that character got. I get that the reveal was necessary for the larger MCU set up, but there&amp;rsquo;s no reason it could have been done or hinted from earlier episodes so that he didn&amp;rsquo;t have to monologue his back story for like 60% of this episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pacing of the entire six-episode runs just seemed so off to me; basically nothing interesting happening during the first three episodes (other than the reveal of a female Loki variant, which should surprise us why?), then some interesting stuff in episodes 4 and 5 and finally this disappointing finale was like 90% dialogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ramifications for the entire MCU at large are huge of course, and as a setup vehicle for the greater cinematic multiverse the series does the job well. But on the smaller scale, as a series standing by itself we got an anticlimactic finale, Renslayer and Mobius don&amp;rsquo;t get any kind of resolution or advancement to their character arcs, and our protagonist ends up right back where he was from the start - lost and alone. So unsatisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will of course still watch the eventual season 2, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to What If in August, but this finale just left a sour taste in my mouth.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Weeknotes 2020-03-29 Time Is Meaningless
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-29/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/weeknotes-2020-03-29/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/covid19/&#34;&gt;COVID19 Diary&lt;/a&gt; is still ongoing, although that TOC is starting to get unwieldy. Need to think of a better UX solution for that.&lt;/p&gt;








    
    
        
    
    
    
        
            
            
            
            
              
            
            
            &lt;a href=&#34;#ebaca044327af45cfc02b507f864565e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
                &lt;figure&gt;
                  &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1242953238497751040/ET_bYDoUMAA8vty_hu61559ea2fb5b54ac6f28ab0474d68098_8100_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;ldquo;Time is meaningless under extreme enhanced community quarantine&amp;rdquo;&#34; title=&#34;&amp;ldquo;Time is meaningless under extreme enhanced community quarantine&amp;rdquo;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
                  &lt;figcaption&gt;“Time is meaningless under extreme enhanced community quarantine” (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
                &lt;/figure&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;ebaca044327af45cfc02b507f864565e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
              &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1242953238497751040/ET_bYDoUMAA8vty.png&#34; /&gt;
              &lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
                &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Time is meaningless under extreme enhanced community quarantine&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
                &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;29 Mar 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;29 Mar 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/1242953238497751040/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;            
        
    

&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;rsquo;s probably unrealistic, but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the lockdown somehow gets lifted sooner rather than later. It&amp;rsquo;s not that I crave social interaction (I don&amp;rsquo;t), but I miss going out for food. I miss pizza. And japanese curry. And fancy sandwiches with sesame seeds and such. The food at the house is fine and all, but tends to get repetitive. And during the last grocery run, the only mayonnaise they had was Best Foods Mayo Magic. Bleah. I&amp;rsquo;m so gonna eat at so many places after all of this is over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the upside, I did get to do much more stuff this work compared to last week, among other things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/blog/&#34;&gt;few posts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;participated in 2 online quiz nights!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a bit more consulting work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some room cleanup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some cleanup/sorting of old files and stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;did the groceries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;paid my dad&amp;rsquo;s credit card bills online (he was actually planning to go to the bank to pay them!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;watching-lately&#34;&gt;Watching lately&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ll retire the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately/&#34;&gt;watching lately tag&lt;/a&gt; and just include my media notes here in the weeknotes. More convenient, and more fine-tuned. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how it works out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watched &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;4 new movies&lt;/a&gt;. Rate has slowed down a lot, but I figure I could get to a 100 for the year still. Princess Mononoke and Logan Lucky were particularly good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also started watching Picard (via Amazon Prime Video), since all the episodes have aired. I&amp;rsquo;m only a couple of episodes in, but I can already tell it has a completely different feel than TNG (or any of the TV series pre-Discovery for that matter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;greatly enjoyed Brooklyn Nine-Nine this week with JK Simmons!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gaming&#34;&gt;Gaming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since everyone&amp;rsquo;s at home, I&amp;rsquo;m getting a lot of multiplayer gaming done. This week our gaming group got into team Starcraft 2 vs AI battles. (We find ladder too stressful!). Since we have discord these days for voice, there is much more coordination in the team battles. And we even have some post-match analysis going on in our discord channel!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the singleplayer side, I managed to finished Megaman 1 in the Legacy Collection! Easily the toughest of the early Megaman games. Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MiWhBlrGiK8&#34;&gt;a video of me struggling to beat the yellow devil/cyclops&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to be able to beat all 6 of the games in the collection. I&amp;rsquo;m old and rusty and don&amp;rsquo;t have the reflexes of 1990s Roy, but at least I have savescumming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I passed on this month&amp;rsquo;s Humble Choice. I kind of wanted Fell Seal, but not that badly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal projects: Minor bug fixes mostly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent site changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I added the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/albums&#34;&gt;albums&lt;/a&gt; section under photos (similar to how FB has albums I guess?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mass formatting cleanup of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/source/quora&#34;&gt;old posts imported from quora&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minor CSS changes in various places&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have anything specific to look forward to in the coming week. Time under the lockdown moves at a different scale, we just take everything one day at a time.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately, Feb 2020 - Not Much Apparently
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/watching-lately/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/watching-lately/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/page/lists/2020/movies/&#34;&gt;2020 Movies&lt;/a&gt; update: 7 movies watched in Feb. Probably the best movie I&amp;rsquo;ve seen this month was &lt;strong&gt;Knives Out&lt;/strong&gt;. (&lt;strong&gt;Jojo Rabbit&lt;/strong&gt; close second.) The goal of 200 movies for the year is getting farther!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for TV, I think most of my watching time was spent rewatching &lt;strong&gt;Rick and Morty&lt;/strong&gt; for quiz purposes lol. Well, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/criminal-minds/&#34;&gt;Criminal Minds&lt;/a&gt; ended, so there&amp;rsquo;s that. Arrowverse has been meh, though I did enjoy &lt;strong&gt;Supergirl&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;s 100th episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hm, I guess I haven&amp;rsquo;t actually watched a lot of stuff in the past month. There&amp;rsquo;s a ton of stuff that I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to watch but haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to: The Expanse, Star Trek Picard, new season of Jack Ryan, Birds of Prey/Harley Quinn, and so on. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if things get better next month maybe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonus, since this entry was kinda short: Here&amp;rsquo;s three movies I started watching but didn&amp;rsquo;t manage to finish:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/strong&gt;. It started off with like 20 minutes of some monkeys shouting at each other and a mysterious black box and I kind of lost interest. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that kind of thing was fine in 1968 when the movie came out and the people whose butts were already in the theatre were like &amp;ldquo;this is strange, but we&amp;rsquo;re already here, so we might as well sit through it&amp;rdquo;, but it&amp;rsquo;s 2020, I kind of need something to hold my internet-broken attention span more easily. It&amp;rsquo;s also one of the most renowned and highly-praised movies of all time, so I&amp;rsquo;m probably losing something here. Will try to resume it sometime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Conjuring&lt;/strong&gt;. We have a horror-movie themed quiz category coming up so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d watch a horror movie. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve voluntarily done so since having been mentally scarred by &lt;strong&gt;The Gate (1987)&lt;/strong&gt; as a kid. I picked The Conjuring, it was first on Netflix&amp;rsquo;s list of horror movies. I sat through the appropriately-creepy intro, then one of my quiz teammates told me he&amp;rsquo;d already unwillingly seen it before and couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep for a week after, and I was like &amp;ldquo;You just gave me an excuse not to watch it.&amp;rdquo; so I stopped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carrie (2013)&lt;/strong&gt;. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to give up on horror movies just yet, so I picked another title from Netflix. I chose this one because it had Hit-Girl. It started out with typical teenage bullying stuff before she manifested her mutant powers and after that I kept thinking they needed to contact Professor Xavier, and couldn&amp;rsquo;t take it seriously after that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately, Jan 2020: Arrow, The Good Place, The Witcher, Kim&#39;s Convenience, The Expanse
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/watching-lately/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/watching-lately/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if I should continue this &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/watching-lately&#34;&gt;watching-lately&lt;/a&gt; series since I already set up a separate page for &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/lists/2020/movies&#34;&gt;listing my 2020 movies watched&lt;/a&gt;. It might have been more consistent to have a list for the 2020 TV shows also? But then again, TV shows are a much different beast, since each show/season is broken into an episode and sometimes you watch them all in one go or sometimes over the span of a few months. So maybe let&amp;rsquo;s keep this going for the while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah, movies. From the list for January, I think the best one was Parasite. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any expectations on what this movie was about yet somehow I still feel like it subverted those expectations anyway. I only saw 15 movies in January, which is below rate if I&amp;rsquo;m targetting 200 for the year. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s one of those NYR things that peters out after a month or so. Too early to tell, and besides, that&amp;rsquo;s not an insurmountable deficit. And 200 isn&amp;rsquo;t a hard target either so let&amp;rsquo;s just see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the realm of TV, this kind of explains why my movie-watching trailed off in the second half of the month, since the regular TV series started coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/01/arrowverse-crisis-on-infinite-earths/&#34;&gt;wrote about the Arrowverse crossover&lt;/a&gt; when the back half aired. This month the last two episodes of Arrow aired. The first one was a backdoor pilot for a new spinoff series, Green Arrow and the Canaries, starring Mia Queen. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what to think about the spinoff or whether I&amp;rsquo;ll even try it out. The whole time travel thing seems so convoluted as a way to bring Mia, E2 Laurel and Dinah together. The second episode was the series finale, basically a retrospective on the entire series. They pulled out all the stops, bringing back supporting characters from all 8 seasons of the show (Except for Malcolm Merlyn, apparently John Barrowman was busy reappearing in a different series), and even surrendering to some long-time fan wishes such as Digg picking up a mysterious green object dropped from space. In spite of all my complaints about the poor writing on this show (and the related ones) through the years, I will admit the finale was pretty good and they stuck the landing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the rest of the Arrowverse, some comments that I&amp;rsquo;m not sure where else I can post, mostly on the post-crisis set up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently in the rebooted universe, there was still a multiverse (since E2 Laurel exists, and doppelgangers showed up in Supergirl), but then the other universes were destroyed in a crisis (probably similar but different than the one we actually watched.) This is totally different from the &amp;ldquo;it became one universe from the very start&amp;rdquo; ending of the original CoIE and took away from the crossover a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was mildly annoyed when Jonn turned out to be able to restore pre-crisis memories. This only makes sense if what he&amp;rsquo;s restoring are part of his own memories, but not events he never knew about, otherwise, where did those pre-crisis memories come from? This annoyance was exacerbated by the GAatC backdoor pilot introducing a &amp;ldquo;device made by Cisco that replicates&amp;rdquo; Jonn&amp;rsquo;s powers so now anyone can restore pre-crisis memories, even from people Jonn has never met like future JJ. And in the Arrow finale, it seemed like everyone at the funeral was aware of the previous universe, did Jonn reset them too?? Seemed wholly unnecessary, but I suppose then we get difficult to explain things like Tommy wondering why E2 Laurel seems different&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fun fact: at Oliver&amp;rsquo;s funeral, Dinah is from before the GAatC episode (since in that episode she says she vanished after the funeral), Mia is from after that episode, and presumably so is E2 Laurel, although this isn&amp;rsquo;t explicitly specified. Timey-wimey!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Good Place&lt;/strong&gt; is also ending this week. As the time this post goes live, I will not have yet watched the season finale, but I did binge the rest of the seasons leading up to it, so maybe I can share some thoughts anyway. The Good Place was a weird series. It&amp;rsquo;s highly acclaimed and covers a lot of interesting topics philosophically, and puts its cast through a lot of interesting situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main issue with TGP is that I don&amp;rsquo;t find it particularly funny. Not like other Schur-influenced shows such as Brooklyn Nine Nine and Parks and Recreation. The characters can be charming sure and ridiculous sure. But their situations are rarely sitcom funny. I think part of it is that the situations they face are always so dire. I mean, their consequences somehow ramped up from eternal torture and damnation to the erasure of earth and all of humanity during the course of the series. Not very light-hearted topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another part of it might be the severe &lt;a href=&#34;https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/Flanderization&#34;&gt;Flanderization&lt;/a&gt; of the most of the characters. Typically this is a process that happens over the lifetime of a show, but with TGP, the characters&amp;rsquo; most annoying traits are highly focused on from the start: Eleanor is an asshole, Jason is an idiot, Tahani is a name-dropping socialite and Chidi is an anxious, undecisive philosopher. Eleanor and Chidi get a bit of character growth through the series (more Eleanor than Chidi), but Jason and Tahani are kind of still the same people by the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I like the show, but more for the questions it raises about how the afterlife could possibly work, rather than for pure comedic value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some friends somehow convinced me to watch &lt;strong&gt;Kim&amp;rsquo;s Convenience&lt;/strong&gt; (it was on NF). I have no regrets. It&amp;rsquo;s a smart, funny show about a Korean immigrant family in Canada. There were 3 seasons to binge on NF and it was very easy to side-watch since it&amp;rsquo;s a sitcom. The best character is the father of the family, a first-generation Korean immigrant who owns a convenience store (hence the show title). My only complaint is that it&amp;rsquo;s challenging my suspension of disbelief that the first generation immigrants still speak in English when among themselves, but as a friend said, it was probably for the sake of avoiding subtitles. Also, I wanted to see what the future Shang-chi actor looked like. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it kind of weird that he&amp;rsquo;s Chinese but he&amp;rsquo;s playing a Korean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A shorter series I saw on Netflix was &lt;strong&gt;The Witcher&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty good, and I much prefer Henry Cavill as Geralt in this show rather than as Superman. (Although he looks nothing like W3 Geralt). I wish I had seen this series before playing the games, as it sets up a lot of the character back stories that I kind of just accepted in the games. Looking forward to future seasons!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I managed to watch the first half of The Expanse season 3. It takes me a whole to catch up with this show because each episode is heavy and a lot of things are always happening, so it always needs my full attention. It&amp;rsquo;s so good, and it&amp;rsquo;s not like those shows where you never get any answers, things actually get resolved at a reasonable pace. One and a half more seasons to catch up on!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: December 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/watching-lately-december-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/watching-lately-december-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Been watching a lot of things this December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally got back on &lt;strong&gt;The Expanse&lt;/strong&gt; after finishing S1 more than a year ago. I only finished S2, but it was already a vast improvement over S1. S1 felt like a lot of meandering around until the characters actually ran into the plot. S2 was stronger, faster-paced, and there&amp;rsquo;s always a lot of things going on in each episode. I really like this series now, looking forward to S3 and S4 when I have the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix-wise, I enjoyed their recently-added &lt;strong&gt;Jeopardy&lt;/strong&gt; series (always a great show to have playing in the background), the new documentary &lt;strong&gt;The Movies That Made Us&lt;/strong&gt; (loved their selection of movies to feature), and the second season of &lt;strong&gt;Final Space&lt;/strong&gt; (a fun sci-fi space romp if ever there was one).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of crazy sci-fi, &lt;strong&gt;Rick and Morty&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve caught up with the recently released S4 as well. This series seems a lot more self-aware now, and a lot more unafraid to make fun of tropes and genre conventions. I liked the heist episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Broadcast-wise, I enjoyed the front half of the Arrowverse&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Crisis of Infinite Earths&lt;/strong&gt; crossover. It had that same feeling as Avengers Endgame where I knew what was likely to happen based on comic book knowledge, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t think they could do it, but they did it! Whenever discussion of this crossover leaked over to the mainstream TV subreddits/forums, there was a lot of criticism of how it looked so low-budget, but I think any expecations of them being able to provide Avengers-quality costumes and effects on a broadcast TV show budget are unrealistic. The Arrowverse shows certainly have a lot of flaws, but this type of multiversal crossover isn&amp;rsquo;t something that could have been achieved without all the setup of the past eight years (and even beyond, considering older shows like Smallville and 90&amp;rsquo;s Flash), and that&amp;rsquo;s something comparable to what the MCU has built, even at a fraction of the budget. I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll have more words for this series and the Arrowverse in general when the back half airs in January.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend also somehow tricked me into watching &lt;strong&gt;Sky High&lt;/strong&gt;, a rather old and campy and totally predictable superhero-type movie. I did finish it so I guess I enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nieces were over this weekend so I finally got to watch &lt;strong&gt;Toy Story 4&lt;/strong&gt;. I was a bit skeptical that they decided to add another installment when I felt the trilogy was already pretty tight. I have to admit I was surprised with the direction this movie took and the ending it gave, which leaves an opening for future movies in the franchise, though they might already be quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;Star Wars: Rise of Skywalker&lt;/strong&gt; before Christmas, here are &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/12/star-wars-rise-of-skywalker-spoilers/&#34;&gt;my thoughts on the film and the trilogy&lt;/a&gt;. WHile I wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely happy with it, I did enjoy watching the film and I recognize that it was a good retelling of Star Wars for new/modern fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also rewatched &lt;strong&gt;The Last Jedi&lt;/strong&gt; for the first time about a week later, it was still pretty good, especially that third act. (Casino subquest still felt superfluous). I did come out a bit more disappointed that ROS didn&amp;rsquo;t follow through with some of the themes of TLJ. I can only assume there are a couple of alternate universes out there where both Rian Johnson&amp;rsquo;s direction and JJ Abrams direction came true for the Skywalker saga ending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Star Wars, I enjoyed the ending of &lt;strong&gt;The Mandalorian&lt;/strong&gt;, although it did have a couple of weaker episodes in the middle that felt like filler (or maybe just there to seed characters for the eventual second season). The final two episodes are pretty good, and we get the payoffs of actualy learning the Mandalorian&amp;rsquo;s history and all. I do find it ridiculous that the Jedi and the Force are still unknown enough that the Mandalorian has never heard of them considering it probably hasn&amp;rsquo;t even been more than 30 years since Palpatine took down the Republic, which had literally an entire council of Jedi as an advisory body to the Senate and featuring prominently in the Clone Wars. Do they not have recorded history? Lol. In any case, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to season 2 whenever it lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for the decade!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: November 2019: Broly, Justice League, Arrowverse, Mandalorian
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-nov-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-nov-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Nothing in the cinema this month (going to the cinema is expensive!). I did watch a couple of animated movies this month:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dragonball Super: Broly. I have some vague recollection of watching the original Broly movie, and I believe this one is much better. DBS Broly is a slightly more nuanced character than just &amp;ldquo;random raging monster&amp;rdquo; from the previous non-canon movie. The animation was okay, you could tell the animators were having fun with some of the battle parts. Also, I watched the English dub, and I just realized Goku&amp;rsquo;s voice is super annoying, so I pity the Americans who had to grow up with that voice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Justice League vs the Fatal Five. I&amp;rsquo;m still a bit behind on the DC animated stuff. I liked this one because I think it handled Jessica Cruz fairly well, and it got me backreading Justice League Odyssey for more Cruz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, since I got a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/new-video-card/&#34;&gt;new video card&lt;/a&gt; and have a second monitor again, side-watching is back on the menu, so I was able to catch up with some of the ongoing series: Modern Family (meh), Simpsons (meh), Rick and Morty (ok so far, only 3 eps in).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caught Season 3 of The Toys That Made Us on Netflix. Not as fun as S2 for me since that one had Transformers, and I only have secondary interest at best in the toylines for S4, but some of the stories here were pretty interesting, like they say that the giant robot from Japanese Spider-Man was the one that inspired sentai robots! What! The TMNT ep was also pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrowverse is still going on (somehow), with their upcoming big-deal Crisis crossover kicking off in mid December. Surprisingly, Arrow itself has been pretty good this season (perhaps because no Felicity? lol), followed by Flash, with Supergirl dead last. I am not fond of Lena&amp;rsquo;s heel turn in Supergirl, I felt like it was a disservice to the character who when introduced was desperate to get out of her brother&amp;rsquo;s shadow. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been watching Batwoman, even though it&amp;rsquo;s part of the crossover, we&amp;rsquo;ll see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to watch the first ep of Mandalorian, but haven&amp;rsquo;t had time yet for the most recent eps. It&amp;rsquo;s not the sort of thing I&amp;rsquo;d side-watch, so I have to dedicate time for it. I better do that before the spoilers catch up with me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next month I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crisis on Infinite Earths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star Wars: Rise of the Skywalker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-nov-2019/broly_hu4d06564a23f2e71ac7d3766ad33b0777_2995425_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: October 2019: Joker, Scorsese, Stuber, Bloodlines, Brotherhood
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-oct-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/watching-lately-oct-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Actually watched something in the cinema this month: &lt;strong&gt;Joker&lt;/strong&gt;. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t originally sure if I wanted to see it, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t hyped for it at all in the months prior. But as the showing date came nearer, there was a lot of buzz around it so I decided to go anyway. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like it lived up to the hype and the warnings about promoting incel stuff, but at least it&amp;rsquo;s one of the higher-grossing DC movies, so maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll have more to come in that vein. MCU movies all have kind of same-y tone and feel, so probably DC can differentiate itself by doing these heavier movies with a different kind of style. My spoiler-free review of this movie is &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/10/1180086308963618816/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching Joker and also reading Scorsese recent comments about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/film/2019/oct/04/martin-scorsese-says-marvel-movies-are-not-cinema&#34;&gt;MCU movies not really being cinema&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to watch one of his movies and decided on &lt;strong&gt;Goodfellas&lt;/strong&gt;. (The only other one I had seen prior to this was &lt;em&gt;Shutter Island&lt;/em&gt;, which for a long while I thought was a Nolan flick.) Goodfellas was pretty good, definitely nothing like an MCU movie. They are obviously different kinds of &amp;ldquo;cinema&amp;rdquo; altogether, with the MCU movies leaning more towards the &amp;ldquo;popcorn&amp;rdquo; side of the spectrum. I did find it a bit hard to take Joe Pesci seriously here since I only really knew him from &lt;em&gt;Home Alone&lt;/em&gt;. I believe this is also the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen Ray Liotta in a film, so now I know who he is. I definitely enjoyed the &amp;ldquo;slice-of-life&amp;rdquo; look into the old-school gangster lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also watched &lt;strong&gt;Stuber&lt;/strong&gt;, mostly because this movie kept being advertised when I was in the US and it reminded me of Deadpool and that taxi driver friend of his. I was only expecting Batista, but Karen Gillan is also here (briefly!), so there&amp;rsquo;s a tiny GotG reunion there. Indian taxi driver dude was cool, the movie was ok, moderately funny, nothing too genre-busting. More popcorn movies for scorsese to snub his nose at, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catching up on my backlog of DC animated films, I decided to watch &lt;strong&gt;Wonder Woman: Bloodlines&lt;/strong&gt;. Plot spoilers, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a gaggle of WW villains (Silver Swan, Doctor Poison, Doctor Cyber, Cheetah, Giganta) plotting to invade Themyscira, I suspect to make them more well-known among the DC animated viewers. Coincidentally, I had also recently read the WW Rebirth story arc where a gaggle of WW villains tried to trick her into revealing the location of Themyscira, so I had a fresh point of comparison. In the comic book arc, everything was masterminded by Veronica Cale, a pharmaceutical CEO who had been created in the early 2000s with the intent of being the Lex Luthor to WW&amp;rsquo;s Superman. In the movie Cale works with WW for a while, and along I was waiting for the reveal that she was behind everything, but that never came. I would guess they have some bigger plans for Veronica Cale down the line in the DC animared film-universe. Otherwise, the movie was ok. Nothing too spectacular, missable, but also good enough to watch. EDIT: I found out after I wrote this that Bloodlines had a mid-credits scene where WW figures out Cale was behind everything all along!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, not much to say right now. The fall shows are back, that means the Arrowverse is in full swing again (except for Legends, they&amp;rsquo;ll be back in January). The &amp;ldquo;science&amp;rdquo; on &lt;strong&gt;Flash&lt;/strong&gt; is still ridiculous. The flash forwards on &lt;strong&gt;Arrow&lt;/strong&gt; are still boring (I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why they want to make a spinoff for Mia Smoak!), &lt;strong&gt;Supergirl&lt;/strong&gt; is also a bit meh. I&amp;rsquo;m really only looking forward to the Crisis crossover this season (and of course, &lt;em&gt;Legends of Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;.) Haven&amp;rsquo;t watched Batwoman yet, maybe I should since she has one of the five Crisis episodes. Also been following some of the regular stuff: The Good Place, Modern Family, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s also a lot of superhero shows still on the backlog, some of which I may never get to watch: Runaways, Cloak and Dagger (cancelled!), Krypton (cancelled!), Legion (finished!), Doom Patrol, Titans S2, etc. Maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a point where there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;too much&lt;/em&gt; content for comic book fans? Lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix: I saw that Jenny Slate has a standup special out and I tried watching it, but eh, not for me, found it very boring and stopped about a third of the way through. I also found myself re-watching the end of &lt;strong&gt;Full Metal Alchemist: Brotherhood&lt;/strong&gt;, mostly because I was envious of a friend who was watching it for the first time. Was surprised to learn the anime is 10 years old as of this year! Still held up well, possibly my favorite anime of all time. The final confrontation and fight scenes were great, although the epilogue episode was a bit anticlimactic and awkward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for this month. Maybe next month we manage to dent the ever-growing backlog? Maybe?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: September 2019: Dark Phoenix, The Ranch
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/watching-lately-sep-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/watching-lately-sep-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I finally got around to watching &lt;strong&gt;X-Men Dark Phoenix&lt;/strong&gt; which I skipped when it came out mainly because (a) poor reviews, and while normally I&amp;rsquo;d have watched it anyway since I have not missed any of the X-Men movies in the cinema, not even the horrendous Wolverine Origins, there was also to consider that (b) I was in the US at the time and was only willing to spend my precious dollars on one expensive American cinema and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/&#34;&gt;Spider-man Far From Home&lt;/a&gt; won out. The movie wasn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; bad really, at least I felt better about it than the aforementioned Wolverine Origins. Here are &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes/2019/09/1171737237135867906/&#34;&gt;some of my nitpicks&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not what would&amp;rsquo;ve been the best ending for the X-Men series which was really one of the pioneers of the superhero movie revolution (alongside Raimi&amp;rsquo;s Spider-Man), but that&amp;rsquo;s what we got. At least it ended with a big fiery bird explosion in the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also watched Part 7 of &lt;strong&gt;The Ranch&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. The Ranch is one of those weird family comedy/drama shows that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally seem to be in my spheres of interest, especially since the show is probably a lot more appealing to conservative/right-wing viewers. (It&amp;rsquo;s often punctuated by country music and the characters regularly criticize Hillary Clinton and mock the idea of climate change.) I will not admit that I got into it mostly because of Elisha Cuthbert. It is a moderately enjoyable show, the kind you don&amp;rsquo;t mind having run in the background while you&amp;rsquo;re doing something else, although it did lose a bit of its comedy punch with the firing/writing off of Danny Masterson (&amp;ldquo;Hyde&amp;rdquo; from the 70s show) last season due to #MeToo issues, and the guy they replaced him with hasn&amp;rsquo;t been super impressive thus far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow month again this time. The lull should pick up in October once the fall US shows start off. And there&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of movies I want to watch too but some combination of laziness and lack of time always puts them off.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: August 2019: Young Justice, The Boys, Fleabag, One Cut of the Dead
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/watching-lately-aug-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/watching-lately-aug-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Hmm, surprisingly I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched too much stuff this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eigasai&#34;&gt;Eigasai&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched a Japanese film at Eigasai in UP Diliman for the first time ever, upon the invite of some friends. We saw &lt;strong&gt;One Cut of the Dead&lt;/strong&gt; a comedy zombie film. It was great and it was hilarious, although you must make sure not to lose patience with the first thirty minutes. I went in blind not knowing anything about it other than &amp;ldquo;Japanese comedy zombie movie&amp;rdquo;, so you should too! Easily one of the funniest movies I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;young-justice&#34;&gt;Young Justice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back half of Young Justice Outsiders finished this week. I&amp;rsquo;ve honestly been a bit whelmed for this half of the season as I feel like they&amp;rsquo;re all over the place and there&amp;rsquo;s too many plot threads going on at once. Still an enjoyable watch especially for DC fans of course. The thing about having such a large cast is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to focus on any one of them too long, but this season was all about Halo, Geoforce and Cyborg so the arc endings pretty much revolved around those three. It feels like so many status quo changes happened in the last episode though, felt a bit crammed. Also, some spoilers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like the Light declaring at the end that their gains were sufficient vs Luthor&amp;rsquo;s original plans seemed ridiculous (i.e. controlling Markovia vs controlling and registering all superhumans). They already had one puppet nation under their control (Queen Bee is right there!) and they&amp;rsquo;re literally planning to go against Darkseid, how does controlling Markovia help? Feels like a very post-facto justification.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I did like that they chose not to complete their Judas Contract re-telling in a similar manner and we get a &amp;ldquo;redeemed&amp;rdquo; Tara to contrast with the &amp;ldquo;fallen&amp;rdquo; Geoforce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fleabag&#34;&gt;Fleabag&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about this Amazon Prime series going in either, only that it was a comedy and it was well-reviewed. I did enjoy watching it, although it&amp;rsquo;s more of a tragic comedy than anything else. Basically about how people deal with absurdly difficult situations in their daily life. The story is well-told, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I get all the hype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-boys&#34;&gt;The Boys&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Amazon Prime series. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read the source material, and I was a bit turned off by the first episode, but I powered through. I knew it would be dark going in, and possibly gratuitous in terms of the sex and violence at some points, so not many surprises there. The plot seems in my head to be &amp;ldquo;What if superheroes were driven by a greedy corporation&amp;rdquo;, which certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t help address my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/capitalism/&#34;&gt;misgivings about capitalism&lt;/a&gt;. The plot also reminds me of Sanderson&amp;rsquo;s book Reckoners, which was also a story about a resistance trying to oppose a superhuman regime led by a Superman-like figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking over the Wikipedia entry for the comic book series, it seems the TV show had some significant divergences, which is understandable, so I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll be seeking out the comic books. The series was enjoyable enough to binge over a few days, although some parts are a bit predictable. I did like the treatment given to Hugh and Annie/Starlight. The cast is pretty good too, I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t recognize Simon Pegg (because it was such a serious role) and Elisabeth Shue (because&amp;hellip;I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen her in anything in a while?). Oh and Gus Fring is also here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I ended up enjoying the season overall, as it tackles a lot of issues I relate with. I will probably be watching Season 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rockos-modern-life-static-cling&#34;&gt;Rocko&amp;rsquo;s Modern Life: Static Cling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix tried to bring Rocko into the modern era, although strangely none of the characters have aged at all. Although they are cartoon characters so I guess that makes sense? The special is about as ridiculous as the old cartoon was, unsurprisingly, although it does try to convey a message about how change is an inevitable part of life. I did like that they had a reference to my favorite episode, R-E-C-Y-C-L-E Recycle~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More next month! Maybe!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: June and July 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/watching-lately-june-and-july-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/watching-lately-june-and-july-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I was travelling for most of the past two months, so this covers both June and July, and I guess I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to watch too much. Maybe? IDK, we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was in the US, I took the opportunity to finish watching &lt;strong&gt;Voltron: Legendary Defender&lt;/strong&gt; which only had two seasons available on PH Netflix. Pretty good adaptation, lots of fun callbacks to the old series. Some annoying filler eps, especially in the middle seasons onwards. I like how they spent the entire series going through the main Voltron villains one by one: first Zarkon, then Lotor, then a little bit of Sendak, then finally Hagar. It got a bit too hocus pocus magicky BS near the finale for me, but overall a pretty good watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we were staying with relatives in the US, it turns out they&amp;rsquo;re really fond of watching Filipino movies. I&amp;rsquo;m not big on Filipino movies, most of them seem either uninspired, formulaic or outright ridiculous. I did enjoy a couple of the ones that I sat through, at least enough to comment on them, coincidentally both starring Eddie Garcia (RIP). The first one was &lt;strong&gt;Rainbow&amp;rsquo;s Sunset&lt;/strong&gt;, which has Eddie Garcia playing a senior citizen ex-politician who comes out as gay and explores the repurcussions to his children and grandchildren. This movie had a strange ending that came out of nowhere though. The second movie was &lt;strong&gt;Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Waiting&lt;/strong&gt; where Garcia portrays an old man who has died and finds himself in a waiting area before he can be sent to heaven, basically purgatory. In this place he finds an old flame of his from his youth, who has secretly been waiting for him all this time, refusing to advance to heaven. The movie explores themes of life and death and love and regret and commitment, but in a context outside of the typical Filipino love team movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a bunch of other Netflix movies watched - these folks didn&amp;rsquo;t have that much to do at home - but the only other one I remember sitting through was &lt;strong&gt;Murder Mystery&lt;/strong&gt; starring Adam Sandler and Jennifer Aniston. Basically a comedic whodunnit, it was entertaining enough to sit through, but nothing too special. I did like the car chase scene at the end though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from watching on Netflix, I also tried out an American cinema and watched &lt;strong&gt;Spider-man Far From Home&lt;/strong&gt; with a friend. I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/07/spider-man-far-from-home/&#34;&gt;separate blog post&lt;/a&gt; for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Murder Mystery might not have been too special, but it did inspire me to watch the copy I had of &lt;strong&gt;Murder on the Orient Express&lt;/strong&gt; when I got back home. It was my first exposure to Hercule Poirot, and I was pleasantly surprised by the star-studded cast. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of movie where you can&amp;rsquo;t watch it twice though; I suppose all whodunits are like that, but now I can&amp;rsquo;t watch the older movie based on this book. There&amp;rsquo;s supposedly a sequel coming out next year, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll watch that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the trip, there was a whole lot of shows to catch up on. The only one I managed to complete was &lt;strong&gt;Jessica Jones S3&lt;/strong&gt;, the final season among the erstwhile Netflix-Marvel shows. I liked this season, mostly because it went way more dark than I expected and had a very &amp;ldquo;Criminal Minds&amp;rdquo;/procedural kind of vibe since her main antagonist here was a serial killer, and one of the themes is how a hero has to play by the rules and can&amp;rsquo;t just do whatever he wants like killing criminals. (This kind of message always resonates with me now because of where the country is.) While I feel like it might have been better to cap the Netflix-Marvel venture with Daredevil&amp;rsquo;s fantastic season 3, this one isn&amp;rsquo;t a bad ending either. I suspect I will do a more detailed look back on these shows soonish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I have a ton of shows to catch up on. Good Omens, Stranger Things, Doom Patrol, Legion, etc to name a few. And I missed out on a few movies though, like Dark Phoenix, which I was tempted to watch in the cinema despite the bad reviews, because I&amp;rsquo;ve never missed any of the prior X-Men movies, not even Wolverine Origins. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll have time to catch up on all of this stuff before the Fall TV season comes in!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: May 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/watching-lately-may-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/watching-lately-may-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The big TV thing of May 2019 was of course, the much maligned finale for &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve written about that separately &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/game-of-thrones/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the US TV series also ended their runs in May. Arrowverse show seasons were littered with poor writing as usual. I rank the seasons in this order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;best is &lt;em&gt;Legends of Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt; season 4. The reason Legends is the best is that they&amp;rsquo;re not afraid to be outrageous. My favorite moment was from before the midseason break, Puppets of Tomorrow!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;second best is &lt;em&gt;Supergirl&lt;/em&gt; season 4. I don&amp;rsquo;t like that Supergirl always felt very preachy about modern-day issues like feminism and diversity and immigration, and this season amped that up a lot, but I still enjoyed it because (a) Lex Luthor was great; and (b) they adapted a couple of my favorite DC Superman storylines, namely Manchester Black and the Elite and Red Son (Red Daughter in this case).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;third best is &lt;em&gt;Flash&lt;/em&gt; season 5. Cicada was a terrible villain and the rules of when and how the dagger works were just screwy, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad Eobard gets to come back in the ending (though I still don&amp;rsquo;t know why he has Wells&amp;rsquo; face)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;last is &lt;em&gt;Arrow&lt;/em&gt; season 7, just poor all-around writing, including an episode where Roy Harper flat out murders two innocents and everyone else on Team Arrow is like &amp;ldquo;Huh, okay, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover this up so the police don&amp;rsquo;t find out&amp;rdquo;, and a poorly explained road to Star City&amp;rsquo;s future. The season finale tellss us that Oliver dies during the upcoming Crisis of Infinite Earths. Arrow had a good run, but a few of the seasons were really week. It didn&amp;rsquo;t get as many seasons as Smallville did, but it has a legacy of its own (and arguably Smallville lasted a couple of seasons too long as well). More on this when Arrow&amp;rsquo;s abbreviated eighth and final season finishes later this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all my complaints, I&amp;rsquo;m still looking forward to this year&amp;rsquo;s Crisis crossover!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of DC TV series, &lt;em&gt;Gotham&lt;/em&gt; also ended its 5-season run, and although the show diverges significantly from the traditional Batman mythos, I still liked it. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t spectacular or anything, but there were some nice portrayals of many Batman characters and events. We never get to see Bruce don the cape and cowl, although it is heavily foreshadowed in the last episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Big Bang Theory also had its series finale, and I liked it. Overall as a series it had its flaws, and at many times promoted smart-shaming and nerd stereotypes, but its a sitcom, so I don&amp;rsquo;t take it too seriously. I think the ending of Sheldon getting his nobel prize (with Amy) and finally acknowledging how difficult he has been as a friend is an appropriate ending for the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my attempt to watch/read more &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/manga/&#34;&gt;manga&lt;/a&gt;/anime again, I started watching &lt;em&gt;Boku no Hero Academia&lt;/em&gt; on Netflix a few months ago, but only got two episodes in. This month I finally binged the rest of the anime and for good measure caught up with the manga as well. This series feels like some cross of One Punch Man (for the superpowers and the modern society) and Naruto (for the kids being supervised by adults), except I&amp;rsquo;d say the depth of the lore so far is not that much, more OPM than Naruto. Still a fairly enjoyable read/watch, since I usually enjoy shonen manga/anime, and it got me thinking that Marvel should make a shonen version of an X-Men comic someday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much movies-wise this month, though I did do a rewatch of &lt;em&gt;Winter Soldier&lt;/em&gt; the other day, mostly because I had watched some videos ranking the MCU movies now that Endgame is done. Winter Soldier was always in my #1 slot, and the rewatch basically affirmed that. I had only meant to watch a little bit before going off to do something else, but the pacing of the movie was so great I just ended up watching it to the end. I think the themes of freedom vs security also really resonate with the liberal in me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for this month! Next month I&amp;rsquo;ll be travelling, so who knows what I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to watch! I&amp;rsquo;ll have access to US Netflix!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: April 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/watching-lately-april-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/watching-lately-april-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve already written extensively about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/more-thoughts-on-avengers-endgame-and-the-mcu/&#34;&gt;Avengers Endgame&lt;/a&gt;, but there are other things I watched this month too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shazam&lt;/strong&gt; came out early this month, and while it was unfortunately sandwiched between MCU blockbusters, it was a fun adventure romp and surprised me in a few ways. I wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/183916511215/shazam-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;short spoiler-free review&lt;/a&gt; over on Tumblr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a rewatch binge of &lt;strong&gt;30 Rock&lt;/strong&gt; that unfortunately started with season 4 due to Amazon Prime&amp;rsquo;s weird way of presenting things. I&amp;rsquo;ve already blown past the series finale and wrapped around to the start and currently at season 2, so close to completion. The series is as great and insane as I remember. It&amp;rsquo;s like a more outrageous version of ensemble comedies like Parks and Recreation, and though I am fonder of PNR, I can see why 30 Rock is the more award-winning show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;The Orville&lt;/strong&gt; finished their second seasons this month. Discovery closed off their time loops neatly and sent the Discovery into an unknown future, meaning they get to start season 3 now no longer bound by Star Trek history and free to forge their own path. The season was ok, I enjoyed the classic Trek references and all the timey-wimey stuff. The Orville had a great season, with the introduction of a new enemy empire and possibly one of the best TV space battles of all time. They ended their season with a timey-wimey episode as well, looks like that&amp;rsquo;s a trend for April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/strong&gt; final season started up in April of course, and its only halfway through. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have a lot more to say about it when the season ends in May.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: March 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/watching-lately-march-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/watching-lately-march-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The big one this month was &lt;strong&gt;Captain Marvel&lt;/strong&gt;. I posted &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/183266384975/captain-marvel-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;the usual spoiler-free review over on Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, but I have some more spoiler-y thoughts over here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I thought the movie was ok, I was underwhelmed by the third act and specifically the lack of any serious threat for Carol to defeat towards the end of the movie. As this &lt;a href=&#34;https://mabeloni-sandwich.tumblr.com/post/183645870983/the-biggest-problem-with-every-single-bad-review&#34;&gt;tumblr post explains&lt;/a&gt; more clearly than I ever could, perhaps the issue is that the narrative is not something targetted towards me as a man, who has not experienced the emotional gaslighting IRL that many women are exposed to. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting way to frame the narrative, and probably explains why some movies (i.e. chick flicks) really don&amp;rsquo;t appeal to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did enjoy most everything else about the movie, especially most of the comic book tie-ins and links to other MCU movies. I appreciated how they re-told the &amp;ldquo;Carol getting her powers from an explosion&amp;rdquo; and Mar-vell still being there. I appreciate the surprise that Annette Benning was Mar-Vell all along. I appreciate their reimagination of the Kree Supreme Intelligence. I appreciate that by the time Avengers Endgame or any potential Captain Marvel 2 rolls around, Monica Rambeau will be old enough to be her own superhero as well. I appreciate all the little things connecting this movie to the first Iron Man, the first Avengers, and even to Infinity War itself. I also appreciated that their depiction of the Kree did not rule out the Agents of SHIELD versions existing! (That being said, I would have appreciated an explanation for why some Kree are blue and some are not!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much else to report. The Arrowverse is limping along. Recent episodes of &lt;strong&gt;Supergirl&lt;/strong&gt; have been great, I loved Jon Cryer as Lex Luthor, and I love how they&amp;rsquo;ve been able to adapt multiple comic book storylines this season such as &lt;em&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s So Funny About Truth, Justice, &amp;amp; the American Way?&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;American Alien&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Red Son&lt;/em&gt;. (Excuse me, red daughter.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In more sci-fi land, &lt;strong&gt;The Orville&lt;/strong&gt; has been fantastic, with their surprise twist to the Isaac storyline culminating in one of the best space battles portrayed on TV. &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; is not as good, but I still like it, as it feels a lot more classic Trek than S1 and the overarching S2 plot is more interesting to me too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next month is looking packed. The big headliners to look forward to are of course &lt;strong&gt;Avengers Endgame&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Shazam&lt;/strong&gt;, and the final season of &lt;strong&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: February 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/watching-lately-february-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/watching-lately-february-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;Alita: Battle Angel&lt;/strong&gt;, with the friend who introduced me to the series in the first place. The movie looked fantastic and the fight scenes were great. Plot was supercondensed, several books&amp;rsquo; worth of story combined into one. Ended in a weird place, kinda? Easily the best western live action anime adaptation by far.&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2019-02-07 14:06:10&#34;&gt;7 Feb 2019 2:06pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&lt;/p&gt;

        









  



&lt;a href=&#34;#18a9e28c111c6e73a78bad7b0dd717a5-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/1093511652643762176-DyzvBZ9W0AAC1JS_hu8c01b3250c12dfdca724a95257de8ea7_116708_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up
After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&#34; title=&#34;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up
After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div  class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;18a9e28c111c6e73a78bad7b0dd717a5-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/1093511652643762176-DyzvBZ9W0AAC1JS.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Watched Alita: Battle Angel earlier today. Pretty good. Fast pace, excellent visuals and fight scenes. They tried to cram a lot of the source material into a two hour movie. I felt like they ended in a weird spot, obviously expecting to be able to do a follow up
After watching I immediately passed by a friend&amp;rsquo;s house to borrow these. Must be more than a decade since I last read them&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;7 Feb 2019 2:06pm&#34;&gt;7 Feb 2019 2:06pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/1093511237898448896/&#34;&gt;View post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;







    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another volume of &amp;ldquo;catching up with older films to improve my geek cred&amp;rdquo;, I watched &lt;strong&gt;The Usual Suspects&lt;/strong&gt; on Netflix. The movie was still really good, despite the internet having spoiled the Keyser Soze twist for me (and countless others) many years ago. I can see why Spacey won an Oscar for his performance here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw &lt;strong&gt;Ralph Breaks The Internet&lt;/strong&gt; with the nieces last weekend. The younger one really enjoyed the scenes with the Disney princesses. Movie was pretty good, despite losing the novelty of the first film. Many tropes were visited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over on the Netflix side, I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying &lt;strong&gt;The Patriot Act with Hasan Minaj&lt;/strong&gt;. Highly informative about a wide range of topics, I thought it would be solely about politics, but there were some surprising discussions on things like, uh, shoes? Conservatives may be annoyed by the liberal bias, but otherwise the show does a good job of breaking down complicated topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also had a few seasons of &lt;strong&gt;Family Guy&lt;/strong&gt; up recently, and it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good series to have running in the background while I&amp;rsquo;m working on other stuff so I managed to watch all of it fairly easily. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s good for my mental health though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Seth MacFarlane shows, I&amp;rsquo;ve caught up with &lt;strong&gt;The Orville&lt;/strong&gt; recently, and this show has been great. It&amp;rsquo;s basically &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; for a newer generation, but with a different (and sometimes more interesting) mythos and history and so on. The show is much more willing to tackle complex ideas relevant to the modern world as well. I hope it does well and goes on for many seasons to come.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: January 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/watching-lately-january-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/watching-lately-january-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bumblebee&lt;/strong&gt; only came out over here in January (thanks to the usual MMFF shenanigans), and I decided to watch it on a whim. Pretty decent soft reboot, read my &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/181926569205/bumblebee-spoiler-free-review-attached-image&#34;&gt;spoiler-free review over on the Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first half of &lt;strong&gt;Young Justice Outsiders&lt;/strong&gt; is out, and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. Focus is back on a smaller group after the larger team in YJ season 2. A few new characters are introduced and I learned about a couple of DC heroes I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with before. Probably still the best animated superhero show to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Netflix side, season 2 of &lt;strong&gt;Punisher&lt;/strong&gt; is out as well. I finished watching it but didn&amp;rsquo;t bother posting a spoiler-free review this time. It was okay, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have much commentary. Not as strikingly good as the first one was, but pretty decent. It feels weird now watching these shows knowing they are likely to end soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Season 2 of &lt;strong&gt;Star Trek Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; has also started! Only two episodes in so far, but still very good. Feels a lot more classic Trek than the previous season, and a much lighter tone, not just because their captain isn&amp;rsquo;t afraid of the light anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Netflix history also says I watched Bird Box, which became a bit viral early this month for some reason, but that was just my niece making my mom watch it with her, even after I warned her she would get scared (she did).&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: December 2018
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/watching-lately-december-2018/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/watching-lately-december-2018/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I very much enjoyed &lt;strong&gt;Elseworlds&lt;/strong&gt;, the Arrowverse crossover this year. I mean sure, a lot of it didn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense, but it was like a love letter to DC fans. I actually consider myself more of a Marvel fan than DC, but I still loved it! I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/181046297550/aquaman-spoiler-free-review-i-came-in-with-low&#34;&gt;a spoiler-free review over on the Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;strong&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/strong&gt; on a couple of &amp;ldquo;Best TV of 2018&amp;rdquo; lists so I decided to catch up with it since it was on Netflix. I was actually two seasons behind. This series is great, and I really enjoy Bob Odenkirk&amp;rsquo;s portrayal, but it might be just a bit overhyped for me. We already know where Jimmy/Saul, Mike, the Salamancas, and Gus Fring end up given &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt;, so that kind of takes away a bit of tension. Still, it&amp;rsquo;s a fine TV show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got caught up with &lt;strong&gt;The Ranch&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a weird show for me to watch given how hillbilly it is, but I find the perspective strangely refreshing. Also, Elisha Cuthbert really helps. I was surprised that they had killed off Danny Masterson&amp;rsquo;s character (oops spoilers), apparently it was a #MeToo thing or such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Into the Spider-Verse&lt;/strong&gt; was great, especially for a fan of the comics. You can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://tumblr.roytang.net/post/181171084805/into-the-spider-verse-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;my spoiler-free review on tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched &lt;strong&gt;Aquaman&lt;/strong&gt; with a friend at UPTC, my first time watching at the theaters there. I had low expectations, but the movie was a surprisingly fun spectacle. You can read &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/181046297550/aquaman-spoiler-free-review-i-came-in-with-low&#34;&gt;my spoiler-free review on tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At home, I watched &lt;strong&gt;Incredibles 2&lt;/strong&gt; with the niece, who has a bad habit of spoiling things for movies she&amp;rsquo;s already seen. To the tune of &amp;ldquo;Oh, did you know &lt;code&gt;Character&lt;/code&gt; is actually &lt;code&gt;Villain&lt;/code&gt;?!?&amp;rdquo;. Still, the movie was nice, exceeded my expectations. It expanded the Incredibles&amp;rsquo; superhero universe and there was even some surprise Bob Odenkirk!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also watched &lt;strong&gt;Solo: A Star Wars Story&lt;/strong&gt; on Christmas eve (since we didn&amp;rsquo;t get a Christmas Star Wars film this year). We didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to finish it before we went to mass though, so I finished the movie myself a couple of days later. I had skipped watching this in the theater given the mediocre ratings, but now that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it, that&amp;rsquo;s a decision I&amp;rsquo;ve come to regret. It&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable movie with a servicable plot, especially given it&amp;rsquo;s basically meant to expound upon a couple of throwaway lines from the original trilogy. The plot even leaves some dangling threads that could have picked up in succeeding movies, had Disney not decided to scrap (at least for now) the Star Wars spinoff movies. The movie compares unfavorably to &lt;em&gt;Rogue One&lt;/em&gt;, which had the far superior heist scheme. In both movies we expected many of the introduced characters to be killed off, but the Rogue One deaths were much better than the Solo ones. Still, it&amp;rsquo;s an okay addition to the Star Wars universe. I read that it also has some tie-ins to the various animated series, which I&amp;rsquo;m not too familiar with. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get into those someday.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: November 2018
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/watching-lately-november-2018/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/watching-lately-november-2018/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, I watched two biopics this month. The first one is &lt;strong&gt;Hidden Figures&lt;/strong&gt;, about three black women who were instrumental during the early days of NASA leading up to the Friendship 7 mission piloted by John Glenn. The movie is fairly interesting if you are even remotely interested in either the challenges faced in black history or math and science or the early days of the space program competition between the USA and Russia. It feels even more appropriate to have watched this since it helps me appreciate the recent Insight mission. (The Oatmeal has &lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/insight&#34;&gt;a fun preview of this event&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second biopic was &lt;strong&gt;Bohemian Rhapsody&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a magnificent film, both for the music and the Freddie Mercury story. I guess it appeals more to those who are familiar with Queen music though. I&amp;rsquo;ve read that the movie isn&amp;rsquo;t super accurate especially with regards to the timeline, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s fine. Both the liberties they take and the music serve to construct a compelling narrative. The movie ends with a ten-minute recreation of the 1985 Live Aid concert and they do a good job of communicating the insane energy at Wembley Stadium back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In less-biographical movies, I also watched &lt;strong&gt;Teen Titans Go To The Movies&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of Teen Titans Go, it&amp;rsquo;s way too silly and it&amp;rsquo;s obviously for kids, I much preferred the previous Teen Titans series. I only got a copy of this movie because my niece said they watched this all the time back home, so now they can watch it when they&amp;rsquo;re over here either. I did enjoy the ridiculous plot and the Stan Lee cameo, but this isn&amp;rsquo;t something I would have watched in the theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In rewatch land, since I finished the Spider-Man PS4 game lately, I also watched &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man 2&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Spider-Man 3&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Amazing Spider-Man&lt;/strong&gt;, they&amp;rsquo;re nice movies to have playing in the background while you&amp;rsquo;re working on other stuff. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/07/movies-spiderman-2/&#34;&gt;Tobey 2&lt;/a&gt; was pretty good and I think it aged well, I&amp;rsquo;d say comparable with Tobey 1 even. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/05/spider-man-3/&#34;&gt;Tobey 3&lt;/a&gt; was trying to do way too much what with Venom and Sandman and Harry-Goblin. Andrew 1 had a lot of potential, but I think this series leaned too much into the dark and mysterious and sinister plot route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV-wise, nothing much other than the usual superhero series, though I&amp;rsquo;m still behind on Gifted and Doctor Who. I caught Trevor Noah&amp;rsquo;s new Netflix special, it was okay, but too exceptionally. Netflix also added a couple of &amp;ldquo;best of&amp;rdquo; seasons of Jeopardy which I thoroughly enjoyed. Watching these makes me think I&amp;rsquo;d never be able to win an episode of Jeopardy, but of course I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s fair to compare myself to some of Jeopardy&amp;rsquo;s all-time champions.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Watching Lately: October 2018
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/october-2018-watching-lately/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 05:02:53 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/october-2018-watching-lately/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Some things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching lately, aside from the usual TV shows I follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s Jack Ryan (on Amazon Prime)&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; surprisingly good, even if I&amp;rsquo;m not too familiar with the Jack Ryan stuff. I only know John Krasinski from &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spoilers for Tom Clancy&amp;rsquo;s Jack Ryan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The story starts with Ryan tracking down Suleiman&amp;rsquo;s network via financials, but they never follow-up on who was financing his group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what was the point of the whole drone pilot side story (including the weird trip to the casino and the night with the couple), although it was admittedly kind of entertaining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daredevil season 3 (on Netflix)&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I enjoyed the season a lot. I posted a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/179331448050/daredevil-season-3-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;spoiler-free review over on the ireadcomicbooks tumblr&lt;/a&gt;. Over here I can post spoilers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler&#34;&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;(Spoilers)&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with Murdock&amp;rsquo;s parentage from the comics, so the Maggie reveal came as a surprise to me. A+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sad that there was no Bullseye namedrop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ending kind of flubbed it a bit, could have used an explanation of at what point Matt decided not to kill Fisk. It&amp;rsquo;s not clear if it was something he decided on the spot or if the compromise was part of a plan he devised after interrogating Manning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venom&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; I initially wasn&amp;rsquo;t planning on watching this given the terrible early reviews, but eventually I was like, hey I watched &lt;em&gt;X-Men Apocalypse&lt;/em&gt; so might as well watch this too. It turned out not so bad (low expectations helped), although I find the movie&amp;rsquo;s enhancements to the symbiote abilities a bit disconcerting. &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/179008685600/venom-spoiler-free-review&#34;&gt;Read my spoiler-free review here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Batman Ninja &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/post/179485492410/i-found-out-batman-ninja-is-on-netflix-so-i&#34;&gt;I found out this was on Netflix and went ahead and watched it&lt;/a&gt;. The animations and character designs are nice, but the plot is just ridiculous lol. Feels like someone wrote a Batman fanfic.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>