<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>androidquestions on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/androidquestions/</link>
      <description>Recent content in androidquestions on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 20:04:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/androidquestions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/4bh3wa/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 20:04:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/4bh3wa/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;h4 id=&#34;posted-on-randroidquestions-problems-with-asus-memopad-7httpsredditcomrandroidquestionscomments4bh3waproblems_with_asus_memopad_7&#34;&gt;Posted on r/AndroidQuestions: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/AndroidQuestions/comments/4bh3wa/problems_with_asus_memopad_7/&#34;&gt;Problems with ASUS Memopad 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my mom has been using an ASUS Memopad 7 for a while now, and she&amp;rsquo;s been having some trouble with it lately. Namely, many of the apps are now basically unusable and almost always crash with &amp;ldquo;Unfortunately, [app] has stopped&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried checking it before but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any obvious problems (like lack of disk space, etc). I also tried installing an app to check the system logs (I believe it was named CatLog) but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the past couple of days, the problem became significantly worse. The tablet would always pop an alert &amp;ldquo;Unfortunately, Contacts has stopped&amp;rdquo;, and after you dismiss it with [OK], the alert pops up again, repeat ad infinitum. The tablet is practically unusable now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Complicating things is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to get the thing to even boot. If I restart it, it loads into a black screen with the Asus logo and a spinning loading icon and stays there forever. Image for reference: &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/NBhvZ2T.jpg&#34;&gt;http://i.imgur.com/NBhvZ2T.jpg&lt;/a&gt;. My mom says she can get it to boot sometimes but only after restarting several times (I don&amp;rsquo;t have the patience for it, I&amp;rsquo;ve never gotten it to boot)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve already managed to back up her relevant data, so I suggested that I do a factory reset. So I hold Power and Volume Up during startup and boot into the following menu: &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/Anb5Kjl.jpg&#34;&gt;http://i.imgur.com/Anb5Kjl.jpg&lt;/a&gt; There&amp;rsquo;s an error message there, IDK if it&amp;rsquo;s relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the Droidboot Menu, I choose &amp;ldquo;Recovery&amp;rdquo; and it reboots again. This time it boots into a screen with a dead Android mascot and the text &amp;ldquo;No command&amp;rdquo;. Here&amp;rsquo;s a shitty cameraphone image for reference: &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/QgOvHkm.jpg&#34;&gt;http://i.imgur.com/QgOvHkm.jpg&lt;/a&gt; At this point, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to proceed. The Volume buttons are unresponsive. Tapping Power does nothing. If I leave it in this state for a while, it proceeds to try to boot and gets stuck again at the loading icon I showed in the first image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any advice as to how I can get this tablet back into a usable state?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/04/szbq4/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 13:14:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/04/szbq4/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;h4 id=&#34;posted-on-randroidquestions-android-noob-here-i-just-got-an-lg-c660-and-have-a-questionhttpsredditcomrandroidquestionscommentsszbq4android_noob_here_i_just_got_an_lg_c660_and_have&#34;&gt;Posted on r/AndroidQuestions: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/AndroidQuestions/comments/szbq4/android_noob_here_i_just_got_an_lg_c660_and_have/&#34;&gt;Android noob here; I just got an LG C660 and have a question&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The phone is from my brother, though I&amp;rsquo;ve done a reset to clear his data from the phone. It&amp;rsquo;s an LG Optimus Pro c660 with Cyanogen something installed (it&amp;rsquo;s like a custom OS build right?) it says it&amp;rsquo;s android 2.3 somewhere&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My question is: I tried downloading some apps like Google Goggles and Instagram, but the Play store tells me those apps are not compatible with the device. Is this sort of thing a restriction of the phone, or the particular OS version I have?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>