<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Legacy Blog Posts on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/legacy-blog-posts/</link>
      <description>Recent content in Legacy Blog Posts on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2003 04:22:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/legacy-blog-posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Moved to Fateback
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/11/moved-to-fateback/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2003 04:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/11/moved-to-fateback/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Things are flaky. Have setup this blogger thing to publish to the fateback account (roytang.sinfree.net), seems to be working fine now. Ressurrected one of the older page layouts and added the pandaren brewmaster! Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ll also probably most of the website stuff from topcities to fateback, seeing as how topcities has gotten crappy lately with the FTP problem. That is all, back to work&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>14-AUG-2003: Quarter-Life Crisis
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/08/14-aug-2003-quarter-life-crisis/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2003 01:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/08/14-aug-2003-quarter-life-crisis/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well, not exactly. But I am now 25, in any case. Looking back, there are many things I might have regretted, but my life philosphy tells me that there can be no regrets. The past is past, and the future is yet to come. Somehow, I&amp;rsquo;m only a few steps closer towards achieving my lifetime goals, but my gut tells me to keep on dreaming. Such is the folly of a dreamer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering, my lifetime goals include becoming an accomplished indie game developer, and world domination. There are more, but these are the ones that are most constant. Yes, I&amp;rsquo;m serious about the world domination part!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I finally got some free time. Work&amp;rsquo;s been a bitch lately, but I had to call in sick today due to an unfortunate (or fortunate?) case of LBM. Filipinos in the audience know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. Truth be told I would&amp;rsquo;ve taken the slightest excuse to get off work. It&amp;rsquo;s better to be absent today since the workload is rather light while we&amp;rsquo;re waiting for the UAT results, rather than being absent when we have to cram for deadlines. Gee, I wonder if my officemates are reading this. ^_^&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>27-JUL-2003: I have made a terrible mistake
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/07/27-jul-2003-i-have-made-a-terrible-mistake/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2003 01:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/07/27-jul-2003-i-have-made-a-terrible-mistake/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I installed Civilization III, and told myself, &amp;ldquo;Gee, I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll try it out for an hour or so.&amp;rdquo; I didn&amp;rsquo;t stop for six hours. So much for getting anything done over the weekend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luckily (or not), my being awake those six hours of early morning allowed me to catch some late-breaking news. Apparently, disgruntled young officers of the not-so-prestigious Armed Forces of the Philippines had taken control of some building in Makati, laying bombs and stuff around and with snipers on the roof and all. Not sure, what&amp;rsquo;s going on, but hey, at least it&amp;rsquo;s never boring in good old RP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There seem to be quite a number of broken links around here. I&amp;rsquo;ll get around to fixing them soon. Maybe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curses, I ate up my quota of email bandwidth from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.softhome.net&#34;&gt;Softhome&lt;/a&gt; again. Now I have to wait &amp;lsquo;til August before I can check that address again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently, this website is now named &amp;ldquo;roywantsmeat&amp;rdquo;, after my battle.net account. If I ever get a domain name, that&amp;rsquo;s what I would use. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.roywantsmeat.com&#34;&gt;roywantsmeat.com&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>23-JUL-2003: Wow, free time!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/07/23-jul-2003-wow-free-time/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2003 01:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/07/23-jul-2003-wow-free-time/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free time&amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s something I haven&amp;rsquo;t had in a while. Work is tough right now, as we&amp;rsquo;ve got a big deadline coming up in August. I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting in 10-12-hour days on a regular basis over the past couple of weeks or so, so I barely have any time to do anything. (Except for a few quick games of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.battle.net/war3/ladder/w3xp-player-profile.aspx?Gateway=Lordaeron&amp;amp;PlayerName=roywantsmeat&#34;&gt;The Frozen Throne&lt;/a&gt; (yay!) before going to bed of course.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Of course, the other reason I haven&amp;rsquo;t updated this thing in a fairly long while is that my PC broke down! And since it was past the automatic replacement period, I had to wait for three weeks while PC Express ordered replacement parts. I was irritated at PC Express for most of those three weeks, as being without computer leaves me without a healthy outlet for my stress from work. I&amp;rsquo;m not bad about the PC having problems per se, I&amp;rsquo;m fairly sure it&amp;rsquo;s currently impossible to make 100% defect-free electronics. What I&amp;rsquo;m particularly pissed at was the poor customer service. Their phone lines are almost always busy, their testing of components was not done properly (it was only after they replace the mobo and the power supply that they found out that it was a faulty hard drive that caused the problem, forcing me to have to wait another three weeks for a replacement drive&amp;hellip; but I just went out and bought a new one anyway&amp;hellip; ) and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to get to them because of their office hours, and&amp;hellip; I could go on and on. I guess the distinct disadvantage of buying from cheaper stores is that the customer service is poorer. Or maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just unlucky. In any case, my next PC will be an Intel one, this time I&amp;rsquo;ll probably buy one of those pre-assembled &amp;ldquo;Package&amp;rdquo; PCs from a mall outlet, just to have a basis of comparison.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New mailing list! &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/rpg-skies/?yguid=108755291&#34;&gt;RPG-Skies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am tired, more later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>13-JUN-2003: No Title
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/06/13-jun-2003-no-title/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2003 01:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/06/13-jun-2003-no-title/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday, I got a very rare treat (?). I was invited (under false pretenses I might add) to a seminar trying to sell me to the concept of network markets. It was by a group of people called &amp;ldquo;Network 21&amp;rdquo; who supposedly have a corporate partner in Amway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I have nothing against these people, I&amp;rsquo;m sure they&amp;rsquo;re enjoying themselves looking for sucke-I mean clients, and convincing them to buy Amway toothpaste and shampoo and vitamins and god-knows-what. I wish them well. What I&amp;rsquo;m particularly annoyed at is the guy who invited me there, a guy from my university &lt;em&gt;who I don&amp;rsquo;t even know&lt;/em&gt;, supposedly to talk about a &amp;ldquo;career opportunity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello!!! I&amp;rsquo;m an engineer, why the hell would I want to sell toothpaste!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh no,&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; he says, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;That was my mistake at first. I thought they were going to tell me to sell door-to-door. All you have to do is refer people to our products.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Excrement!&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; I wanted to shout in his face, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You get paid if you convince people to buy your products? I think that&amp;rsquo;s why it&amp;rsquo;s called selling!&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Here, why don&amp;rsquo;t you take this tape before you decide?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;, he goes on. &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;After all, as an engineer, you can&amp;rsquo;t make a decision without information!&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah right, and let you waste another hour-and-a-half of my life? (In addition to the two hours I had to listen to the talk that is.) &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not for me,&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; I tell him, not wanting to be rude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why not?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; he persists, &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;How can you know if you don&amp;rsquo;t listen to the tape?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; I wanted to smack him around a bit right there and then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hello! There&amp;rsquo;s a part of my brain that goes screaming ‘Nooooo!!!!&amp;rsquo; if I don&amp;rsquo;t wanna do something, that&amp;rsquo;s how I know! If I was the type of person who enjoys gathering people and convincing them to buy expensive toothpaste, then that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;d be doing.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; Grrr. I left Megamall quite riled up after that. I had lost two hours, possibly of sleep, and I still had work the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re lucky I didn&amp;rsquo;t have homicidal tendencies and a gun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yesterday was the anniversary of Philippines Independence. On June 12 1898, Emilio Aguinaldo first raised the Philippine flag at his home in Malolos, Cavite, officially declaring independence from Spain. At that time the Republic of the Philippines, the first such government in Asia, was born. And today is a legal holiday ^_^&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Random linkage: Click &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.randomhouse.com/doubleday/davinci/main.html&#34;&gt;here &lt;/a&gt;if you enjoy being tortured by puzzles. I&amp;rsquo;m currently at the second gate. It has annoying BGM though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got a pleasant surprise yesterday. Former members of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/Final-Fantasy-Forum&#34;&gt;FFF&lt;/a&gt;, disgusted by the tyrannical ways of a mad dictator banded together to form a new mailing list, inconveniently named the &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.yahoo.com/AntiFFF&#34;&gt;AntiFFF&lt;/a&gt;. (Inconvenient because, well, the group would be stuck with that name forever, always living under the shadow of needing to be better than the FFF was. Well, maybe that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing in some ways.) Anyway, they&amp;rsquo;re a fine bunch of guys, the same people who came together at the FFF&amp;rsquo;s peak.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Recruit
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/04/the-recruit/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2003 01:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/04/the-recruit/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Good plot twists you could see from a mile away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we had arrived at the theater too late to catch the start of the last showing of &lt;em&gt;Gangs of New York&lt;/em&gt;, so we had to settle with the second choice. &lt;em&gt;The Recruit&lt;/em&gt; didn&amp;rsquo;t get as much critical acclaim as &lt;em&gt;Gangs&lt;/em&gt;, but what the heck, Al Pacino in a spy thriller? How could I lose?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is simple enough. Colin Farell plays James Clayton, a young man just out of MIT, recruited by CIA agent William Burke (Pacino). Clayton is obsessed with finding out what happened to his father, who was lost in an accident some fifteen or so years ago. Pacino taunts him by dropping the occasional hint about his father&amp;rsquo;s fate, and Clayton throws away the promising career he would have had in Engineering to join the CIA. The third entry to this little affair is Leila, Clayton&amp;rsquo;s batchmate at the Farm, a chick who may or may not be a double agent, but definitely has the hots for him. The three of them expectedly get involved a complicated plot involving double agents, unofficial operatives and the standard amount of secret agent sex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best parts of the movie involve the CIA training. We get a glimpse into the kind of psychological warfare business they teach the recruits at the training centre affectionately called &amp;ldquo;The Farm.&amp;rdquo; Here Al Pacino does what he does, drilling his principles into his students: &amp;ldquo;Trust no one.&amp;quot;; &amp;ldquo;Nothing is what is seems.&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Everything is a test.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weakest part has to be the character of James Clayton himself. The character of Leila puts it best: Why the hell does James feel like doing anything he can to please Burke? James never has any real motivation for following Burke like he was the Messiah. Aside from that mysterious star on the CIA wall at Langley (which may or may not be related to his father), there is nothing stopping James from just calling it quits and heading home. Hell, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have wanted to go through that training, secret agent or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall: Enjoyable enough, despite the predictability of the overall plot. Ending is a bit disappointing, but only a bit, as it leaves an important plot point hanging. I hope we see these characters again sometime&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>23 Jan 2003: Working Joe
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/01/23-jan-2003-working-joe/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2003 01:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/01/23-jan-2003-working-joe/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;How&amp;rsquo;s work you ask? It&amp;rsquo;s going pretty well actually. Everything&amp;rsquo;s still easy-peasy for me as I&amp;rsquo;m undergoing some training and stuff. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit worried about what happens after the training though, from the looks of it people put in a lot of overtime here. :( The best thing about the job is that I&amp;rsquo;m learning a lot of stuff. In two weeks I learned SQL, PL/SQL and Delphi. Starting tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be training on Oracle Developer. The work itself looks easy enough — nothing I can&amp;rsquo;t handle. Since most of the coding is done using high-level RAD Tools, I should be fine. On a side note, it&amp;rsquo;s a weird feeling actually having access to money. It&amp;rsquo;s like everything looks different because there&amp;rsquo;s always the possibility of buying stuff. On another side note, I&amp;rsquo;m paying a lot in taxes. My annual salary is like a couple of ten thousand above the minimum for my bracket. It&amp;rsquo;s irritating.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>19 Jan 2003: I need more screws!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/01/19-jan-2003-i-need-more-screws/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2003 01:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2003/01/19-jan-2003-i-need-more-screws/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Yes I do. I bought a new hard drive yesterday, a 40Gb 5400RPM Seagate. It took me a while to get the system up and running again after my plugging it in. First I had to wrestle with my PC&amp;rsquo;s small case, trying to figure out where to place the thing. Then, given how old my PC is, it predictably failed to detect the whole capacity of the drive, insisting it was only 8 Gb. I went down to Seagate&amp;rsquo;s website and did some Dynamic Drive Overlay thing that let me overcome the BIOS limitations. But the DDO installed a Bootloader that would often hang the PC upon booting! I had to send in an email to Seagate tech support and wait til the next morning before I could get everything fine and dandy. Now I have a nice healthy 36 Gb of space&amp;hellip; almost 20 times as much capacity as the old drive. Sw33t. The only problem now is that the hard drive didn&amp;rsquo;t come with any screws — so I just placed it on top of the old one. And I had to move my floppy so it&amp;rsquo;s lopsided.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>31 Dec 2002: Happy New Yearwhatever
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/12/31-dec-2002-happy-new-year-whatever/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2002 01:30:59 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/12/31-dec-2002-happy-new-year-whatever/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well, trying to make this a weekly format thing obviously fizzled out.  What with me starting work on Friday, I just give up. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep this site  up and put up stuff of interest whenever I feel like it, just like before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s new? As I said, work starts Friday. I went to an orientation for the job last Friday and it seems like a tough and demanding job, but I rise to the challenge in any case. What I&amp;rsquo;m worried about is that the hour and a half commute might sap my energy too much. Maybe I should carry chcocolates to work. 😛&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We got a PS2&amp;hellip; in fact most of my free time these past couple of weeks have been sapped by two huge beasts named Suikoden III and Fallout 2. Actually, I haven&amp;rsquo;t touched Fallout 2 in a week or so because of Suiko3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the New Year I resolve to give up on resolutions, they never work anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Square Enix
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/11/square-enix/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2002 01:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/11/square-enix/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a couple of days to think about it, so I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my thoughts on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the facts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enix and Square are merging. Square stock will be bought out for Enix stock at 0.81 Square per 1 Enix. The Square president will be head of Square Enix, the Enix board remains in place, they&amp;rsquo;ll move into Enix headquarters in Shibuya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All currently announced releases will go on as scheduled. A FF/DW merger may be in the offing, but no definite plans, and probably only as a side release. No personnel will be let go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squaresoft is: Final Fantasy, Chrono, Xeno, SaGa, Mana and assorted other titles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enix is: Dragon Quest/Warrior, Soul Blazer series, 7th Saga, Actraiser, Tri-Ace (Star Ocean, Valkyrie Profile), and a lot of stuff that never made it outside Japan. Enix also has a deal with GameArts on co-developing the Grandia series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sony, one of Square&amp;rsquo;s major stockholders, will have it&amp;rsquo;s shares diluted to 8% of Square/Enix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Namco, another game company also has some stock in both Square and Enix, and is the publisher of Xenogears&amp;rsquo; prequel, Xenosaga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Square also has a US publishing deal with EA, set to expire at the end of the year. (This last tidbit may not mean anything&amp;hellip; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Square also recently acquired the Quest team (responsible for Tactics Ogre series) and the rights to the Ogre Battle franchise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, what can we see?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, Enix will be in control, at least at first. Although the Square guy will be Pres, the Pres can always be overridden by the board, and the Enix board will remain in place until they hold a stockholder election thingy, whatever that&amp;rsquo;s called. You might think this is bad &amp;ldquo;Oh no, Enix is in control, that means FF is doomed!&amp;rdquo; Of course not. They&amp;rsquo;re not stupid. The fact is that Enix being in control of the company&amp;rsquo;s vision and direction makes more sense in light of Square and Enix&amp;rsquo;s overlapping powers. Square develops most of it&amp;rsquo;s products in-house, while Enix publishes a lot of products from other developers like Tri-Ace and Gamearts. Therefore, it makes more sense for Enix to be in control of administrative/business stuff, leaving Square staff to focus on what they do best — game development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what does this mean to us as gamers? In the immediate future, nothing really. All the currently announced projects are unaffected: we&amp;rsquo;ll still get FFXI, FFXII, FF:Crystal Chronicle, FFTA, Unlimited Saga, etc. The only thing I&amp;rsquo;ve found people to be questioning on message boards is whether FF1-2 (which still doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a definite announcement of a US release) will have an English version. This is a possible concern, as Enix didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother to release an English version of their own DW4. Who knows, maybe we&amp;rsquo;ll get a collection of DW4 and FF1-2? 😛 (Addendum: FF1-2 has been announced for US release.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after the immediate future, what then? Square Enix will almost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;certainly continue the Final Fantasy and Dragon Warrior lines. The future for the Chrono series also seems bright, as the original Chrono Trigger was a collaboration between Square and some of Enix&amp;rsquo;s creative staff. Stuff from Tri-Ace and GameArts will probably go on as before, seeing as these development studios are mostly independent of Enix anyway. And if we&amp;rsquo;re lucky, we&amp;rsquo;ll get another Soul Blazer trilogy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I worry about are Square&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;secondary&amp;rdquo; RPG series: SaGa and Mana. Now that Square Enix will have two &amp;ldquo;big&amp;rdquo; series under it&amp;rsquo;s roof, will they still have time to develop these still-young series?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although not really related to the merger, things also look bright for fans of FFTactics. Aside from the upcoming FFTA, Square&amp;rsquo;s acquisition of Quest and the Ogre Battle franchise means we&amp;rsquo;ll probably see more FFT/TacticsOgre type games coming from them. Combined with the unique gameplay perspective of Tri-Ace, who knows what interesting games will come out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking around on message boards after the news came out, and it seems a lot of people are worried about how Enix might screw up Final Fantasy, or Square screw up Dragon Warrior or anything like that. To this, again I say: They&amp;rsquo;re not stupid. FF and DW, although they have the same roots, are completely different series now, and their different styles again reflect how Square and Enix can complement each other&amp;rsquo;s strengths. Well, I guess DW will benefit the most, as it&amp;rsquo;s sorely lacking in FFs specialty: really good graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another concern that has been raised has been the possibility of a monopoly in RPG games. With this merger, a lot of the big RPG names are now under one roof. Won&amp;rsquo;t the lesser competition cause more lackluster RPGs to be put out? Maybe, but I doubt it. Square Enix still can&amp;rsquo;t afford to let up on the quality, as there are still a good number of other good up-and-coming series out there: Suikoden (Konami), Wild Arms (Sony?), Tales (Namco) and Breath of Fire (Capcom) all still have quite some following and good potential. In fact the above titles will probably slug it out for the Number 2 Console RPG Developer slot&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, the opinions I&amp;rsquo;ve read on the web are mixed: some are good, some are bad. My own personal take is that it&amp;rsquo;s good; mergers generally mean two companies wanting to capitalize on each other&amp;rsquo;s strengths, not share each other&amp;rsquo;s weaknesses. Let&amp;rsquo;s just wait and see, and hope for the best. 😛&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Bourne Identity, Goldmember, Signs
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/09/bourne-identity-goldmember-signs/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2002 01:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/09/bourne-identity-goldmember-signs/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;h5 id=&#34;the-bourne-identity&#34;&gt;The Bourne Identity&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new action hero is Bourne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a bit anxious to see this movie, as I had thoroughly enjoyed the book of the same name a long time ago, and I was hoping the movie would give me the same satisfaction. The Bourne Identity stars Matt Damon as rogue CIA agent/amnesiac Jason Bourne. In his quest to uncover his own identity, Jason travels all around Europe pursued by the CIA&amp;rsquo;s agents and dragging along an innocent gypsy girl who just happened to be his best shot for a ride to Paris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I haven&amp;rsquo;t read the book in ages, so I can&amp;rsquo;t say for sure how faithfully the story translates to the movie (although as I recall there was a lot more traipsing across Europe — I may be wrong though) so I have to judge the movie on its own merits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On its own merits, the movie falls short of my expectations. Mainly because I was expecting some fast-paced action, but most of the time it&amp;rsquo;s just Jason and Marie running and hiding from the CIA. It&amp;rsquo;s more of an action/thriller than a straight action flick — Jason spends a lot of time trying to uncover the conspiracy behind his pursuers. However, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to pull off either the thriller part or the action part very well. The thriller part doesn&amp;rsquo;t fly because we know what&amp;rsquo;s going on well before Jason does — the movie shows us what&amp;rsquo;s going on at CIA HQ, how his boss travels to Paris to mete him, et cetera. The action part doesn&amp;rsquo;t fly because the thriller parts get in the way. DOn&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, there are some cool action stunts here — Jason riding a free-falling body down the center of a spiral stairway to gun down one of the CIA agents — but they are few and far between. Also, the director seems to enjoy some sort of shaky, jarring camera work — not really a problem but occasionally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall: Good enough, I suppose. The director is no Robert Ludlum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but the story is told well enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;austin-powers-in-goldmember&#34;&gt;Austin Powers in Goldmember&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do I make you horny baby?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Austin Powers movie? Well I knew what to expect — more of the same. I got what I expected, but that isn&amp;rsquo;t really a bad thing. As usual with Austin Powers movies, some parts tend to drag on, while some parts are simply &amp;ldquo;laugh-out-loud&amp;rdquo; funny. This time, Dr. Evil enlists the aid of 70&amp;rsquo;s criminal mastermind Goldmember in a nefarious plot to extort money from the world leaders (as if you didn&amp;rsquo;t know.) Austin himself gets some help (aside from the requisite Powers girl Beyonce Knowles as Foxy Cleopatra) — from none other than his dear old dad, legendary secret agent Nigel Powers (played by Michael Caine) This one has a bit more story than the first two — you get to find out more about Austin and Dr. Evil&amp;rsquo;s history, and some strange plot twists ensue. Expect the return of such characters as MiniMe, Fat Bastard and Dr. Evil&amp;rsquo;s wayward son Scott. Also a new character on the side of British Intelligence is played by Wonder Years star Fred Savage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funniest parts are mostly during the opening sequence and towards the end. Expect more gross, insensitive and blatantly offensive humor, more naked bodies, more Fat Bastard crapping, more silhouette jokes, more making fun of MiniMe, hollywood cameos, movie spoofs and the like. This time however, things don&amp;rsquo;t stay the same. Some changes in the status quo happen towards the end and this will obviously not be the last Austin Powers movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall: I liked the second one better, but this one&amp;rsquo;s good too. As is the case with Austin Powers movies, it&amp;rsquo;s not for the easily offended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;signs&#34;&gt;Signs&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crop circles? This isn&amp;rsquo;t the X-files is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the three movies I saw this week, &amp;ldquo;Signs&amp;rdquo; was the one I was looking forward to the least. The trailer didn&amp;rsquo;t really give me a good impression — looked like some cheap X-Files ripoff with Mel Gibson as Fox Mulder. As it usually happens, turns out I was wrong about the whole thing &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Signs&amp;rdquo; is one helluva good movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get it out first: &amp;ldquo;Signs&amp;rdquo; is about an alien invasion. We&amp;rsquo;re talking spaceships and green men. However, unlike movies like Independence Day which tell the story of how the world comes together to defeat an alien menace, &amp;ldquo;Signs&amp;rdquo; tells the story of how a family comes together to survive fear, paranoia and green men knocking on their door. All of the Independence Day stuff happens, but never at the forefront of the story — the giant spaceships are there, somewhere in the background, shown on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story is about a farmer and his family in a small rural town. Overnight, mysterious crop circles appear in his fields. Later on, more signs appear — prowlers around their house, strange radio noises. As a former minister, Mel Gibson faces what he fears the most — the idea that there is no God, and that he and his family are left to fend for themselves against whatever threat is there lurking in the shadows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie is extremely well-written, with all the characters playing their parts well, and all the elements coming together towards the end to make a whole lot of sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall: Go see it. Now. Unless you&amp;rsquo;re like my kid brother who would probably get nightmares just thinking about an alien invasion.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>rant.07.12.2002: personal websites
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/07/rant-07-12-2002-personal-websites/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2002 01:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/07/rant-07-12-2002-personal-websites/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I originally wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to have a rant today, but while surfing the web I thought about one of the things I like about it: personal websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s right, personal pages. Some people might argue that personal pages are like the dregs of the internet. And they&amp;rsquo;re probably right. Given that any random joe-on-the-street can get on Geocities and build his own website, (like &lt;a href=&#34;http://royness.vze.com&#34;&gt;royness.vze.com&lt;/a&gt; for instance) we&amp;rsquo;re certainly bound to see all sorts of stuff (and accordingly, all sorts of crap) on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, that&amp;rsquo;s the thing: &amp;ldquo;All sorts of stuff.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much the same way Forrest Gump describes a box of choc&amp;rsquo;lates: You never know what you&amp;rsquo;re going to get. And occasionally, you get some good stuff. And for people like me, who are obsessed with the trivial, stuff is good. The same way that people browse through bargain bins looking for good deals, I like to browse through personal pages looking for something read-worthy (or even better, download-worthy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with most personal pages on the ‘net however, is that they are crap. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong there are a lot of good ones out there. (Try &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.toastyfrog.com&#34; target=&#34;_top&#34;&gt;Toastyfrog&lt;/a&gt; or maybe &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.seanbaby.com&#34;&gt;Seanbaby&lt;/a&gt;) But the fact is that a whole lot of websites are done by people just learning to do HTML or trying it out. Not that being a newbie is a bad thing; the bad thing is when you make a website just for the sake of having one, just so you can say you know how. Websites built in this manner typically end up the sort that&amp;rsquo;s filled with all sorts of tricks like animated GIFs, scrolling marquees or a ton of Javascript. Lots of flash but not much content really.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips for people who want to make their own website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have something to offer.&lt;/strong&gt; Many people build personal sites with the attitude of &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s my website, what do you care what I put on it, anyway!&amp;rdquo; Yeah well, if you don&amp;rsquo;t care what people think about it, why are you putting it up on the net? Leave it on your computer if that&amp;rsquo;s your attitude. Websites are put up for public consumption, so there has to be something there for people to consume. If you&amp;rsquo;re going to put up a website, make sure you have something to offer the public other than an &amp;ldquo;under construction&amp;rdquo; page. Otherwise, you&amp;rsquo;re just wasting people&amp;rsquo;s bandwidths aren&amp;rsquo;t ya? When you&amp;rsquo;re just starting out with the idea of &amp;ldquo;I want to have my own webpage&amp;rdquo;, it might be hard to think of what your webpage can offer the world. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be anything big or extra popular, you can start small. I originally put this website up just to host some fanfiction. (And then I put up more and more stuff&amp;hellip; ) You can put up your writings, reviews of things you like, links to interesting places, info about yourself, announcements about events you&amp;rsquo;re involved with, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be original.&lt;/strong&gt; This is hard to do in today&amp;rsquo;s web. Most of the things people put up on their websites can undoubtedly be found elsewhere on the web. What can you do to set yourself apart from the crowd? Use more original content, or if you&amp;rsquo;re lacking in that department, look for different ways to present your content. An example would be when I was first learning HTML, I tried to make a Rurouni Kenshin web site. At first I was going to put in info about the characters, story etc. But after looking around a bit, I saw that there were already many websites around for this popular anime series. So instead, I put up info about the fighting styles and techniques of the RK characters, something that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find at that time. (Don&amp;rsquo;t try looking for this so-called RK site of mine, I took it down a long time ago. I still have the files and may revive it someday though.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know what contrast is.&lt;/strong&gt; Look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geocities.com/i_am_obsessive/&#34;&gt;this site&lt;/a&gt; and you&amp;rsquo;ll know what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t try to do everything at once&lt;/strong&gt; There are people who make websites with the idea that their site will be &amp;ldquo;next big thing&amp;rdquo; of the internet. It won&amp;rsquo;t, trust me. Not anytime soon at least. Although there are a lot of crap sites, there are also a lot of good sites, and the best ones have developed from small sites with a limited following to being read by millions. You, with your meager resources and staff of (probably) one can&amp;rsquo;t hope to achieve that overnight. Start small, focus on what your site can provide to your viewers right now instead of trying to be a really big thing. See that site I linked to above? The front page says &amp;ldquo;Your number one sorce for your anime needs.&amp;rdquo; Not only is that misspelled, but it&amp;rsquo;s so far from the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know how to spell and know how to write proper English (or whatever language is your choice).&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ll cite the above link as an example again. How do you expect your readers to take your website seriously if you can&amp;rsquo;t even spell &amp;ldquo;sorce&amp;rdquo; properly? Go back to school first, then make a website. Additionally, you may want to leave the l33t sp33k for mIRC, unless that&amp;rsquo;s what your audience expects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write for your audience&lt;/strong&gt; That way, they can come back later. Don&amp;rsquo;t do things like writing in l33t when your viewers will probably hate it. For a personal site, your initial audience is probably going to be mostly you, and maybe some friends and family. When you want to start attracting more people to your site, you may also consider writing for people who think like you. This are the best kind of viewers, as they will like what they see and will usually come back for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know how to take criticism&lt;/strong&gt; Actually, this is advice for being on the internet in general. Remember that the internet is a public medium, and anything you offer on the internet can be criticized by anyone. A lot of stupidity on the internet comes from people not knowing how to take criticism. Study the criticism and correct your mistakes. Accordingly, I want to apologize in advance to the owner of the site I&amp;rsquo;ve been using as a bad example — I have nothing against you, yours was just the website I had open at the time of this writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have links.&lt;/strong&gt; Links are always good because if the rest of the website is bad, at least there&amp;rsquo;s a chance of finding something better to read. If your website could have only one thing, have links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dang, this turned out longer than I thought it would. I have a lot more to say on this topic, I&amp;rsquo;ll say them next week. Later!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Cheap Rushing
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/07/cheap-rushing/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2002 01:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/07/cheap-rushing/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;[Posted on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cgi.gamefaqs.com/boards&#34;&gt;GameFAQs message board&lt;/a&gt; in response to endless whining about rushes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last I heard, Battle.net had a competitive ladder system, meaning if you want to go up on the ladder, you have to win. If rushing is the means for that win, you should go for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this mean? If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be rushed, don&amp;rsquo;t play on Battle.net, because on Battle.net people play primarily to win and secondarily for fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get a bunch of friends together and hook up a LAN and play amongst yourselves, where you can have your own rules like &amp;ldquo;No rushing!&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Announce before attacking!&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;No building fifty million towers!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you insist on playing on Battle.net, don&amp;rsquo;t play 3v3 or 4v4; it&amp;rsquo;s in these formats that rushing is a very viable strategy. I find that 2v2 is best, as there is little human interaction in 1v1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think that rushing makes the game &amp;ldquo;no fun&amp;rdquo;, then maybe you should be playing another game. Warcraft III is a &lt;em&gt;strategy game&lt;/em&gt;, the &amp;ldquo;fun&amp;rdquo; is in finding strategies to beat your opponent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rushing is a strategy, just like any other, and it can be defeated just like any other strategy (otherwise 100% of people would be rushing, which isn&amp;rsquo;t true)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you always get beaten by rushes? Maybe you should look at your build order to see how you could improve speed-wise or get more defense early on. Look at replays to see how people beat off rushes. Scout ahead to know they are coming. Practice against two or more computer opponents to test yourself. The key to improving is not to whine about things that are &amp;ldquo;cheap&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;no fun&amp;rdquo; but to study ways to beat those things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a note, I am not a rusher. Not often anyways. I will rush every so often, but only for variation. I attack when I can, creep when I can, and tech as fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The One Where I Run My Mouth, As Usual
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/06/the-one-where-i-run-my-mouth-as-usual/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2002 16:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/06/the-one-where-i-run-my-mouth-as-usual/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Well I finally decided to start a full-blown web journal. I used to keep one some years ago — I think it greatly helped me develop my english skills. Or not. Anyway, I tend to run my mouth off for paragraphs at a time anyway, and so many things run through my head at any given time it probably makes sense to put down at least some of it on paper (or in a computer at least.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I decided to make over this site because nothing much of anything else has been happening around here lately. With Mon in town, the two of us and David have been spending every other day at David&amp;rsquo;s wonderful airconditioned room playing Capcom vs SNK 2 and Final Fantasy X. Mon mentioned that modded PS2&amp;rsquo;s are now able to play copied PS1 discs, so it&amp;rsquo;s probably a good time to buy one now. Assuming of course, that I have cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still for the most part unemployed. Oh who am I kidding, I&amp;rsquo;m still a bum. Or &amp;ldquo;employment challenged.&amp;rdquo; Whatever. At least Mon and David aren&amp;rsquo;t working either. =P I really need a job — seeing as how I really want both a new computer and a PS2. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;m already seriously considering a call center job, however dead-end it may seem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another time.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Someday we&#39;ll all look back and laugh.
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/04/someday-well-all-look-back-and-laugh/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2002 05:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/04/someday-well-all-look-back-and-laugh/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So the ECE board exams are now over. Six months (okay three) of hard work and preparation (well alright, occasionally glancing at my books) and what do we get? A bunch of questions chosen seemingly at random. The Math and Electronics parts were good enough actually, and I felt pretty confident there. The second day was bad. The Communications exam might as well have been a random set of questions about cookie dough and displacer beasts. Me, Marc and Dennis went through at least a hundred questions in various topics an hour and a half before the exam but not one of the stuff we reviewed came out. Instead we&amp;rsquo;re bombarded with questions about obscure standards and various laws. *Sigh*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just sour-graping because I didn&amp;rsquo;t make the &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;top ten [link broken]&lt;/a&gt;. Then again I was expecting at least Dennis to make it in, but no such luck. Are there any other UP studes in the top ten? I don&amp;rsquo;t know, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I care anymore. Oh well, that&amp;rsquo;s the breaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished &lt;a href=&#34;http://alexandria.rpgclassics.com/game.php?game=166&#34;&gt;Tales of Phantasia&lt;/a&gt; yesterday, finally. I must&amp;rsquo;ve been playing it for about half a year before I managed to finish it. Emulators are really bad for your attention span — I&amp;rsquo;ve got a Seiken Densetsu game near the end but I haven&amp;rsquo;t touched it for maybe a year now. Anyway, I went and kicked Dhaos butt, even though I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to complete the better subquests, complete Arche&amp;rsquo;s spells or even get Gremlin and Shadow. Maybe another time. Or if Namco decides to be nice and release it for the PSX. Oh yeah, I put up the ending save state &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;here [link broken]&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully one of these days I can finish the Ranma RPG, SD3 and DQ5, not necessarily in that order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing Hoshigami lately. When I first bought it and tried it out I thought it was a horrible game. It&amp;rsquo;s quite hard, and you will easily die if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what you&amp;rsquo;re doing. Now I realize the reason I was having such a hard time was because I was trying to play it like FF Tactics or Tactics Ogre. Instead, the RAP gauge encourages an entirely different way of thinking. You have to learn how to conserve your RAP, to know how to use the turn sequence properly, when to shoot and when not to shoot, and when to attempt a session. Granted, knowing all this stuff doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the game that much easier — but I find myself enjoying it once I familiarized myself with the different tactics. Sadly, very few people will be able to appreciate this game. I&amp;rsquo;m in Chapter 2 and I&amp;rsquo;ve already burned 20 hours of game time and probably a lot more in real-time — I tend to lose battles often. =P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following web sites are graciously hosting some of my fiction, so be nice and visit them: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.icybrian.com&#34;&gt;Icy Brian&amp;rsquo;s RPG Page&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Laura&amp;rsquo;s Sailor Moon Shrine [link broken]&lt;/a&gt; (although why a SM shrine would have FF fanfiction is beyond me. =)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week we saw The Count of Monte Cristo. Two more weeks before Spiderman, and a full month before the next Star Wars movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, and have you ever wondered where you could get &lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;RPG Books online [link broken]&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Beavers and Ducks
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/04/beavers-and-ducks/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2002 04:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/04/beavers-and-ducks/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;April Fools day today. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thegia.com/&#34;&gt;Gaming Intelligence Agency&lt;/a&gt; says they&amp;rsquo;re shutting down, but it&amp;rsquo;s likely one of their famous AFD pranks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Board exams coming up next week, Tuesday and Wednesday. I need to borrow a calculator — the one I have isn&amp;rsquo;t on their list. I really should study more but for some reason I&amp;rsquo;m really confident. promises to study more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I applied for a job at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asti.dost.gov.ph/&#34;&gt;ASTI&lt;/a&gt;. Sure it&amp;rsquo;s a government place, but I know a lot of guys there and it looks like fun. Interviewed last week, hope they call back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so another Holy Week went by uneventfully. Another 8-hour 7th heaven marathon. Another trip to St. Vincent&amp;rsquo;s for confession and way of the cross. So the wheel turns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local matinee idol Rico Yan dead at 25 last Good Friday. I&amp;rsquo;d tell you more about it, but the TV stations have already covered the story to death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw the Star Wars trailer! Lots of fighting, and the Jedis look like they&amp;rsquo;re gonna get their butts whupped. Lousy title though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Movies seen lately: Bandits and Ice Age. Oh, and for the umpteenth time, Austin Powers: TSWSM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Random Links of the day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phoenixgenesis.com/&#34;&gt;Phoenix Genesis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Rant -- Where Have All the Flatmen Gone?
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/03/rant-where-have-all-the-flatmen-gone/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2002 15:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/03/rant-where-have-all-the-flatmen-gone/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;(Originally available on the now-defunct NFT Zu website)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2018 Edit: I found this in my WordPress drafts folder, not sure why it wasn&amp;rsquo;t published when I first imported it. It&amp;rsquo;s true it was on my old site, but I can not find a reliable indicator of what date it was published. So I will publish it with an arbitrarily chosen date of March 1, 2002.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officially, this rant should be available upon the re-opening of the NFT Zu webpage, version 4.something. As much as I&amp;rsquo;d like to babble on about anime or fanfiction, several of my associates here at the Zu know a lot more about those than I do. So I&amp;rsquo;ll stick to something where I can claim some sort of specialized knowledge: video games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing Legend of Mana. It&amp;rsquo;s a little-known Square game for the PSX, the fourth installment in the Seiken Densetsu series of games. It&amp;rsquo;s a quirky little game, but what will strike you most about the game is the amazing graphics. No, I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about FFVIII-style FMVs or such. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about the detailed hand-drawn animations. The characters are portrayed by detailed sprites, the backgrounds are colorful,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hand-drawn landscapes, nothing like the mundane realism of FMV-based games. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I&amp;rsquo;m not knocking FMV. I certainly appreciate a great CG movie in a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these days practically every game and its mother has FMV, and frankly, I tend to grow tired of it. What&amp;rsquo;s wrong with good ol&amp;rsquo; 2d animation? We see a lot of games pushing the envelope as far as 3d CG FMVs are concerned, but where are the games pushing the envelope of 2d animation? As Legend of Mana and games like Parappa the Rapper show, there are certainly games and stories which are much better told in 2d animation than the mundane 3d videos of today. And for all their technical sophistication, 3d engines are still far more limited than what hand-drawn animation could show us, visions far closer to the artist&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where are all the 2d RPGs? Sadly, outside of Square and Capcom, no one seems to be capable of thinking for themselves and differentiating themselves from the pack. In this case the console RPG scene suffers from a common problem: lack of innovation. Aside from a couple of industry leaders, few companies can afford to &amp;ldquo;try something different&amp;rdquo; when they have sales to make. It&amp;rsquo;s far easier to do what everybody else is doing than to try out something which may or may not sell. The 2d RPG seems to be going the way of the handheld, as practically all 2d RPGS these days are being announced for GBA only, with the PS2, XBOX and GC all geared towards powerful 3d apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, all of this might be chalked up to the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m an old-school gamer of sorts, and you could argue that &amp;ldquo;3d is the wave of the future!&amp;rdquo; But if you look at Legend of Mana, and its younger SNES brother Secret of Mana, you can&amp;rsquo;t help but see how 2d animation has improved by leaps and bounds over the years, albeit unnoticed compared to the attention 3d animation has been getting. Five years ago, all these 3d games were getting noticed because they were bringing us something new, a greater sense of realism than what 2d animation could bring. Back then 3d WAS the wave of the future. Today, it IS the future, and 3d games are the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;norm, and 2d animation offers us something different, something fresh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What am I saying? I want to see more 2d games, RPGs specifically. I want to see more Saga games, more Mana games, more Breath of Fire. I want to see new sprite-based RPGs. I want to see more fantasy worlds that look fantastic, more anime cut-scenes. Is it all too much to ask?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Thinking about getting a GBA before a PS2&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>12 Feb 2002
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/02/12-feb-2002/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2002 04:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/02/12-feb-2002/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Website updates: New text files in features section!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ack&amp;hellip; haven&amp;rsquo;t been doing much lately. My time has been consumed by the evil monster that is Sierra&amp;rsquo;s Betrayal at Krondor. It&amp;rsquo;s an RPG based on Raymond Feist&amp;rsquo;s Riftwar series of books. Haven&amp;rsquo;t read the books myself, but the game is well done, and is still enjoyable despite its age (I think it was released in &amp;lsquo;92 or such). The game was released by Sierra as freeware to promote the sequel, and it can be downloaded at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.happypuppy.com&#34;&gt;happypuppy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing, is trying to catch up on my board exam review, and I&amp;rsquo;m fairly behind schedule. There&amp;rsquo;s around a month and a half left before the exam, but so far I&amp;rsquo;ve only reviewed most of the electronics topics. (The reviews are in 3 parts: electronics, communications and mathematics.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing was working on my own RPG. The Palefire thing was great, but it seems no one in the group has time to do it anymore. While I still want to do Palefire, it&amp;rsquo;ll have to go to the back burner while everyone gets their acts together. Since I don&amp;rsquo;t have a new comp yet, no RPG programming of any sorts going to take place soon. Right now it&amp;rsquo;s mostly design, world-building, and setting the rules into place. I don&amp;rsquo;t even have a very solid plot yet, but I want to thresh out the world before focusing on the plot. Good luck to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things I&amp;rsquo;m not doing: Learning more Japanese (which I promised myself I would do); Studying more programming (same); Writing fiction. I&amp;rsquo;d update the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fanfiction.net/s/566295/1/&#34;&gt;Mecis story&lt;/a&gt; but I found the first part of it severely lacking. When I have time, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably rewrite it altogether.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>12 Jan 2002
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/12-jan-2002/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2002 04:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/12-jan-2002/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Updates: Added Square NES ROMs, Programming section, updated links. Went back to text-based navigation. While image navigation is nice, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to update and slow-loading. Added links to funtrivia trivia quizzes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a slow couple of days really. Some board reviewing, sporadic Japanese learning. Finished DW7 a couple of nights ago — finally! Currently playing on PS: Ehrgeiz Quest Mode! Kinda tough, tho. For the NES, a discussion on FFFade me download a whole bunch of Square NES ROMs! Also been playing a lot of Megaman! (finished 1 and 2 already, on my way with 3) Job fair next week atUP Eng&amp;rsquo;g. Also came down with a bad cold.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>07 Jan 2002
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/07-jan-2002/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2002 04:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/07-jan-2002/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;For some reason, I keep wanting to update this site. I&amp;rsquo;m actually doing this more often than studying for the board, studying game development, studying Japanese or writing anything else. I wonder why? Anyway, I added a humor page and a special &amp;ldquo;Who Am I?&amp;rdquo; page. Check &amp;lsquo;em out. Also the Anime ROMs site should be fully operational by now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I went and saw Lord of the Rings last Friday. As everyone expected, it was an excellent movie, and the theater was jam packed. We had to use all our mighty skills to get seats. Even my first brother, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t normally watch movies, enjoyed it and said it was great. My only complaint is that the movie is too long! I mean, I know Tolkien created a huge world and all, but did they really have to show the party traveling through numerous forests, mountains and snow without advancing the plot? That&amp;rsquo;s one of the reasons I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to finish the book, I felt the plot dragged along in favor of the lengthy descriptions. The movie does this too, but to a lesser extent.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>06 Jan 2002
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/06-jan-2002/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2002 04:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/06-jan-2002/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Hopefully, the site is now Netscape-safe&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uploaded more stuff today: I put up an ECE Board Exam Reviewer — it&amp;rsquo;s a software that helps me review for the upcoming ECE boards. It&amp;rsquo;s in the files section. I really should add that to the list of resolutions: WILL STUDY FOR BOARD EXAM!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also decided to renovate and re-use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geocities.com/zroytang&#34;&gt;geocities site&lt;/a&gt; so I put up an Anime ROMs site there. I wanted to put up the Anime ROMs before, but I was worried about what Topcities might do, since Ihaven&amp;rsquo;t heard anything about what they do to copyright violations on member sites. They might delete all my files or something. At Geocities, the worst case scenario is that I lose the ROM files!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sore wa watashi no homupeiju desu&amp;hellip; See? I&amp;rsquo;m working on it!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>04 Jan 2002
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/04-jan-2002/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2002 04:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/04-jan-2002/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Well&amp;hellip; you learn something new everyday! And today I learned that Netscape is very strict about HTML coding. Unclosed tags will screw up even the simplest of web pages! Spent quite some time rewriting the HTML to be Netscape friendly&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>03 Jan 2002
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/03-jan-2002/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2002 04:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/03-jan-2002/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Changed the layout even more! Added a start page containing the menu only, so that visitors wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to listen to me ranting all the time. Uploaded some stuff, since my COMPUTER IS PROBABLY GOING TO DIE SOON! It&amp;rsquo;s on its last legs&amp;hellip; I can feel it. Over the next couple of days I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be uploading stuff that I don&amp;rsquo;t have backed up elsewhere. For now the only new upload is a bunch of high school pics. See the Files section for more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards my resolutions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went on over to FF.net to see if the last fic (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fanfiction.net/s/447644/1/&#34;&gt;Nobody Wants to Live Forever&lt;/a&gt;) got any reviews. Whee! Got some positive ones. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to write more soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I downloaded a free Win32 C++ compiler+GUI. It&amp;rsquo;s Dev-C++, available at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bloodshed.com&#34;&gt;Bloodshed Software&lt;/a&gt;. Also, I downloaded some of the old Win32 programming lessons from ReliSoft. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably redo all the work since my previous trials had been lost in an HD formatting a while back. The sad thing is that the DirectX SDKs are unbelievably huge, 100+ Megs, even the older DX5.0, so I probably won&amp;rsquo;t be doing any DX programming &amp;lsquo;til I get a new computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning Japanese? Well&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m working on it I guess. I checked out some lessons at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.japanese-online.com&#34;&gt;Japanese-Online.com&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through them before, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really follow through so I forgot. =)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything else? Okay:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out another Square SNES game has been gifted with a translation patch! The game is Live-a-Live, a strange sort of RPG. I tried it out a bit, but now I&amp;rsquo;m stuck. =( It&amp;rsquo;s really weird. Hulk Hogan appears in it! Except that he&amp;rsquo;s named MaxBomber or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More new links:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.htmlgoodies.com&#34;&gt;HTML Goodies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;has a lot of info for would-be webmasters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.happyhacker.org&#34;&gt;Happy Hacker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;teaches you some neat hacking tricks, all of &amp;lsquo;em legal!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>01 Jan 2002
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/01-jan-2002/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2002 04:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2002/01/01-jan-2002/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolutions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write more. Fanfiction, original works, whatnot. I need to shape up my writing skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devote more time to game development. My interest sort of waned after a certain group project I was on fizzled out, but I&amp;rsquo;m gonna get back on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>