<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Self-Improvement on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/self-improvement/</link>
      <description>Recent content in Self-Improvement on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/self-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Social Media, High School Reunion Anxiety, and Envy
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/social-media-hsra-envy/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/09/social-media-hsra-envy/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The following article made the rounds recently: &lt;a href=&#34;https://joshcsimmons.com/2019/09/10/i-quit-social-media-for-a-year-and-nothing-magical-happened/&#34;&gt;I Quit Social Media for a Year and Nothing Magical Happened&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting enough not only on its own, but also for the discussion generated around any piece about qutting social media. I will admit I&amp;rsquo;ve been flirting with the idea myself, but that&amp;rsquo;s a topic for another day. Of particular interest to me at the moment is this comment about the article on &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=20934675&#34;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest issue with social media is less that it&amp;rsquo;s distracting (IMO not necessarily an unhealthy thing) but that it has, for me, more than anything else seemed to make all aspects of my life a competition with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Instagram, you&amp;rsquo;re competing with others on who has the happiest life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On LinkedIn, you&amp;rsquo;re competing with others on who has the steepest career trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even on Twitter, perhaps more acutely in certain jobs or industries, it seems like you&amp;rsquo;re competing with other in gaining professional influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It creates a lot of anxiety that stems from a feeling like you&amp;rsquo;re constantly on the verge of falling behind others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plenty of scholars/thinkers/philosophers have said something to the effect of focusing on just being a better version of you. Social media enables the exact opposite i.e. forcing you to constantly evaluate how you compare to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminds me of my previous post &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/comparison-is-the-thief-of-joy/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Comparison is the Thief of Joy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. This kind of mindset is applicable to real life as well as social media, though I do agree that social media tends to exacerbate the problem. If you are the type of person who has this mindset, then yes it&amp;rsquo;s probably a good idea to reduce/control/filter your social media usage accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I generally don&amp;rsquo;t suffer from this problem, mainly because I outgrew comparing myself to other people a long time ago, but also because I tend to aggressively filter my social media channels so that I&amp;rsquo;m only seeing content from people that are of interest to me. I wonder sometimes about those people who whine that Twitter is so toxic or some such complaint. Don&amp;rsquo;t they know they control the kind of people who appear in their feed? Why are they following toxic people? (I understand that this may be more of a problem that is difficult to control once you get to higher follower counts, but hey that&amp;rsquo;s the price you pay I guess.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat related: Our 25th high school reunion is coming up next year, and this early our batch has a thread about High School Reunion Anxity (HSRA). Here are some excellent words from a batchmate that I thought were good to share (removing some stuff specific to this person and the batch, since the post was to a private group. Will happily cite the original poster if she requests it):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re not alone. It&amp;rsquo;s common to feel a lot of anxiety about attending a high school reunion. Our 25th at that. Kasi ohmaygad ganyan na ba tayong katanda?!
&amp;hellip;
The second common barrier to attending is HSRA. Mostly because you might feel your life didn&amp;rsquo;t turn out the way you wanted and that other batchmates have done so much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So 2a - your life didn&amp;rsquo;t turn out the way you wanted. You know what? My life didn&amp;rsquo;t turn out the way I wanted. &amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m willing to bet nobody&amp;rsquo;s life turned out exactly the way they planned. And that&amp;rsquo;s OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2b - other batchmates have done better. OK so please for your own mental and emotional health do NOT compare other people&amp;rsquo;s external stuff (visible on Facebook, Instagram, etc) to your internal stuff. That&amp;rsquo;s illogical and bad science. Also will drive you crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Ghurka and the map
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/the-ghurka-and-the-map/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/the-ghurka-and-the-map/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Ghurka rifleman escaped from a Japanese prison in south Burma and walked six hundred miles alone through the jungles to freedom. The journey took him five months, but he never asked the way and he never lost the way. For one thing he could not speak Burmese and for another he regarded all Burmese as traitors. He used a map and when he reached India he showed it to the Intelligence officers, who wanted to know all about his odyssey. Marked in pencil were all the turns he had taken, all the roads and trail forks he has passed, all the rivers he had crossed. It had served him well, that map. The Intelligence officers did not find it so useful. It was a street map of London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;https://stevenpressfield.com/2018/11/a-map-of-the-unknown-world/&#34;&gt;Steven Pressfiekd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s some kind of message here about confidence, faith, optimism, persistence, and so on. But I found that last line hilarious.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Learning from failure
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/learning-from-failure/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/learning-from-failure/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success is not final, failure is not fatal: it is the courage to continue that counts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Winston Churchill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already typed the above quote into the post, then realized I had already &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/dealing-with-failure/&#34;&gt;used it before&lt;/a&gt;. Whatever, just goes to show, I&amp;rsquo;m no stranger to failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reminded of this quote because recently I prepared a demo for a project that didn&amp;rsquo;t push through. At first I was annoyed at the wasted effort, but I realized that I had wisely taken the demo project as an opportunity to learn/sharpen some skills. Specifically, I used it to study the Django Rest Framework (for the backend API), and a little bit of VueJS (for the frontend), which means that even if the project isn&amp;rsquo;t going anywhere, I was at least able to hone some technical skills. The advantage of always looking to try new things is that your worst case scenario still leads to some self-improvement.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Ship of Theseus
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/the-ship-of-theseus/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/the-ship-of-theseus/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I found myself poring over the Wikipedia entry for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ship_of_Theseus&#34;&gt;the Ship of Theseus&lt;/a&gt; the other day. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a thought experiment along the lines of &amp;ldquo;if a given ship&amp;rsquo;s parts are replaced at every port it visits, and eventually none of the parts are from the original ship, is it still the same ship?&amp;rdquo; The thought experiment questions the meaning of identity of a whole composed of many individual parts, such as a ship, or even a human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about this while I was &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/04/digging-through-time/&#34;&gt;digging through time&lt;/a&gt; (read: old posts) the other day. In all these years I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging, I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve fundamentally changed, I still feel like I&amp;rsquo;m the same person I was back then writing those posts, and yet at the same time I know I&amp;rsquo;ve grown and adapted in many different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People change over time of course, but in terms of identity I tend to think of it as something like a codebase that undergoes version control. At any given point of time there is a version of you, slightly different from who you were yesterday or who you will be tomorrow, but still fundamentally the same. As time passes, the person you are adapts to the path and circumstances you travel, resulting in the next versions. All of this reminds me of this quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No man ever steps in the same river twice, for it&amp;rsquo;s not the same river and he&amp;rsquo;s not the same man.&amp;rdquo; - Heraclitus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Performance Art and Picking Up New Hobbies
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/performance-art-and-picking-up-new-hobbies/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/performance-art-and-picking-up-new-hobbies/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not much for public performance. But sometimes I think about doing some stuff that involves some level of public performance. My examples for this post are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;game streaming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;public speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;standup comedy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public speaking and standup comedy are basically the same, and might be interesting to do (standup seems more fun). Like many people, I used to have a mild fear of speaking in front of a bunch of people/strangers, but as I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten older and cared less about what other people think, this kind of faded away. But the main issue with these two items is that they require a lot of prep, and that&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;m generally bad at (chalk it up to lack of discipline etc). I generally tend to prefer to &amp;ldquo;wing it&amp;rdquo;, even back in the college days, not that I&amp;rsquo;m particularly good at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game streaming seems like it could be good. Not much prep needed aside from some general familiarity with the game I&amp;rsquo;m playing. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;ve already set up &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitch.tv/twitchyroy&#34;&gt;a twitch channel&lt;/a&gt; before and did a few test broadcasts. My main problem with game streaming is that there&amp;rsquo;s a need to be talking all the time - avoiding dead air. And it can feel weird doing that with nobody around. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s more of a beginning streamer problem? If there were people in the twitch chat it would probably be easier. Or if there was someone else in the room with me while I&amp;rsquo;m streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend also sometimes suggests I make a webcomic, that also seems like a viable option. My problem with that one is the prep again. You need to be able to come up with material on a regular basis, and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I can do that. As I say to my friend, I&amp;rsquo;m a generally witty guy, but my wit is more of &amp;ldquo;in the moment&amp;rdquo; insted of something I can summon on command. But then again, maybe the fact that I&amp;rsquo;m now able to make daily blog posts means a regular (weekly?) webcomic would now be viable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An issue I have with trying to pick up new hobbies is the climb you have as a beginner, where everything you try sucks at first. I really dislike that initial learning period. But as Jake the Dog says &amp;ldquo;Dude, sucking at something is the first step towards being sort of good at something.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Anxiety
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/anxiety/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/anxiety/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A friend was worried and jittery about an event he&amp;rsquo;d been preparing for a while now. He just wanted it to be over and things to not go wrong. I told him not to worry, that he&amp;rsquo;s already done the best preparation he could and that no matter what things will surely work out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to fall into the trap of anxiety, overthinking things that might go wrong, or things that might not go according to plan, and so on. And you know what? It&amp;rsquo;s fine. Not everything goes according to plan. Unexpected things happen. People understand. We laugh about it and move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fall into this trap often. I try to tell myself that worry does nothing. If there&amp;rsquo;s something you can do to make things better, then do it. Otherwise, why worry?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can&amp;rsquo;t get past your overhtinking, I find that it sometimes helps to think about the worst-case scenario. You&amp;rsquo;re already worrying about problematic things happening, so why not go all the way right? Often you&amp;rsquo;ll find the worst-case scenario is something survivable, and it&amp;rsquo;s so ridiculously out-of-left-field that the rest of the worries just fade away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is too short for worrying.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Things that bring me joy
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/things-that-bring-me-joy/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/things-that-bring-me-joy/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;After yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/konmari/&#34;&gt;post about Konmari&lt;/a&gt;, I thought about some stuff that brings me joy, some of them despite my better judgment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/finding-time-to-learn-new-things/&#34;&gt;learning new things&lt;/a&gt;. This is a bit uncommon I guess, so it makes me a bit of a nerd. Luckily nerds are cool now, or something. Okay, this is super positive I guess.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being argumentative. I love a good debate. However, since the 2016 election season, I&amp;rsquo;ve cut back on this significantly. It&amp;rsquo;s only fun if the debaters aren&amp;rsquo;t fanatics and understand that the goal of debate isn&amp;rsquo;t victory, but progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;following at least one person on social media who I disagree with. Like, there&amp;rsquo;s this guy I follow on Twitter, an American expat living in the PH, and he&amp;rsquo;s so pro-Trump and pro-guns and so on. He is anti-Duterte though, which I find kind of fascinating. I also have a token pro-Duterte friend I still have unmuted on Facebook. It helps to get an occasional glimpse of what &amp;ldquo;the other side&amp;rdquo; is thinking. Maybe not too much though, and definitely avoid anyone too toxic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;complaining about things. There are people who say you should avoid being so negative, but sometimes complaining about things can be cathartic. Also, if we didn&amp;rsquo;t voice disapproval about things going on in society, how would politicians know how to pivot? Complaining can sometimes be unreasonable, but all progress depends on the unreasonable man&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;diving into the comment section. Oh boy. Someone posted an article and warned not to go into the comments because they&amp;rsquo;re toxic, and I kind of take that as an invitation. It&amp;rsquo;s not advisable to do this all the time (you might get cancer), but sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll dive in just to see how ridiculous humans are&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually, some of these might be worth blog posts on their own. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll stop here.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Konmari
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/konmari/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/konmari/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about this Konmari thing. I think it&amp;rsquo;s been around for a while, but got a boost recently due to a Netflix special. I think I agree with it in principle, or at least what I know of it from secondary social media commentary. Minimalism is a worthwhile goal, and so is getting rid of things that do nothing for you other than take up space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people aren&amp;rsquo;t reacting well to the idea of throwing away books though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit 22 Jan: The account has gone private, so the previous embedded tweet is no longer accessible. I&amp;rsquo;m quoting the original text here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do NOT listen to Marie Kondo or Konmari in relation to books. Fill your apartment &amp;amp; world with them. I don’t give a shite if you throw out your knickers and Tupperware but the woman is very misguided about BOOKS. Every human needs a v extensive library not clean, boring shelves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Anakana Schofield (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AnakanaSchofiel&#34;&gt;@AnakanaSchofiel&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jaymelynilao/status/1080957281636835328&#34;&gt;January 3, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s missing the point of decluterring though. The idea is getting rid of things that &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t give you joy&amp;rdquo;, so if having books give you joy, then obviously you keep your books, regardless of whether those books are challenging, difficult, depressing etc. Maybe the point is that you have to be constantly re-evaluating whether the hoarding is a positive spin in your life. (And I say this as someone who has a bunch of books waiting to be read just lying around his room.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this kind of decluttering and minimalism doesn&amp;rsquo;t just apply to possessions though. You should also be looking to give up things like friends, relationships, habits, routines, traditions, and so on, that are no longer net positives or &amp;ldquo;bringing you joy&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s sometimes a bigger picture to look at too. Maybe a specific thing doesn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;bring you joy&amp;rdquo;, but your gradnchildren really like seeing that thing when they visit, and seeing them happy brings you joy, so you keep it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe the bigger lesson is to not rely on someone from a Netflix show to tell you how to live your life. It&amp;rsquo;s good to take advice from other people, but everyone has different tastes and different things can bring you joy. You decide what brings you joy.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Broken streaks
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/broken-streaks/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/broken-streaks/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Here I am writing about &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/duolingo/&#34;&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/dont-break-the-chain/&#34;&gt;keeping up streaks&lt;/a&gt;, then just a few days later, this happens:&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/1081815886468542464/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2019-01-06 07:33:01&#34;&gt;6 Jan 2019 7:33am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ah crap I broke a 97 day Duolingo streak D:&lt;/p&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a problem with Duolingo&amp;rsquo;s streak notifications that I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to solve. It send you a daily reminder at around the same time you did the work the previous day. If you&amp;rsquo;re unable to do it at that time, there are no further reminders later in the day. I feel like there should also be another reminder near the end of the day if you haven&amp;rsquo;t done the work yet and your streak is in risk of breaking, but the late reminder has the issue that if you sleep early, you&amp;rsquo;re likely to miss it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, can&amp;rsquo;t win &amp;lsquo;em all. Surprisingly, the same thing also happened around the same time last year:&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/949751434915954688/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2018-01-06 21:16:02&#34;&gt;6 Jan 2018 9:16pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ah crap I already lost my duolingo streak&lt;/p&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goes to show how reliable a &amp;ldquo;New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolution&amp;rdquo; really is. Or maybe there&amp;rsquo;s something about this time of the year or the coming back to work that makes it easier to break streaks around this time? I&amp;rsquo;ll watch out for it next year!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>My 2018 in review
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/my-2018-in-review/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/my-2018-in-review/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Happy new year! Last year I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/my-2017-in-numbers/&#34;&gt;posted some year-end statistics&lt;/a&gt;. That seems like a good way to recap the year, so let&amp;rsquo;s do it again. Random statistics from 2018:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work, Learning and Self Improvement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hours worked: 1,163 (up around 50% from last year)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming languages/frameworks learned: I&amp;rsquo;ll say 4. I&amp;rsquo;m counting:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C++ which I revisited this year after more than a decade of not using it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go, which I used for the templating in the Hugo blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flask, which I had dabbled in before but only used in a full-scale project this year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laravel, which I also used in a couple of projects this year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books read: 4. Sad. Down 5 from last year. Must finish more books in 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duolingo streak: 92 days (Hooray!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing and Social media:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook status updates: 1093, down from 1463 last year, that&amp;rsquo;s a good sign I think. Last year I measured my FB activity using the &amp;ldquo;facebook report&amp;rdquo; on Wolfram Alpha, but this seems to no longer work, probably due to the recent FB API changes. This time I instead downloaded an archive of my FB activity and counted the &amp;ldquo;status_updates&amp;rdquo; from your_posts.json using a python script.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram posts: 21 (Down 100 from last year. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll continue using it too much&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweets: 1566 (up from 1484 last year)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Answers written on Quora: 3. Down by 14. I may be &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/quora/&#34;&gt;winding down my Quora participation anyway&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;104 blog posts (including this one; total of 818 up 59 from last year)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0 words written for [Nanowrimo][2] (hopefully I can have another go next year)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0 sketches submitted to [r/sketchdaily][3] (I might try to pick this up again this year)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Games purchased (not including any I got for free for some reason): 37, not including DLC, most of it from my three-month experiment with Humble Montly. This is a huge improvement from last year&amp;rsquo;s 67. In fact, my gaming spend for 2018 was 1/3 what it was in 2017, so huge props to me lol. Breakdown: 4 steam, 34 humble, 3 dlc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Games &amp;ldquo;finished&amp;rdquo; (story/campaign completed OR achievement complete): 10, up 2 from 2017! The list:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/974999316036136960&#34;&gt;Twilight Princess HD&lt;/a&gt; (WiiU)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/review-eternal-or-eternal-primer-for-mtg-players/&#34;&gt;Eternal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/late-game-review-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim/&#34;&gt;Skyrim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/late-game-review-ni-no-kuni-wrath-of-the-white-witch-2013/&#34;&gt;Ni No Kuni (PS3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/11/game-review-marvels-spider-man-for-ps4/&#34;&gt;Spider-man (PS4)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invisible Inc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Orwell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tomb Raider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/949318192073121792&#34;&gt;Life is Strange&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Papers Please (not yet achievement complete, but close)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final Fantasy XII: Zodiac Age (I had this on last year&amp;rsquo;s list as 95% done, I decided to finish it a few hours before 2019 lol)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best Eternal Rank: Ranked Master (363), Draft Master&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best MTGA Rank: Gold 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average points per turn in Words with Friends: 26 (down from 27)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MTG GPs attended: 0, but I did &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/06/kuala-lumpur-and-the-mtg25a-rptq/&#34;&gt;do an RTPQ in KL&lt;/a&gt; this year. Most likely 0 again for 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fitbit activity: 1,820,053 steps, 1,419.64 km walked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Donuts eaten: 4 (down from 12 last year!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other countries visited: 0, as predicted. Likely 0 in 2019 as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baptisms attended: 1 (same as last year)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weddings attended: 0 (down 1)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wakes attended: 0 (thankfully)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Things watched on Netflix: 789 (Up 69 from last year)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quiz nights attended: 8 (we won once) - down from 3/19 in 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uber trips: 18 (down from 64 in 2017, RIP uber)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grab trips: 101 (!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Times I won the lotto: 0 (I kind of regret putting this number two years ago, as now I can&amp;rsquo;t remove it without looking suspicious)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bears defeated in single combat: 0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the year was a lot busier than 2017, since I took on a lot more work, especially in the middle half of the year. I&amp;rsquo;m looking to lighten the load a bit in 2019, we&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Form good habits and become their slave
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/form-good-habits-and-become-their-slave/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/form-good-habits-and-become-their-slave/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/suggested-new-years-resolutions/&#34;&gt;New year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions&lt;/a&gt; are hard to maintain, so much so that people will make jokes about opening a gym that only runs during January, since most gym NYRs run out of steam by then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best pieces of advice I&amp;rsquo;ve found regarding acquiring new behaviors comes from the first motivational books I ever read - &lt;em&gt;The Greatest Salesman in the World&lt;/em&gt; by Og Mandino, which for some reason we had a copy of in our house when I was young.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book tells us that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;humans are slaves to habit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bad habits can only be replaced by good habits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, in order to improve your life, you should form good habits and become their slave. So if you have a NYR like &amp;ldquo;quit smoking&amp;rdquo;, you should choose a &amp;ldquo;good habit&amp;rdquo; to replace the &amp;ldquo;bad habit&amp;rdquo; of smoking with. Maybe every time you get an urge to smoke, you pick up a book instead and start reading? Just a suggestion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The rest of Mandino&amp;rsquo;s book consists mostly of recommended self-affirmations, which is the &amp;ldquo;good habit&amp;rdquo; he recommends to improve your life.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Don&#39;t Break the Chain
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/dont-break-the-chain/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/dont-break-the-chain/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/suggested-new-years-resolutions/&#34;&gt;New year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions&lt;/a&gt; are hard to maintain, so much so that people will make jokes about opening a gym that only runs during January, since most gym NYRs run out of steam by then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best pieces of advise I&amp;rsquo;ve read on this is &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t break the chain&amp;rdquo;, most often anecdotally attributed to Jerry Seinfeld. This advice means that for a recurring activity, once you get a streak or chain going, as much as possible you should avoid breaking the chain. So if your NYR is to exercise daily, you should try to avoid breaking that chain for as long as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps if you&amp;rsquo;re tracking how long your current streak is, either via a calendar or an app, or some other method. The longer the streak gets, the more incentivized you are not to drop the ball by breaking the chain. I mentioned this in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/duolingo/&#34;&gt;my Duolingo post&lt;/a&gt; - I feel quite bad when I break a months-long streak in Duolingo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, at some point you&amp;rsquo;re going to fail, and the streak will break. We&amp;rsquo;re only human after all, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/you-dont-have-to-be-on-all-the-time/&#34;&gt;we don&amp;rsquo;t have to be on all the time&lt;/a&gt;. Failures happen, and that&amp;rsquo;s okay. If the activity is important to you, it should be a simple matter to simply try again and start the chain over. This is of course, a point of weakness: at the time you break the chain, this is when you are most vulnerable to quitting. That&amp;rsquo;s why you have to minimize breaking the chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all NYRs or recurring activities have to go on forever though. Sometimes you just want to do 30-day challenges. Or maybe you want to try this activity for a while to see if it works out for you. No need to push yourself to continue with a chain that you find isn&amp;rsquo;t worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New Year&#39;s Checklist 2019
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/new-years-checklist-2019/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 01:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/new-years-checklist-2019/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Most of these are carried over from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/new-years-checklist/&#34;&gt;2017 checklist&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe an annual thing, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greet your loved ones and friends and anyone else you hold dear. Maybe even those you disagree with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ponder why people give so much significance to the transition between an arbitrarily-chosen pair of 24 hour periods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take stock and reflect on the past year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about what you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn this year or how you want to improve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Count your blessings for the past year and be grateful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change your passwords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy a new toothbrush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a New Year&amp;rsquo;s joke (&amp;ldquo;If you must use fireworks of any kind tonight, at least try to limit your injuries to the left leg only. That way you can start the new year on the right foot.&amp;quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a target of how many books you&amp;rsquo;ll read in 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose the first book to read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throw away a few things you no longer need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of where you will travel to in 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out what movies are coming out this year and which ones you want to watch (see below)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audit your financials &amp;ndash; where is your money going, how much do you owe, how much are you earning, where should you invest, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make another New Year&amp;rsquo;s joke (&amp;ldquo;If you go to the toilet at 11:59PM, you won&amp;rsquo;t get out til next year!&amp;quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick up your keyboard and shake out all the grime that&amp;rsquo;s gathered there over the past year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of projects you want to do in 2019&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose something from the past year that you&amp;rsquo;re going to stop watching or doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat your favorite food. Or ice cream. Ice cream is great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember that there&amp;rsquo;s a new Doctor Who special today (well January 1 in the UK)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get rid of 2018 calendars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list for the new year!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean up the photos on your phone, tablet and computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete all files downloaded 2017 or earlier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow up on the people who owe you money or things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review your recurring luxury costs (Netflix, etc) and evaluate whether you still really need them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Export your FB, Instagram and Twitter data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2019 Movies/TV/Games calendar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Movies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;08 Jan Bumblebee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;06 Mar Captain Marvel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;05 Apr Shazam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;26 Apr Avengers Endgame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;07 Jun X-Men Dark Phoenix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;05 Jul Spider-Man From From Home&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;02 Aug New Mutants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;04 Oct Joker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20 Dec Star Wars Episode IX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;11 Jan Tales of Vesperia Definitive Edition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25 Jan Kingdom Hearts III&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15 Feb Civ6 Gathering Storm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TV:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jan Punisher S2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apr Game of Thrones S8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fall Crisis on Infinite Earths Arrowverse crossover&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Suggested New Year&#39;s Resolutions
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/suggested-new-years-resolutions/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/suggested-new-years-resolutions/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a big believer in New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions, but here&amp;rsquo;s some suggestions if you&amp;rsquo;re into that sort of thing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/duolingo/&#34;&gt;learn a new language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;talk to strangers more often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;visit 12 museums (one per month)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;step away from your devices once a week (increase the duration every time)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;read at least 12 non-fiction books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;read at least 12 physical books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;write a poem; maybe write 12 poems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;walk in the rain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;travel somewhere alone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn to draw&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;stop a fight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;walk two thousand kilometers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make more puns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;find something you can change in your local community and try to change it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;figure out what it means to be happy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;start twelve new side projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finish one side project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once a week, throw out a few things you no longer need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These aren&amp;rsquo;t things I&amp;rsquo;m committing to, but they are examples of the sort of NYRs I&amp;rsquo;d be likely to take on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also not a fan of big lifestyle changes like going to the gym or quitting smoking as NYRs, I feel like those things need a completely different approach and level of discipline/commitment than just deciding to arbitrarily switch over on a certain date. I prefer incremental life improvements as NYRs, similar in scale to the above. Also consider: Instead of one resolution for the entire year, try 12 30-day challenges instead. The smaller scale makes the goal less daunting and a bit more achievable. Sticking to something for 30 days is way easier than a whole year.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Duolingo
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/duolingo/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/duolingo/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolution, why not try learning a new language? Since late 2014, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duolingo.com/&#34;&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt; to teach myself new languages. Learning a new language not only helps when you&amp;rsquo;re travelling, but it unlocks different ways of forming thoughts in your brain, helping cognitive development (I may have made up that last part with absolutely no basis except my own speculation.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first language I tried to study using Duolingo was Spanish, mainly because back then we had an &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/04/europe-2015-barcelona-part-1/&#34;&gt;upcoming trip to Europe (including Barcelona)&lt;/a&gt; planned in 2015 so the Spanish would have helped. The Philippines also has a lot of history with the Spanish, so there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of words I could pick up easily. I figured there&amp;rsquo;s no reason to make things too difficult right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t finish the course before our trip, there was far too much content! At some point during the following year (2016), I did manage to complete all of the available Spanish courses though, so yay! The most challenging part was understanding the use of reflexive pronouns like &lt;code&gt;te&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;me&lt;/code&gt;, since using them changed the structure of sentences. I also had to adjust to male/female words, and the vast number of verb tenses. But otherwise, Spanish wasn&amp;rsquo;t too tough. At some point, Duolingo claimed that I was &amp;ldquo;50% fluent&amp;rdquo; in Spanish, but that seems ridiculous lol. This statistic no longer appears after a recent revamp, so they probably realised that too. I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself anywhere near fluent, but I know enough Spanish to recognize a few words here and there when watching the Spanish scenes in &lt;em&gt;Better Call Saul&lt;/em&gt;, so that&amp;rsquo;s a thing. Listening to spoken Spanish is much tougher than reading words off a screen. I suppose if I want to further my mastery of the language, I would need to listen to more Spanish convos or read more Spanish prose or such, but for now I&amp;rsquo;m happy with continuing the Duolingo lessons. They have since revamped the course and introduced more exercises, so there&amp;rsquo;s still quite a bit to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometime in 2017, I also decided to add a second language to my daily Duolingo exercises. Hard mode this time, I chose Japanese. The main reason being I&amp;rsquo;m a bit of a weeb lol. Japanese is a lot more challenging than Spanish because in addition to learning a whole new vocabulary and sentence structure, I have to learn new characters as well! I actually gave studying hiragana/katakana a go back in high school, when a friend and I tried learning Japanese to decipher some Japanese RPGs (maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll write about that someday). Whatever I learned there has largely faded though, but I did retain some minimum vocabulary from all those years of exposure to anime. It&amp;rsquo;s still very challenging - even up to now I&amp;rsquo;m still in the introductory sections learning hiragana and simple sentences, I find myself having to repeat lessons and exercises often and even up to now I&amp;rsquo;m still not super familiar with many of the hiragana characters. I should probably be doing some writing exercises as well (which Duolingo doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide) - the mechanical act of drawing the characters should help with recall - but I&amp;rsquo;ve been too lazy to get into that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duolingo is free to use. That of course means there&amp;rsquo;s stuff like ads and in-app purchases, which might annoy you if you dislike that kind of thing. I dislike them too, but I can kind of tolerate them I guess. The in-app purchases don&amp;rsquo;t really have any effect on what I want to be doing with the app anyway. Completing the lessons also earns you some in-game currency which you can use to unlock some extra lessons/exercises. I&amp;rsquo;ve never had to use them though, so I still have a ton of the in-app currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duolingo has that nice feature where it tracks when you&amp;rsquo;re doing the exercises on a regular daily basis and tracks your &amp;ldquo;streak&amp;rdquo;, which is psychologically very effective on me. I often hold the streaks for months and then I accidentally break the streak for some silly reason like being too busy with work, then I&amp;rsquo;m sad and annoyed and I leave Duolingo alone for a couple of weeks so I can move on. Then I start over. I&amp;rsquo;m currently at an 86-day streak again. Duolingo is a rare example of a new thing I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to stick with for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One weird thing about Duolingo is that although it offers lessons/exercises on different platforms - web, mobile, tablet - the method of delivery is not consistent across all platforms. Web is more limited obviously, since they often won&amp;rsquo;t have access to a microphone. But I don&amp;rsquo;t understand why their mobile and tablet (IPad) versions aren&amp;rsquo;t consistent. The main inconsistency is the way they track in-app &amp;ldquo;experience&amp;rdquo;. The mobile version gives a &amp;ldquo;streak bonus&amp;rdquo; for maintaining a streak, while the IPad and web versions do not, so you can earn more experience when using the mobile version. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter to me - my daily targets are set such that I always need to do two sets per day (one Spanish and one Japanese), but I find it mildly annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all Duolingo provides a positive experience, and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be using it for yearrs to come. I don&amp;rsquo;t really have any specific goals for why I&amp;rsquo;m learning Spanish and Japanese, both just seem like really good languages to know, or at least be able to partially understand. Who knows, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll even try to add a third language some day lol.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Easily Distracted
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/easily-distracted/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 01:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/easily-distracted/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://davemart.in/resistance/&#34;&gt;a blog post by Dave Martin&lt;/a&gt;, I read about Steven Pressfield&amp;rsquo;s quotes on &amp;ldquo;The Resistance&amp;rdquo; that keeps us from doing our work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The danger is greatest when the finish line is in sight. At this point, Resistance knows that we’re about to beat it. It hits the panic button. It marshals one last assault and slams us with everything it’s got.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Side note: I&amp;rsquo;ve put his books on an Amazon wishlist. I should remind myself to do this whenever I find books that sound interesting)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think about new projects all the time: game dev ideas, app ideas, programming projects, plot ideas for a novel, and so on. Very few of them go on to completion or at least some version of production. Some reasons I&amp;rsquo;ve had difficulty finishing side projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I tend to start losing interest when I come across the boring parts of a project or parts I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do. Some examples are UI/design, or promo work/sales/marketing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I might also be overwhelmed by how much work there is that needs to be done. I understand making breaking down the work into a list and then just choosing one task at a time until you get something done. Hmm, I guess sometimes doing the work breakdown is one of the things that falls under the first bullet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sometimes I might also be frustrated by a lack of technical skill in implementation. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking this applies mostly to stuff like writing or drawing, where I feel like my execution or creativity isn&amp;rsquo;t good enough. This frustration can be overcome by practice, but practice risks the first bullet again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll also lose motivation if the project turns out too difficult or too time-consuming, as if it&amp;rsquo;s not worth the effort. This can be a legitimate reason for dropping a project, as long as I make sure my assessment is rational.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of my main problems seems to be that I&amp;rsquo;m easily distracted by new, shiny ideas that come along. That&amp;rsquo;s why reading this comic felt a bit like a personal attack:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.redd.it/48lvp1vv4p121.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt; via &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/ProgrammerHumor&#34;&gt;/r/ProgrammerHumor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do have the ability to go into hyperfocus and gain the flow, enough to immerse myself in what I&amp;rsquo;m doing, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t always last, and it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a double-edged sword, because if something else grabs my attention, there&amp;rsquo;s a good chance I&amp;rsquo;ll hyperfocus on that. (Another edge being of course, I can be so hyperfocused in burns me out).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Slight tangent: When I&amp;rsquo;m in a team project, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good at getting things done, because (a) there&amp;rsquo;s usually someone else holding me to account and making sure stuff gets done; and (b) there&amp;rsquo;s usually team mates to help take up those parts that I find uninteresting.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t list plain old laziness among the reasons above, though I&amp;rsquo;m surely guilty of that. But I think usually laziness is a symptom of one of these other reasons and me making excuses for not getting stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these are some demons I need to tame if I really want to become more independent; I guess at least recognizing them is key and compensating for them where necessary, and making sure I only drop projects if I&amp;rsquo;m convinced they&amp;rsquo;re not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally relevant webcomic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;inspiration strikes &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/qihgd0Q8to&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/qihgd0Q8to&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; the Awkward Yeti (Nick Seluk) (@theawkwardyeti) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/theawkwardyeti/status/1070082567402110977?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 4, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Comparison is the Thief of Joy
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/comparison-is-the-thief-of-joy/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/comparison-is-the-thief-of-joy/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The aforementioned quote is attributed to Theodore Roosevelt. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about this lately as I try to plan for what&amp;rsquo;s ahead and what I want. I think one has to be able to decide what one wants independently of what other people are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a concrete example, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to fall into the trap of &amp;ldquo;Oh, this other person in my field did X and now they are making so much money, should I take that path as well?&amp;rdquo; In a situation like this it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to ask yourself if &amp;ldquo;more money&amp;rdquo; is really what you want. Sure, &amp;ldquo;more money&amp;rdquo; is always good, but you need to consider what you are giving up in exchange for that money. Is X really something you want to be doing? Or would you be miserable doing it? Sometimes you decide that the tradeoff is okay, I&amp;rsquo;ll give up a little happiness in exchange for a little more money, and that&amp;rsquo;s fine if that&amp;rsquo;s what you really want. But that conclusion should come from knowing what it is you want and you need, not out of envy for what other people have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s especially difficult to avoid comparison to other people in the modern age of social media. It&amp;rsquo;s just another form of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/choose-without-regret-and-the-fear-of-missing-out/&#34;&gt;FOMO&lt;/a&gt;. You have to remember that what people project on social media isn&amp;rsquo;t often the entire picture of their lives. They are more likely to hold back on the failures, troubles, problems, and other negative aspects that they have to go through. Comparing your own life to others on social media is inherently an imbalanced situation - you will have a tendency to compare your worst days against their best days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can also be challenging and tempting to compare yourself to other people when you find yourself wanting to make unconventional choices. In such a case, even society itself will sometimes challenge you with comparison. It&amp;rsquo;s important to have a firm understanding of what you want for yourself, to avoid falling into the trap of letting comparison decide to take away your joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess the saying isn&amp;rsquo;t absolute. Comparison can be a good thing, as long as it&amp;rsquo;s used in service of what you truly want.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Expanding Horizons
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/expanding-horizons/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/expanding-horizons/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Aside from my hobbyist readings (keeping up with gaming and comics news, etc), my usual reading diet used to consist of current events and tech news, primarily through apps like Flipboard and Feedly, secondarily through social media like Reddit and Twitter. Recently though I&amp;rsquo;ve started following more sources and blogs that are focused on more&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;cultural&amp;rdquo; affairs. When I started doing &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/&#34;&gt;#sketchdaily&lt;/a&gt; a couple of years ago, I started following more artists. During the past few months, as a sort of counterbalance to the prevalently negative current events and tech industry news, I&amp;rsquo;ve also begun following a few more people who are focused more on things like philosophy, history, poetry, literature, creativity, and so on. A lot of it goes over my head - I don&amp;rsquo;t really have any formal background in the humanities - but many times I come upon posts I appreciate and that help expand my horizons and point me down new avenues of thinking. And I can still enjoy good art and good poetry and good prose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also purposely cut back a bit on the more political follows, especially on Twitter. Following current events feels a lot like being a spectator at a car crash; everything is terrible, but you can&amp;rsquo;t help but be fascinated by what&amp;rsquo;s going on. Even much of the tech industry news tends to be negative - Facebook has done something horrible; there&amp;rsquo;s a new data breach; people are spending too much time on their computers; big tech is helping fascist countries do censorship; and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s too easy to lose yourself in current events and be angry all the time about the state of the world or the country or our leadership. I&amp;rsquo;m not planning to disconnect completely from the news, like some people do, and I&amp;rsquo;m still always open to discussion about any topic (though I have decided to be more restrained in my urge to debate people and respond to every possible outrage).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still believe that good citizens have a responsibility to stay abreast of what&amp;rsquo;s going on in the world and to be informed so that we can make good decisions. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it has to be outrage 24/7. We&amp;rsquo;re not going to run out of bad news any time soon. We have to find the space as well for appreciating what&amp;rsquo;s good in life and for broadening our horizons.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Price for Being the Best
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/the-price-for-being-the-best/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/the-price-for-being-the-best/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The price for being the best is always&amp;hellip; having to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; the best.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Terry Pratchet, &lt;em&gt;Lords and Ladies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favorite quotes. For context: in the story, one of the characters has a special talent that he can shoe anything anyone gives him (like when you put horseshoes on a horse). And Granny Weatherwax tells him that the price he pays for that talent is that when someone brings him something to shoe, no matter how wild or ridiculous the request, he has to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In real life of course, the literal interpretation is ridiculous. You are not obligated to do something just because you are the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; at that something. But being the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; at something implies two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People are more inclined to come to you whenever they need help or advice with what you&amp;rsquo;re best at.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to keep being the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; at that thing, you have to keep doing it, and you have to keep surpassing yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a variant of this quote that I used a lot in a previous job, where people often came to me with their technical problems and asked me for help in solving them, so a lot of my time was taken up by helping solve other people&amp;rsquo;s problems. I would jokingly complain &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ang hirap talaga maging magaling!&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s hard being so good! - implying that being &lt;em&gt;magaling&lt;/em&gt; gave me so much additional work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you put yourself in a position of leadership in your field, there will be pressure to maintain that position by constantly improving and learning and showing your skills by helping other people. Humility disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not claiming to be the best software developer by any stretch, it was probably more of a big fish in a small pond scenario. But the quote above is a reminder for me that pursuing excellence has a price often unmentioned, and you have to be sure you are willing to pay that price, and that it&amp;rsquo;s worth it for you.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Work is Never Done
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/the-work-is-never-done/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/the-work-is-never-done/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I remember a conversation I often had with a friend, the first team lead I ever worked with. Many times she would be putting in extra hours for days at a time and I would say to her &amp;ldquo;Put that off until tomorrow, it&amp;rsquo;s time to go home.&amp;rdquo; and she would reply along the lines of &amp;ldquo;But I still have so much work to do.&amp;rdquo; and my usual rejoinder would be &amp;ldquo;Are you expecting to finish all of that work tonight?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern working world is full of problems, issues, tasks and other work that needs to be resolved, and it can be overwhelming at times. It can seem like the list of to-dos is endless. Software development in particular can seem like never-ending crises and issues and tickets to be resolved, especially for larger teams and larger projects. But that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t mean we sacrifice all our time in pursuit of emptying that to-do list. We put in our hours and pare down that list the best we can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One learns this quickly when faced with any nontrivial project with an issue tracker. Often the list will seem to keep growing with no signs of slowing down. You might have a tendency to say &amp;ldquo;but we can&amp;rsquo;t release software with this many issues!&amp;rdquo; But deadlines are real, and you learn that you have to triage and make trade-offs with the time you have available. Real-world software is released with issues still pending, simply because there isn&amp;rsquo;t enough time to do everything. So you prioritize and choose the most important things, the most critical bugs, and fix what you can in the available time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One has to apply this to one&amp;rsquo;s personal workload as well. No matter how many things you have to do, you don&amp;rsquo;t have infinite time. You have to figure out what&amp;rsquo;s important for you and that&amp;rsquo;s where you focus your time and effort. Pushing yourself beyond what your time and health allow will do no good. That way lies madness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even for personal goals this is an issue for me. I want to do a lot of things. There are so many things I want to read, write, create, draw, learn, watch, and try out. I want to do everything. There are so many things I want to have mastery over. Mastery implies regularly spending hours on practice and effort. But there are only so many hours in the day.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Two-Pronged Decision Making
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/two-pronged-decision-making/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/two-pronged-decision-making/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;When making difficult or life-changing decisions, there are two levels of decision making we go through. One level is the rational, conscious mind. The mind is the part that considers all the options, weighs the pros and cons, and compares the metrics against your personal goals. The second level is subconscious and instinctive, sometimes called the human heart (not to be confused with the organ that pumps blood). The heart makes decisions using instincts and biases honed from your own life experiences and baser needs such as fear, anger, or self-preservation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you find yourself hesitating or unsure or conflicted about a particular decision, more often than not the reason is because your heart and mind are at odds. Your rational mind weighs all the factors and comes to a decision, but your heart has also made a decision and they disagree. Moving past your hestiation means giving more weight to one or the other. It will often be better to find a way to resolve those differences instead. This means asking your mind to probe into your heart&amp;rsquo;s concerns. Sometimes the rational mind will be able to use reason to allay the instinctive fears of the heart. Sometimes the subconsious heart will be able to identify something that the conscious mind has overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When heart and mind are one, this is no guarantee that it will be the correct decision (neither side can see into the future after all), but you can make the decision without regret knowing your full self has approved of it.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>168 hours vs 10000 hours
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/168-hours-vs-10000-hours/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 05:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/168-hours-vs-10000-hours/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;According to Malcolm Gladwell’s book Outliers, you need 10,000 hours of continuous sustained practice to become an expert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 168 hours in a week. If you never sleep and you eat as you practice, you can become an expert in 60 weeks. (Around 14 months)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you sleep 8 hours a day, you only have 112 hours in a week. If you eat as you practice, you can become an expert in 90 weeks. (Around 22 months)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you sleep 8 hours a day and spend 4 hours a day for meals and leisure (TV, movies, etc), you only have 84 hours per week. At this rate, you can become an expert in 120 weeks. (Around 2 years and 4 months)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you sleep 8 hours a day and spend 4 hours a day for meals and leisure and have a day job that takes 9 hours (including travel time), you only have an extra 3 hours per day, or 21 hours per week. At this rate, you can become an expert in 477 weeks. (Roughly 9 years and 2 months)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are there shortcuts to expertise? Probably talent can help some. But for most of us, it takes a whole lot of hard work. You can make things go faster if you like, but you need to sacrifice a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal note: I mentioned before that I had &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2018/10/working-hours-and-overtime/&#34;&gt;my own effort data from 2003-2015&lt;/a&gt;. The total is 23621.36 hours of work in various software development projects. I shouldn’t be shy about calling myself an expert, impostor syndrome be damned.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Let Go or Be Dragged
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/let-go-or-be-dragged/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 01:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/let-go-or-be-dragged/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &#34;Let go or be dragged&#34;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Zen proverb&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days back I read something on &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=18071909&#34;&gt;a Hacker News thread&lt;/a&gt; that kind of resonated with me:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#e80c6b298d2e8dc2d62711db308235c5-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/let-go-or-be-dragged/image_huc8f94616749a2c3bd9895285c236a037_13276_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;e80c6b298d2e8dc2d62711db308235c5-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/let-go-or-be-dragged/image.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;8 Oct 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;8 Oct 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to claim to be the most workaholic person ever &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ve certainly known a lot of people who work far harder than me. But I do recognize that I have this problem of emotional attachment to a project, especially if I&amp;rsquo;m the main person responsible for it. When working on anything you of course need a certain amount of drive or passion that commits you to the project and pushes you to do the best work you can, but there&amp;rsquo;s a line you can cross where it becomes unhealthy for you. It&amp;rsquo;s when the project and the stress that comes with it starts to take over your life, such that it starts eating up your personal time and you can&amp;rsquo;t get it out of your mind and maybe you even start having nightmares about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key to realize this is happening and take a step back and think about whether you need to let go of things for a while. Maybe take some time off even. Learn to compartmentalize and set aside work when you leave the office. Emotional detachment is a skill I still have to learn and master, but it&amp;rsquo;s essential. Otherwise (as the quoted zen proverb states), you get dragged. That means the stress starts to cascade through your personal life and your health and that can&amp;rsquo;t be good for you. As the HN thread notes, work is not the end-all and be-all of life, and on your deathbed you won&amp;rsquo;t wish you had worked more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;But how can I possibly scale back my involvement, there&amp;rsquo;s so much stuff to do!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt; Delegate. Ask for help. Ask to adjust the schedule. Trust your team to get things done. Find a better approach. Regardless, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t sacrifice your well-being for the sake of work. As the airline safety videos tell you, you have to take care of your own oxygen mask before taking care of others!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually find this to be a problem with me with personal matters as well, not just with work. I tend to get attached to particular problems or issues and won&amp;rsquo;t give it a rest until I&amp;rsquo;ve somehow managed to resolve the issue. Most of the time this isn&amp;rsquo;t a big problem (I rarely have big personal issues), but some time ago a close friend and I drifted apart because I was insisting that she should follow my advice. I don&amp;rsquo;t regret giving my advice &amp;ndash; I still think I was right &amp;ndash; but I do regret pushing so hard for it, it was her life to live, not mine. (This particular situation led to the creation of one of my personal rules: Don&amp;rsquo;t insist on helping people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to be helped.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A small side note: I binged seasons 3-7 of &lt;em&gt;Parks and Recreation&lt;/em&gt; lately (seasons 1-2 weren&amp;rsquo;t very good sadly). While I&amp;rsquo;ve always considered myself most similar to the characters of Ron (loves breakfast food, hates government inefficiency, prefers substance over form) and Ben (nerdy, loves pop culture and boardgames and Batman), I realized after this rewatch that I also embody one of the character Leslie&amp;rsquo;s worst traits. And that trait is the inability to detach from her work and even her personal problems. She gets a certain tunnel vision when she&amp;rsquo;s focused on a particular issue and tenaciously never lets go of it. Granted, she does get a lot of stuff done over the course of the series, but more than once the other characters have had to point out how her overzealousness creates problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yes, letting go. I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself super religious, but there&amp;rsquo;s a prayer I like, called the serenity prayer, that I think kind of embodies the kind of personal detachment I want to strive for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    God, grant me the serenity to accept the things I cannot change,&lt;br /&gt;Courage to change the things I can,&lt;br /&gt;And wisdom to know the difference.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/10/let-go-or-be-dragged/image_huc8f94616749a2c3bd9895285c236a037_13276_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Book Review: Tribe of Mentors by Tim Ferris
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/06/book-review-tribe-of-mentors-by-tim-ferris/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 01:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/06/book-review-tribe-of-mentors-by-tim-ferris/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This book was on sale on Amazon Kindle a while back, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d give it a whirl. Some years ago I had read one of the author&amp;rsquo;s previous books, &lt;em&gt;The Four Hour Workweek&lt;/em&gt;, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t too impressed. It was interesting at least, but a lot of the advice seemed either difficult to apply to my personal situation or involved doing stuff I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really interested in (i.e. sales and marketing and whatnot). But this new book intrigued me &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s a collection of life advice from &amp;ldquo;mentors&amp;rdquo;, basically successful people from a wild variety of fields including entrepreneurs, celebrities, venture capitalists, athletes, chefs, scholars, bloggers, authors, and so on. I&amp;rsquo;m always a sucker for this sort of thing &amp;ndash; even if I don&amp;rsquo;t learn anything myself personally, it&amp;rsquo;s always interesting to learn how other people approach life. Spoilers: I enjoyed the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s some common themes that are often repeated among the different mentors in the book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many recommend some form of meditation, whether it be transcendental or something else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many stress how important it was to them to be able to say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to unnecessary commitments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of them recommend some form of nonconformity and taking the time to find your own path&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some great examples of learning from failures and really makes you think about how we often overreact to failures that later on turn out to be not that big a deal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was often pleasantly surprised by how well-read some of the celebrities turned out to be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each mentor also gives a short list of books they often give out as gifts, and there&amp;rsquo;s a *lot* of interesting books mentioned, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably try to read quite a few of them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also started using this function in the Kindle app which let&amp;rsquo;s me highlight some parts and save them for later. I would send those quotes to Google Keep. (Although to be honest there were a lot I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to note down, mostly because I was lazy.) Here are the ones I did manage to save:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;People think focus means saying yes to the thing you’ve got to focus on. But that’s not what it means at all. It means saying no to the hundred other good ideas that there are. You have to pick carefully. I’m actually as proud of the things we haven’t done as the things I have done. Innovation is saying no to 1,000 things.&amp;rdquo; –Steve Jobs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I say no to nearly everything. I make a lot fewer short-term compromises. I aspire to only work with people who I can work with forever, to invest my time in activities that are a joy unto themselves, and to focus on the extremely long term.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Naval Ravikant, CEO and co-founder of AngelList&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;God will not have his work made manifest by cowards.&amp;quot;—Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Desire is a contract that you make with yourself to be unhappy until you get what you want.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Naval Ravikant, CEO and co-founder of AngelList&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;First, whenever possible, connect with others. Second, with enthusiasm, strive always to create fun and delight for others. And third, lean into each moment and encounter expecting magic—or miracles.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Adam Robinson, educator, freelance author, and US Chess Federation life master&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&amp;ldquo;Too often, I hear people effectively given advice that is consistent with sunk cost fallacies. I certainly heard it a lot. &amp;ldquo;You’ve spent X years learning Y, you can’t just up and leave and now do Z,&amp;rdquo; they say. I think this is flawed advice because it weighs too heavily the time behind you, which can’t be changed, and largely discounts the time&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Peter Attia, Surgeon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&amp;ldquo;Yet change is usually stressful, and after a certain age, most people don’t like to change. When you are 16, your entire life is change, whether you like it or not. Your body is changing, your mind is changing, your relationships are changing—everything is in flux. You are busy inventing yourself. By the time you are 40, you don’t want change. You want stability. But in the twenty-first century, you won’t be able to enjoy that luxury. If you try to hold on to some stable identity, some stable job, some stable worldview, you will be left behind, and the world will fly by you. So people will need to be extremely resilient and emotionally balanced to sail through this never-ending storm, and to deal with very high levels of stress.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Yuval Noah Harari, author of Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&amp;ldquo;So you have no choice but to really get to know yourself better. Know who you are and what you really want from life. This is, of course, the oldest advice in the book: know thyself. But this advice has never been more urgent than in the 21st century. Because now you have competition. Google, Facebook, Amazon, and the government are all relying on big data and machine learning to get to know you better and better. We are not living in the era of hacking computers—we are living in the era of hacking humans. Once the corporations and governments know you better than you know yourself, they could control and manipulate you and you won’t even realize it. So if you want to stay in the game, you have to run faster than Google. Good luck!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Yuval Noah Harari again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I read a book like this it refreshes me a little bit and gives me a better sense of perspective and inspires me to do more things that I want to do and maybe live life a little bit more on my own terms. (Whether I actually execute on that, well that&amp;rsquo;s a different matter all together.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Let&#39;s Encrypt!
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/03/lets-encrypt/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 01:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/03/lets-encrypt/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;figure style=&#34;width: 559px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignnone&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.redd.it/hfd9ok7bstf01.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;559&#34; height=&#34;235&#34; /&gt;&lt;figcaption class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;(Image credit: r/ProgrammerHumor)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to add SSL to this blog ever since I first heard of &lt;a href=&#34;https://letsencrypt.org/&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt; last year. Unfortunately, support on my otherwise awesome webhost was not yet first-class and seemed complicated at the time, so I kept putting it off. But recently I was testing something unrelated and found out that I &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/requests/requests-oauthlib/issues/287&#34;&gt;needed to have SSL on my server in order for OAuth2 to work&lt;/a&gt;, so I grudgingly got to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily I found out about a handy utility written in Ruby that does most of the stuff for me: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/will-in-wi/letsencrypt-webfaction&#34;&gt;letsencrypt-webfaction&lt;/a&gt;. It was surprisingly easy to setup, with only a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/will-in-wi/letsencrypt-webfaction/issues/116#issuecomment-368930373&#34;&gt;single false start because I had a silly typo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now this site has SSL! Hooray!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Trying out 3d Modelling with Blender
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/02/trying-out-3d-modelling-with-blender/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 01:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/02/trying-out-3d-modelling-with-blender/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I decided to try learning some 3d modeling. For the past couple of weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been following this beginner &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blender.org/&#34;&gt;Blender&lt;/a&gt; tutorial where I had to make donuts. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JYj6e-72RDs&amp;amp;index=2&amp;amp;list=PLjEaoINr3zgHs8uzT3yqe4iHGfkCmMJ0P&#34;&gt;Link to the tutorial series on Youtube&lt;/a&gt;.) Here&amp;rsquo;s my output!&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#e122ce97c5258e307e77a24c36181c12-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/02/trying-out-3d-modelling-with-blender/donut4_hu6e8b1665346fb560094f645dbbdad573_3005276_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;e122ce97c5258e307e77a24c36181c12-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/02/trying-out-3d-modelling-with-blender/donut4.png&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;1 Feb 2018 1:00am&#34;&gt;1 Feb 2018 1:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This image took around 40 minutes to render. I had to do 2000 samples per tile which is why it was so slow. I was getting too much noise/graininess at lower sampling rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t follow the tutorial exactly. My plate is square and made of glass for one thing. The chocobutternut donut wasn&amp;rsquo;t part of the tutorial, I just wanted to try it (obviously did not turn out too well and all those orange particles on the donut probably really slowed down the render lol). I also didn&amp;rsquo;t bother too much with the stuff in the last two videos of the series which involved adjusting the lighting and other stuff to make the image prettier (wasn&amp;rsquo;t really interested). I actually also tried to model a fork (not in the tutorial), but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the tines right and gave up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A long time ago I read an interview in an old PC gaming mag about how they implemented Age of Empires and there was an image of a 3d mesh of a knight on horseback and I remember thinking &amp;ldquo;That looks really complicated, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably never be able to do something like that.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now that I&amp;rsquo;ve tried this tutorial, I have to agree with that initial assessment &amp;ndash; any complex modelling would surely try my patience. But I was also pleasantly surprised with how advanced Blender is &amp;ndash; I sort of imagined that you had to position and adjust all the mesh nodes/vertices/faces by hand a lot, but actually there&amp;rsquo;s a ton of functions to make some common operations simpler (but it&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One complaint is that Blender&amp;rsquo;s user interface is very obtuse and daunting though &amp;ndash; I don&amp;rsquo;t usually do video tutorials but I doubt I could have figured this stuff out on my own. Though I suppose it can&amp;rsquo;t be helped given the sheer complexity of the task involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m probably not going into any sort of significant 3d modelling or 3d artwork soon (like I said, not enough patience), but it was good to give it a try so at least I have a passing knowledge of some of the concepts involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/02/trying-out-3d-modelling-with-blender/donut4_hu6e8b1665346fb560094f645dbbdad573_3005276_300x0_resize_box_2.png&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New Year&#39;s Resolution: Do at least one personally productive thing per day
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/new-years-resolution-do-at-least-one-personally-productive-thing-per-day/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 01:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/01/new-years-resolution-do-at-least-one-personally-productive-thing-per-day/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not super big on New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolutions anymore. (I seldom even do the 1920×1440 joke these days.) I mean, I&amp;rsquo;m all about productivity and improvement and changing for the better, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found that very specific resolutions don&amp;rsquo;t often work for me. Mostly because I have very little focus (obviously something that an be improved).&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2015/12/682613316246585344/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2015-12-31 17:24:31&#34;&gt;31 Dec 2015 5:24pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;New Year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions: Read, write, watch, play, create, destroy, win, learn, improve, chill, move forward&lt;/p&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my tendency now is to stick to general, high level resolutions (like the above) that don&amp;rsquo;t go into anything too specific. And so this year I decided on something like that. My NYR for this year is: Do at least one personally productive thing per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By &lt;em&gt;personally,&lt;/em&gt; I mean something outside of work, something I do for myself. By &lt;em&gt;productive&lt;/em&gt;, I mean something that helps me improve or grow or live a better life in some manner. And this excludes any manner of consumption (reading, eating, watching TV, browsing reddit, playing games, etc)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yes, it&amp;rsquo;s still kind of vague, but my intent is to minimize or even completely avoid those days where I just totally laze out the entire day and not do anything outside of what I needed to do for work. Not that there&amp;rsquo;s anything wrong with that &amp;ndash; chilling out is important too &amp;ndash; but I felt like maybe I had a bit too many of those days last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some examples of things which I think will qualify for this resolution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Writing a blog post.&lt;/em&gt; (Hooray, I already got one done today!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doing some work on one of my many secret projects that I never get going or never get finished.&lt;/em&gt; There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of these to choose from. It helps a bit with my lack of focus &amp;ndash; I can do other projects if I&amp;rsquo;m not in the mood for the previous one I was working on. If you&amp;rsquo;re curious, this typically means some kind of writing or programming project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some art thing.&lt;/em&gt; I did get back into drawing and sketching in 2016 and kinda tapered off in 2017, hopefully I can get back on track.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learning something new&lt;/em&gt;. Arguably reading or being on the internet always lets me learn something new, but let&amp;rsquo;s say this means dedicating some focused time to a learning activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Throwing out or deleting stuff I don&amp;rsquo;t need anymore.&lt;/em&gt; Not all growth comes from expansion; we also need to throw out old stuff we don&amp;rsquo;t need anymore to make room for the new.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reorganizing/Cleaning up/Optimizing.&lt;/em&gt; This is pretty broad, but basically anything that streamlines some aspect of my life or makes it easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the previous year, I had actually wanted to pursue many of these things all at once &amp;ndash; I wanted to be able to do daily sketching AND writing AND cleaning up AND side projects, etc. Didn&amp;rsquo;t really work out, so this year we lower our standards a bit. Just one of those things per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges would be finding the time to be personally productive even during those days when I&amp;rsquo;m mentally tired out from work stuff &amp;ndash; you know, the kind of day where you get home and you just kinda wanna sit in a chair and not think about stuff too hard. Hopefully I don&amp;rsquo;t get too many of those days, but hopefully the resolution inspires me to do even one small thing during the difficult days.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Compartmentalization
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/compartmentalization/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 01:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/08/compartmentalization/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;div class=&#34;&#34; data-block=&#34;true&#34; data-editor=&#34;2b9ka&#34; data-offset-key=&#34;6mhs1-0-0&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;public-DraftStyleDefault-block public-DraftStyleDefault-ltr&#34; data-offset-key=&#34;6mhs1-0-0&#34;&gt;
    &lt;span data-offset-key=&#34;ctdlb-5-0&#34;&gt;I had been looking into a software performance problem for a few hours now and had decided to call it quits for the day. I turned off the lights and climbed into bed, hoping to get to sleep early for a change. I hadn&#39;t been in bed five minutes when I thought about something I hadn&#39;t tried yet. I picked up the tablet that was beside my bed and did a few google searches and soon I was back on my desktop trying out some parameters I hadn&#39;t tried yet.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
  Ideally one practices some sort of compartmentalization. There should be a clear boundary between work and non-work and you can set work aside as needed. It&#39;s something I&#39;m really bad at, as seen in the example above.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
  It&#39;s something that needs a certain kind of discipline, and we all know discipline isn&#39;t my strong point. Working from home and with everything in the cloud and accessible online makes that discipline even more important. And even more difficult! It&#39;s a lot easier to create separation when your work stuff is only accessible from the office.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
  My tendency for multitasking probably doesn&#39;t help either. Even when I&#39;m playing a video game or out on a walk, I can still get distracted by notifications on my phone. I&#39;m used to it and I expect it and I don&#39;t really want to disconnect -- so maybe I&#39;m kind of asking for it too.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
  The other day I was supposed to take a day off from work and was planning to chill all day and maybe work on some personal projects. Still I ended up replying to a few emails and discussing some stuff on slack even while I was playing Persona 5. It wasn&#39;t much work time but still drove home that I was so bad at compartmentalization.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
  Software development is also like any other professions that involves creative problem solving. It&#39;s hard to set aside the problems you&#39;re trying to solve. You can&#39;t just suddenly quit on a problem at a certain time. They tend to keep spinning around in your head and will pop back into mind at random. And once a new idea or solution does come to you, one might think it wise to just write it down and pursue it later, but then you risk losing flow. Flow is a valuable commodity in professions like mine, so you kind of want to ride along with it when it decides to come.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
  Supposedly you should be setting aside specific times of the day for when you hunker down to work. That way your mind gets conditioned that &amp;quot;this is work time&amp;quot;. And it makes it easier for you to create that separation between work time and nonwork time. And hopefully flow comes to you at the proper time instead of randomly while pooping. That&#39;s not always easy though, and not always viable due to scheduling concerns. But it should be a step in the right direction. Hopefully it&#39;s not too late to learn that kind of discipline.&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New Year&#39;s Checklist
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/new-years-checklist/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 05:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/01/new-years-checklist/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;In no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greet your loved ones and friends and anyone else you hold dear. Maybe even those you disagree with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ponder why people give so much significance to the transition between an arbitrarily-chosen pair of 24 hour periods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take stock and reflect on the past year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about what you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn this year or how you want to improve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Count your blessings for the past year and be grateful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change your passwords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy a new toothbrush&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a New Year&amp;rsquo;s joke (&amp;ldquo;My New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolution is 1440×900!&amp;quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a target of how many books you&amp;rsquo;ll read in 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose the first book to read&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throw away a few things you no longer need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of where you will travel to in 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out what movies are coming out this year and which ones you want to watch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audit your financials &amp;ndash; where is your money going, how much do you owe, how much are you earning, where should you invest, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make another New Year&amp;rsquo;s joke (&amp;ldquo;I haven&amp;rsquo;t taken a bath since last year!&amp;quot;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick up your keyboard and shake out all the grime that&amp;rsquo;s gathered there over the past year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list of projects you want to do in 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose something from the past year that you&amp;rsquo;re going to stop watching or doing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat your favorite food. Or ice cream. Ice cream is great.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember that there&amp;rsquo;s a new episode of Sherlock today (well January 1 in the UK)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get rid of 2016 calendars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a list for the new year!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Learning New Skills
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/learning-new-skills/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 01:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/learning-new-skills/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;When Hanamichi Sakuragi from the manga &lt;em&gt;Slam Dunk&lt;/em&gt; tries to get into the basketball club, he insists he&amp;rsquo;s a genius who doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to practice the basics and instead wants to go immediately to doing spectacular things like Slam Dunks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the vast majority of us cannot claim to be geniuses at anything, and we are forced to undergo a bit of hard work if we want to learn a new skill. Malcolm Gladwell says one needs 10,000 hours of work at something to become proficient, but that probably only holds true if you&amp;rsquo;re using those hours &amp;ldquo;smartly&amp;rdquo; and not just trying to brute force your way to expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try to always keep myself on a learning path, trying to pick up new skills on a regular basis. Here are some things I&amp;rsquo;ve noted down about how to work smartly towards self-improvement in any given skill:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start with the basics, and keep up with the basics&lt;/strong&gt;. When Sakuragi joined the club, they first made him practice dribbling in the corner, and despite his complaints it paid off when he actually got to play because he had really smooth dribbling. It can suck and be boring to be stuck doing simple things or studying theory or background first when you want to skip ahead to the fun, complicated, show-off stuff, but having a solid foundation to work on will help you get a lot further later on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Have a target. **What&amp;rsquo;s your goal when studying this skill? Do you want to become the best in the world in a competitive sport? Do you want to be able to converse in a foreign language? How much time and effort are you willing to spend? Knowing the answers to these questions lets you understand when you are pushing yourself too hard or not putting in enough effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice, practice, practice.&lt;/strong&gt; I sometimes answer questions on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/&#34;&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;, and one of the common questions I see there is of the form &amp;ldquo;How can I get better at X&amp;rdquo;? And my response is inevitably some form of &amp;ldquo;There is no substitute for regular practice, good old time and effort.&amp;rdquo; followed by specific suggestions for the particular X. I used to play competitive Magic the Gathering a lot, and used to place decently in local tournaments on a regular basis. But that was when I had a larger playgroup that I spent a lot of time with and when I was still playing a lot. These days I will only pop in for a tournament every so often, and predictably I seldom do so well anymore. Even if you&amp;rsquo;ve been doing something for a long time, regular practice makes a hell of a lot of difference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Try to improve at least a little bit every time. **Every practice session, every time. Even if you improve only 0.1% every time, the magic of compound interest means those gains will scale up quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Study how other people do things and overcome challenges. **I love fighting games like &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter&lt;/em&gt;, and one of the great things about the modern age is that fighting game enthusiasts have access to a whole lot of replays of top-level competitive fighting that they can watch and study to help improve their own fighting games. (Sadly I do not yet have the execution skills necessary to become competitively good at it &amp;ndash; not enough practice probably, see above.) Studying other people&amp;rsquo;s work gives you insight into different ways of doing things and can unlock different pathways in your brain, allowing you more opportunities to think outside your own box and find more chances for improvement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Keep pushing the difficulty. **Try not to settle for the same level of skill so you can keep improving. Take small steps to improve your game. Handicap yourself in different ways and see how you can compensate. Compete against people who are better than you, and study how they fight you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Study different approaches. **Try out new strategies or new ideas; even if you just discard them later you will have learned something. You might find that the most common approach to learning a skill is not necessarily the best one for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know your weaknesses and shore them up.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a certain style or technique you have a hard time with, practice that more or study it more intensely. While studying Spanish on Duolingo, I know that I always have trouble constructing sentences that use object pronouns so I try to special attention when such sentences come up, and I try to review them more often.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Keep track of your progress. **While not always practical or doable, being able to track your progress, even as a high-level estimate, allows you to measure the rate at which you improve. It gives you a good idea of when you are doing well and when you are having difficulty and helps you compensate accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;**Reward yourself when you do well, and take a break every so often. **As with all things, balance is something to consider.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Are you willing to accept criticism?
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/are-you-willing-to-accept-criticism/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 01:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/are-you-willing-to-accept-criticism/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;If a friend found out your work was horrible, would you want to know? Or would your feelings be hurt?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your coworkers think you&amp;rsquo;re doing something wrong, would you prefer that they keep quiet or that they call you out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a leader, do you prefer to have sycophants who sing your praises or people who are willing to tell you that you have no clothes?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is your ego more important than doing a good job or self-improvement?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But what if the guy is just being an asshole who hates me and wants to discredit me?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not someone is an asshole is independent of whether or not his criticism is valid. You can call him out for being an asshole if you want, but you owe it to yourself to consider if any criticism given to you is valid and something you can act on regardless of whether the messenger is an asshole or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are afraid that having your mistakes called out will be damaging to you, consider how damaging it will be if you keep doing those mistakes and develop a reputation for them.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Feedback Loops
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/feedback-loops/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 01:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/11/feedback-loops/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A feedback loop happens in a system when you are able to use an output of that system to influence the inputs, which in turn influences the outputs and repeats the cycle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-full&#34; src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/ed/Ideal_feedback_model.svg/2000px-Ideal_feedback_model.svg.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;2000&#34; height=&#34;824&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In engineering, feedback loops are useful to generate steady-state outputs. We had an entire subject dedicated to feedback loop controllers back in college. I enjoyed the topic so much I took the subject twice! An example of the use of feedback loops would be a thermostat that has a sensor to detect the current temperature. Once it senses the current temperature, it compares that with the target temperature and uses the difference in values to adjust the thermostat input. In this way, the temperature eventually reaches the target value&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans are also machines subject to feedback loops. We enjoy receiving positive feedback. The more feedback we receive about how well we are performing, the happier we are and the more we are able to perform well. This is part of why we enjoy getting paid a salary regularly &amp;ndash; some part of our brain treats money as a way to &amp;ldquo;keep score&amp;rdquo; and as feedback that hey, you&amp;rsquo;re not doing so bad, here&amp;rsquo;s some cash to keep you going!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feedback can be negative too, but the effect can vary based on the person&amp;rsquo;s attitude. If you accept feedback and criticism of your work and use it to learn and move forward, then you can use even negative feedback as positive reinforcement. If you refuse to acknowledge legitimate negative feedback and instead take it personally or criticize the one giving feedback, then you are failing to learn from the feedback and it either becomes useless or in the worst case can even reinforce negative behavior&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quicker feedback loops allow humans to iterate faster and determine which behavior is best to achieve his goals. My favorite example of feedback loops is in games. Computer and video games are very good at providing near-instant feedback. Run into an enemy? Okay that means you take damage, so that&amp;rsquo;s not good. Finish a task? Ah, you gained some experience points, so it looks like that&amp;rsquo;s good. And games will even tell you immediately how far you are from achieving your goal! How many experience points until I unlock a new ability? How much more damage can I take before I die?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People enjoy this sort of instant feedback loops, so more and more systems are using some form of &amp;ldquo;gamification&amp;rdquo; to improve adoption and usage. Websites like stackoverflow grant you points for answering questions. Fitness trackers give you immediate feedback on how many calories you&amp;rsquo;ve lost. And so it goes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The downside of this instant feedback culture is that it becomes more difficult for us to appreciate things that have long feedback loops. And they are already difficult in the first place, since the feedback takes a long time to get back to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite example of this is dieting. Dieting is hard mainly because you suffer regularly (due to having to eat food you don&amp;rsquo;t like) but the effect isn&amp;rsquo;t measurable immediately. It takes a while to notice any changes, so it takes more discipline to maintain the diet in the absence of that feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why people have systems like calorie counting &amp;ndash; it provides an intermediate feedback to substitute for the feedback you don&amp;rsquo;t have yet on how much weight you&amp;rsquo;ve lost or gained. But it&amp;rsquo;s still an abstract concept and doesn&amp;rsquo;t translate too easily into weight gained or lost. And also it can be difficult to track precisely since not everything you eat will have a calorie count available. I reckon that once we have an app where you just take pictures of the food you just ate it tells you how many pounds you gained or lost, a lot of people will be better at keeping to their diets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to look at the activities I pursue regularly and see if there is anything I can measure to help provide feedback loops for self-improvement. This is why I enjoy daily habits that track streaks &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s simple, instant feedback that tells me I accomplished something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, humans are not machines that need to have perfect systems and be slaves to their feedback loops. So it&amp;rsquo;s also okay to break your daily habits every so often or to cheat on your diet once a week or such, it is one of the privileges of being human. And breaking your patterns also provides some feedback which you can use later&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Daily Habits
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/10/daily-habits/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 01:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/10/daily-habits/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up quite a few daily habits since the start of the year. To name a few: I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing &lt;a href=&#34;http://roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/&#34;&gt;daily sketches&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve been going on a daily walking routine, learning Spanish on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duolingo.com/&#34;&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt;, I have a quick stretching/exercise routine I do in the mornings, etc. (I&amp;rsquo;m also supposed to be writing daily, but this has proven more difficult to keep doing consistently&amp;hellip; )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like those daily habits that can be easily tracked with technology. Duolingo tracks my Spanish learning streak (currently on a 147-day streak). &lt;a href=&#34;http://reddit.com/r/sketchdaily&#34;&gt;r/sketchdaily&lt;/a&gt; tracks my drawing streaks. I have an app on my phone that tracks how often I meet my daily walking target (usually the only problem is if it rains)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a productivity tip &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/281626/jerry-seinfelds-productivity-secret&#34;&gt;supposedly advocated by Jerry Seinfeld&lt;/a&gt; called &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Break the Chain&amp;rdquo;. It recognizes the power of tracking your streaks. The longer your streak gets, the more it motivates (or pressures?) you to maintain the streak and keep it going. It also helps you realize that doing things repeatedly on a daily basis leads to small, incremental improvements that can quickly compound into big improvements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daily habits can be difficult sometimes unless you live a totally boring life. Most people will have differing circumstances from day-to-day that may cause you to miss your daily habits every so often. Maybe you have an out-of-town trip that makes your daily gym habit impossible, or maybe you needed to go overtime all week so you needed to skip your extra learnings, and so on. That&amp;rsquo;s kind of fine &amp;ndash; as long as you understand the tradeoffs you&amp;rsquo;re making (it is your life to live and prioritize after all)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even when you&amp;rsquo;re short on time, you can still look for ways to keep your streak going. With Duolingo, I usually do it in the mornings on my desktop pc, but if I&amp;rsquo;m busy all day I can do a quick Duolingo session on my mobile. For sketches, if I don&amp;rsquo;t have much time I can pick up a small post-it and do a quick and small doodle. If it&amp;rsquo;s raining too hard for me to go out and take my walk, I can go to the nearest mall and just do a walkabout there, maybe even running some errands at the same time. I&amp;rsquo;m also supposed to be reading books daily &amp;ndash; one of the daily habits I&amp;rsquo;m not consistent at &amp;ndash; but if I don&amp;rsquo;t have time, maybe I can just read a few paragraphs or pages right before I sleep&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on your personality, trying to maintain a streak can seem to be a burden sometimes. You feel like you&amp;rsquo;re becoming a slave to the habit. But as the book &amp;ldquo;The Greatest Salesman in the World&amp;rdquo; implies, humans by nature are slaves to habit, and if we must be slaves to habit we might as well be slaves to good habits of our own choosing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/10/daily-habits/10155030141473912/14718694_10154316241449550_5539217550198018238_n_hu707c706a3a414a07de6449544bf7b5ab_4041_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Dealing with Failure
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/dealing-with-failure/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 01:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/dealing-with-failure/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone&#34; src=&#34;http://www.thequotepedia.com/images/02/success-is-not-final-failure-is-not-fatal-it-is-the-courage-to-continue-that-counts-by-winston-churchill.png&#34; alt=&#34;&amp;quot;Success is not final, failure is not fatal: it is the courage to continue that counts&amp;quot; - Winston Churchill&#34; width=&#34;601&#34; height=&#34;447&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my the first semester of my second year in University, I failed four out of five classes I was taking due to slacking off a lot. Those same classes were only available during the first semester of each year, which meant I could not retake them during the second semester or over the summer to catch up. So effectively, I had fallen one year behind everyone I knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got the news, it was devastating. Up until that time I had always been a pretty good student and I felt like I had always made my parents proud and happy. I did not know how I would tell them about it, I felt that I had failed them utterly. I knew I only had myself to blame as I had let most of these classes go by without paying much attention to them. Sometimes when you’re used to doing well academically all the time you might get lax and feel complacent and then you’re surprised to find out there’s a lot you haven’t picked up but it’s too late to catch up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents were very understanding. My friends did not make fun of me or anything like that. I decided to take the failure for what it was &amp;ndash; a failure &amp;ndash; and simply learn from my mistakes and move on. I had to toughen up. I accepted that I would not be graduating on time, and that it was my own fault. I spent a semester under academic probation, but from that point onwards I did not fail any other classes, and I successfully graduated some years later, got a good job and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Failure is a setback yes, but it’s a setback you can learn from and that you can recover from. Failure is not fatal (most of the time &amp;ndash; obviously try not to fail at skydiving). As long as you can find a way to move forward there is no reason you would not be able to surpass it. In time you will look back on your failures as struggles that you learned from and made you stronger and more resilient&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally written &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-deal-with-the-fact-that-I-failed-my-year/answer/Roy-Tang&#34;&gt;as a Quora response&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Above Average
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/06/above-average/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2008 00:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/06/above-average/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Above average &amp;ndash; a level of competency at a given subject such that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are good enough that average people look at your work and tell you &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve got a lot of talent!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are good enough that you know there&amp;rsquo;s a huge gap between you and those who are truly excellent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was wondering the other day whether being above average was a curse. It&amp;rsquo;s like being good enough to be in movies, but never good enough to be the star. Everyone around you is happy that they know someone who appears in movies, but deep inside you wish you were the star.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone ever dreams of being above average. Unfortunately most of the time there&amp;rsquo;s a huge gap between &amp;ldquo;above average&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;excellent&amp;rdquo; that requires so much more effort for incremental gain. When looking at that plateau, it may seem insurmountable so many people just settle for being above average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find myself thinking about this now because I&amp;rsquo;m often faced with one of those plateaus in one aspect of life or another. And when you&amp;rsquo;re there looking at that plateau you need to ask yourself: Is it worth it to devote your time and energy to becoming the best you can be in this particular area?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My curse then, is that there are many areas where I consider myself &amp;ldquo;above average&amp;rdquo;, such that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult for me to decide on the path I want to take in life. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to choose just one path, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to choose just one area to be excellent in. I&amp;rsquo;m greedy; I want it all damn it! And this might be why I&amp;rsquo;m cursed to remain merely above average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>The Four Agreements
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/04/the-four-agreements/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2006 04:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/04/the-four-agreements/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessballs.com/thefouragreementsdonmiguelruiz.htm&#34;&gt;the four agreements, don miguel ruiz book &amp;ndash; a code for life and personal development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;agreement 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be impeccable with your word &amp;ndash; Speak with integrity. Say only what you mean. Avoid using the word to speak against yourself or to gossip about others. Use the power of your word in the direction of truth and love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;agreement 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t take anything personally &amp;ndash; Nothing others do is because of you. What others say and do is a projection of their own reality, their own dream. When you are immune to the opinions and actions of others, you won&amp;rsquo;t be the victim of needless suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;agreement 3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t make assumptions &amp;ndash; Find the courage to ask questions and to express what you really want. Communicate with others as clearly as you can to avoid misunderstandings, sadness and drama. With just this one agreement, you can completely transform your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;agreement 4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always do your best &amp;ndash; Your best is going to change from moment to moment; it will be different when you are healthy as opposed to sick. Under any circumstance, simply do your best, and you will avoid self-judgment, self-abuse and regret.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not really a fan of reading self-help books. But I like to have short lists like these. They&amp;rsquo;re nice sounding.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>