<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>into the spider verse on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/tags/into-the-spider-verse/</link>
      <description>Recent content in into the spider verse on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 16:36:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/tags/into-the-spider-verse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2018/12/181171084805/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 16:36:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2018/12/181171084805/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;
Into the Spider-Verse spoiler-free review
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- this is a great animated comic book movie, it makes me happy&lt;br/&gt;- I may have been a bit overhyped by the early reviews, but it was very entertaining, funny and had brilliant presentation, melding the medium of movies with comic books in a way that has never been seen before&lt;br/&gt;- again, the presentation is fantastic, the animation is great and intentional and the funky alternate universe stuff is represented well&lt;br/&gt;- IDK if I would call it the best comic book movie of all time, or even the best Spider-Man movie of all time, but definitely one of the best animated movies of all time, for a comic book fan (highly specific lol)&lt;br/&gt;- in fact, much respect to the writers who dared to bring this story to life. imagine the challenge of pitching a story idea to Sony about not just one new Spider-man, but several alternate universe versions of them. It’s not exactly comparable to a Disney movie plot after all, but they pulled it off&lt;br/&gt;- between this movie and the PS4 game, I’m happy that Miles is making further inroads into the cultural zeitgeist&lt;br/&gt;- Miles appearance here reminds me of Hey Arnold’s black friend lol&lt;br/&gt;- maybe I would have appreciated the movie a bit more if I was into hip-hop or such&lt;br/&gt;- comic book fans will be happy to know that this movie does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; follow the actual Spider-Verse comic book arc along with its convoluted background of the inheritors. The plot and the opposition are much more straightforward&lt;br/&gt;- Will Mama like it? Well …like all animated movies, with enough viewings at home by my nieces/nephews, maybe.&lt;br/&gt;- This movie has the best post-credits scene of all time&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://roytang.net/2018/12/181171084805/181171084805_hu0c2c1a0f92fa5ba5b2cf07594a16512b_113340_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>