<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>dark tower on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/dark-tower/</link>
      <description>Recent content in dark tower on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2006 02:09:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/dark-tower/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Dark Tower VII
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/11/dark-tower-vii/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2006 02:09:13 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/11/dark-tower-vii/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;What a long, arduous journey it has been for Roland of Gilead, last gunslinger, in his inexorable quest for the Dark Tower. And now that I&amp;rsquo;ve read the final volume of Stephen King&amp;rsquo;s magnum opus, I find out that it is an even crueler fate that awaits him at the end of the seven books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dare not spoil it, though &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Dark_Tower_%282004_novel%29&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; has a nice summary, say thankya. Save to say that Stephen King seems to be correct &amp;ndash; the ending of the Dark Tower series does seem to be the &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; one, despite some disappointments in writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, the Dark Tower series remains an incredibly good read, and Stephen King is admirable for having completed the epic story over a more than twenty-year period. People often know King as the &amp;ldquo;guy who writes those creepy horror stories&amp;rdquo;, but the Dark Tower series shows his bent is really towards a type of dark fantasy. I wish I had time to read his other novels, as many of them tie up with the Dark Tower story itself.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Dark Tower VI -- Song of Susannah
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/10/dark-tower-vi-song-of-susannah/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2006 09:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/10/dark-tower-vi-song-of-susannah/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I was holding off on buying the sixth installment of the Dark Tower until I could find a printing which matched the previous five books, but as I was browsing through the new Fully Booked at SM North I felt a compulsive urge to buy *something*, and lo and behold, Stephen King was on the shelf right beside me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As usual, the tale of Roland and his party on their quest for the Dark Tower is quite the page-turner, especially since this particular piece of fiction intersects with the real world in an intruiging way&amp;hellip; the author himself, Stephen King, appears in this book as the would-be creator of Roland&amp;rsquo;s world! Reminds me of one of those &amp;ldquo;self-inserts&amp;rdquo;, a term used for fanfiction where the author writes himself in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, one more book before the end of King&amp;rsquo;s epic twenty-years-in-the-making western fantasy saga. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably buy the next book this week.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Books: Dark Tower V -- Wolves of the Calla
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/09/books-dark-tower-v-wolves-of-the-calla/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2005 04:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/09/books-dark-tower-v-wolves-of-the-calla/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;There will be water if ka wills it.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Roland of Gilead&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a Powerbooks gift certificate the other week, and the Powerbooks at Megamall happened to have a sale, so I took a look around. And lo, I was lucky enough to find a copy of the fifth book of Stephen King&amp;rsquo;s epic western fantasy, The Dark Tower. It was a huge book, larger than my copies of the first four, but with the same cover style and by the same publisher, so it was the copy I wanted. I spent less than a hundred pesos on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so it was that I once again journeyed into the world/s of the Dark Tower, following the path of Roland of Gilead and his ka-tet of gunslingers along the path of the Beam, heading inexporably towards the Dark Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dark Tower series has always been a weird sort of hybrid. Primarily a western, set in a fantasy multiverse which intersects with multiple versions of our own reality, Roland and his posse find themselves facing robots, bears, wizards, psychotic trains, undead and such. This time they face &amp;ldquo;Wolves&amp;rdquo;, an unknown new enemy who plague a farming community along the path of the Beam. Like any good RPG-party, the gunslingers decide to offer aid to the people of the Calla, though not all would accept their help. In exchange, they are granted the power to travel back to New York, the nexus of all New Yorks, where they must protect the Rose, an incarnation or manifestation of the Dark Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing I did not like about this copy: It had illustrations. Normally, that would be a good thing, but I find I did not really want to know what Roland of Gilead looked like, even to another person, as it spoiled my own vision of what the book tells me. That&amp;rsquo;s how good the series is — it&amp;rsquo;s the type of series where you form your own version of it in your head and you are completely drawn into its saga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, the book is dark and compelling. Despite the hectic work schedule last week, I finish the thick book in less than four days, and the volume ends in cliffhanger, as the ka-tet is broken. Two more books to go before the end of their quest; I can only hope the last two come out in my preferred format soon.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Books: Dark Tower series
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/03/books-dark-tower-series/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2005 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/03/books-dark-tower-series/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I do not aim with my hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who aims with his hand has forgotten the face of his father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I aim with my Eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not shoot with my hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who aims with his hand has forgotten the face of his father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shoot with my Mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not kill with my gun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who kills with his gun has forgotten the face of his father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kill with my Heart.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;The Gunslinger&amp;rsquo;s Catechism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve finished books 3 (Wastelands) and 4 (Wizard and Glass) of Stephen King&amp;rsquo;s amazing Dark Tower series. The sprawling worlds travelled by Roland of Gilead and his band of gunslingers continues to draw me in; I guess the romantic western atmosphere really appeals to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During these two books, we follow Roland Deschain, the last gunslinger, Eddie and Susannah, gunslingers-in-training as they forge ahead on the road to the Dark Tower, where the fate of all worlds may be decided. Along the way, they gain new allies, one thought previously dead. They storm across the fallen city of Lud, blaze across the wastelands on an insane sentient train, and finally land in Kansas. It is in Kansas that Roland narrates a tale of his youth, and of his days and Gilead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is Roland&amp;rsquo;s tales of Gilead that I most enjoy in the series. Roland&amp;rsquo;s world, the world that has moved on, is a medieval-western hybrid of sorts. A world where people look to gunslingers with fear and respect, a world where a misspoken word in a tavern can get you killed, a world fraught with danger and adventure. In this tale we learn of what happened to Roland after he passed his rite of passage, his first love, and his decision to pursue the Dark Tower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look forward to the last three books&amp;hellip; all of which are out in hard cover versions. Wizard and Glass ends on much less of a cliffhanger than Wastelands, so I&amp;rsquo;m willing to wait a bit for the paperback copies to come out, though I hope it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take too long.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>