<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>quezon city on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/tags/quezon-city/</link>
      <description>Recent content in quezon city on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/tags/quezon-city/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>The Quezon City Public Library
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/01/the-quezon-city-public-library/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/01/the-quezon-city-public-library/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I pass by the Quezon City Hall every so often, and I&amp;rsquo;ve always been curious about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quezoncitypubliclibrary.org&#34;&gt;QC public library&lt;/a&gt; they have there. It got a bit of press a while back about how it was a nice place to hang out (for a government institution at least), so I had a todo list item about checking it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, last week I did! I passed by on a weekday afternoon about 4pm after running some errands. The library was open until 7pm, so the timing was fine. I went up to the building and the guard asked me what my business was and I said I just wanted to check out the library. He told me that bags weren&amp;rsquo;t allowed inside so I had to go to the baggage counter. Oops, luckily I only had my sling bag and not the full backpack I usually had when carrying a laptop. I left my sling bag at the counter and went inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The space wasn&amp;rsquo;t as large as I thought it would be - the pictures on the website made it seem a bit larger in my imagination. The tables and seats were maybe 75% full, mostly with students and library staff. The main library area was in the first floor. Second floor seemed to be some offices and an outdoor cafe, I didn&amp;rsquo;t explore the second floor too much. I walked around the ground floor rooms for a bit, browsing the shelves. Aside from the main area, there was a separate room specialized for Philippine history and such, a room for kids&amp;rsquo; books, a &amp;ldquo;puppeteers room&amp;rdquo;, and a smaller round room with periodicals and such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a small section for fiction books in the main area; the selection was decent, mostly mainstream titles like Hunger Games, some Robert Ludlum, a few sci-fi/fantasy titles, and so on. For the reference materials, it was about what you&amp;rsquo;d expect from a public library - most of it was dated and donated. The tech/comptuers sections had the sort of obsolete computer books you&amp;rsquo;d find at book sale - like &amp;ldquo;How to use Microsoft Access 95&amp;rdquo;, that kind of thing. There were The World is Flat by Friedman, and Obama&amp;rsquo;s book about hope or such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone showed me how to use one of the computer kiosks to search the library&amp;rsquo;s catalog, and I was told it should be accessible via the website, so that seems fine. If you wanted to know whether they had a particular book, you could just check the website first. Also, the catalog said they had some Thor comics, but they were in the children&amp;rsquo;s corner, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like going in there lol. I also tried connecting my iPad to the local wifi, but the internet wasn&amp;rsquo;t very good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came away not too impressed with the library. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what I was expecting. I guess I was kind of hoping to see if it was a good place to hang out, maybe if I was stranded near city hall due to traffic or waiting around in that area for something. It seems like a fairly good place for students from nearby schools though, especially those with no internet access at home. At least my curiosity was sated and I managed to tick an item off my todo list!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>