<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>blogging on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/blogging/</link>
      <description>Recent content in blogging on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 05:36:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>&#34;Async read access to your brain&#34;
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/async-read-access-to-your-brain/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 05:36:44 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/08/async-read-access-to-your-brain/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I read this quote from Twitter recently that I really liked:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging is creating async read access to your brain. Highly recommend. &amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/brian_lovin/status/1422602248203300866&#34;&gt;@brian_lovin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like this is very true for me because a lot of the time, I write posts in an unfiltered, stream-of-consciousness manner, so in many ways it is in fact a direct look at how I think (barring the limitations of language of course). Basically a documentation of thought processes. More often than not the beneficiary of that documentation is myself, or at least, a future version of me; but having a blog also gives other people insight to what and how I think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat related: I read &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamierubin.net/2021/08/04/unposted-writings/&#34;&gt;this post from Jamie Rubin about unposted writings&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before a post goes into the world, there is really only one person who can judge whether it is good enough to be posted and that is me. This blog is a one-man operation. I play the role of writer, editor, and marketing department all by myself. And sometimes I write something and think, nope, that just isn’t very good. It used to be that I’d post the bad stuff anyway, but over time I realized that I wanted to show the very best of what I write. So I’ve gotten better at weeding out the bad stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I found it interesting because it&amp;rsquo;s the opposite of how I approach things. Generally if some thread of thought surfaces in my brain that I feel is good enough to at least start writing a post about, I&amp;rsquo;m going to write it out and probably publish it, even if the end result is not super coherent. It&amp;rsquo;s part of my blogging process being mostly unfiltered - you kind of get the bad with the good here. It&amp;rsquo;s part of an evolving thought process: if ever I decide to revisit the topic in the future, I have this reference for my thoughts on it at the time and see how my views and opinions may have changed or become clearer or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you blog is of course a mostly personal affair. What topics you discuss, what quality of writing you expect from yourself, these are all personal decisions, and what works for some people may not work for others. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect other people to blog the same way I do; it&amp;rsquo;s not like I&amp;rsquo;m a wildly successful blogger worth emulating, but I think my methods generally work for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do find that recently my standard for &amp;ldquo;what deserves a blog post&amp;rdquo; has gotten a bit too high though, as I am blogging less and mostly reliant on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/weeknotes&#34;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; to document my thoughts, and I may be leaving too much on the table, leaving quick thoughts mostly to social media or the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/notes&#34;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; folder. I&amp;rsquo;m kind of tempted a bit to lean in towards blogging more like I did in the early days before social media, with shorter, more frequent posts. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Blogs of Yesteryear Part 2
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/blogs-of-yesteryear-part-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 02:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/blogs-of-yesteryear-part-2/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;This is a follow up to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/blogs-of-yesteryear/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Blogs of Yesteryear&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. This is the remainder of my blogroll from 2004/2005. I feel like the second half is less interesting than the first half, but I figured I might as well go through them as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;geekiness&#34;&gt;geekiness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the blogs under this session are about general geeky topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Absurd Genius&lt;/strong&gt; - looks this was a tech and gaming-focused blog that featured a web portal for the PSP browser. But I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anymore information about the author. It was formerly hosted on base2.org, but that domain doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have any content now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forever Geek&lt;/strong&gt; - this was a blog that covered a lot of geeky topics - tech, anime, gadgets, games, etc. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://forevergeek.com/&#34;&gt;still around&lt;/a&gt;! I no longer follow them though, mainly because that&amp;rsquo;s not really the sort of site I follow anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kuro5hin&lt;/strong&gt; - this was a slashdot-like discussion site that was a bit popular back in the day. According to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kuro5hin&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, the site was taken down permanently in 2016. Kuro5hin was owned by Rusty Foster, who now writes a newsletter, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.todayintabs.com/&#34;&gt;Today in Tabs&lt;/a&gt;, one of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/newsletters-redux/&#34;&gt;newsletters I follow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gaming&#34;&gt;gaming&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I followed a lot of gaming sites back in the day. I no longer follow these, mostly because I&amp;rsquo;m not interested anymore in having 100% gaming feeds in my feedreader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;game girl advance&lt;/strong&gt; - a gaming blog with all women writers. Back then most of the people writing about games were male (I think), so following a site like this one helped diversify your POVs. The site is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gamegirladvance.com/&#34;&gt;still up&lt;/a&gt;, but the last update is from 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GameDevBlog&lt;/strong&gt; - this is a blog by game developer Jamie Fristrom. I think I followed this site after I read an interesting article he wrote about implementing web-swinging in the 2004 videogame Spider-man 2. His &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gamedevblog.com/&#34;&gt;site is still up&lt;/a&gt; and updated as recently as last October!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Games from Within&lt;/strong&gt; - this was another game developer&amp;rsquo;s blog (in case it isn&amp;rsquo;t obvious, it is/was one of my interests). The &lt;a href=&#34;https://gamesfromwithin.com/&#34;&gt;site is still up&lt;/a&gt;, last post is from 2018. (Annoyingly, it&amp;rsquo;s one of those sites that doesn&amp;rsquo;t show the post date on the listing screens.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RPGamer&lt;/strong&gt; - a gaming site focused on computer/console RPGs. This and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rpgfan.com/&#34;&gt;RPGFan&lt;/a&gt; were my main source of RPG news back in the day. RPGamer is &lt;a href=&#34;https://rpgamer.com/&#34;&gt;still up&lt;/a&gt; and going strong. (The site even still has the same dragon logo and font!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These Damned Machines Are Killing Me&lt;/strong&gt; - another gaming focused blog, this one was short-lived, looks like it wasn&amp;rsquo;t updated past 2007, after which the site went down. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.damnedmachines.com/&#34;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt; currently redirects to a site called Furious Games, not sure if related.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3rd World Game Designer&lt;/strong&gt; - this was a blog by Gabby Dizon, a game designer from the Philippines! (I&amp;rsquo;m always interested in local content). The site is no longer accessible and the domain is parked. I think I found the author on Twitter, but he seems to be a crypto guy now or some such.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comics&#34;&gt;comics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still read webcomics these days, though not as much, and almost never through a feed reader (most of the time.) Related: &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/10/webcomics-i-like-2006-edition/&#34;&gt;Webcomics I Like, 2006 Edition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PvPonline&lt;/strong&gt; - this was a webcomic about the employees at a gaming publication, it was quite popular back in the day. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://pvponline.com/&#34;&gt;site is still up&lt;/a&gt; and the author recently rebooted/time-skipped the story. I currently follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pvponline&#34;&gt;the author on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and catch up on it whenever I see him update.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Penny Arcade&lt;/strong&gt; - one of the longest-running mostly-gaming-focused webcomics (and one of the most well-known). The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.penny-arcade.com/&#34;&gt;site is still going strong&lt;/a&gt; after all these years, sporting largely the same color scheme. I get updates because I follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cwgabriel&#34;&gt;the artist on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comics: Foxtrot&lt;/strong&gt; - one of my favorite slice of life strips, I have a few of the books. It stopped being released as a daily a while back, and the author now only releases a new comic every Sunday, I think. Once again, I am following &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/billamend&#34;&gt;the artist on twitter&lt;/a&gt;. (Starting to see a pattern here.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comics: Sinfest&lt;/strong&gt; - it started out as a dark humor strip about this guy Slick who tries to hit on a girl named Monique and just kept expanding and expanding its scope, covering topics such as politics, patriarchy, religion, that kind of stuff. It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://sinfest.net/&#34;&gt;still running&lt;/a&gt; but I mostly lost interest when he tended to do arcs that ran really long. I much preferred his silly, standalone strips like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sinfest.net/view.php?date=2004-04-05&#34;&gt;this one about Apples and Oranges&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/08/1042004246/&#34;&gt;another one that I liked&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dilbert&lt;/strong&gt; - this famous strip is of course still running (currently at &lt;a href=&#34;https://dilbert.com/&#34;&gt;Dilbert.com&lt;/a&gt;), although the author has in recent years come out as Trump supporter with many bad takes. I still read the strip, mostly because it comes with our daily newspaper. (On paper! We still have those!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real life comics&lt;/strong&gt; - this was a semi-autobiographical slice-of-life comic about a guy named Greg. I had stopped following it for a while because of reasons, but last year I found out that (a) it was still going strong; and (b) the author recently &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/reallifecomics/status/1284587454968651777&#34;&gt;came out as as trans&lt;/a&gt;. The strip is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reallifecomics.com/index.php&#34;&gt;still running&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comics: Calvin and Hobbes&lt;/strong&gt; - the quintessential comic about a little kid and his tiger. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why I bothered following this one, since the author stopped drawing the strip in 1995. I believe that I have already read every single strip of C&amp;amp;H, so there&amp;rsquo;s no reason to follow it now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websnark&lt;/strong&gt; - this was a commentary blog about stuff on the internet, mostly webcomics. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember following it for too long, probably lost interest at some point. The domain currently has nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lifehacks&#34;&gt;lifehacks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are blogs I followed about self-improvement, productivity, that kind of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working Smart&lt;/strong&gt; - looks like this was a blog from a guy who was head of a Christian publishing company. I guess I followed him because he sometimes published about topics like getting things done, communication, tech, gadgets, and blogging. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember following him for very long, so I imagine I lost interest quickly. The site is no longer accessible and he no longer seems to be blogging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steve Pavlina&amp;rsquo;s Blog&lt;/strong&gt; - this is a guy who became well-known as a self-help author and motivational speaker. He often wrote about personal development. I&amp;rsquo;m not really into that kind of content anymore so I no longer follow him. He still writes at stevepavlina.com.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;43 Folders&lt;/strong&gt; - a site about &amp;ldquo;tricks, hacks and other cool stuff&amp;rdquo;, named after the number of manila folders in a tickler file. The site is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.43folders.com/&#34;&gt;still around&lt;/a&gt;, but the last update is from 2011. I&amp;rsquo;m currently following &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hotdogsladies&#34;&gt;the author on twitter&lt;/a&gt;, he no longer seems to be blogging and is more of a podcaster now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;feed-readers&#34;&gt;feed readers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the old site, my feeds back then were powered by an app called Bloglines. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bloglines&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; says Bloglines became unavailable in 2015, but presumably I stopped using it in 2007 when I &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/01/newshutch-feed-aggregator/&#34;&gt;switched to a different app called Newshutch&lt;/a&gt;. At the time, I was complaining that &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Reader&#34;&gt;Google Reader&lt;/a&gt;, released in 2007, was &amp;ldquo;slow as molasses&amp;rdquo;! I eventually did migrate to Google Reader and was a faithful user until &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/06/347364993144074241/&#34;&gt;it was killed off in 2013&lt;/a&gt;. (In hindsight, this was more recent than I thought it was!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-about-now&#34;&gt;what about now?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I follow a mostly different set of blogs now. There&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/blogroll/&#34;&gt;a blogroll&lt;/a&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s a touch out of date and could use some updating. Maybe sometime soon. Looking over the list, it seems I prefer not to follow single-topic blogs anymore and enjoy slice-of-life blogs where people talk about their day-to-day pursuits on a personal level (instead of say, writing as a general-purpose article for any reader). Feel free to send me blogs or blogrolls you recommend, I will gladly spend an hour or so scrolling through a blogroll and clicking through links and checking out blogs!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Blogs of Yesteryear
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/blogs-of-yesteryear/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 18:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/blogs-of-yesteryear/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;During a recent session of spelunking through old web stuff, I managed to find some older versions of the blog that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t found before (and hence aren&amp;rsquo;t available in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/archives/ancient/&#34;&gt;ancient archives&lt;/a&gt;). Screenshots of those old versions have been &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/12/layouts-2004/&#34;&gt;inserted back in the timeline&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it&amp;rsquo;s one of those things I never bothered to archive because in theory all of that content had already been exported from &lt;a href=&#34;https://roywantsmeat.blogspot.com&#34;&gt;Blogspot&lt;/a&gt; to Wordpress and eventually to the current site. But there was some content from this archive I hadn&amp;rsquo;t recovered before: the list of blogs I link to in the sidebar! This content was exported from Bloglines, an RSS reader service available at the time (Google Reader had yet to be invented!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of these old blogs no longer appear in my current follows. I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be fun to look at each of them and see where they are in the current web, both as a look at the kinds of stuff I (used to) follow and as a commentary on how very few blogs last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;around-here&#34;&gt;around here&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is blogs of people who I knew to also be in the Philippines, though not all of them I knew personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the beautiful rookery&lt;/strong&gt; - this was a blog written by a batchmate of mine from HS, hosted on blogspot. The blogspot account apparently still exists, but you need to be invited to be able to access it, so IDK what&amp;rsquo;s going on there. I still follow the writer on social media like Insta.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Entertainment Capital of UP Village&lt;/strong&gt; - another HS batchmate, this blog was hosted on LiveJournal which means it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://zukeeper.livejournal.com/&#34;&gt;still accessible online&lt;/a&gt;! He hasn&amp;rsquo;t written anything there since 2015 though. We are still good friends and are in constant contact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sassy Lawyer&amp;rsquo;s Journal&lt;/strong&gt; - this was the blog of a female lawyer in Metro Manila; IDK who it was, and the site is no longer accessible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sachachua&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/strong&gt; - I didn&amp;rsquo;t know Sacha personally, although I knew some of her batchmates. Her url is still active and redirects to her &lt;a href=&#34;https://sachachua.com/blog/&#34;&gt;current blog&lt;/a&gt;, where she writes mostly about Emacs stuff, something she&amp;rsquo;s been doing since 2004 apparently, so that&amp;rsquo;s a bit of dedication there. I think she also used to write about some productivity stuff, but I stopped following her when she started focusing mostly on Emacs, since that&amp;rsquo;s not an interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the babel machine&lt;/strong&gt; - hosted on blogspot and written by a guy called Joey Alarilla. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I knew him personally. He wrote mostly about games and tech and such. The blogspot site is no longer accessible. Looks like he moved to a wordpress site in 2006 and to a personal domain in 2009, but neither are accessible now. He founded a digital media startup called &lt;a href=&#34;https://digitallifeasia.com/&#34;&gt;Digital Life Asia&lt;/a&gt; and I found him &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/joeyalarilla&#34;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clair&amp;rsquo;s Tech Blog&lt;/strong&gt; - I knew Clair from HS, though we weren&amp;rsquo;t batchmates. She used to write about Linux, Emacs, tech, blogging, etc. Her site is no longer available, but I still follow her on Insta. She does art stuff on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/claircolors/&#34;&gt;public instagram&lt;/a&gt; and takes commissions, if that&amp;rsquo;s your thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;general-purpose&#34;&gt;general purpose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Waxy Links&lt;/strong&gt; - by Andy Baio. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://waxy.org/category/links/&#34;&gt;site is still up&lt;/a&gt; to this day and still on my follows!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;J-Walk Blog&lt;/strong&gt; - by John Walkenbach, well-known for his Excel knowledge. His blog was &amp;ldquo;all sorts of things&amp;rdquo; kind of blog, and he was prolific, blogging daily. Looks like he &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bitsandpieces.us/2011/10/14/the-end-of-an-era/&#34;&gt;stopped blogging in 2011&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://j-walkblog.com/&#34;&gt;domain is still up&lt;/a&gt;, but IDK if it&amp;rsquo;s still by the same person - the posts seem like the sort of thing I&amp;rsquo;d expect to find in like copy-paste blogs out to earn money from advertising. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any social media presence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boing Boing&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://boingboing.net/&#34;&gt;Boing Boing&lt;/a&gt; is still up, but no longer written primarily by Cory Doctorow I think. Doctorow now writes a new daily blog on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralistic.net/&#34;&gt;Pluralistic&lt;/a&gt; and is still one of my follows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tech-blogs&#34;&gt;tech blogs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Daily WTF: The Daily WTF&lt;/strong&gt; - this was a blog that highlighted one programmer&amp;rsquo;s mistakes every day, some of them were funny. &lt;a href=&#34;https://thedailywtf.com/&#34;&gt;The site is still up&lt;/a&gt;! I think I stopped following them a while ago because I kind of lost interest in that kind of thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Blog&lt;/strong&gt; - I think this blog used to cover mostly Google&amp;rsquo;s tech and engineering stuff. The site is still up at &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.google/&#34;&gt;a slightly different URL&lt;/a&gt;, but because of how much stuff Google is into now, it feels like many of their posts aren&amp;rsquo;t of interest to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Joel on Software&lt;/strong&gt; - Joel wrote a lot about running a software company back in the day, and his writing certainly influenced a lot of the dev culture at the time (for better or for worse?). His &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joelonsoftware.com/&#34;&gt;site is still up&lt;/a&gt;, but he doesn&amp;rsquo;t post very often these days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ned Batchelder&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/strong&gt; - Ned wrote about tech / programming stuff; his &lt;a href=&#34;https://nedbatchelder.com/blog/&#34;&gt;blog is still up&lt;/a&gt; (and still has roughly the same layout!). I still follow him and he mostly writes about Python these days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scobleizer: Microsoft Geek Blogger&lt;/strong&gt; - Robert Scoble was a tech evangelist for Microsoft I believe. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I followed him for too long, as I wasn&amp;rsquo;t super interested in Microsoft tech stuff back then. A few years ago he was embroiled in a #MeToo controversy and apparently no longer has a social media presence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;interesting-blogs&#34;&gt;interesting blogs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Troutgirl&lt;/strong&gt; - Troutgirl worked in the tech industry, but her blog was a combination of tech stuff, industry stuff and other nontech things. At some point she moved from her own domain to &lt;a href=&#34;https://troutgirl.wordpress.com&#34;&gt;a Wordpress blog&lt;/a&gt;, which is now only sporadically updated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ButtUgly&lt;/strong&gt; - ButtUgly is a Finnish blogger who ran his blog on JSPWiki. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ecyrd.com/ButtUgly&#34;&gt;site is still up&lt;/a&gt; but the last post is from 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critical Section&lt;/strong&gt; - this was a blog by Ole Eichhorn, who was very prolific, multiple posts a day, posts whatever interesting things he find, that kind of thing. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://w-uh.com/&#34;&gt;site is still up&lt;/a&gt; and regularly updated and even has the exact same layout!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extraordinary Ordinary Guy In Japan&lt;/strong&gt; - this is a well-written English blog by a Tokyo native. I guess I followed him for more exposure to Japanese culture. It looks like he stopped blogging in 2004. The site &lt;a href=&#34;https://xogij.blogs.com/xogij/&#34;&gt;is still up&lt;/a&gt;, but the actual post contents don&amp;rsquo;t seem to load, I can only see sidebars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gapingvoid&lt;/strong&gt; - a blog by Hugh MacLeod who got some traction back then for drawing cartoons on the back of business cards. He is the source of one of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/04/3ac092f01e360750d83d1beb1112efa0/&#34;&gt;my favorite quotes&lt;/a&gt;. His domain currently resolves to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gapingvoid.com/&#34;&gt;company site&lt;/a&gt;, where he is listed under the staff. It looks like &lt;a href=&#34;https://thejerusalemseries.com/&#34;&gt;he&amp;rsquo;s writing elsewhere&lt;/a&gt; now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MarkTAW&lt;/strong&gt; - Mark blogged about a variety of topics including economics, psychology, marketing, music, etc. For some reason his domain now redirects to Amazon. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any instance of him writing elsewhere recently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WIL WHEATON dot NET&lt;/strong&gt; - Wil Wheaton is of course of Star Trek fame. Followed him mostly for interesting showbiz-adjacent stories. I believe I kept following him until recently during the Trump era, when his content started becoming mostly about anti-Trump rants. That content is fine with me, but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t subscribe to it. His site is still up!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s Journal&lt;/strong&gt; - Gaiman is of course a well-known fantasy writer, even back then. He&amp;rsquo;s still &lt;a href=&#34;https://journal.neilgaiman.com/&#34;&gt;journalling regularly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GELATOMETTI&lt;/strong&gt; - I think this guy was some kind of comic book artist. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://gelatometti.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;blogspot site&lt;/a&gt; is still up, but the content seems different from what the internet archive has, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated since 2005.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fishbowl&lt;/strong&gt; - Another blog by a dev, writing mostly about dev stuff. &lt;a href=&#34;https://fishbowl.pastiche.org/&#34;&gt;The site is still up&lt;/a&gt; and is still being updated. Not sure why I&amp;rsquo;m no longer following his blog, but I don&amp;rsquo;t really subscribe to blogs with mostly dev content anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GirlHacker&amp;rsquo;s Random Log&lt;/strong&gt; - she works in tech, but her blog is more general purpose, things of interest stuff. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.girlhacker.com/&#34;&gt;site is still up&lt;/a&gt;, but she hasn&amp;rsquo;t posted there since 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;in my mind&amp;rsquo;s zen garden&lt;/strong&gt; - this was a blog by a guy called randomguru on a site called RiceBowlJournals, which was kind of like a community for Asian blogs. Both sites are no longer accessible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;kottke&lt;/strong&gt; - kottke.org is still up and running and going strong, still blogging after all these years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tricks of the Trade&lt;/strong&gt; - this was a weblog that posted tips and tricks for different professions. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it lasted very long. The domain currently returns an error.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s actually a few more categories in the blogroll there, but they&amp;rsquo;re mostly gaming related, lifehacks stuff, or webcomics. And this post is fairly long already. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to them in a future post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of old blogs from that blogroll that are still active is actually more than I expected! Though still a lot of them that are dead or inactive now, which says a lot about how pervasive &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/link-rot/&#34;&gt;link rot&lt;/a&gt; is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should make sure to archive a present-day version of my current blogroll and check those sites out around a decade from now, at which time I would hopefully still be blogging!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Sincere Blogging
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/sincere-blogging/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 13:53:08 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/sincere-blogging/</guid>
            <description>
            
            

    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/23ef43058c482c829265e01e331d53c2/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2021-02-03 15:11:53&#34;&gt;3 Feb 2021 3:11pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Please write more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not just on social media, FB, Twitter, whatever. Write on your own sites and blogs. On your tumblrs, wordpresses, whatever. Long-form, rambling, incessant. The world could use more sincere blogging.&lt;/p&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above was written mostly as a response to finding &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2021/02/link-rot/#2&#34;&gt;so many of my friends&amp;rsquo; old and inactive blogs in my RSS reader&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the term I coined there, &amp;ldquo;sincere blogging&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;d define it as any blogging that isn&amp;rsquo;t for any kind of commercial purpose like for selling something or to generate ad revenue. Sincere blogging can be intended as informative or aspirational or purely for self-expression, as long as it&amp;rsquo;s not mainly commercial in purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it served as reminder to me, as I haven&amp;rsquo;t been writing here as often as I could have. I feel like in the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve filtered my writing a bit by only writing blog posts when I feel like I have something longish or elaborate or profound to say, and that led to making it harder to write posts when I was low on energy or whatever. Most probably a consequence of the proliferation of microblogging, as if a post needed to justify it&amp;rsquo;s length so that it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get relegated to the ranks of &amp;ldquo;notes&amp;rdquo;. And I&amp;rsquo;ve been restricting myself to at most one post a day, which is a bit arbitrary and entire meaningless. So, let&amp;rsquo;s change all that, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping. I should be free to post more than once if I want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here I am with my nonsense again, if you&amp;rsquo;ll have me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Not like I ever left, mind you&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Thoughts on Blogging, 2020 Edition, Vol 2
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/thoughts-on-blogging-2020-v2/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/thoughts-on-blogging-2020-v2/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/thoughts-on-blogging-2020-edition/&#34;&gt;Previously&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/05/weeknotes-2020-05-17/&#34;&gt;most recent weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;, I mentioned this &lt;a href=&#34;http://tttthis.com/blog/if-i-could-bring-one-thing-back-to-the-internet-it-would-be-blogs&#34;&gt;post about bringing blogs back to the internet&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23205588&#34;&gt;ensuing discussion on Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some further thoughts on blogging based on the HN discussion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;on-traffic-and-engagement&#34;&gt;On Traffic and Engagement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone mentioned that one of the reasons most people stop blogging is that it feels like there&amp;rsquo;s nobody reading their work. This reminds me of a convo I had with a friend a couple of years back when he saw one of my blog posts. He was getting into content creation himself via a Youtube channel and he asked me what kind of traffic or how many visitors I see on my blog, and I was like &amp;ldquo;You know what, I have no idea!&amp;rdquo; because I never really got into that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to have Google Analytics on the site back when I first migrated to Hugo, because the initial theme I used supported it and why not right? But I got rid of it when I did the redesign because I didn&amp;rsquo;t really use it and didn&amp;rsquo;t care for the additional JavaScript and tracking and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I do have are server-side stats via AWStats, which I do look at maybe once every couple or years or so. For the purposes of this post I decided to pull the server-side stats into a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/stats/awstats/&#34;&gt;page on this site&lt;/a&gt;. So if you check that page, I had 29292 unique visitors for the entirety of 2019. That&amp;rsquo;s around 80 visitors per day. The peak was in 2017, when I had around 135 visitors per day. These are pretty weak numbers I guess? I don&amp;rsquo;t really know, but obviously I haven&amp;rsquo;t gone viral or gotten on the frontpage of HN/reddit or anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s fine! Traffic isn&amp;rsquo;t why I write, and any visitors above 0 are kind of a bonus, since I write mostly for myself! I feel like optimizing for traffic or SEO or whatever would be a bit like selling your soul. I think the whole point of the original post was a nostalgia for the old-style blogs that were writing for the sake of writing, and not to cater to the whims of the search engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do like engagement though, mostly in the form of comments, which is something I have &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/stats/site/&#34;&gt;been tracking before&lt;/a&gt;. (Other than the comments, you can see that most of the stats that I track are &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; stats, i.e. how much I post and so on.) Again, it&amp;rsquo;s not a whole lot, but it&amp;rsquo;s enough to feel a bit rewarding every time a new comment comes in. I recently disabled the comment form for the site (been getting too much spam), but this site can still get new comments via webmention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is nice to know that there are actually people out there reading my words. I do know some friends of mine follow the blog somehow (or maybe they just pick up the posts when I syndicate to Twitter), but it&amp;rsquo;s actually more fun when a stranger leaves a good comment!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;on-self-censorship&#34;&gt;On Self-Censorship&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone on HN mentioned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this is why I don’t have a blog. I have a lot of strong opinions that might be interesting to some people, but I don’t want to miss opportunities because some HR person googled my name and found a post they disagreed with. Or, in the future, not a real person but an algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this is a result of the current climate, where people can get &amp;ldquo;cancelled&amp;rdquo; for things they&amp;rsquo;ve said in the past etc. And I guess that&amp;rsquo;s a valid concern, if you want to live your life that way. But really, how strong are your opinions if you can&amp;rsquo;t stand for them in public?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I write something, on this blog or elsewhere on the internet, it&amp;rsquo;s because I believe it to be true, at that time. (Or I may also be shitposting, but it should be obvious when I&amp;rsquo;m shitposting.) I&amp;rsquo;ve written some political stuff on the blog and elsewhere on the internet before, and I often criticize my country&amp;rsquo;s government when the opportunity arises. This might become problematic recently, as Duterte&amp;rsquo;s administration has started harassing critics by filing charges against them and so on. But even if it comes to that, I like to think that I would be willing to stand by what I write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to think it&amp;rsquo;s because I tend to be right all the time (LOL), but also if I&amp;rsquo;ve said or done or posted something before that would later turn out to be inaccurate or offensive or whatnot, I have no concerns about walking that back and saying &amp;ldquo;Hey, I made a mistake!&amp;rdquo;. That&amp;rsquo;s another advantage running your own blog has over something like Twitter. On Twitter you can only delete your past mistakes. Here I can preserve them, but add a note saying something like &amp;ldquo;My opinion on this has changed&amp;rdquo; or such. I have not yet had a reason to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I think it helps that I largely hold non-controversial opinions and generally try to avoid being an asshole to people, but that&amp;rsquo;s probably the topic of another post entirely.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also the idea that you may want to write things that you don&amp;rsquo;t want associated with you IRL. I can understand that. For those kinds of things, you can make one-off posts using throwaway accounts I guess? For me, from the very beginning of my internet presence, I haven&amp;rsquo;t considered anonymizing or protecting my content. My geocities URL had my full name in it for example (and so does this domain!). But I have made some throwaway posts that aren&amp;rsquo;t tied to me, for example when talking about sensitive information or such. But I think for a large majority of the content a regular person would post, this isn&amp;rsquo;t really necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;on-originality&#34;&gt;On Originality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often notice when I start writing on a particular topic, I learn more about my thoughts and opinions of it and realize my thoughts are wrong or not really novel. Halfway in I give up since I feel like, &amp;ldquo;oh, this actually isn&amp;rsquo;t really adding anything new to the conversation&amp;rdquo;. Then I leave with a new humbleness about my beliefs but also a sense of &amp;ldquo;when am I actually going to know enough to warrant writing about it?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in a blogging lull around 2010-2015 (as seen on &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/stats/site/&#34;&gt;the stats page&lt;/a&gt;!) and thinking of getting back into it and writing more software-related content, but I mentioned to a friend that I was worried that the internet was already oversaturated with such writers/bloggers and I would not have anything original to contribute. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember his exact words, but it was one of the best pieces of writing advice I had ever gotten, something along the lines of: &amp;ldquo;No one else is going to be writing with your perspective and your point of view, so no matter what, you are bringing something to the table.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;on-discoverability&#34;&gt;On Discoverability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people on the HN thread said that Google no longer surfaces older blog content. I anecdotally know this to be not true, because a Google search for the terms &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=killer%20killer&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;killer-killer&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=pasmado&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;pasmado&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; still shows posts from my blog from 2008 on the first page. I suspect this is because my blog has been continuously updated since 2002, hence my posts never fall &amp;ldquo;out of rotation&amp;rdquo;? Is that a thing? Who knows! SEO, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original post was correct however in that it is difficult to find old-school blog content if you are searching specifically for that kind of thing. I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/04/fe45adb8c24e654605b9906dea2df749/&#34;&gt;before&lt;/a&gt; that I want some kind of indieweb federated search focused on searching content from &amp;ldquo;indie&amp;rdquo; blogs (for lack of a better term. We need a better term?). Maybe someday I&amp;rsquo;d write down how I imagine that would work. And implement it maybe? IDK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until then, there are still a lot of blogs around, if you know where to look. One of my favorite avenues is Kicks Condors&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickscondor.com/hrefhunt/&#34;&gt;monthly HrefHunt updates&lt;/a&gt;. And I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned before, but whenever anyone posts anything remotely nostalgic about old-school blogging on Hacker News, the comments are always full of links to blogs. There&amp;rsquo;s specialized subreddits like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/SpartanWeb/&#34;&gt;r/SpartanWeb&lt;/a&gt; (not many users!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you run a blog, you can help by having a page where you list other blogs you like! Some kind of roll call, but for blogs. Like&amp;hellip; a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/blogroll/&#34;&gt;blogroll&lt;/a&gt;? And if they make a post you like, share it on your blog, and maybe on other social media channels too! Us indie and old-school bloggers need to have each other backs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;more-to-come&#34;&gt;More To Come&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am 99.9999% sure this is not the last time I&amp;rsquo;m going to blog about blogging.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Thoughts on Blogging, 2020 Edition
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/thoughts-on-blogging-2020-edition/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/thoughts-on-blogging-2020-edition/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I found this great article the other week about &lt;a href=&#34;https://guzey.com/personal/why-have-a-blog/&#34;&gt;Why You Should Start A Blog Right Now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing is absolutely worth a read, but my favorite part is at the start where he enumerates a list of reasons why he wrote particular posts, and it sent me down a rabbit hole again of evaluating why I write on this blog, and whether it was an endeavor worth continuing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably, having a blog has a lot of possible benefits, but the one important for me personally are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it helps me clarify step through my own thoughts and understand my own thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it serves as an archive of my state of mind at the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it helps me improve my own writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably, you can also use a blog to advance your career, build a brand/reputation, finding an audience, etc. And those are fine, but for me they are only incidentals, nice-to-haves. Fundamentally, I still always write for myself first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, I said to myself, why write in public at all? If those three reasons are the most important, then something like &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/private-writing/&#34;&gt;private writing&lt;/a&gt; should already suffice. I even asked my self the very same question back in 2005 at the end of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/11/why-do-i-blog/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;, and at that time I had no answer. Today I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write in public because we as humans have so much in common, even if we aren&amp;rsquo;t aware of it. And while writing down one&amp;rsquo;s own thoughts or opinions or everyday happenings may seem like it would be entirely uninteresting to the average reader, there will always be some aspect of your stories that will resonate with someone else, somewhere, because of that shared human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, everyone can have a platform for writing, whether it&amp;rsquo;s in one of the social media silos or your own site like this one, so the whole &amp;ldquo;writing in public&amp;rdquo; thing isn&amp;rsquo;t so novel anymore. But even in this age, not everyone chooses to participate in social media, not everyone tweets or posts all the time, and that&amp;rsquo;s fine. I can accept that writing in public isn&amp;rsquo;t for everyone. But to have that voice, that ability to express yourself and share your human experience with others, to have stories to share and advice to dispense and objections to raise - to have it and not to exercise it in a meaningful way? For me that seems a waste. And so I write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I actually haven&amp;rsquo;t been writing much the past couple of weeks, aside from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/weeknotes&#34;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;. I pumped out a couple of longish and in my mind pretty good posts early in the month (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/old-web/&#34;&gt;Tales of the Old Web&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/burnout/&#34;&gt;Burnout&lt;/a&gt;), but after that I found myself struggling to put some new ones together. Somehow in my mind I became trapped in the idea that I needed to have these long, profound, well-researched essays as posts. Browsing blogs like Alexey Guzey&amp;rsquo;s (author of the post linked at the start of this one) certainly hasn&amp;rsquo;t helped - on his &lt;a href=&#34;https://guzey.com/notes/&#34;&gt;notes page&lt;/a&gt; he mentions that some of his better posts take upwards of 100+ hours to write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I kind of fell into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/comparison-is-the-thief-of-joy/&#34;&gt;trap of comparison&lt;/a&gt; and wanted to be writing thesis papers? Except that&amp;rsquo;s not really my style. I can probably churn out some longer pieces if they&amp;rsquo;ve been formulating in my head for a while, but for the most part, my regular blogging consists of thoughts-in-the-moment, a snapshot of where my thinking is at that time, to be built upon and to be evolved later on. And I think that&amp;rsquo;s fine, I think everyone has their own unique writing/blogging style and voice that they need to develop to see what works best for them. Maybe as time goes on, I will tend more towards longer-form posts, but for now I have to listen to my own advice and remember that &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/not-all-posts-have-to-be-profound/&#34;&gt;not all posts have to be profound&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past few years or so, and especially since I got interested in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/indieweb/&#34;&gt;Indieweb stuff&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve also been more on the lookout for interesting blogs to read. Personal blogs, none of that &amp;ldquo;professional blogger&amp;rdquo; crap. There&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of interesting sites out there, a lot of them long-running ones even. With the rise of social media silos, having personal websites and blogs hasn&amp;rsquo;t really gotten mainstream attention, but there&amp;rsquo;s still plenty of people writing out there. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve added more blogs to my RSS reader over the past 12 months than I have over the preceding 5ish years or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It saddens me a bit that among people of my cohort I am one among very few who are (still) actively blogging. I have a large folder of RSS feeds named &amp;ldquo;people I know&amp;rdquo;, many of them have tried blogging at some point or another, and all of those links are inactive or even inaccessible. Friends: please write more! You can revive your old sites if you like, you don&amp;rsquo;t even have to explain!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have a bunch of reorganizing my RSS feeds to do, but I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to put enough feeds into a folder called &amp;ldquo;blogroll&amp;rdquo; that seems suitable for sharing, so I created a new &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/blogroll&#34;&gt;Blogroll page&lt;/a&gt; where you can see some of the blogs I follow. Very few of these are people I know IRL, mostly I just stumbled upon their blogs via some method or other. Many of them are tech-related though not all of them are. All are reasonably active. I thought about tagging or categorizing them somehow, but it&amp;rsquo;s rude to put people into boxes, so maybe it&amp;rsquo;s rude to do that for their websites too, just let people be people and let blogs be blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to maintain an older blogroll back in the day, but it seems that has already been lost to the dustbin of history, so this one is brand new and built from scratch. (If I find the older one, I might put it on that page too as a record of history.) As with many other things on the site, the blogroll is perpetually under renovation, so if you find (or have) a personal blog that you think I might find interesting, feel free to tell me about it and maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll add it there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Technical note: The blogroll listing is automatically imported from a JSON-formatted OPML file. I got the idea from &lt;a href=&#34;https://jlelse.blog/dev/auto-blogroll-hugo/&#34;&gt;this post by jlelse&lt;/a&gt;, and coincidentally he is also on the blogroll.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me: I&amp;rsquo;m having trouble writing long-form posts recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also me: Hey, I wrote a thousand words on blogging without thinking about it!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>NaBloPoMo Epilogue
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/nablopomo-epilogue/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/nablopomo-epilogue/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;So NaBloPoMo complete, no big deal. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t much of a challenge since blogging every day for a month is something that I&amp;rsquo;ve done multiple times over the past couple of years. It comes out to around 15,900 words written in November, not counting this post. Definitely not as big a thing as completing nanowrimo for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing on a regular basis is great, and generally a reasonable use of your time. But the thing about writing daily though is that like any activity that you want to do on a regular basis, you don&amp;rsquo;t always have the energy for it. I could probably keep up the daily posting indefinitely, if blogging were the only thing I was wanted to be doing, but alas that is not true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not to say I&amp;rsquo;m going to stop posting regularly of course, just that I don&amp;rsquo;t commit myself to doing it every day. The decade&amp;rsquo;s end is coming up, and for sure there&amp;rsquo;s going to be something to be said about that. There are also some longer posts I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to write, but those are more likely to come after the turn of the year, depending on how my own musings turn out. So chances are that posts still come out on a semi-regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>One Year with Hugo: Highs and Lows
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/one-year-with-hugo/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 19:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/one-year-with-hugo/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;It was a bit more than a year ago that I decided to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/site-migration-from-wordpress-to-hugo/&#34;&gt;haphazardly and suddenly migrate from Wordpress to Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a good time to look back and reflect on that decision and consider where we are now, and how to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am extremely happy with the site&amp;rsquo;s browser performance. It currently scores an insanely high 96 on &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/speed/pagespeed/insights/?url=https%3A%2F%2Froytang.net&#34;&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s Pagespeed tool&lt;/a&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I I know how to close the remaining 4% gap. (I just need to get around to it.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;generally all the advantages listed in the original post a year ago. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly happy with managing the posts through the file system, especially with a decent editor like VS Code. I don&amp;rsquo;t miss Wordpress&amp;rsquo;s clunky editor at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The main sticking point right now is that the build time is really high. I have a Travis build script setup that automatically builds the hugo site from source whenever I push a new commit, then the output is committed to a second repo, which is the one deployed to the live site every 15 minutes. This build right now takes on average around 8 mins, which is ridiculous. The hugo build itself takes around 3 mins, the rest is copying files and git clones and push and so on. The build times really skyrocketed when I did the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/archive-of-my-own/&#34;&gt;social media archiving&lt;/a&gt;, since the number of markdown files skyrocketed from around 1000 to almost 16,000. For sure, a lot of it is the fault of the theme I am using on this site, because I am adding a lot of features like static comments, image resizing, monthly archives, a bunch of taxonomies, and so on. I don&amp;rsquo;t blame Hugo at all, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure any other static site generator would simply choke on the amount of posts I have. There are surely a lot of optimizations that can be done, but even if I manage to pare down the template generation to bare minimum, I am most probably hitting the limits on disk I/O. As mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io/t/performance-expectations-for-large-number-of-pages/21887&#34;&gt;this discussion I had on the Hugo forums&lt;/a&gt;, simply copying the entire content folder already takes 30 seconds on my local computer, so that is the bare minimum I could go. This is not an intolerable problem, but it means I don&amp;rsquo;t have immediate feedback when I push a post, it can take at least 15 minutes or more for recent changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are also a number of dynamic features I want to implement, which are impossible with just a static website. I have a python web app backing the static hugo site which I use for things like search, comments, and so on, but basically there is nontrivial effort when I want to implement new things. This is even less of an issue than the last one, mostly because I enjoy working with Python anyway lol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The build performance is such a big issue for me that I briefly considered the option of migrating back to Wordpress. Ha! I&amp;rsquo;m not ruling it out, but the fact is I find managing posts through the Wordpress interface to be extremely clunky, especially compared to my current set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another option would be to write my own database-backed webapp. This is something I&amp;rsquo;ve done before after all, and again, I enjoy working on Python anyway. But it&amp;rsquo;s a lot of work, so maybe shelve that for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to stay with my current static hugo + dynamic python support, and try to optimize the build time as much as I can. I will probably be on the look out for possible alternative solutions, some other blogging software perhaps, or some other hybrid approach.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>A Cradle for Imperfect Thoughts
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/a-cradle-for-imperfect-thoughts/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/a-cradle-for-imperfect-thoughts/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A lot of people seem to think that blogging as an activity is about writing a well-thought out first draft, revising and researching and revising again until the post is perfected, then finally hitting publish (then possibly realize you had some editing errors and upadating and republishing). I tend to think this sort of perfectionism holds one back, I prefer to publish even when thoughts are yet half-formed and maybe even incomplete, laying the groundwork for revisiting the topic in a later post. One&amp;rsquo;s thoughts or positions on certain issues aren&amp;rsquo;t always set in stone, it can be helpful sometimes to commit to writing your thoughts as they are, in the moment, and iterating over them over a longer stretch of time, giving you a view into the history and evolution of your thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a blog after all, if not a repository of your thoughts and ideas as they were in the moment, a history of your thinking through the years?&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>NaBloPoMo: Just Write
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/nablopomo/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/nablopomo/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Apparently, &lt;a href=&#34;http://nablopomoguideunofficial.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;NaBloPoMo&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;em&gt;National Blog Posting Month&lt;/em&gt;) is a thing. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite roll off the tongue as the original &lt;em&gt;Nanowrimo&lt;/em&gt; (which was already a tough sell), but I think it&amp;rsquo;s a worthy endeavor nonetheless. Some friends were inviting me to do Nanowrimo again this year, but due to general life and busyness and other things, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to prep. I could just wing it (maybe I still will!), but that likely leads to disaster! Let&amp;rsquo;s do this easier challenge instead. Easier because I&amp;rsquo;ve already done daily posting on multiple months this year, and also in comparison to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/inktober-2019/&#34;&gt;last month&amp;rsquo;s challenge&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some helpful tips and reminders for those who want to bring blogging back (did it ever really leave?):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; (noun) is series of entries, called &lt;em&gt;blog posts&lt;/em&gt;, often primarily presented in reverse chronological order. A &lt;em&gt;blog post&lt;/em&gt; (noun) or simply a post is a single entry in a blog, usually consisting of a title, a date, and some content in either text or some other media. To &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; (verb) is to write one or more posts on a blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog posts can be anything you want them to be. They can be short or long. They can be focused on a particular topic, or discuss multiple topics, or be about no one topic in particular. They can have a title or have no title. They can be posted in the past, in the present or in the future. The sky&amp;rsquo;s the limit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just write. Some may struggle with putting their thoughts into words because they&amp;rsquo;re always looking for the perfect words or structure. Your posts don&amp;rsquo;t have to be the best, impeccable writing. They can written first and then improved upon. The goal of an exercise like this one or Nanowrimo is to force you into the habit of writing freely and without filter, to learn to embrace the imperfect. So just write.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Struggling to find something to write about? Here are some prompts, choose one:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what have you been watching/reading lately?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s something you tried recently?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what recent accomplishments are you proud of?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s a recent failure you experienced and what did you learn from it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when was the last time a friend asked you for advice, and what did you tell him?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when was the last time someone exceeded your expectations?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what happened the last time you went to a government office to get something done?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s something you do or enjoy that none of your friends do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what always annoys you when people ask about it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what recent unexpected find made you happy?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;try to draw a horse. then, mock your drawing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what recent article did you read that really impressed you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what new blogs or social media accounts have you recently discovered and found interesting?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s your strategy for saving money?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s a recent restaurant meal you really liked? write a review!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what&amp;rsquo;s a recent government decision you think was really good or really bad? discuss!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy blogging!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Internet Commercialization
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/internet-commercialization/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/08/internet-commercialization/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;h3 id=&#34;0&#34;&gt;0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A while back, I read this post from 2015: &lt;a href=&#34;http://veekaybee.github.io/2015/07/28/who-is-doing-this-to-my-internet/&#34;&gt;Who is doing this to my internet?&lt;/a&gt; lamenting the changing nature of the internet due to commercialization and advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit funny that the OP was lamenting about the &amp;ldquo;good old days&amp;rdquo; of the internet back in &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, when by then the big social media networks like Facebook and Twitter were already relatively well-entrenched. When I think of the &amp;ldquo;good old days&amp;rdquo; of the internet I tend to harken back pre-social media to the heyday of blogging around 2005-2008 maybe? Those were times when instead of everybody holed up in social media silos, there were still a lot of people running independent websites and blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commercialization and advertising pretty much ruined blogging too, well before the silos started consolidating people&amp;rsquo;s personal writings into their title-less posts and shares and retweets. When people caught on that you could run advertising on your blogs and earn money from increasing traffic, there began a trend of content writers who would write for money. Even now you can see job listings on sites like Upwork for people needed to write content for blogs, with the aim of earning money off advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest and tell you I thought about this myself, and added the Google Adsense to the blog back in the day. But that would never really have worked out for me, as to make money off blogging you have to find a niche and to focus on that topic and be writing about that constantly and be doing SEO and marketing to drive the traffic to you site. Being focused to one topic and marketing are kind of very off-brand for me. I like being able to write about whatever I want and whatever comes to mind. I did try spinning off some dedicated blogs at some point, for topics like for &lt;a href=&#34;http://royondjango.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Django programming&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2007/09/roy-on-magic/&#34;&gt;Magic the Gathering&lt;/a&gt;, and I even made a &lt;a href=&#34;https://ireadcomicbooks.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;comic-book focused tumblr&lt;/a&gt;. The efforts never last too long. Like I said, focus doesn&amp;rsquo;t become me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media killed blogging (or tried to anyway), but advertising ruined blogging in the same way it ruined social media. People thought they could earn money, so they changed what they posted to try to earn more views/followers/clicks. It became less about being genuine (if it ever was) and more about pandering to a wider audience and driving traffic. There was a rise in clickbait and polarizing headlines and replicating content from other sites. Things like truth or originality didn&amp;rsquo;t matter, clicks and views did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not begrudging anyone their right to try to earn a living. I just wish the business model didn&amp;rsquo;t have to be so annoying lol. The advertising business model existed before the internet of course, and was good enough to drive &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; industries like radio and television. So when people wanted to start making money off the internet, it was easy to adopt the same model. People online were used to other people providing content for free after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What other business models could exist on the internet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s hiding content behind a paywall, which is the approach of newspapers like the New York Times or the Washington Post or sites like Medium. That kind of thing gets annoying too and commercialization can ruin the site as well. I recently read &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.elementary.io/welcome-to-the-new-blog/&#34;&gt;this writeup&lt;/a&gt; about how a company moved their blog away from Medium because it gradually became a worse proposition as they started to monetize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at free-to-play gaming, there&amp;rsquo;s one other model that I think could work: microtransactions. I mean something like cosmetics and content packs and making money off &amp;ldquo;whales&amp;rdquo;, the same way games like Hearthstone and Magic Arena does it. Magic Arena&amp;rsquo;s model doesn&amp;rsquo;t annoy me at all. I don&amp;rsquo;t play regularly enough to want to buy things and am content just being free-to-play. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop other people from making purchases for cosmetics and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I realize I might not enjoy that world either. Imagine if Twitter or Instagram had cosmetic purchases where you could buy like stuff to decorate your profile page or custom frames for your posts or something like that. I think it would be a huge hit among some people, at the same time be really annoying for other people (people like me lol).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess what I&amp;rsquo;m saying is: I wish we could live in an (online) world where people weren&amp;rsquo;t constantly trying to make money off each other. I realize that this comes from a position of privilege - of having enough so that I don&amp;rsquo;t need to be thinking about earning money all the time. I realize that&amp;rsquo;s not the world works and that commercialization is a sad reality that I have to live with, but a man can dream.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Defy Categorization
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/defy-categorization/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/05/defy-categorization/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I follow a lot of strangers &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang&#34;&gt;over on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, each one usually for a different reason that I find interesting. Sometimes they follow me back for one reason or another, and it gives me a little bit of anxiety. The anxiety is because here is this person whose content I like, who followed me back probably because of an interaction we had, and she is expecting that my tweets will be more of the same kind of content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But often it&amp;rsquo;s not. I don&amp;rsquo;t write about the same kind of thing all the time - one only needs to look at this blog to see that. I write on a variety of topics that interest me, from &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/software-development/&#34;&gt;stuff I learn working as a software developer&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/movies/&#34;&gt;movies&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/games/&#34;&gt;games&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/tv/&#34;&gt;tv shows&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/philippines/&#34;&gt;things that are going on in my country&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/quotes/&#34;&gt;quotes I like&lt;/a&gt; and all other kinds of stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while I considered that blogging might be more effective if I had a more focused blog, instead of this chaotic willy-nilly mess I&amp;rsquo;ve refused to give up on since 2002. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried starting topic-centered blogs before, about stuff like &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/mtg/&#34;&gt;Magic the Gathering&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/comics/&#34;&gt;comic books&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/royondjango/&#34;&gt;software development using Django&lt;/a&gt;, but most of those efforts collpased and I just absorbed the contents back into this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think having a focused blog depends really on your goals. Like, if your goal is to have a blog with a lot of followers and to grow your audience and to monetize through ads or newsletters or other methods, then focused, specific content is the way to go. But for me and this blog, as I like to remind myself, I&amp;rsquo;m writing largely for myself. This blog and this website are my presence on the internet, more than any social media account. Thus, it should reflect all my interests in totality, not just the ones that I can monetize or get me more work or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of how sometimes on Twitter famous people like tech personalities will comment on something like politics and they&amp;rsquo;ll get people who are disagreeable and go &amp;ldquo;I follow you for your tech content, please keep your politics out of this&amp;rdquo;, which is ridiculous. Just because a person is primarily known for a certain thing doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean their opinions and personalities can be limited to that thing only and for all time. People are multi-faceted, they have many views and many interests and they should be allowed to express themselves on whatever topic they like (within reasonable limits obviously no to hate speech thanks.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a barely related blog note: something I&amp;rsquo;ve been putting off for a while, I merged categories and tags on this blog. It just seems to make more sense. I probably broke some links somewhere though, I&amp;rsquo;ll figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Four Hundred Thousand Words
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/four-hundred-thousand-words/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/03/four-hundred-thousand-words/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Sometime in the last week, I broke past four hundred thousand words total on this blog, as noted on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/archives/&#34;&gt;archive page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four hundred thousand words! That number sounds insane for some reason. Over 17 years of blogging, that&amp;rsquo;s an average of 23,500+ words a year. I could have written like 17 short stories or 8ish novelettes or 3-4 decently sized novels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is just me navel-gazing over that number. Four hundred thousand! In mid-March, there&amp;rsquo;s gonna be another milestone too - we&amp;rsquo;re gonna hit 1,000 posts total (assuming I don&amp;rsquo;t quit blogging daily before then). I should get an achievement somehow!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Broken Streak
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/broken-streak/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/broken-streak/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I thought I had a post scheduled yesterday, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t. That broke a continuous streak of 124 days of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/daily-blogging/&#34;&gt;daily blogging&lt;/a&gt;. I thought about writing a post and publishing it retroactively, but that seems like the kind of BS Type A behavior I kind of want to avoid these days. At least I did a lot better than the last time I tried daily blogging in October 2006, when I only managed &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/10/&#34;&gt;23 posts for the month&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the bright side, that gave me something easy to write about today. And now that I&amp;rsquo;ve broken the streak I thought, &amp;ldquo;Does this mean I can go back to an irregular blogging schedule?&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s like the way Kenshin was wondering if he had to return to the vagabond life after he thought he was forced to kill Chou using a regular blade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, as I mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/dont-break-the-chain/&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Break the Chain&lt;/a&gt;, breaking streaks are inevitable, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you stop. I feel like the daily blogging has generally been a net positive so far, so it&amp;rsquo;s something that&amp;rsquo;s gonna go on, as much as possible. Here&amp;rsquo;s to hoping I don&amp;rsquo;t screw up and immediately miss tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s post as well.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Not all posts have to be profound
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/not-all-posts-have-to-be-profound/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/not-all-posts-have-to-be-profound/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I think that&amp;rsquo;s one of the reasons why it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to keep up a blog. Blogs feel a bit like they have to be long-form, highly profound, useful or informative pieces or prose that a wide audience can appreciate. We don&amp;rsquo;t have this same pressure when posting to other social media like Twitter or Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to think of a blog (or this blog at least, at this moment) as a living, evolving thing, with each post capturing a single moment in a timeline, building upon previous thoughts, helping us see how the author&amp;rsquo;s thinking changes with time. There is no need for each post to be perfect, only that they be honest.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Daily Blogging
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/daily-blogging/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/daily-blogging/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Looking at my &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/archives&#34;&gt;archives&lt;/a&gt;, I was blogging regularly from 2005-2009, mostly because I was really active in competitive &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/categories/magic-the-gathering/&#34;&gt;MTG&lt;/a&gt; during that time. Starting 2010, my blogging activity started to taper off, with less than 60 posts until 2015. I tried to revive the habit around mid-2016, posting at least once a week, but the writing slowed down again around April this year (coinciding with one of the more busy periods for me work-wise). Starting in October I had a bit more free time so I decided to fire on all cylinders again. Instead of the previous 1-2 posts per week I was going for in 2016, this time I would go for posting every day. Not even every weekday, but seven days a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried this, as an experiment, back in &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/10/i-will-blog-every-day/&#34;&gt;October of 2006&lt;/a&gt;, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t last the month with the habit (though I did continue to post regularly for the next few years).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is kind of secondhand-blog-linking, but the post [Seth Godin Explains Why You Should Blog Daily] (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cjchilvers.com/blog/seth-godin-explains-why-you-should-blog-daily&#34;&gt;https://www.cjchilvers.com/blog/seth-godin-explains-why-you-should-blog-daily&lt;/a&gt;) explains well the advantages of posting daily:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Everyone should write a blog, every day, even if no one reads it. There’s countless reasons why it’s a good idea and I can’t think of one reason it’s a bad idea.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you know you have to write a blog post tomorrow, something in writing, something that will be around 6 months from now, about something in the world, you will start looking for something in the world to to write about. You will seek to notice something interesting and to say something creative about it. Well, isn’t that all we’re looking for? The best practice of generously sharing what you notice about the world is exactly the antidote for your fear.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first fear of course, is: do I actually have enough material, enough stuff to write about on a daily basis? The article above mentions that the mere act of committing to daily writing means you will naturally tend towards notcing more things and having more opinions and thus more things to write about. But I was skeptical, since I had tried the regular writing before and it didn&amp;rsquo;t really stick. One thing that helped however was that since 2016 I&amp;rsquo;ve been regularly listing down blog post ideas. I got this idea from &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesaltucher.com/2014/05/the-ultimate-guide-for-becoming-an-idea-machine/&#34;&gt;James Altucher&amp;rsquo;s post about becoming an idea machine&lt;/a&gt; where he recommend&amp;rsquo;s thinking of 10 ideas daily. I did start out writing 10 blog post ideas every day, but that tapered off after a while because I was only posting a couple of times I week, I had far too many ideas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all of those ideas would be good enough to be posts of course. I wrote up a few posts first, creating a buffer of posts that could be scheduled in advance. I started posting daily on the second week of October, and have kept it up since, I&amp;rsquo;m at more than 60 posts now, so the habit has already stuck longer than the last attempt. I find that between the long list of post ideas I already had (some 600+ in total), &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/benefits-of-walking/&#34;&gt;my daily walks&lt;/a&gt; and the fact that &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/expanding-horizons/&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a voracious internet reader&lt;/a&gt;, it was actually quite easy to maintain a continuous stream of posts to write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t spend too much time on each post, maybe 30 minutes at most, sometimes much less. On a good day I can knock off up to five posts. I find that most of my recent posts clock in under 1,000 words, which I think is perfectly reasonable. I think my increased participation in internet debates back during the 2016 election period also made me more willing to post opinions online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re writing to become a &amp;ldquo;professional blogger&amp;rdquo; of some sort, or otherwise trying to optimize for engagement or such, &lt;a href=&#34;https://smartblogger.com/posting-every-day/&#34;&gt;daily posting might not be such a good idea&lt;/a&gt;. The front page of this blog changes every day, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have a search function at the moment, so it&amp;rsquo;s not straightforward to find something you miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I of course write mostly for myself, though I do appreciate it when I find out people are reading the blog. I prefer posts that I can look back to in a few years to remember what was going on with me at the time. I try to write about things I&amp;rsquo;m doing, shows I&amp;rsquo;m watching, projects I&amp;rsquo;m trying out, games I&amp;rsquo;m playing, opinions on current events, and generally random thoughts going through my head and so on. I find that the daily writing, like the daily walking, helps improve my thinking processes. And it often encourages me to be a bit more experimental - I can try things out and even if I fail, the floor is that I have a story for a blog post. There is also less pressure for new posts to be super deep or meaningful or otherwise with my daily blogging, there is no room for perfectionism to get in the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how long I can keep this up on a daily basis. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to revisit this after a year maybe to see how far I&amp;rsquo;ve gone.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Blogging and the Decentralized Internet
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/08/blogging-and-the-decentralized-internet/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 15:36:32 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/08/blogging-and-the-decentralized-internet/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;(Somehow I now have a series of posts about blogging in 2018. Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2017/06/blogging-and-social-media/&#34;&gt;the first one&lt;/a&gt;. Two is a series, right?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://np.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/96ug3n/vimeo_just_decided_to_remove_content_from/e43gtq8/?context=1&#34;&gt;Great comment&lt;/a&gt; the other day on reddit (found via r/bestof), in response to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2018/8/9/17669144/twitter-alex-jones-jack-dorsey-del-harvey&#34;&gt;Twitter&amp;rsquo;s inaction vs Alex Jones&lt;/a&gt;. Quoting part of the comment:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    How can the OG generation of web users possibly hope to maintain the Internet as a free and decentralized medium when a growing majority &lt;em&gt;of the current userbase&lt;/em&gt; accept centralization of content and audience, as not only the status quo but as the way things &lt;em&gt;should be&lt;/em&gt;? To such an extent that they make the perverse argument that YouTube shouldn&#39;t be able to ban people for inciting violence?
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    2007 (or possibly earlier) was the end of the personal Internet and the beginning of the corporate silo Internet. People from 1997 would be totally confused that everyone visits ONE SITE to participate in forum discussions. The 1997 way of doing things would be two hundred different forums for subject interests and if you wanted to find another one you would have to Ask Jeeves or use a web ring. People from 1997 would be &lt;em&gt;appalled&lt;/em&gt; that Reddit not only doesn&#39;t ban Stormfront, we let them run communities &lt;em&gt;under our noses&lt;/em&gt; like redpill and the D (or gradually take them over, like tumblrinaction and cringepics). But the bitterness in our cup, we mixed for ourselves: this is the logical consequence of &#34;wouldn&#39;t it be great if all forums were just a click away from each other?&#34; Why have forums when you can have THE forum? And then let&#39;s put a corporation in charge of it, a corporation that&#39;s too much of a fucking pussy to actually take action against evil that&#39;s happening on their watch -- except sporadically, hypocritically and only when the media spotlight burns too bright.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    So, sure, the Jones defenders are half right in that the modern internet is a corruption of the original Dream of the Web: far from a decentralized &#34;web&#34; of users, everything now is a natural monopoly, and the corporations rent the actual function of the Internet back to us, piecemeal. We are no longer a web, but a series of watering holes.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I miss the decentralized internet of 2007 that the comment above alludes to. A few weeks ago I was cleaning up some old files and found a list of blogs I used to follow. Most of them are dead now, either unavailable or no updates in years. Probably the owners thought &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s the point&amp;rdquo; and started hanging out in one of the corporate silos instead. Some of them were people I knew IRL, while others were strangers I met or online or whose blogs I stumbled upon and found interesting enough to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slight tangent 1: Hill I am willing to die on: a &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; is a website with a series of posts, often reverse chronological nature. A &lt;em&gt;blog post&lt;/em&gt; is a single post on a blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understandably, running and maintaining your own blog isn&amp;rsquo;t for everybody; it&amp;rsquo;s much easier to set up a Facebook page or a Twitter account or a subreddit and just post everything there, and that&amp;rsquo;s fine. But what&amp;rsquo;s disappointing is the lack of open interoperability between these channels that makes it difficult for smaller sites to operate independently of the large behemonths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slight tangent 2: I miss RSS, I really wish it took off. I mean, fundamentally, sites like Facebook and Twitter aren&amp;rsquo;t that much different from feedreaders of yore (Okay, I still use a feedreader, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://feedly.com/&#34;&gt;Feedly&lt;/a&gt;), except we&amp;rsquo;d probably need to expand the protocol to standardize on reply/commenting systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.5. If you want to give RSS a slight boost, &lt;a href=&#34;https://opml.glitch.me/&#34;&gt;there&amp;rsquo;s a tool&lt;/a&gt; I found recently that lets you export URLs from your twitter follows to an OPML that you can import to an RSS reader. It&amp;rsquo;s net!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With Twitter&amp;rsquo;s current Alex Jones problem and the recent troubles at Facebook, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking into some interesting approaches to decentralized/federated social media. One that I found interesting is &lt;a href=&#34;https://joinmastodon.org/&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;. I currently have an account, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.social/@roytang&#34;&gt;@roytang@mastodon.social&lt;/a&gt;, not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll migrate to a different server at some point. It&amp;rsquo;s much less toxic than Twitter, and I&amp;rsquo;m especially fond of their &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.joinmastodon.org/2018/07/cage-the-mastodon/&#34;&gt;declared philosophy re: abuse and harassment&lt;/a&gt;. However, there isn&amp;rsquo;t that much interesting content yet, at least as far as I can tell. If you know of someone interesting to follow on Mastodon, tell me about it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.5. Andy Baio of &lt;a href=&#34;https://waxy.org/&#34;&gt;waxy.org&lt;/a&gt; recently posted an interesting &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/waxpancake/status/1027793032676962305&#34;&gt;tweetstorm talking about how it was in the early days of Twitter and how Mastodon feels by comparison&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I run a personal blog with very few readers (I&amp;rsquo;m fine with that), and I use social media cross-posting to notify Twitter followers and Facebook friends when I have new posts. Or at least I used to, until Facebook recently pulled the plug on their APIs that now make it impossible to autopost from Twitter. I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to stop crossposting altogether lol. (At the very least I know there&amp;rsquo;s at least one person that reads my blog without me posting the link to Facebook, so that&amp;rsquo;s nice.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a kind of relevant Oatmeal comic about this &lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/reaching_people&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. (Not that I produce anywhere near as good content as Oatmeal does but w/e)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;7&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All hope is not lost though, there are still people out there blogging tirelessly. A while back I found quite a few interesting blogs from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchi.mp/kottke/blogging-is-not-dead-edition-2575912502&#34;&gt;Kottke post&lt;/a&gt;. One of the ones I like best is &lt;a href=&#34;https://karigee.com/&#34;&gt;karigee.com&lt;/a&gt;, and she puts it quite well as to why she still blogs (this quote also conveniently quoted in the same Kottke post above):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;wp-block-quote&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    I also keep it out of spite, because I refuse to let social media take everything. Those shapeless, formless platforms haven&#39;t earned it and don&#39;t deserve it. I&#39;ve blogged about this many times, but I still believe it: When I log into Facebook, I see Facebook. When I visit your blog, I see you.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s highly unlikely that we get anything close to the decentralized internet back. The internet trend of megacorps and centralization and consolidation is reflective of real-life trends after all (capitalism and economics of scale and mass consumerism and all that seem to point in this direction.) But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we can&amp;rsquo;t keep writing our blogs.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Blogging and Social Media
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/blogging-and-social-media/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 01:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/06/blogging-and-social-media/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging too much recently. I got busy for a while and had to skip a few weeks, and then general laziness prevented me from resuming a regular posting schedule. (Hopefully that ends now.) Most of the time my ranting was on social media, which got me thinking: Is writing on your own blog still useful in this day and age of social media?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging for a long time &amp;ndash; my archives say 2002 &amp;ndash; waaay before Facebook or even Twitter came around. If for some reason you felt like digging through my older posts you&amp;rsquo;d find that I kind of used the blog like Twitter or FB: I&amp;rsquo;d have some short posts, updates about what&amp;rsquo;s going on, share some links, and so on. These days we have social media for that, so why blog at all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, social media is a perfectly valid channel to post your thoughts obviously. But I feel like blogging serves a different purpose. And when I say blogging, I mean on a platform dedicated to blogging, preferably on your own server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the obvious differences/advantages of blogging:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogs are publicly accessible commentary. Contrast this with Facebook, which I use mostly for interacting only with family and friends. I sometimes make some FB posts public, but mostly on request because people want to share it. It would make more sense for me to have such content on the blog so that people can share it directly without me having to fiddle with post privacy settings on FB.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogs are long-form. Contrast this with Twitter&amp;rsquo;s post-length limitation and even Facebook where I also tend to spout out one-liners or short paragraphs. I like a blog post for longer, more detailed content. Twitter users use workarounds like the &amp;ldquo;1/N&amp;rdquo; format to post longer text content, but I&amp;rsquo;m not really a big fan of that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A blog should contain your own content. Contrast this with almost all social media where your own content is interspersed with retweets, shares, reblogs, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogs are searchable, either using your internal search form (I have one on the sidebar!) or via Google search. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit annoying sometimes trying to scroll through your FB or Twitter timeline trying to find something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The above point means social media posts feel a lot more&amp;hellip;  ephemeral, maybe? I consider blog posts a lot more &amp;ldquo;permanent&amp;rdquo;, while social media are more of &amp;ldquo;at this point in time.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blogs are under your control. You&amp;rsquo;re not subject to someone else&amp;rsquo;s moderation. Of course that also means you&amp;rsquo;re on your own if you get DDOS&amp;rsquo;ed or such hehe. Well, there&amp;rsquo;s pros and cons of course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can still push your blog content to your other social media channels. I have systems set up to push my blog posts to Twitter, Facebook and Tumblr.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, the various social media channels have their pros too, so I still use them for various purposes. &lt;em&gt;(I thought about splitting this blog post into two, but I literally just wrote about long-form content, so let&amp;rsquo;s try to justify that a bit!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook &amp;ndash; I use this mainly to interact with friends and family and for sharing family pictures. There was a thread on reddit a while back about how a lot of people recommend quitting FB (or even social media altogether) since it&amp;rsquo;s not good for your self-esteem to be always checking how other people are doing. I find that this is really only an issue for people who already have low self-esteem and feel a need to compare themselves to other people (I guess teenagers mostly?). I don&amp;rsquo;t have any such issues. I like seeing how my friends are doing even if they&amp;rsquo;re people I don&amp;rsquo;t see often anymore and it gives you good convo material when you randomly run into them. I also tend to share on FB things I know will interest my friends and family, or at least some subgroup of them: family pictures, tech stuff, hobby stuff (gaming/MTG/comics), cat pictures, puns, memes, etc. I try not to dive into public groups too much, since FB has a low barrier of entry, the content/discussion is not that good IMO. My public Facebook profile is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/stephen.roy.tang&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Twitter &amp;ndash; my twitter stream is public. I use it for interacting with strangers. (Sophie Turner never replied to me that one time!). Twitter has a higher barrier of entry compared to FB, so the discussion is a bit higher quality. When posting to Twitter, it&amp;rsquo;s typically a stream of consciousness thing for me &amp;ndash; I just randomly decide to post things. On FB I tend to filter myself a bit as I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be too spammy, but on Twitter, I spam away about what I&amp;rsquo;m doing. If I&amp;rsquo;m playing in a big Magic tournament I&amp;rsquo;ll probably be tweeting every round about my horrible misplays. I will oft tweet about games I&amp;rsquo;m playing, books I&amp;rsquo;m reading, and so on. Same philosophy applies to sharing/retweeting: it&amp;rsquo;s a lot more impulsive, I&amp;rsquo;ll just share anything that looks interesting. My twitter feed is basically my FB feed except with less pics of people I know and more random thoughts throughout the day. If that sounds like your kind of thing, my twitter profile is &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instagram &amp;ndash; quick story about how I got an instagram account. I tried to create one but found out that someone had already registered an account using my email. Of course I went ahead and used password recovery to take control of the account. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t very active so he probably didn&amp;rsquo;t mind, although I think some of his followers still follow me lol. I mostly post pics of food, board games, sketches, or random things I buy. You can view my instagram &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/roytang0400&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reddit &amp;ndash; I use reddit more for content consumption. It can be shallow sometimes, but you can also find some good/witty/insightful convos. If I want to find some discussion about recent events or tv shows or movies, reddit is always a good place to look. The barrier to entry here is very high, so discussion tends to be higher quality than either FB or Twitter. &lt;em&gt;(Still lots of shitposting though, that&amp;rsquo;s the internet for you.)&lt;/em&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t publicly acknowledge my reddit profile, but it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to find haha.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tumblr &amp;ndash; just random odds and ends. It&amp;rsquo;s not very important, but I do have it. I used to use it only to reshare tumblr content I found amusing, but these days I also push sketches and blog posts to &lt;a href=&#34;http://tumblr.roytang.net/&#34;&gt;my tumblr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LinkedIn &amp;ndash; terrible! I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of LinkedIn, as it seems to be mainly a way to get harassed by recruiters who didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother reading my profile. Still, it occasionally has a use so I keep it around and update &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/roytang/&#34;&gt;my profile&lt;/a&gt; sometimes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quora &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Quora for a while now but recently also started answering questions every so often as a bit of writing practice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takeaways: Blogging is great, even if you&amp;rsquo;re already using social media. Try it out! Social media has its place too, but don&amp;rsquo;t let it control your life!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>A checklist for improving the writing style of technical blog posts ...
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/04/a-checklist-for-improving-the-writing-style-of-technical-blog-posts/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2010 07:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2010/04/a-checklist-for-improving-the-writing-style-of-technical-blog-posts/</guid>
            <description>
            Shared via delicious:
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://pietro.open-lab.com/2010/02/23/a-checklist-for-improving-the-writing-style-of-technical-blog-posts/&#34;&gt;A checklist for improving the writing style of technical blog posts ...&lt;/a&gt;

            


            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>