<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>logic on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/logic/</link>
      <description>Recent content in logic on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 09:02:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/logic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/10155212566278912/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 09:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/12/10155212566278912/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;International media making a fuss about our president? Must be a conspiracy theory to condition people to oust him, it can&amp;rsquo;t possibly be all the stupid and inane and outright sociopathic things he keeps saying.  James Taylor boycotts our country due to concerns on killings? Must be due to poor ticket sales, it can&amp;rsquo;t possibly be because sometimes people act on principle.  People raising an outcry due to killings and human rights concern? Must be due to partisan politics. After all, when you use politics to promote an environment of death and killing, everyone who is against killing can be considered partisan!  PH govt abstaining on UN vote help for Aleppo? Well of course, the UN shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be interfering with member states, since they&amp;rsquo;re our employees, right?   #logic  Lol, dami lang naipon na nakakainis na things. Hopefully our president shuts up til after Christmas (or maybe even forever! One can hope.)  To all those who I disagree with on politics: good morning and happy holidays! May we be ever woke and maybe sometimes find some common ground even.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/767729878259032065/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 14:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/767729878259032065/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Killings in Davao under #PresidentDuterte: hindi naman involved si mayor!
Drug lords doing business in Bilibid: kasalanan ni Delima! #logic&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>