<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>sleep on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://roytang.net/tags/sleep/</link>
      <description>Recent content in sleep on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://roytang.net/tags/sleep/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Out of sync with the world
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/08/out-of-sync-with-the-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/08/out-of-sync-with-the-world/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/02/insomnia/&#34;&gt;insomnia&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, my friend said, &amp;ldquo;You have something like a 28-hour sleep cycle.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I laughed and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/1160159147762913280&#34;&gt;uttered &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m out of sync with this world!&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was describing why I was almost late meeting the group for lunch, telling him I had trouble going to sleep and slept at 7am, only waking up at 10am. During the past few days my sleep times have steadily been moving later and later until they pushed into the early morning. And once I was close enough to breakfast time, well, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to miss breakfast, so I would often push through whatever hazy fog of sleepiness I had and just do stuff until breakfast. It would have been even odds that the sleepiness would have led to actual sleep anyway, I&amp;rsquo;ve been lied to before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not surprised to find that I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://roytang.net/2019/02/insomnia/&#34;&gt;written about my insomnia (or whatever it is) before&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s an intractable problem. I even had a relatively good 7hr sleep from Sunday to Monday so I had assumed that I had successfully done a hard reset on my sleep cycle, but no here we are again on Tuesday morning and it&amp;rsquo;s 4am and I&amp;rsquo;m writing a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking about this made me export my fitbit data so I could see if I was right about how rare it is for me to get even 6-7 hours of sleep, but after getting the data export and looking through the JSON files I realize that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of data to parse and statistics to generate and I haven&amp;rsquo;t slept yet so I might not be smart enough for this at the moment, so maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll do that another time. (Added to task list.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Insomnia
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2019/02/insomnia/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2019/02/insomnia/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I love sleeping. And taking naps. But I&amp;rsquo;m not very good at doing it at night. Insomnia is a common problem for me. I often find it difficult to go to sleep at night, taking upwards of 1-2 hours in bed before I can manage to fall asleep. Of course all that time lying there feels unproductive, so I&amp;rsquo;ll often be tempted to to grab a nearby screen and read something online or such, which makes it even harder to get to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t blame the electronics devices completely, though. I remember even when I was a kid I would sometimes have trouble sleeping at night due to a hyperactive brain having too many trains of thoughts to resolve. Something I still carry to this day, though I like to imagine my ability to compartmentalize thoughts has improved since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember when Warcraft III came out, one of the hero characters had an ability to send other units to sleep and I always chose that ability because I wanted to have it IRL. Not to use on other people, but on myself so I could sleep on demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting a continuous block of eight hours of sleep (or even six or seven hours) is pretty rare for me as well. Usually I&amp;rsquo;ll wake up after 1-2 hours, then if I&amp;rsquo;m lucky I manage to go to sleep again. If not, sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll give up and work on stuff until it&amp;rsquo;s breakfast time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I try to force-reset my sleep cycle by going like 36 hours without sleep so I can&amp;rsquo;t help but be real tired and sleep continuously for a while. But it usually doesn&amp;rsquo;t last. And I&amp;rsquo;m at that age where going 36 hours without sleep isn&amp;rsquo;t really that easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that since I quit working full-time I usually have a highly irregular daily schedule. Combined with a tendency to take naps during the day, it leads to the irregular sleep cycle. I also like having breakfast early so I often wake up at like 5 to 6 in the AM, no matter how late I went to sleep, then just recover sleep with naps during the day, making it harder to go to sleep early in the night, and so on. A bit of a vicious cycle. Also, it makes me a weird kind of cross between a morning person and a night owl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the problems with sleep is that even though it feels great, when you sleep so much it feels unproductive, like you could&amp;rsquo;ve put that time to better use. I remember maybe a decade or so ago, I was reading about the idea of polyphasic sleep. I liked the idea because it meant fewer sleep hours overall during the day, which meant more time for doing stuff. Sadly, I never got it to work. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit challenging to do it with a nine-to-five job, but even without that, I don&amp;rsquo;t really have the discipline to keep it up. And also, I like sleeping a lot sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll end this post with this tweet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;GOD: You have probably 70-80 years at most before you die, ideally.&lt;br&gt;MAN: oh. well, i&amp;#39;ll make the most of-&lt;br&gt;GOD: You&amp;#39;ll be unconscious for 1/3 of the time. &lt;br&gt;MAN: ..uh&lt;br&gt;GOD: *leans in* That&amp;#39;ll be your favorite part.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ray 🦔 (@SirEviscerate) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SirEviscerate/status/943137889977819138?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;December 19, 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;then I&amp;rsquo;ll go take a nap.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://roytang.net/2012/11/266698975304896513/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 00:29:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://roytang.net/2012/11/266698975304896513/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;p&gt;Was up way too late and on the road way too early. #sleepy&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>