<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>bumblebee on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/bumblebee/</link>
      <description>Recent content in bumblebee on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 16:32:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/bumblebee/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New photos
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181926569205/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 16:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181926569205/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;BUMBLEBEE Spoiler-Free review!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- attached image summarizes the plot. loljk (credit: Transformers (1985 - Marvel) #2)&lt;br/&gt;- I&amp;rsquo;m a big Transformers fan, more G1 than Bayverse (I didn&amp;rsquo;t even watch the last Michael Bay one). If you are like me, you will probably enjoy the film&lt;br/&gt;- if you grew up in the 80s like me, you will enjoy the film a bit more. Props to the 80s soundtrack&lt;br/&gt;- the plot is simple, straightforward and unambitious, unencumbered by any of Bayverse Megatron&amp;rsquo;s super-complicated plans that he has been plotting for million of years in case he gets stranded on earth&lt;br/&gt;- not having a plethora of autobot and decepticon characters to develop on each side means the transformers are more distinctive and easier to identify, a big problem I had with the later bayverse films&lt;br/&gt;- i didnt understand some scenes where it looked like the characters were talking to some kind of human soldier but I can&amp;rsquo;t see him?&lt;br/&gt;- foolish humans!&lt;br/&gt;- there is a &amp;ldquo;mid-credits&amp;rdquo; scene; I say &amp;ldquo;mid-credits&amp;rdquo; because they really only show the director credit before immediately going into the &amp;ldquo;mid-credits&amp;rdquo; scene&lt;br/&gt;- magugustuhan ba ni mama: no, she&amp;rsquo;s not into giant robots. the movie is family-friendly, other than the violent explosions&lt;br/&gt;- after the movie, I went to the CR to pee, and I overheard two kids talking: &amp;ldquo;Ano pangalan nung autobot na pula? Christopher?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Cliffjumper!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/181926569205/181926569205_huf9e3058d4702a20330a95b2179790058_213102_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>