<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>writingprompts on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/writingprompts/</link>
      <description>Recent content in writingprompts on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 12:36:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/writingprompts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/feul4l/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 12:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/03/feul4l/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;h4 id=&#34;posted-on-rwritingprompts-wp-the-year-is-2034-everybody-has-covid19-toilet-paper-is-but-a-distant-memory-a-young-woman-claims-to-be-immune-crowds-flock-around-to-watch-her-touch-her-own-facehttpsredditcomrwritingpromptscommentsfeul4lwp_the_year_is_2034_everybody_has_covid19_toilet&#34;&gt;Posted on r/WritingPrompts: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/feul4l/wp_the_year_is_2034_everybody_has_covid19_toilet/&#34;&gt;[WP] The year is 2034. Everybody has COVID19, toilet paper is but a distant memory. A young woman claims to be immune. Crowds flock around to watch her touch her own face.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[removed]&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/12/7n8qo5/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 22:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/12/7n8qo5/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;h4 id=&#34;posted-on-rwritingprompts-wp-he-had-24-hours-left-before-the-new-guy-would-manage-to-chase-him-down-and-take-him-out-or-so-they-thought-2017-wasnt-going-to-go-meekly-like-the-others-he-was-ready-for-2018-and-he-had-a-planhttpsredditcomrwritingpromptscomments7n8qo5wp_he_had_24_hours_left_before_the_new_guy_would&#34;&gt;Posted on r/WritingPrompts: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/7n8qo5/wp_he_had_24_hours_left_before_the_new_guy_would/&#34;&gt;[WP] He had 24 hours left before the new guy would manage to chase him down and take him out. Or so they thought. 2017 wasnt going to go meekly like the others. He was ready for 2018 and he had a plan.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Explorers - FirstChapter
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/explorers-firstchapter/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 05:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2017/03/explorers-firstchapter/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;h4 id=&#34;posted-on-rwritingprompts-pi-explorers---firstchapter---2105-wordshttpsredditcomrwritingpromptscomments5zeytfpi_explorers_firstchapter_2105_words&#34;&gt;Posted on r/WritingPrompts: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/5zeytf/pi_explorers_firstchapter_2105_words/&#34;&gt;[PI] Explorers - FirstChapter - 2105 Words&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hurry up Michael,” the woman urged as she led the way forward through the brush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ease up Raine, you know I’m an academic right, not a field researcher?” Michael said between short breaths. It was true, he wasn’t used to this much climbing. They were almost at the hill’s peak, but the vegetation didn’t seem to taper off. The trek from base camp had taken them the better part of four hours, most of it only under the light of the second moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Look!” He heard Raine’s voice call out from up ahead. “Hurry up and see!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Alright, alright,” he said. He finally broke out of the brush and found that the hill’s surface levelled off a bit. As he caught up with Raine he put a hand on her shoulder. “Ok now, what’s so&amp;ndash; Oh.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His words trailed off as he finally saw what Raine was pointing at. A vast field of bioluminescent blue greeted him. The sea of bright blue lay in stark contrast to the dark of night. It covered most of the hill top and even some of the slopes that trailed off to the adjacent mountain ranges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raine was already running forward and unstrapping her gear bag. “Hey, wait up!” Michael called as he ran after her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raine stopped at the edge of the field and lay down her bag. She knelt down and ran her hand through the flower petals glowing with a vivid blue hue. “Look at them Michael! It’s like they’re pulsating!” She looked up and across the clearing. “There must be more than tens of thousands of them here.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, we’ll never be able to harvest that many samples,” Michael said with a wry voice. Raine glared at him in return. She began digging through her bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’ll only need less than a dozen samples. Don’t you dare touch the rest of them!” Raine said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael pulled out his handheld and tapped the screen a few times. He raised his eyebrow at the display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was a good call not taking a shuttle here. Not that I enjoyed the hike I mean. The energy field they’re putting out is subtle, but there’s a good chance it would have wreaked havoc with the shuttle’s instrumentation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Give me that,” Raine said. She didn’t even wait for an acknowledgement and just snatched the handheld out of his hands. She scrolled through the displays. “I think it’s the same signature we saw from the scout telemetry! Similar to the radiation fields on Al Ghedo Prime!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Give me that!” Michael grinned as he grabbed back his own handheld. Raine could be like an excitable child when it came to her research. Maybe that was the reason he had found it so easy to join her on this first landing expedition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was very rare for an academic to join the preliminary colony establishment missions, much more someone who had spent the past decade in a remote lab. Michael understood the spirit of exploration that drove humanity to colonize as many worlds as they could, but he was no explorer. He rarely travelled, and even when he preferred travelling to well-established colonies, the ones with full populations and their own rich culture. And preferably not trips that take almost four months in hyperspace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Raine was a completely different creature, he mused. She followed her research wherever it took her, whether it was to the heart of a hollow moon or here to the farthest world humanity had ever attempted to colonize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was completely engrossed now. She had laid out her portable instrumentation platform at the edge of the field and was taking a variety of measurements. Michael sighed. There was no talking to her when she was like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, he swiped on his handheld and scanned the display. “The signal here is really great, even though we’re not too high up.” He stared upwards at the second moon and the stars beyond. “In fact, I think the sky tonight is clear enough to see the orbital platform.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hmm?” Raine said, looking up at him. She had a stylus in her mouth, an odd habit of hers. “Whachusaid?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying not to laugh at her, he looked at his display again. “Ark Thirty-Seven should be dropping out of hyperspace in a few hours.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh, you have a clear signal from here?” She obviously hadn’t been listening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeap. It’s even clear enough for me to see Christine’s telemetry,” Michael said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ah, you must be excited. You haven’t seen each other in almost a year right?” Raine got up to stand beside him and look at his display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah. It’s the longest we’ve been apart in a decade actually,” he confessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah well, you guys don’t really travel that much right?” she grinned at him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Thanks for this Raine.” He said after a short pause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Thanks for what?” She gave him a puzzled look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“All of this.” He waved his free hand in the direction of the field. “And all of that,” he waved again at the multitude of stars in the sky. “I never had it in me to be an explorer, but damn if I don’t see the appeal of it right now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I know right? For a lot of people, they don’t really think about this stuff,” Raine said. “Like people in the core systems or the factory worlds. They don’t care that humanity is still exploring, they don’t care that we’re still finding new worlds to live on.” She pulled out her own handheld from her pocket. She swiped to the GalWeb app and scrolled through a few dozen posts. “I mean, look at all these people. They’re just happy to have their weekends or their expensive off-world coffees. Thirty-seven different worlds to visit and all they want is to upvote vids of their space cats. They don’t think about what a wondrous age we’re lucky enough to live in.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I didn’t take you to be the philosophical kind,” Michael said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hah, I’m not, usually. But come on!” It was like a light had come on in her eyes, and she couldn’t hide the spark in her voice. ‘Ark Thirty-Seven! Isn’t that hard to believe? Who would have thought? I mean, two centuries ago before the core systems first developed hyperdrives, did they ever imagine we’d have thirty-seven colonies up and running in such a short time span? Back then, travelling to strange far-off worlds just to study alien flowers might have seemed like pure science fiction!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As she was giving her spiel she was continuously browsing her friends’ posts across the GalWeb. Michael smiled and didn’t bother pointing out the other technology she was taking for granted. The technology she was using to see what was going on with her friends on a dozen other planets light-years away, the very same technology that let him monitor Christine’s trip remotely. The ansible. Two hundred years ago, they still had to deal with significant lag between planets in the core system. Faster than light communications would have been unimaginable back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looked up again at the shining green light in the night sky, larger than the other stars. He knew it was the orbital platform. Tens of thousands of tons of heavy machinery, all designed to power and the two machines that drove human exploration - the hyperdrive beacon and the ansible. It had been humanity’s sheer luck that both breakthroughs were made within the same decade, enabling the human colonization of remote worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Don’t get too excited, young lady. This colony isn’t officially ‘up and running’ you know,” he smiled at her. “At least not until Christine and the ten million other colonists on the Ark get settled in.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hey listen, about that,” Raine said with some hesitation. “You’re not mad are you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Mad? About what?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That I made you join the advance mission with me? I mean, you’d be with her right now if it wasn’t for me right?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Heh,” he said. “You know, Christine and I actually had a short fight about it back when I first told her about the trip.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Really?!? I’m so sooorrrry,” Raine drawled in that weird tone her generation had a habit of using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Don’t be. It wasn’t much of a fight,” he reassured her. “More of a debate. We’re scientists, we don’t really fight. But she didn’t understand why we had to go on the advance mission. She said the planet wouldn’t be going anywhere. I had to walk her through your telemetry data slides so she understood why we couldn’t miss the window.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raine nodded. “Christine’s a scientist too, I knew she’d understand.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Well, she also wasn’t happy that I’d be spending my time with a hot young thing like you,” he grinned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“‘Hot young thing!’” she slapped him on the back. “What the hell Michael, sexism went out of vogue back in the twenty-first you know!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m joking!” he laughed at her. Then he turned serious again. “Christine knows why our research is important. The scoutships really need this sort of data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael thought about the scoutships. Small, autonomous ships travelling at sublight speeds to unexplored star systems. Literally thousands of them spread across the nearby regions, searching for new habitable worlds - or even the remote possibility of alien intelligence. The scoutships relied on surface survey data from scientists like Raine, allowing their machine intelligence to profile similar planets. The more surface data they could feed to the scouts, the more likely they were to be able to identify possible habitables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He walked up to the edge of the hilltop. It gave him a clear view of the valley below and the forward bases not too far away. The gigantic steel constructs were at rest now, their job mostly done. They had created a clearing, around one hundred and twenty square kilometers in total, he had been told. In just under a week, the ark’s landing module would come to rest in that clearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern arks were marvels of decades of engineering. Self-sustaining systems, filled with robotics, communications, supply lines, replicators, and anything else needed to quickly establish a modern city. They were a far cry from the early ark models, which were mostly just life support systems that could barely keep ten thousand colonists alive during the first hyperdrive colonization missions. Back then the first wave of colonists had to rough it, setting up their own hydroponic farms and comm systems, and dealing with the local wildlife themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, everything was set up to be ready for the ark as soon as it arrived. Forward missions like the one he and Raine had joined went ahead, bringing the heavy machinery needed to prepare the landing zone and to boost the orbital platform’s capabilities. Explorer teams would have already scouted out the entire continent, making sure there weren’t any threats to the colony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An instant city, with ten million brave souls ready to become the colony’s first official citizens. Many of them would be people like him and Christine and Raine - scientists, engineers, explorers, pioneers, volunteers. But many more would simple be people from the other colonies, hoping to start over with new lives for whatever reasons they had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Michael?” he heard Raine’s voice snap him out of his musings. She was pointing up at the sky. “What is that?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“That’s the orbital platform, didn’t I tell you?” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The platform is the bright green one, right?” she shook her head. “I was pointing at that other one.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What other one?” Michael squinted, but then he saw it. Another pinprick of light, bluish-gray. Difficult to see against the night sky. Raine’s vision was much better than his. “What is that… is it moving?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, I think so. It looks like it’s headed for the platform,” she pointed at Michael’s handheld. “Is the ark here early?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No, it shouldn’t be due for a few days yet,” Michael shook his head. He frowned and began swiping through the displays on his handheld. “I’m not registering any other ship out there, I&amp;ndash; hey!” He slapped the handheld against his palm. “What the heck, I just lost the connection!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Michael&amp;ndash;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Wait, just let me see what’s up with this,” Michael said as he tapped a few buttons on the display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Michael! Look!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He finally looked up at where the orbital platform was. The second light was gone, apparently having already arrived at the platform. And for some reason, the green light from the platform was pulsating wildly. And then moments later, the green light died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What in blazes&amp;ndash;?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then the endless night sky was set afire.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/538erf/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 02:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/538erf/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;h4 id=&#34;posted-on-rwritingprompts-wp-we-always-knew-the-apocalypse-was-coming-but-nobody-could-have-predicted-what-kind-of-apocalypse-it-would-behttpsredditcomrwritingpromptscomments538erfwp_we_always_knew_the_apocalypse_was_coming_but&#34;&gt;Posted on r/WritingPrompts: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/538erf/wp_we_always_knew_the_apocalypse_was_coming_but/&#34;&gt;[WP] We always knew the apocalypse was coming, but nobody could have predicted what kind of apocalypse it would be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;[TT] A veteran that has just been decommissioned from duty receives a letter from to government. The letter reads, &#34;Your not done, soldier. There is still more to you that needs to be done.&#34;&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/521hmp/tt_a_veteran_that_has_just_been_decommissioned/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/d7gm7h4/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 04:35:39 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/09/d7gm7h4/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;[TT] A veteran that has just been decommissioned from duty receives a letter from to government. The letter reads, &amp;#34;Your not done, soldier. There is still more to you that needs to be done.&amp;#34;&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/521hmp/tt_a_veteran_that_has_just_been_decommissioned/:

            &lt;p&gt;Lieutenant Rogers sighed and set aside the letter. He picked up the pen and pulled out a clean sheet of paper. His handwritten reply consists of one word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;*You&amp;rsquo;re&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by QuicklessQuixotic on &#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &#34;Flashback&#34; Contest - Final Voting Round!&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4q3lsq/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_final_voting/d4tq5wb/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/d50bi7q/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 18:33:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/d50bi7q/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by QuicklessQuixotic on &amp;#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &amp;#34;Flashback&amp;#34; Contest - Final Voting Round!&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4q3lsq/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_final_voting/d4tq5wb/:

            &lt;p&gt;Thanks! I&amp;rsquo;m glad you enjoyed it :D&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by thelastdays on &#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &#34;Flashback&#34; Contest - Final Voting Round!&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4q3lsq/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_final_voting/d4w862l/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/d50bht0/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 18:33:34 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/d50bht0/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by thelastdays on &amp;#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &amp;#34;Flashback&amp;#34; Contest - Final Voting Round!&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4q3lsq/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_final_voting/d4w862l/:

            &lt;p&gt;Thank you for the feedback! :D&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by mathspook777 on &#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &#34;Flashback&#34; Contest - Final Voting Round!&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4q3lsq/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_final_voting/d4wagoh/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/d50bh5q/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 18:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/d50bh5q/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by mathspook777 on &amp;#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &amp;#34;Flashback&amp;#34; Contest - Final Voting Round!&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4q3lsq/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_final_voting/d4wagoh/:

            &lt;p&gt;Thank you for the feedback! :D&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &#34;Flashback&#34; Contest - Final Voting Round!&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4q3lsq/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_final_voting/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/d50bgaw/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 18:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/07/d50bgaw/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &amp;#34;Flashback&amp;#34; Contest - Final Voting Round!&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4q3lsq/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_final_voting/:

            &lt;p&gt;My vote goes to Stay Out of My Path by /u/MindInTheClouds, it was the one I most enjoyed reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an aside, I want to say I&amp;rsquo;m very happy I made it to this round of the contest. It&amp;rsquo;s a pleasant surprise since I basically decided to join at the last minute and rushed out an entry on the day of the deadline. This is officially my excuse for any poor editing on my part :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m fairly new to this sub, so IDK how often contests like these are held, but I look forward to participating in the next one (and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to start earlier next time!). I&amp;rsquo;ve already learned a lot, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to say thanks to everyone who read my entry and who voted for me and gave me feedback, it&amp;rsquo;s been great :D&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by MajorParadox on &#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &#34;Flashback&#34; Contest - Final Voting Round!&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4q3lsq/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_final_voting/d4r32hf/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4rckyy/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 16:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4rckyy/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by MajorParadox on &amp;#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &amp;#34;Flashback&amp;#34; Contest - Final Voting Round!&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4q3lsq/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_final_voting/d4r32hf/:

            &lt;p&gt;Alright, thanks! :D&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by MajorParadox on &#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &#34;Flashback&#34; Contest - Final Voting Round!&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4q3lsq/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_final_voting/d4pv6fd/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4r1mwa/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 10:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4r1mwa/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by MajorParadox on &amp;#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &amp;#34;Flashback&amp;#34; Contest - Final Voting Round!&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4q3lsq/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_final_voting/d4pv6fd/:

            &lt;p&gt;So, this probably makes me totally self-serving but I might as well ask: am I allowed to vote for myself? Lol, so that I don&amp;rsquo;t get zero votes! :D&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by EndlessEnds on &#39;[PI] Two Monsters â€“ Flashback - 1,885&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4ohvmu/pi_two_monsters_flashback_1885/d4mfvpd/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4mgzhp/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 17:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4mgzhp/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by EndlessEnds on &amp;#39;[PI] Two Monsters â€“ Flashback - 1,885&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4ohvmu/pi_two_monsters_flashback_1885/d4mfvpd/:

            &lt;p&gt;Thank you for the kind words!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still places in the world even today where villagers bringing vegetables to market happens on a regular basis, mostly in rural areas in less developed countries. I do however agree that I might have chosen some other activity to better represent the period :)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by AloneWeTravel on &#39;[PI] Two Monsters – Flashback - 1,885&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4ohvmu/pi_two_monsters_flashback_1885/d4l1ttz/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4l27mh/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 17:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4l27mh/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by AloneWeTravel on &amp;#39;[PI] Two Monsters – Flashback - 1,885&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4ohvmu/pi_two_monsters_flashback_1885/d4l1ttz/:

            &lt;p&gt;Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Dragon hunters
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/dragon-hunters/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 17:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/dragon-hunters/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What? Where?&amp;rdquo; Steve muttered over the cackle of his walkie-talkie. He dropped his fork on the plateful of bacon and started packing up. &amp;ldquo;I’m nearest, I’ll be there ASAP. Have Glen and Lynn follow me as soon as possible.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His companion was looking at him quizzically from across the table. &amp;ldquo;Relax, John. You didn’t screw up this time. In fact, I guess it’s time for your trial by fire.&amp;rdquo; He got up and tossed him the keys. &amp;ldquo;Come on, you’re driving.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John just nodded and followed as Steve got up and stepped out of the supply depot. John had been on this internship for three days now and he still had that feeling of awe and majesty whenever he gazed upon the vast expanse. The green grassy fields were bounded to the north by a heavily wooded area and to the southwest by a small mountain range. The sun was on the way down by the mountains; it would be dark soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where we going?&amp;rdquo; John asked as he stepped into the driver’s seat of the open-air off-road jeep they had been using for patrols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve jumped into the passenger seat and gestured. &amp;ldquo;North by northeast. Floor it, we need to be there fast.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John nodded and soon they were speeding down the grassy plains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Are we headed into the forest?&amp;rdquo; John asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yup,&amp;rdquo; Steve was rummaging around in the supplies in the back of the jeep. To John’s surprise, Steve pulled out a scoped hunting rifle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What’s going on? There’s going to be trouble?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I hope not,&amp;rdquo; Steve said, loading and readying the rifle. &amp;ldquo;But best be ready.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before John could ask any more questions, they both heard a loud thunderous roar ring through the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is that&amp;ndash;?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yup,&amp;rdquo; Steve nodded. &amp;ldquo;It’s Amethyst.&amp;rdquo; Steve pointed to the edge of the forest. &amp;ldquo;There! Look!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were still some distance away, but the dragon was large enough for John to see. Amethyst was on the ground, her amber-yellow scales glistening in the receding sunlight. Her large wings were pinned to the ground somehow and she seemed to be struggling with some sort of ropes. It was starting to get dark, but John could still see a number of small figures milling around the dragon. &amp;ldquo;What are they doing&amp;ndash;?&amp;rdquo; John wondered aloud as they got closer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Poachers.&amp;rdquo; A grim look took over Steve’s face as he aimed the rifle and took a shot. It was a warning shot, there was no way he would hit anything at this distance. &amp;ldquo;Hang on Amy!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The poachers turned at the sound of the warning shot. John saw that there were six of them in all, and they had a large truck nearby, barely large enough to carry a small dragon. Two had trapped Amy in a net of ropes weighted down by what looked like metal drums. One of them, a stocky man with a dark tan and wearing army fatigues was shouting instructions to the others. Three were holding rifles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Shit, &amp;quot; John said, recognizing the threat. He quickly braked and turned, sending the jeep into a spinning drift. &amp;ldquo;Get down Steve!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two of them ducked as shots rang overhead. The jeep skidded to a stop and John and Steve quickly spilled out the passenger side and crouched down, using the vehicle as a cover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Great instincts kid! Here!&amp;rdquo; Steve tossed the rifle to John as he pulled out the walkie-talkie from his belt. &amp;ldquo;Keep ‘em busy!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nodding, John picked up the rifle. Now he understood why weapons training had been a requirement for this internship. He took a peek over the jeep’s side. The poachers were still firing, but keeping their distance. Amethyst struggled uselessly against the weighted ropes and her roars kept echoing. John fired a shot, then sat back to reload. &amp;ldquo;I think the dragon’s wounded Steve! Her left wing looked like it was bleeding!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve nodded. &amp;ldquo;Bastards! They probably clipped her wings to force her to land.&amp;rdquo; He spoke into the walkie-talkie again. &amp;ldquo;Glen, Lynn, where are you? These guys are heavily-armed!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ten minutes out!&amp;rdquo; a voice cackled back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not nearly quick enough,&amp;rdquo; Steve grunted as more shots rang overhead and John managed to fire back a few times. &amp;ldquo;You got any of them yet kid?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;They’re too far, I can’t get a good shot,&amp;rdquo; John shook his head, &amp;ldquo;I don’t understand, why doesn’t the dragon breathe on them?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Amy’s too young kid, just like you,&amp;rdquo; Steve replied, &amp;ldquo;You saw her snort out a couple of small fireballs outta her nostrils the other day right? That’s all she can do without getting exhausted.&amp;rdquo; A few more shots rang over their heads. &amp;ldquo;Well, we only got one shot now. Cover me.&amp;rdquo; He reached over back into the jeep again, being careful not to expose his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don’t suppose you have a rocket launcher in there,&amp;rdquo; John said as he fired off a couple more shots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Better,&amp;rdquo; Steve said, finally pulling out a weapon only slightly larger than a pistol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A flare gun? How is that going to help?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It doesn’t fire flares kid,&amp;rdquo; Steve aimed the gun upwards. &amp;ldquo;Watch and learn.&amp;rdquo; He pulled the trigger. What shot out certainly looked like a flare to John, as it slowly arced upwards into the sky. At the peak of the shot, where a flare would have exploded into bright light, instead a loud roar pierced the heavens. &amp;ldquo;Gotta hope she’s nearby…&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John saw the poachers look up at the sound in alarm. &amp;ldquo;What the heck was that?&amp;rdquo; John asked, &amp;ldquo;Who is nearby…?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was cut off by another roar, seemingly a short distance away, from beyond the woods. He looked to the sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There we go,&amp;rdquo; Steve grinned. &amp;ldquo;You’re in for a treat kid.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large winged figure was descending towards them quickly. &amp;ldquo;Another dragon!&amp;rdquo; John exclaimed, &amp;ldquo;And she’s a lot bigger too!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not just any dragon, kid,&amp;rdquo; Steve said, &amp;ldquo;That’s Amy’s mom!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her shadow was almost fifty-feet long as she flew over the two of them and circled back towards the poachers. She flew so close to the ground that her scales glistened with the reflections of the fading sunlight, and every flap of her enormous wings sent a strong gust towards John and Steve. John was pretty sure his mouth was agape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The larger dragon roared again in fury. John looked behind the jeep just in time to see the poachers in a panic, dropping their ropes and guns and making a mad dash for their truck. He looked up and saw the larger dragon take a deep breath and then what seemed like pure hot boiling rage burst forward from her open jaws. The grass seemingly parted way to burnt leaves as the fiery breath scorched the ground, heading straight for the poachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leader of the poachers was already in the truck’s driver seat, willing the engine to start. The others were scrambling into the back of the truck. But it was too late for them. The dragon caught up with them and in a matter of seconds the truck was completely wrapped in flames. With another roar, she swooped back upwards and around for another go, but it wasn’t necessary. As she turned away from the truck, it exploded into a violent ball of fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amy cried out to the skies as her mother circled around and finally landed next to her. The mother’s majestic wings spread out as she landed and she let out another roar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come on kid,&amp;rdquo; Steve said, finally getting up, &amp;ldquo;Just stick close to me, they know who I am.&amp;rdquo; He started jogging towards the dragons. John shook himself out of his stupor and followed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We’re gonna need the water choppers over here,&amp;rdquo; Steve was talking into the walkie-talkie again as they jogged past the burnt grass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amy and her mother let out quiet wails as they approached. Not quite roars, but more like cries of… recognition? That’s what it seemed like to John.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Easy there, girls,&amp;rdquo; Steve said in a soothing voice as he slowed down and walked towards the ropes holding Amy to the ground. He kicked one of the barrels the ropes was tied. &amp;ldquo;Must be fifty pounds of rocks in there,&amp;rdquo; he muttered as he pulled out a knife and started cutting off the ropes as the two dragons quietly looked on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Amy had been cut loose. She loosed another cry again, perhaps in gratitude. &amp;ldquo;She looks tiny in the shadow of her mother,&amp;rdquo; was all John could say as Amy tried flapping her wings. The left wing was useless, she wouldn’t be able to fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mother let out a subtle roar, and started flapping her wings. Steve held on to his hat as the gusts blew over them. She hovered over the two of them and Amy for a bit, before she finally grabbed the smaller dragon with her hind claws and lifted her up. The two of them took altitude and flew off towards the mountains, into the sunset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wow.&amp;rdquo; John said. Then after a while he said it again. &amp;ldquo;Wow. That was… intense. What happens now?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve nodded towards the mountains. &amp;ldquo;She has a nest there somewhere. She’ll nurse Amy for a few weeks until the wing heals. Dragons have naturally good healing, so she’ll probably make a full recovery.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John looked back at the charred remains of the poachers’ truck. &amp;ldquo;Does this happen a lot?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not really,&amp;rdquo; Steve shook his head. &amp;ldquo;They don’t often go for the dragons themselves. Couple of times a year, they’ll try raiding the nests for eggs or scales or leavings, that kind of thing. You’ll be surprised what they can get on the black market.&amp;rdquo; He mused. &amp;ldquo;The last time they got a live one must’ve been something like seven or eight years ago. It’s why we only have eight dragons here in the preserve. Used to be nine.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No new ones have been born since then?&amp;rdquo; John said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nope. Dragon births have been getting rarer and rarer. Not enough males. We haven’t seen our male in a few months,&amp;rdquo; Steve nodded towards the mountains again. &amp;ldquo;Amy’s the most recent birth we know of. No one knows if there’re any in the wild. The older ones are starting to die off too, so there’s a good chance the eight we got might be the last ones ever.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John shook his head. &amp;ldquo;It’s sad isn’t it, in a few generations, kids might think they’re fairy tales.&amp;rdquo; Steve had no response, so they stood there in silence staring at the charred grass until the sounds of a helicopter started coming in from the east.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, took ‘em long enough,&amp;rdquo; Steve muttered before gesturing John back to the jeep. &amp;ldquo;Cheer up kid, you did good today. Who knows, maybe we make a difference. Maybe soon, dragons will be all over the world again.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by sback113 on &#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &#34;Flashback&#34; Contest - Round 1 Voting!&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4opxyf/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_round_1_voting/d4eo06h/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4jgzs6/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 15:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4jgzs6/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by sback113 on &amp;#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &amp;#34;Flashback&amp;#34; Contest - Round 1 Voting!&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4opxyf/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_round_1_voting/d4eo06h/:

            &lt;p&gt;Thank you! Happy you enjoyed the story :D&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by avukamu on &#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &#34;Flashback&#34; Contest - Round 1 Voting!&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4opxyf/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_round_1_voting/d4f2xqr/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4jgzlm/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 15:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4jgzlm/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by avukamu on &amp;#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &amp;#34;Flashback&amp;#34; Contest - Round 1 Voting!&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4opxyf/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_round_1_voting/d4f2xqr/:

            &lt;p&gt;Thank you! Happy you enjoyed the story :D&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by Syraphia on &#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &#34;Flashback&#34; Contest - Round 1 Voting!&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4opxyf/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_round_1_voting/d4ig78j/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4jgza8/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2016 15:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4jgza8/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by Syraphia on &amp;#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &amp;#34;Flashback&amp;#34; Contest - Round 1 Voting!&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4opxyf/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_round_1_voting/d4ig78j/:

            &lt;p&gt;Thank you! Happy you enjoyed the story :D&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>At the edge of everything
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/at-the-edge-of-everything/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 14:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/at-the-edge-of-everything/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;“I don’t understand,” Liz said, scratching her head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What’s not to understand?” The old man looked at her with a look that was somewhere between condescension and amusement. “There’s simply nothing there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You mean like, no one lives there right? Behind your house? Or is it just a steep cliff that I’d fall off if I tried to walk into whatever that mist is?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old man shook his head, “No, no. No cliff. A cliff is something after all. There’s nothing there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t understand,” Liz repeated, looking even more confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tell you what, why don’t you go out back, pick up a stick, and poke it through the “mist”, see what happens,” the old man turned his back to her and started fussing around with the oven again, “After all, this pie will be a few more minutes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz didn’t really have anything to do but wait, so she decided to satisfy her curiosity. She still wasn’t sure if she could fully trust the old man (although he didn’t look he was in any condition to assault anyone), so she picked up her backpack before heading out the door at the back of the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She stepped out into a small, grassy back yard (not very well-maintained) surrounded by a number of trees of varying age. Beyond the yard and beyond the trees, a swirling black and grey and white shrouded her view, and she could not see anything more than a few dozen meters from the house. The black and grey and white extended in both directions, as far as her eyes could see, interspersing with the trees that dotted the landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slowly, Liz walked towards the mysterious black and grey and white. She glanced back at the house as she did so, the aging red-bricked walls no different from the facade she had sighted from the distance. The house looked a lot smaller up close, even though it was two stories. It must have been some trick of perspective that made it look like a mansion when she first spotted it not thirty minutes ago. Or perhaps a trick of her mind, deliriously happy to see smoke coming from the chimney indicating someone was home who could help her find her way back to town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The house didn’t have a fence or a gate, so she had just walked up to the wide oaken doors and knocked as hard as she could. The old man who opened the door had been happy to see her and had been a gracious host. She had explained her predicament and the old man was more than willing to help her get back to town, but he was in the middle of something in the kitchen. Liz, famished from her long trek, had followed the old man and the sweet aroma of apple pie into the kitchen, where she had finally asked him about that strange black and grey and white behind his house. It was neither fog or mist, she had been told. Simply nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She had assumed the old man was just pranking her, and that it would clear up a bit as she stepped closer, that she would see the faint outline of trees beyond the black and grey and white. But here she was now, not three paces from the edge of the mist, and still she could see nothing beyond the swirling grayscale colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz knelt down and found a short twig, about the length of her arm, fallen from one of the nearby trees. She stood up and took a step closer to the edge. She looked at the twig in her hand, shrugged and thrust it forward. Into the black and grey and white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing happened. As far as she could tell. A full foot and a half of the twig was beyond the edge now. Not that she could see it in the swirling grayscale. She pulled the twig back and was shocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The twig, once almost three feet long, was now shorter by a foot and a half. She had no idea what had happened to it. She had felt no force that could have snapped the twig in half. She examined the end of the twig, and it seemed like a perfectly natural endpoint for the twig. As if it had never had that extra foot and a half of length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz stared across the edge for perhaps an eternity, her curiosity completely piqued. She raised her hand and waved it vertically in front of the black and grey and white, less than an inch from the edge. For some reason she was expecting a cold sensation emanating from the “mist”, but there was nothing. Nothing to indicate there was anything beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She looked at the mist, then she looked at her hand, then back at the mist. Should she?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Not a good idea lass!” She heard the old man’s voice from the house and she half-turned. The old man had stepped just out the kitchen door and had cupped his hands to project his voice. “Better get back here, pie’s ready!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz took another look at her hand, a mere sliver away from the edge, and reluctantly pulled it away. She shouted back to the old man as she got closer. “Is it really just nothing?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yep,” the old man nodded. “People never believe it either. Always have to make them go out and do the stick thing.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Has it always been there?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old man shrugged. “It was there before I bought this house eight years ago at least. Previous owner didn’t tell me nothin’ about it either. It didn’t bother me much at first since it used to be a lot farther out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It moves?” Liz said incredulously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A few meters every year, near as I can tell. Maybe more. Seems to be getting faster too. I’ll probably need to think about moving out in a couple of years, if I live that long,” he chuckled. The old man waved Liz towards the kitchen door as she approached. The smell of apple pie was much stronger now, and she could see beyond the open door that the old man had set down a couple of plates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I&amp;ndash;” Liz wasn’t sure what to say as she stepped up to the door. She held it open for a moment. “I don’t understand how there could be nothing there. Hasn’t someone come up here to study it or something?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, couple years back some government folks set up a research facility a few miles yonder,” the old man said, nodding mountain range in the distance. “You’ll meet ‘em soon, we’re going to pass by their checkpoint on the way back to town, and they’ll probably ask you not to tell anybody about it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Am I in some sort of trouble?” Liz wondered what madness she had stumbled upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Nah, they’re friendly folk, they might want to ask you a few questions though. So we should have some pie before we go.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liz stopped for a moment then nodded. “I guess I could use some apple pie.”&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to &#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &#34;Flashback&#34; Contest - Round 1 Voting!&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4opxyf/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_round_1_voting/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4f4e6r/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 05:59:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4f4e6r/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to &amp;#39;[MODPOST] 6 Million &amp;#34;Flashback&amp;#34; Contest - Round 1 Voting!&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4opxyf/modpost_6_million_flashback_contest_round_1_voting/:

            &lt;p&gt;/u/GenreBless in group F for &amp;ldquo;At A Loss&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honorable Mention: /u/startoffs for &amp;ldquo;The Playmaker&amp;rdquo;. These two felt like the most well-written to me, I had a hard time choosing.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Two Monsters – Flashback
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/two-monsters-flashback/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/two-monsters-flashback/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;h4 id=&#34;posted-on-rwritingprompts-pi-two-monsters--flashback---1885httpsredditcomrwritingpromptscomments4ohvmupi_two_monsters_flashback_1885&#34;&gt;Posted on r/WritingPrompts: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4ohvmu/pi_two_monsters_flashback_1885/&#34;&gt;[PI] Two Monsters – Flashback - 1,885&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you’re going to kill me, then kill me,” the old man said to her without a hint of fear or desperation. “If not, then stand aside.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Are you kidding?!?” The young woman in front of him was tall and stocky, her outstretched arm holding the outgun steady not five feet in front of the old man. At this range, she would not miss. “You don’t know how long I’ve been searching for you Scorpion! You don’t deserve a quick death!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She heard the crowd milling around them start to whisper and murmur. A young man stepped forward, arms raised. “Miss, please. There must be some sort of mistake. This kindly old man is our town doctor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She shook her head. “There is no mistake. For years, your little village has hidden a monster!” She addressed the old man again. “Tell them Scorpion!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All eyes went to the old man and he shut his eyes for a moment. It’s been years now, and that name still haunted him. The memories came back to him easily. The smell of the blood and violence and the poetry in motion. And of course the pride. Always the pride. The Scorpion was the best, which was why he was the most well-known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the old man spoke. “I haven’t heard that name in many years… May I ask who sent you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Who sent me?” The young lady sneered. “No one sent me, old man. You probably don’t recognize me. After all, it has been more than twenty years since that night in Albany.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Albany… that house on the cliff, wasn’t it?” The old man wasn’t surprised that he could still remember it. The memories don’t really go away. He had scouted the perimeter three times before making his entrance. A sniper bullet took out the man on the balcony, then a quick climb over the fence. Two guards near the back door fell in quick succession seconds after he had drawn his knives. A maidservant was unlucky enough to be in the kitchen. She was a noncombatant, so he made sure she did not suffer. Three more guards in the upper hallway. He had loved it back then, wading into melee with multiple opponents. It was like a dance. A bloody dance as crimson spilled from their necks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, the bedroom. He had begged for mercy. They’re always so smug while their security was around, but they always beg for mercy in the end. He had pinned the man to the wall and carved his symbol on the man’s chest in blood. The man screamed for all of two minutes before he finally cut his throat. And then a slight noise, a movement nearby, behind him. He spun towards the armoire. He stepped forward and opened the doors wide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old man came back to the present. “I see. You were the little girl then.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Now you remember!” the woman’s calm exterior started to crumble, the rage building in her voice. “I had to listen to his screams! He was begging for mercy and you made him suffer!” This was it, this was what she had waited for all these years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her mind went back as well. All the suffering she had endured. The training she had to go through. The Scorpion was the best, they had told her. Every time she tracked down one of his contacts, it was the same warning. You’ll never get him. She had killed those contacts, but her rage never quelled. Her thirst for vengeance kept her moving forward. If the Scorpion was the best, I would have to be better. She had told herself that time and time again. She had immersed herself in his world. He had vanished off the face of the earth, she was told. But she would find him, and she would make him pay. Following the trail of contacts and clients and assassinations. She took her own contracts, built her own reputation. To earn their respect. The men who knew how to find the Scorpion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She came back to the present. “They didn’t give you up easily you know. Your old clients. Your contacts. That’s why they all died, slowly. I had to piece together your movements slowly. And finally, where do I find you? Some small backwater village, playing doctor?!?” She sneered again. “I was looking for The Scorpion, the best assassin there ever was! I was ready to show you how I had surpassed you, to make you pay for your sins! And I find you here, this decrepit old man?” She shook her head. “Don’t worry, I’ll make sure you suffer!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The young man from the crowd turned to the old man. “Doc… is it true, what she’s saying? Are you this… Scorpion?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was a long time ago. I was a different person then…” the old man said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The woman moved quickly, stepping forward and whipping the old man across the face with the pistol before anyone could react. “A different person? Don’t make me laugh!” she said as the old man staggered back and leaned against the wall. She addressed the crowd. “Murderers don’t change people! He’s a wolf, and he’s been hiding among you sheep for so long, waiting for another chance to bare his fangs!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old man spat out some blood and stood up straight again. “You’re a different person too you know,” he said, looking her in the eye. “There was fear in your eyes back then to be sure. But innocence too. And I took it away. I apologize. I may have spared you, but I also condemned you to this life. Your father was not the only life I took in that bedroom that night.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Enough!” The woman cocked her gun and aimed it at the old man’s leg. “I don’t need to be told what I’ve lost old man! I’ll blow off your legs, then your arms, then let you bleed out for hours, how does that sound?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Please, wait,” the young man said. “He may have been the monster you say, but as our doctor, he’s helped us greatly. He’s a different person now, he’s kind and gentle and&amp;ndash;”
“&amp;ndash;he doesn’t even ask for ourmoney,” one of the old women in the crowd spoke up. “We just pay him in vegetables or invite him over for dinner…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&amp;hellip;an’ he took care o’ my ma when she couldn’t work,” a little boy, perhaps no more than twelve was speaking up, “he helped us bring her goods to the merchants, so we could eat…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another spoke up, speaking of the old man’s kindness. Then two more, then another. Finally, the woman raised her gun in the air and fired a shot. The bang silenced the crowd and many of them stepped back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Shut up, all of you!” the woman said with a quivering voice, “You don’t know this man! He’s killed dozens, maybe hundreds over the years! A few acts of kindness won’t excuse that!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“B-but,” the young man spoke again, “if he has killed so many people, why did he spare you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The woman was silent for a moment. Then she pointed the gun at the old man’s head again. “I don’t know old man, why &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; you spare me? You’re the Scorpion, you were a merciless killer. Why the moment of weakness?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Weakness was it?” The old man spoke again, calmly and softly. “It’s true, I had taken many lives before that night. But I had never killed a child.” He looked her in the eye again. “I told you, I saw the innocence in your eyes. It changed me. And I fled. If you spoke to my clients, you know I never took the payment for that night. And I have never killed again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Never killed again?!? What bullshit is this old man? You expect me to believe that?” She was practically shouting at his face. “Everyone I spoke to, they told me about The Scorpion’s bloodlust, his need to kill. And you expect me to believe you just walked away from that?!?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looked at her, this time with pity. “You can’t imagine it, can you? Because you have it now. That bloodlust, that rage. You can’t imagine your heart changing so much that it takes it all away. You’ve lived with this rage for so long, you can’t imagine life without it. I am truly sorry.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She spun her arm around to pistol-whip him again, but this time the old man caught her arm in mid-air. Her rage momentarily gave way to surprise, then almost immediately to alertness. She quickly wrested her arm and stepped back. “I knew it. Your old instincts, all still there eh?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He did not answer her but instead pointed towards the far end of the town plaza. “Those two men you shot. They are still alive. Let me tend to their wounds, stabilize them. Afterwards, you can do with me as you wish.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her eyebrow went up. “Hah! You’re just going to let me kill you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You said I deserved it, didn’t you? I won’t disagree.” He picked up the small bag he had dropped earlier. “My medical instruments, don’t worry.” He started walking slowly towards the injured men. “As you can see, I could not run from you even if I wanted.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She looked skeptical, but she let him pass and followed just behind him. The small crowd followed them. The old man knelt beside one of the victims, who had been shot in the shoulder. He began tending the wounds. She watched him silently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Perhaps it is fitting that you should be the one to kill me,” the old man spoke finally as he moved on to the second victim. “After all, you were the one who changed me.” She didn’t respond so he kept going. “I tried to kill myself you know. I could never do it. The famous killer, afraid to take his own life. Finally I decided, I could not take back the sins of my past, but perhaps I can balance the scales, even a little bit. I’ve been a doctor here for almost eight years now, but I fear I’m no longer as strong as I used to be. I would not have been of use to them much longer. And so I can at least give you your vengeance. One final act of atonement.” He finished dressing the wound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He stood up and looked at her. “I can only hope that you too find someone to change you, once you have taken your vengeance. Perhaps you can move on, and this cycle of death can end.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Move on?” She finally spoke again, slowly and in a lower voice this time, all trace of rage gone, only bitterness remained. “To what? I don’t have anything, old man.” She raised her gun again. “All I have is vengeance. All I have is the monster I’ve been hunting down all my life. And now I find the monster is gone!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He stepped towards her slowly. She did not waver, her arm outstretched. “Then there is but one more monster to slay,” the old man said. This time he reached his own hand out and tapped her chest lightly. “The monster you have become.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wept, and fell to her knees.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by mooman9 on &#39;[WP] The day after a man invents the world&#39;s first time machine, he receives a mysterious letter inviting him to a dinner party to be held on the night of May 26th, 1923&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4o4qr5/wp_the_day_after_a_man_invents_the_worlds_first/d4b5chd/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4b68ts/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 04:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d4b68ts/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by mooman9 on &amp;#39;[WP] The day after a man invents the world&amp;#39;s first time machine, he receives a mysterious letter inviting him to a dinner party to be held on the night of May 26th, 1923&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4o4qr5/wp_the_day_after_a_man_invents_the_worlds_first/d4b5chd/:

            &lt;p&gt;Thank you for the kind words. I have something rolling about in my head about how Alex and Harry&amp;rsquo;s relationship devolve into what it&amp;rsquo;s going to be. I may write it up someday.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reply to a comment by rwage724 on &#39;[WP] The day after a man invents the world&#39;s first time machine, he receives a mysterious letter inviting him to a dinner party to be held on the night of May 26th, 1923&#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4o4qr5/wp_the_day_after_a_man_invents_the_worlds_first/d49vwyp/:
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d49zkde/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 10:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/d49zkde/</guid>
            <description>
            Reply to a comment by rwage724 on &amp;#39;[WP] The day after a man invents the world&amp;#39;s first time machine, he receives a mysterious letter inviting him to a dinner party to be held on the night of May 26th, 1923&amp;#39; on /r/WritingPrompts at https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/4o4qr5/wp_the_day_after_a_man_invents_the_worlds_first/d49vwyp/:

            &lt;p&gt;Thanks for the feedback!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>May 26th, 1923
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/may-26th-1923/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 05:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/may-26th-1923/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;The building had a nondescript white exterior, with a single grey metal door on the facade and no other hint of what lie within. I tried the knob and a metallic rattle told me it was locked. I frowned, then remembered, then pulled out the mysterious envelope I had found under my door yesterday. I mean, 93 years from now. Well, not 93 years from now for me. Yesterday for me. God, I need to figure out how to think of time again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opened the envelope, equally nondescript as the building exterior, and shook it a bit. The small key fell out of it and I almost miss catching it. Harold would have sneered derisively if he was here. &amp;ldquo;World&amp;rsquo;s clumsiest time traveller!&amp;rdquo; he would have said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harold. Harry. Good old Harry. The argument had been gone sour last night. Will have gone sour? &amp;ldquo;Why should we go? We have no idea what this is. No idea!&amp;rdquo; he had exclaimed, gesturing wildly as he was wont to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I inserted the small key into the lock on the doorknob, and sure enough it clicked into place. I turned the knob and stepped inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harry was always the smart one. The prudent one. He had all these rules. &amp;ldquo;We can&amp;rsquo;t risk collapsing the universe!&amp;rdquo; or some such theoretical physics bullshit. He&amp;rsquo;d be hopping mad if he knew I&amp;rsquo;d actually gone. Well, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to know, it&amp;rsquo;s a fucking time machine isn&amp;rsquo;t it? I&amp;rsquo;ll be back before he knows it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind the door was a long and dimly lit corridor. The only sound was the subtle whirring of a large ceiling fan overhead. Well, that and the creaking of the metal door as I shut it back into place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A desk. There was a desk. And behind it, a person. A stocky woman, her hair tied in a bun, wearing spectacles. She looked up from what looked like a sudoku puzzle as I stepped closer. Did they even have sudoku in 1923? I reached into my pocket for the envelope again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needn&amp;rsquo;t have bothered. &amp;ldquo;Mr. Reyes, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&amp;rdquo; She nodded towards the far end of the hallway. &amp;ldquo;Take the elevator at the end. There&amp;rsquo;s only one stop.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Er, I was hoping to ask&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Please hurry. It will all be explained to you when you get off the elevator,&amp;rdquo; she cut me off a bit rudely as she penciled a 9 into the lower-right segment of her sudoku, &amp;ldquo;sir.&amp;rdquo; She ended the sentence with a slight hint of boredom, as if she shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to be the one to be entertaining weirdly-dressed men coming into the building at this hour of night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I nodded, sensing that she didn&amp;rsquo;t expect any further argument, and headed down the hallway. I stepped into the elevator and pressed the single button I found inside. Strangely, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell whether it brought me up or down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to squint a bit as I stepped out into a corridor a bit more brightly lit than the last one. This corridor was shorter, and the walls tapered with red velvet, the carpet a burgundy affair. The light was coming from a large open door at the end of the hallway. Looked like some sort of banquet? Well, the mysterious invitation had said it was a dinner after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nineteen twenty three? What the hell happens in 1923? A bloody invite? Who would even send this to us?&amp;rdquo; Harry said when I read the letter out loud to him. &amp;ldquo;You didn&amp;rsquo;t tell anyone did you? I told you we can&amp;rsquo;t go public yet, we need to do more tests!&amp;rdquo; Harry was always so angry for some reason. And secretive about the project. We could never tell anyone about the machine. Not even my family. They thought I was consulting with the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ah, Mr Reyes,&amp;rdquo; another woman, blond this time, stepped out of seemingly nowhere as my eyes adjusted to the brighter lights. She looked strikingly similar to the one I met earlier. Perhaps they were sisters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;She&amp;rsquo;s my grandmother actually, long story,&amp;rdquo; she said, cutting me off before I could ask, &amp;ldquo;sorry sir, we can&amp;rsquo;t waste too much time, please step into the hall.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the hall, there were a number of men milling about. Perhaps ten or a dozen? They were all wearing some sort of cocktail mask. I would have thought it some sort of masquerade ball, except they weren&amp;rsquo;t wearing very formal clothes. Most of them had on simple shirts and slacks or jeans. Nothing to indicate they were out of place in this era though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ah, you&amp;rsquo;re here,&amp;rdquo; an older man came towards me and lowered his mask. His visage was strikingly familiar, but I could not place it. &amp;ldquo;It is almost time, then.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Time, time for what?&amp;rdquo; I said, confused. &amp;ldquo;Who are you? The lady upstairs,&amp;rdquo; Or was it downstairs? &amp;ldquo;She said someone would explain all this to me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Indeed, yet there is little time for introduction, so let us keep this brief. My name is Alexander Reyes, age 61.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a double-take. &amp;ldquo;Wait, what? We have the same name?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know you&amp;rsquo;re clever so you&amp;rsquo;ll have figured it out before I finish this sentence,&amp;rdquo; future me (my future self? myself? I?) said, &amp;ldquo;So let us not dally any further. Harold is coming.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Harold? Harry?&amp;rdquo; I shook my head, still trying to wrap my head around everything as the rest of the men in the banquet hall started to approach mill around us. &amp;ldquo;No, he&amp;rsquo;s not. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t know I came&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He will,&amp;rdquo; another one of the men took down his mask. My own face stared back at me, easily recognizable this time, if only slightly older. &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about it, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing you could have done.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I could go back,&amp;rdquo; I stammer out. I reach into my pocket, looking for the wayback beacon. A terrible name for such a device, Harry had said. Harry. &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s wrong, why is Harry coming?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He knows. Well, he will know. That we mean to stop him.&amp;rdquo; Another version of me spoke. Glad to know I never will get the hang of the verbs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He can&amp;rsquo;t follow me here,&amp;rdquo; I reasoned out. &amp;ldquo;I have the only beacon. And he doesn&amp;rsquo;t know how to operate the machine without me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ll teach him,&amp;rdquo; a grim version of my face said, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t resist, it&amp;rsquo;s a waste of time. He was meant to come here.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry it took this long, all of you,&amp;rdquo; it was sixty-one again who spoke. &amp;ldquo;To arrange this meeting, but then again, you all already know it will.&amp;rdquo; He nodded towards me. &amp;ldquo;You were the first, so you had to be last to arrive. So that he doesn&amp;rsquo;t know we are all here, waiting for him.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To kill him of course.&amp;rdquo; The grim one spoke again. &amp;ldquo;And yes, we will need this many.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The building shook, as if some powerful force was shaking its foundation. Everyone around me started murmuring in anticipation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sixty-one reached out and put his hand on my shoulder. &amp;ldquo;You must go. You cannot fight him, you are not ready. There is but one more thing you must remember,&amp;rdquo; he looked around at the gathered future versions of me. &amp;ldquo;When you are in great peril, recall this gathering and remember that you will surely survive.&amp;rdquo; With that, he reached into my pocket. Is it an invasion of personal space if it&amp;rsquo;s your own future self? That was the last thought on my mind as he activated the wayback beacon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wait, I&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo; The familiar vertigo overcame me again and I knew it was too late. I was going back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m new; be gentle~)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Keep driving
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/keep-driving/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 07:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/06/keep-driving/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;A high-pitched bell rang out a couple of times as I stepped into the diner. Outside had been slightly chilly, the first hints of the coming winter lingering in the air. Inside I gratefully took off my cap and laid it on the counter as I sat down and waved over at the middle-aged lady brewing coffee on the other end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Fresh pot? I&amp;rsquo;ll have some if that&amp;rsquo;s alright. And any bacon and eggs you have,&amp;rdquo; I found myself saying, surprisingly famished. The woman turned as if seeing me for the first time. I spied a name tag against her faded yellow uniform, in gilded letters it spelled out &amp;ldquo;DOLORES&amp;rdquo;. With a surprising assertiveness I followed up, &amp;ldquo;As quickly as possible please Dolores.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dolores&amp;rsquo; raised her eyebrows. I&amp;rsquo;m unsure whether it was because of my unusual order or because of my impertinence, but regardless she turned to the little window behind the counter and whispered something indistinct, I suppose to whoever needed to cook my bacon and eggs. She took her time waddling over with her freshly brewed pot of coffee and poured me a hot cup. She spoke with a long, drawling voice. &amp;ldquo;So, who you running away from honey?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I was the one to look surprised. My eyes quickly darted around the diner, near empty at this surely ungodly hour. The only other patron was a skinny old man at a booth on the far end, slowly going through what looked like a faded newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dolores smiled a knowing smile. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not rocket science hon,&amp;rdquo; She gestured with her mouth to the parking lot outside, in the direction of the van I had been driving for the past seven hours. &amp;ldquo;You drive up here a bit past midnight in a big-name delivery van, the kind that don&amp;rsquo;t do deliveries at this hour.&amp;rdquo; She put the coffee pot down and waved her hand over my face, &amp;ldquo;Your eyes are tired and your clothes are rumpled and you smell like you&amp;rsquo;ve been in that van for what, half a day now?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re awfully perceptive aren&amp;rsquo;t you,&amp;rdquo; I retorted back without thinking, &amp;ldquo;For a waitress at an all-night diner?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not that unusual you know, there&amp;rsquo;s really only two sorts that end up here at this hour, truckers and people who&amp;rsquo;re running,&amp;rdquo; she gestured at the van again, &amp;ldquo;and that ain&amp;rsquo;t no truck.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why do people run?&amp;rdquo; I found myself asking. Just making small talk. Why would I care why other people run?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dolores shrugged, &amp;ldquo;Lots of reasons, I guess. Some&amp;rsquo;re crooks, running from the law. There&amp;rsquo;s those in debt and can&amp;rsquo;t afford to pay so they skip town. More and more these days though, there&amp;rsquo;s folks who maybe just got tired of livin&amp;rsquo; their lives and they figure they could just up and vanish, walk out from their nagging wife and their crazy kids and their shitty jobs that probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t last long anyways. A lot of &amp;lsquo;em think they can just find a cabin in the woods somewhere and disappear for a few years, livin&amp;rsquo; off the land. Or maybe they imagine they can drive up to some big city and lose themselves in the crowds.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grunted perhaps a bit too loudly, thinking about how I had gotten here in the first place. Dolores seemed to be able to read my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let me guess, you have no idea what you&amp;rsquo;re doing here do you?&amp;rdquo; She looked me up and down. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d guess that&amp;rsquo;s your delivery uniform right there, haven&amp;rsquo;t bothered changing out of it. You just kept on driving, no idea where you wanted to go.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, I was thinking maybe somewhere up north&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Honey, if you really wanted to go, you&amp;rsquo;d have ditched that delivery van o&amp;rsquo; yours as soon as you could. You know as well as I do those things got GPS on &amp;lsquo;em right?&#39;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I nodded slowly. I had thought about the GPS, but figured I just needed to leave the van somewhere before morning when they would be looking for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And your cellphone, you got one don&amp;rsquo;t you? Still on you?&amp;rdquo;, she retorted as an indistinct voice called out from beyond the small hole and a plate slid out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yeah, &amp;quot; I said, patting my left-hand pocket, &amp;ldquo;but I turned it off. My wife must have called me a dozen times by now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So tell me hon, why haven&amp;rsquo;t you thrown it out yet?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Throw it out?&amp;rdquo; I was caught a bit off guard, &amp;ldquo;Well, I kind of paid good money for it, and I&amp;rsquo;m still on contract, so&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo; I trailed off, knowing I wasn&amp;rsquo;t making sense. I shook my head. &amp;ldquo;You think I should go back?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Honey, I ain&amp;rsquo;t telling you what to do, it&amp;rsquo;s your own damn life,&amp;rdquo; Dolores said as she served up a plate full of bacon and eggs. &amp;ldquo;But I see you, you keep glacin&amp;rsquo; at that there wedding ring on your hand, out at the van in the parking lot, and I see a man who ain&amp;rsquo;t ready to let go. You gonna run, you gotta be sure, you gotta cut clean.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; My brow furrowed as I frowned at the bacon in front of me, perhaps for the first time in my life. &amp;ldquo;You know, it was my birthday yesterday.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Dolores&amp;rsquo; turn to grunt, &amp;ldquo;Happy birthday then, but I hope you ain&amp;rsquo;t expecting a discount.&amp;rdquo; She finally picked up the coffee pot, turned away from me, and walked over to the other patron who had motioned her over with his coffee cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up the fork and started eating. It was perhaps the best meal I&amp;rsquo;ve had in a long while.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>New note
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/12/2ptz00/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 06:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/12/2ptz00/</guid>
            <description>
            

            &lt;h4 id=&#34;posted-on-rwritingprompts-wp-the-us-government-begins-retaliatory-actions-for-the-north-korea-hack-on-sony-show-kim-jong-uns-perspective-as-he-realizes-whats-going-onhttpsredditcomrwritingpromptscomments2ptz00wp_the_us_government_begins_retaliatory_actions&#34;&gt;Posted on r/WritingPrompts: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reddit.com/r/WritingPrompts/comments/2ptz00/wp_the_us_government_begins_retaliatory_actions/&#34;&gt;[WP] The US Government begins retaliatory actions for the North Korea hack on Sony. Show Kim Jong Un&amp;rsquo;s perspective as he realizes what&amp;rsquo;s going on&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>