<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>favorites on Roy Tang</title>
      <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/favorites/</link>
      <description>Recent content in favorites on Roy Tang</description>
      <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      
          <atom:link href="https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/favorites/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      
          
      
        <item>
            <title>Thoughts on Blogging, 2020 Edition
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/thoughts-on-blogging-2020-edition/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/thoughts-on-blogging-2020-edition/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I found this great article the other week about &lt;a href=&#34;https://guzey.com/personal/why-have-a-blog/&#34;&gt;Why You Should Start A Blog Right Now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing is absolutely worth a read, but my favorite part is at the start where he enumerates a list of reasons why he wrote particular posts, and it sent me down a rabbit hole again of evaluating why I write on this blog, and whether it was an endeavor worth continuing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably, having a blog has a lot of possible benefits, but the one important for me personally are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it helps me clarify step through my own thoughts and understand my own thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it serves as an archive of my state of mind at the time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it helps me improve my own writing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably, you can also use a blog to advance your career, build a brand/reputation, finding an audience, etc. And those are fine, but for me they are only incidentals, nice-to-haves. Fundamentally, I still always write for myself first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, I said to myself, why write in public at all? If those three reasons are the most important, then something like &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/12/private-writing/&#34;&gt;private writing&lt;/a&gt; should already suffice. I even asked my self the very same question back in 2005 at the end of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2005/11/why-do-i-blog/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;, and at that time I had no answer. Today I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write in public because we as humans have so much in common, even if we aren&amp;rsquo;t aware of it. And while writing down one&amp;rsquo;s own thoughts or opinions or everyday happenings may seem like it would be entirely uninteresting to the average reader, there will always be some aspect of your stories that will resonate with someone else, somewhere, because of that shared human experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, everyone can have a platform for writing, whether it&amp;rsquo;s in one of the social media silos or your own site like this one, so the whole &amp;ldquo;writing in public&amp;rdquo; thing isn&amp;rsquo;t so novel anymore. But even in this age, not everyone chooses to participate in social media, not everyone tweets or posts all the time, and that&amp;rsquo;s fine. I can accept that writing in public isn&amp;rsquo;t for everyone. But to have that voice, that ability to express yourself and share your human experience with others, to have stories to share and advice to dispense and objections to raise - to have it and not to exercise it in a meaningful way? For me that seems a waste. And so I write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I actually haven&amp;rsquo;t been writing much the past couple of weeks, aside from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/tags/weeknotes&#34;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;. I pumped out a couple of longish and in my mind pretty good posts early in the month (&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/old-web/&#34;&gt;Tales of the Old Web&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/burnout/&#34;&gt;Burnout&lt;/a&gt;), but after that I found myself struggling to put some new ones together. Somehow in my mind I became trapped in the idea that I needed to have these long, profound, well-researched essays as posts. Browsing blogs like Alexey Guzey&amp;rsquo;s (author of the post linked at the start of this one) certainly hasn&amp;rsquo;t helped - on his &lt;a href=&#34;https://guzey.com/notes/&#34;&gt;notes page&lt;/a&gt; he mentions that some of his better posts take upwards of 100+ hours to write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I kind of fell into the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/11/comparison-is-the-thief-of-joy/&#34;&gt;trap of comparison&lt;/a&gt; and wanted to be writing thesis papers? Except that&amp;rsquo;s not really my style. I can probably churn out some longer pieces if they&amp;rsquo;ve been formulating in my head for a while, but for the most part, my regular blogging consists of thoughts-in-the-moment, a snapshot of where my thinking is at that time, to be built upon and to be evolved later on. And I think that&amp;rsquo;s fine, I think everyone has their own unique writing/blogging style and voice that they need to develop to see what works best for them. Maybe as time goes on, I will tend more towards longer-form posts, but for now I have to listen to my own advice and remember that &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/01/not-all-posts-have-to-be-profound/&#34;&gt;not all posts have to be profound&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past few years or so, and especially since I got interested in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/11/indieweb/&#34;&gt;Indieweb stuff&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve also been more on the lookout for interesting blogs to read. Personal blogs, none of that &amp;ldquo;professional blogger&amp;rdquo; crap. There&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of interesting sites out there, a lot of them long-running ones even. With the rise of social media silos, having personal websites and blogs hasn&amp;rsquo;t really gotten mainstream attention, but there&amp;rsquo;s still plenty of people writing out there. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve added more blogs to my RSS reader over the past 12 months than I have over the preceding 5ish years or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It saddens me a bit that among people of my cohort I am one among very few who are (still) actively blogging. I have a large folder of RSS feeds named &amp;ldquo;people I know&amp;rdquo;, many of them have tried blogging at some point or another, and all of those links are inactive or even inaccessible. Friends: please write more! You can revive your old sites if you like, you don&amp;rsquo;t even have to explain!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still have a bunch of reorganizing my RSS feeds to do, but I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to put enough feeds into a folder called &amp;ldquo;blogroll&amp;rdquo; that seems suitable for sharing, so I created a new &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/page/blogroll&#34;&gt;Blogroll page&lt;/a&gt; where you can see some of the blogs I follow. Very few of these are people I know IRL, mostly I just stumbled upon their blogs via some method or other. Many of them are tech-related though not all of them are. All are reasonably active. I thought about tagging or categorizing them somehow, but it&amp;rsquo;s rude to put people into boxes, so maybe it&amp;rsquo;s rude to do that for their websites too, just let people be people and let blogs be blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to maintain an older blogroll back in the day, but it seems that has already been lost to the dustbin of history, so this one is brand new and built from scratch. (If I find the older one, I might put it on that page too as a record of history.) As with many other things on the site, the blogroll is perpetually under renovation, so if you find (or have) a personal blog that you think I might find interesting, feel free to tell me about it and maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll add it there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Technical note: The blogroll listing is automatically imported from a JSON-formatted OPML file. I got the idea from &lt;a href=&#34;https://jlelse.blog/dev/auto-blogroll-hugo/&#34;&gt;this post by jlelse&lt;/a&gt;, and coincidentally he is also on the blogroll.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me: I&amp;rsquo;m having trouble writing long-form posts recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also me: Hey, I wrote a thousand words on blogging without thinking about it!&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Burnout
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/burnout/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/burnout/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;In the middle of 2015, after 12ish years of working at the same company, I said to myself &amp;ldquo;I think I&amp;rsquo;m burnt out.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember that after a few days of ruminating over it I finally decided and said out loud to myself &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s it, I&amp;rsquo;m done.&amp;rdquo; By the end of the year I had left the company. I didn&amp;rsquo;t write about the burnout then, out of respect for my former employer. But it&amp;rsquo;s been a while, I think the time has come to write about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I know I was burnt out? I don&amp;rsquo;t believe there is any generally accepted consensus of symptoms for burnout, but I had a good set of indicators:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exhaustion, both physical and mental. More and more often I found myself simply &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/08/some-days-you-are-tired/&#34;&gt;tired&lt;/a&gt; of everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;frustration with all the problems at work and the projects I was assigned to, frustration that we kept running into the same issues again and again (mostly relating to scheduling and deadlines and resources), and frustration that any concerns I raised were not being addressed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thinking about work all the time, even on my off hours I would be mentally considered the open Jira tickets, etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a feeling of helplessness in the face of overwhelming and seemingly never-ending project issues, re:scheduling, resources, quality, and so on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a general feeling that that the effort I was putting in wasn&amp;rsquo;t worth it or wasn&amp;rsquo;t appreciated as much as I&amp;rsquo;d have liked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;general lack of free time, and even when there was free time, lack of energy to pursue anything productive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;permanently broken sleep cycle (a problem I still struggle with to this day)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work at my former employer had always been&amp;hellip; challenging, to say the least. Overtime was not uncommon, and many people often quit citing the heavy workload. And yet I was generally happy/content working there for the better part of a decade. I kind of enjoyed and thrived in the environment most of the time, especially when facing technical challenges. Things got worse for me personally starting around 2014ish I think. There were a variety of challenges during this time, some of them due to the company/environment and some due to my own personal shortcomings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environment challenges:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a large project with constantly changing requirements and overly aggressive schedules (due to sales/marketing push) and almost continuous crunch. It felt like we were always jumping from one crisis to the next&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;needing to provide support for demo and live systems during off hours, due to the target clients being halfway across the world&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some clients and coworkers were challenging to work with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;during this period, the traffic situation in Metro Manila had gotten significantly worse, draining even more time and energy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal challenges:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a very strong sense of duty and responsibility. I realize this doesn&amp;rsquo;t sound like a negative, but it&amp;rsquo;d kind of a double-edged sword in that I take my duties as an employee very seriously and will sometimes sacrifice my own well-being if I think it is needed. For the longest time, one of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2012/08/232395423602573312/&#34;&gt;my favorite quotes has been&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Death is lighter than a feather, but Duty is heavier than a mountain” - Japanese proverb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find this quote symptomatic of the &amp;ldquo;hustle culture&amp;rdquo; that tends to lead to burnout. That&amp;rsquo;s probably a topic for another time, but the gist of it is that most companies and projects are a never-ending well of work that needs to be done, so much so that oftentimes the reward for good work is often more work. i.e.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/1185221831990464513/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The price for being the best is always having to be the best&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &amp;ldquo;sense of duty&amp;rdquo; was so strong that even when I realized I was burning out, I still gave half a year&amp;rsquo;s notice for resignation, because I at least wanted to make sure everything was fine before I left. (Spoilers: it would take them a couple more years to actually finish the project). Someone reminded me recently that I expressed regret at leaving &amp;ldquo;in wartime&amp;rdquo; since the project got even further delayed and many of the issues were unresolved at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;related to the above, I also had a strong sense of pride. I considered myself very good at my job (justifiably so, based on annual reviews etc) and somehow had the mentality that I needed to be able to carry the weight of the project by myself. Whenever there was a resource or scheduling problem, one of my first instincts was to be to offer to take on the needed load myself, no matter how busy I already was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhat related to the above, but I also had (and often still have) an obsessive-compulsive need to read and reply to all emails and messages and notifications immediately, even outside of work hours&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;coupled with my strong sense of duty is a lack of ability to say no. As an example, for some reason even after I realized I was burnt out and notified the company I was leaving, I agreed to go live in another country on-site for three months. While it was good to experience another country, the work-life balance while I was there was even worse because the time zone problem still existed (except in reverse, i.e. the dev team was now on the other end of the world), and now I became a bottleneck (since I was one of the only two people on-site) and had to dedicate more time to bridging the gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted, I think many of these issues existed even before, but perhaps most of them were exacerbated by the fact that we now had to provide support across two time zones seven hours apart. That really took a toll on my work-life balance. Looking back at my emails during that period, I would often be replying late into the night or even early in the morning. I think it was really a question of energy and time being in short supply. I almost burnt myself out again in 2018, but at least I had the sense to recognize it faster and to step back as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must point out that I bear no ill will towards my former employer or the people who worked there. There was a lot of room for improvement but everyone was just trying the best with what they were given. And I share some of the blame since I was kind of in a leadership position &amp;ndash; I should have pushed harder to make things better for everyone involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to avoid burnout:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;set reasonable boundaries between work time and personal time. Having a strong sense of duty is probably fine, as long as you know where that ends and to prioritize your own well-being as needed. Guard your free time zealously. As much as possible, don&amp;rsquo;t accept calls/messages outside of agreed upon work hours. The occasional exception for an emergency is probably fine, but don&amp;rsquo;t let it become a regular thing. Having well-defined boundaries allows your brain to avoid overlaps - if you&amp;rsquo;re at home, you should get used to not thinking about work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;understand your own value and your own limits. Having a good understanding of what you bring to the team and the limits of your own ability and capacity means you can more effectively allocate your time and energy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;always be aware of the employee-employer relationship. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to have a good working relationship with your superiors and coworkers and even to be friends with them, but never lose sight of the fact that to the employer, you are an employee. You aren&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;family&amp;rdquo; no matter what the company says. You are being paid to do a job, and that job has limits. You don&amp;rsquo;t owe the company your personal time or your absolute loyalty. It&amp;rsquo;s a capitalist enterprise, not a nation. Remember that in the end, the company will need to look out for itself (especially for publicly-traded companies), so you will need to look out for yourself as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learn to say no. This is coupled with the first two points above. If you know what your boundaries are and what your limits are, it will become easier to say &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo; to unreasonable requests. And remember that your personal time is your own, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to defend or explain why you don&amp;rsquo;t want to work on weekends or such&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;regularly reflect on how things are going. Check your energy levels to make sure they aren&amp;rsquo;t constantly low and that you&amp;rsquo;re getting enough recharge time. If you think are starting to burn out, pull back, take some time off, and reassess how to move forward. Assess also how the company is addressing your concerns, and if they aren&amp;rsquo;t or are unwilling to do so, consider whether it may be time to move on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For people in leadership/management positions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;understand the value and capabilities of your team and build them up. One of the best things about working in larger companies/projects/teams is that you have other people to back you up, to support you and handle things when you reach your limits. Understanding both your own limits and the team&amp;rsquo;s limits allow you to better allocate tasks to avoid burnout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it isn&amp;rsquo;t sufficient to simply be asking your team members &amp;ldquo;Are you still ok?&amp;rdquo;, because if they&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, they may not be aware that they are starting to burn out already. Pay attention to how they are performing and how much time, effort and energy they are putting them in, and don&amp;rsquo;t push them unnecessarily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if your team members raise a concern, make sure to not only listen but to make them know what is being done to address their concerns. Unaddressed problems lead to frustration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, software development is a demanding industry, and it tends to attract people like me - industrious people who enjoy and take pride in their work. (Hence the famous quote about laziness, impatience and hubris.) Add to that the common difficulties in estimation, scheduling and planning, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to understand why burnout is rampant in this industry. All the more reason for everyone involved to be aware of the risks of burnout and how to avoid it, and perhaps to somehow help reshape the industry to better avoid it.&lt;/p&gt;


            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Tales from the Old Web (Development)
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/old-web/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/old-web/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;There was this great (and long!) &lt;a href=&#34;https://eev.ee/blog/2020/02/01/old-css-new-css/&#34;&gt;article that came out recently about the history of CSS&lt;/a&gt;. It reminded me a lot of the old days when I started out in web development. So join me in a walk down memory lane as I reminisce about the trials and tribulations of early web development. (This one isn&amp;rsquo;t about CSS as much as that linked article.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out with web applications during the heyday of the much-maligned Internet Explorer 6, and pretty much the start of the age of webapps. Most of our projects during this time involved government agencies wanting to upgrade from their old existing client-server style systems. Those were often written in programming languages/tools like Delphi, Oracle Forms, PowerBuilder and such. That meant there was a lot of pressure on the web applications we developed to be able to match most of the client-side functionality available in those kinds of programs, which was often a challenge due to the limitations of the HTTP model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;activex&#34;&gt;ActiveX&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, the government agencies at that time used only Internet Explorer in their workstations, so we could write our web applications to target just IE specifically. This meant we could use things like ActiveX to attempt to do things browsers normally can&amp;rsquo;t do. Some of it was for security purposes, like confirming the user&amp;rsquo;s authentication matches the current workstation user, or for Single-Sign On purposes, things like that. There were also some for interfacing with things outside the web browser, like document scanners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also had to use some ActiveX to get around browser quirks. For example, IE6 had this problem with combo boxes/select elements where the width of the drop window would always match the width of the &lt;code&gt;select&lt;/code&gt; element, but this means if the &lt;code&gt;option&lt;/code&gt; text was longer than that width, they would not be readable. We had to make an ActiveX component just to fix this, by making the drop window wider on document load! Sample screenshot recovered from the vaults:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#f47a745a95a668a6f94a9b0ba34a768e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/old-web/Combo_hu3c773b5aac8489cf2c66b31c0ac0d078_147716_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;f47a745a95a668a6f94a9b0ba34a768e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/old-web/Combo.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;4 Feb 2020 12:00am&#34;&gt;4 Feb 2020 12:00am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other ActiveX uses were to do things that would later on become standard features in browsers. Some other examples I can recall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;spellchecking. We used an ActiveX component from a company called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wintertree-software.com/dev/wspell/info.html&#34;&gt;WinterTree software&lt;/a&gt;. I was surprised to find this particular product of theirs is still available, when practically all modern browsers have spellcheck support! I suppose it&amp;rsquo;s still useful for legacy environments maybe?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we had this one project that needed a complicated graphing diagram. Think about those pinboards with pictures and documents connected by wires that conspiracy theorists use in memes, something like that. These days that kind of thing can be done using modern HTML+Javascript only, but during the IE6 days we were still pretty limited. We used another third-party ActiveX (can no longer recall the component name), that we wrapped in our own Delphi program for customization purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, we ended up using ActiveX in some projects up to the early 2010s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gmail-and-ajax&#34;&gt;GMail and Ajax&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our initial webapps also did the thing where we would reload the page whenever doing something like going to the next page of results. This was pretty bad user experience-wise, especially compared to the client-server programs of old, which felt a lot more snappy since they were only loading the database results via the database driver, instead of an entire HTML page. By 2005, we were already using Ajax/XMLHttpRequest to get around these limitations in IE6. (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XMLHttpRequest&#34;&gt;The wikipedia entry&lt;/a&gt; says XHR didn&amp;rsquo;t officially exist in IE6, so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how we did that, but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure we did). Our main use was for paging search result grids, but we weren&amp;rsquo;t even fetching XML or JSON back then, the XHR response would be the grid HTML itself, which we just plop right where the previous page was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember I was talking to the SA for the project about ajax, he asked what it was and why we were using it, my explanations was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ajax is &amp;ldquo;Asynchronous Javascript and XML&amp;rdquo;; it&amp;rsquo;s a method of using
Javascript and XML data that allows us to make server-side (database)
calls without having to resubmit the entire page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use it because it&amp;rsquo;s cool =p With Ajax, we can do something like allow
the user to re-sort a grid of records without reloading the rest of the
page. It is easier for us to meet the performance reqt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve seen the Google Maps or GMail webapps, they both use Ajax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The response was (unedited):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used Gmail.  AJas is client side library??? Seems they process very
fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(I would later kind of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/05/gmail-raises-the-bar-for-everyone/&#34;&gt;regret using Gmail as a comparison&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cross-browser-development&#34;&gt;Cross-browser development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of our projects were for internal systems where the workstations had controlled environments so we were free to target a single browser only (usually IE). Some projects also had a public-facing portal though, and that required we do some cross-browser frontend stuff. Early on, the typical targets other than IE where Netscape and Firefox. This is where the IE6 compatibility headaches come in. It was usually a game of write the code for IE first, then let the testers find any NS/FF issues, then quash accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started checking in Firefox around the quirks mode era, as described in the article linked at the start of this post. The biggest challenge really was getting everything pixel-perfectly the same between browsers. The typical problems were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;browser differences in CSS models (the famous box model issue)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;differences in native controls (typically the &lt;code&gt;select&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;input type=&#39;file&#39;&lt;/code&gt; controls were the more problematic ones)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for cases where we needed ActiveX plugins for IE6, we would also need to develop corresponding FF add-ins, usually targeting Firefox 2.x (It&amp;rsquo;s fun to think about how the current version of Firefox is 70 major versions ahead of that!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did very little cross-browser work at the start, with the proportion accelerating in tune with Firefox/Chrome&amp;rsquo;s rise in marketshare. By around 2010, it was common for projects to be testing across at least 2 versions of IE (6 and 7), 2 versions of Firefox (2 and 3), Google Chrome, and often Safari as well. (We didn&amp;rsquo;t really start thinking about Mac users until around 2007ish).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Chrome came out in 2008, I found some old comments I made to our internal tech team when it came out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an installer in t:\roy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not an OS, but it runs browser tabs in separate processes (literally&amp;hellip;each one has a different PID), such that a single webapp won&amp;rsquo;t crash everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info here: t:\keis\Google_Chrome.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it gets widespread adoption, it may affect the webapps we develop - it uses Webkit as a rendering engine (used by Safari), so it&amp;rsquo;s different from Firefox and IE. Haven&amp;rsquo;t encountered any problems yet though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also tested the memory usage of Chrome vs FF back then:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firefox - open 9 tabs. Check the memory consumption. Close 8 tabs. Check
the memory consumption. (Remains around the same as previous one)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Chrome, the memory usage of closed tabs is 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a far cry from Chrome&amp;rsquo;s modern reputation as a memory hog! (Although I guess that reputation is probably related to people keeping too many tabs open.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side story: while looking up old files for this post, I came upon a thread where we were discussing printing issues across browsers, and there was a problem in printing some pages from the browser because of limitations in IE6, and some management higher-up chimed in with a suggestion to &amp;ldquo;just tell the client to use IE7&amp;rdquo; as if the client will magically upgrade all their workstations for that one problem. :shrug:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;jquery&#34;&gt;jQuery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the linked article mentioned, jQuery raised the bar when it came out, allowing developers to easily paper over cross-browser JavaScript concerns and providing an API that became so prevalent, years later parts of it would become built-in to modern browsers (i.e. &lt;code&gt;document.querySelector&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shared the link to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2006/01/jquery-new-wave-javascript/&#34;&gt;jQuery via delicious&lt;/a&gt; in 2006, but for sure we weren&amp;rsquo;t using it yet in our projects at that time. Based on my own CV, the first time I used it in a project was in 2009. It quickly became part of our standard libraries. I still remember in one particular project I spent some time thrashing out a bunch of issues because we needed to upgrade from like jQuery 1.3 to 1.4? Or something like that. Normally we&amp;rsquo;d fix to a certain version, but I think we needed to upgrade because of a jQuery plugin we needed. This was before the modern frontend development frameworks where you already have dependency management tools, so we had to make sure none of our other third-party JS components would break with the upgrade. The company ended up using jQuery as a standard in projects up to the time I left in 2015. (I&amp;rsquo;m told they later on switched to Vue.js, so more power to them.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I identify as a &amp;ldquo;full stack developer&amp;rdquo;, but these days the &amp;ldquo;frontend&amp;rdquo; half of that usually implies usage of one of the modern frontend frameworks: Angular, React, or Vue. While I am cognizant of those frameworks and have tried them all in some form or another over the past few years, my frontend development experience is still largely defined by the jQuery era. So when setting up personal projects or quick prototypes that&amp;rsquo;s still what I default to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;css&#34;&gt;CSS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The linked article was about CSS, so I figured I should have some CSS stories too, but I find that I don&amp;rsquo;t have much, other than the cross-browser compat above. My main issue with CSS back then was that in a large project with a nontrivial amount of developers each working on separate screens, the CSS style sheets tended to get longer and denser with time. And with bug fixes and whatnot, it would tend to be full of hacks and workarounds like randomly placing &lt;code&gt;!important&lt;/code&gt; in so many places. I just assumed we had a whole bunch of CSS selectors that were no longer necessary but no one would bother cleaning up the style sheets because who knows what you&amp;rsquo;ll break? Basically a whole chaotic mess. IDK if modern tooling handles this because I haven&amp;rsquo;t been on larger projects since leaving the company, but I suppose the stronger delineation/specialization between frontend and backend dev work means less people to mess up the stylesheets, and those who do handle the styles are more aware of such pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thats-it-for-now&#34;&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it (for now)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this was a fun trip down memory lane. This post is already longer than I thought it would be, but those are all the old-timey stories I can recall right now. There&amp;rsquo;s a good chance there&amp;rsquo;s some more of them lodged in my brain somewhere that will come out sooner or later, so maybe there&amp;rsquo;s a part 2 sometime in the future.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2020/02/old-web/Combo_hu3c773b5aac8489cf2c66b31c0ac0d078_147716_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>This is Metro Manila
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/this-is-metro-manila/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/this-is-metro-manila/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Note: This post discusses the traffic situation in Metro Manila. I’ve had this post in the works for a while, and it kept getting longer and longer (possibly my longest post to date). I also had my friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/DavidRamirezSFFwriter/&#34;&gt;David&lt;/a&gt; review it first to make sure I wasn’t saying anything too ridiculous, and he and I discussed some of the things and some of his points made it into the final post.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve basically lived all my 40-odd years in Metro Manila (barring maybe at most half a year total spent outside the Metro). I started commuting around when I was 10-11 years old, so that’s around 1989ish. Jeepney fare then was I think P1.50? Maybe that was the student fare. I remember it took two rides to get to my elementary school so I needed P6 for a round trip. The minimum fare these days is P9, so the increase has been 600% in 30 years. Probably still a bit too low, as jeepney drivers are still quite poor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During GS, HS and college I rarely ventured too far from home (schools were always nearby) and mostly stuck to Quezon City. I only got to go to the other Metro cities when someone else was driving me there for some reason. I do remember one time I had to take a late night bus ride home from Paranaque during HS, it was my first time commuting in a fully-packed standing-room only bus. For the most part, I didn’t care too much about traffic growing up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still remember when the MRT3 opened up (Wikipedia says this was in ‘99), I took a ride during the first week just to go to Robinson’s Galleria, I think, for no reason. I was amazed because the train made it so much easier to go to Ortigas which before that had seemed very far (even back then the buses were always full). I remember thinking back then that the MRT3 had effectively reduced the space between cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003, I got a job in Ortigas in Pasig, around 13-14km from home. Not too far, and the commute route was a reasonable 45-60 minutes most days (and 30 mins on really good days). I took the MRT most of the time to Ortigas, as I still have some notes from around that time telling me it was a 1500-step walk from the MRT station to my office. North Avenue station was the first station on the North side, so although there was often a queue, it was reasonable and it wasn’t too hard to get on a train. On the way home from Ortigas, I’d prefer the bus. Since Ortigas was in the middle of the route, the MRT would be quite full by the time it got to Ortigas station, so the bus was easier and I’d often get to sit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracking my social media, I can tell I started complaining about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/22969325502&#34;&gt;MRT&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/11074462310&#34;&gt;traffic&lt;/a&gt; around 2010 onwards. Most probably the build-up to the problem started a few years before that, in the later half of GMA’s term. Traffic and commuting and the MRT had gotten constantly worse since then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time I left the Ortigas job in late 2015, I had to allocate somewhere around 2-3 hours for travel time, and even then I’d still occasionally be late. Even today, Google Maps tells me driving that distance at around 10am would take around 3 hours. MRT lines famously grew to be sometimes a kilometer long during rush hour at North Avenue. This was the line to get into the station! By this time I usually preferred taking an FX to ortigas, but that queue usually took at the minimum 30 mins to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/242417436496896000&#34;&gt;1 hr&lt;/a&gt;, possibly longer. By this time I had also started taking taxis and ubers where possible (I had the privilege of being able to afford more expensive rides), but even this was quite difficult..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally (or not), the traffic troubles coincide with the continuous years of economic growth since the time of GMA. Then-President Noynoy Aquino famously &lt;a href=&#34;https://ph.news.yahoo.com/aquino-traffic-sign-booming-economy-110430239.html&#34;&gt;pointed out this correlation&lt;/a&gt;, a bit of a tone deaf remark politically (in response to the complaints about traffic), but he was not incorrect. The big problem with the improved economy is that like elsewhere in the world, the gains are not evenly distributed, most of the economic gains went to big metropolitan areas like Metro Manila, which means people are still incentivized to work and move here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would not in and of itself have been a problem if the government managed Metro Manila well and scaled up infrastructure as needed to anticipate the economic growth. It’s not just the current admin or the previous admin or the local governments that’s dropped the ball, it’s basically everyone in the national and local governments since the 80s. This catastrophic traffic was &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.abs-cbn.com/news/10/08/19/palafox-traffic-fixes-8-lrt-lines-edsa-long-walkway-no-more-mm-govt-offices&#34;&gt;predicted at least 40 years ago&lt;/a&gt; yet not much has been done. It’s obvious that Metro Manila is overflowing and congested, even our water and power infrastructure is being pushed to the limit in the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intermission&lt;/strong&gt;: Signs you might be living in Metro Manila:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wearing your backpack in front to avoid theft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not leaving your wallet and cellphone in your pockets while commuting to avoid pickpockets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waiting at least one hour in the queue for an FX or Jeep or a taxi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Waking up at 5am or earlier to get to your 9pm job and just recovering some sleep in the FX or bus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cramming yourselves into the MRT or bus like a can of sardines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Haggling with your taxi driver because your destination is “too far” or “there’s too much traffic”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going to wait for the bus at the no loading/unloading zone like everyone else because if you waited at the actual loading zone you’d never get anywhere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walking a kilometer upstream of where you’re going to get a better chance of actually getting on a bus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allocating an extra hour or two to your travel time to important meetings to allot for the occasional MRT breakdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not enjoying December even though it’s holiday season because you know the traffic is going to be horrendous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hanging around some extra hours at the office or at the mall rather than exhausting yourself trying to get a ride during rush hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actually walking at least 5km to get to work when all else has failed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solutions&lt;/strong&gt;: Before the &amp;ldquo;dami mong angal, ano solusyon mo?&amp;rdquo; crowd get into this, I&amp;rsquo;ll go ahead and make some suggestions. I’m not a city planning expert or anything, just a layperson giving some suggestions that I think are reasonable and/or common sense, and probably better than coming up with inane ideas like “coding by car brand” or suggesting that people just wake up earlier to get to their destinations or denying that we have a mass transportation crisis. The solutions I suggest here are not intended to be a “be-all, end-all”, but perhaps can be the starting point of discussions. And, I know that given the implementation track record of our government this may be difficult, but spitballing solutions to these problems also requires perhaps not a little bit of optimism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short-term solutions&lt;/strong&gt;: It’s sad to say this, but I don’t believe there are any viable short-term solutions. None that can cause widespread relief from the traffic problems anyway. Most of the systemic solutions will be on a timeline of 5 years or more, and will definitely cost serious money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On a personal level&lt;/strong&gt;, the best thing any individual could do would be to adapt his own situation as much as possible. If your commute is in the order of 2-3 hours or more per direction, I would strongly suggest looking for a better arrangement, either look for a job closer to home, rent a place closer to your work, or ask for WFH privileges. I realize that not everyone can afford these changes, but sometimes you’ll be surprised at what you can afford.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that people are often quite bad at evaluating tradeoffs in time vs money, with a general preference towards money. For example if you’re working in an industry like mine (software development) where the salaries are generally higher than the average in the Metro, there’s a good chance you can afford to pay a bit more for rent or accept a lower salary if it brings you closer to home. But many people will refuse that tradeoff because for them money is the most important thing. Never mind that you’re wasting 5-6 hours daily in traffic. If money were really that important to you, consider spending it to save maybe 3-4 hours of travel time and use the extra time to freelance online and earn more money. Being stuck in traffic doesn’t earn you more money, it takes away your time and your energy and your mental health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emergency powers&lt;/strong&gt;: I actually don’t mind giving the government emergency powers to the government to help speed up procurement timelines and such, but senator Grace Poe has a point when she says the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.philstar.com/headlines/2019/09/14/1951678/grace-poe-emergency-powers-ok-if-backed-master-plan&#34;&gt;DoTr has to at least provide a specific plan/outline&lt;/a&gt; as to how they are going to use those emergency powers, instead of just granting them a blank check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move jobs and labor out of Metro Manila&lt;/strong&gt;. Or at least out of the major business districts (Makati, Ortigas, Taguig). Of course, the government can’t force businesses to move to less congested areas or outside the Metro altogether, but perhaps the economics can be made to favor moving out. The problem with this is that labor and capital are caught in kind of a loop: capital wants to establish offices where the labor market is so they prefer the business districts and are willing to pay higher salaries there; labor wants to work where the salaries are high and there are many options so they prefer those areas too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One common suggestion I see (on reddit, etc) is to &lt;strong&gt;increase the minimum wage in the provinces to reduce the flow of labor to Metro Manila&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a reasonable first step, although it affects mainly the lower-skilled workers. For example, if a construction worker could be paid the same rate in his home province as in MM, he would be less inclined to go to MM. For higher-skilled work this can be a challenge, since it requires that those companies move or establish offices in the provinces, and increasing salaries run counter to that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be also good to incentivize (provide tax breaks or benefits) things like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies that provide work from home days for their workers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies that provide shifting or flexible hours to avoid rush hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies that establish in less populated regions (PEZA incentives, but more widespread)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies that provide relocation assistance for new hires in less populated regions (so they live closer to work)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affordable housing in major business areas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the problem with incentives like these is that not only are they revenue-negative, they also add to the administrative burden, i.e. more work is involved to make sure the incentives are going to the right companies. I think it would probably be a simpler approach to &lt;strong&gt;just disincentivize (i.e. tax) companies that have offices in major business areas&lt;/strong&gt;, to discourage further congestion in those areas. The additional tax rate can be made to scale according to the number of employees the company has, so as not to penalize smaller businesses, and the more you contribute to congestion, the more you pay. This has the added benefit of raising money for the needed infrastructure improvements elsewhere. It should be a national government imposed tax (so the cities can’t muddle with it), though the local governments can be asked to help in collections to simplify effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move government offices out of Metro Manila.&lt;/strong&gt; While we can’t force companies to move out of Metro Manila, there is one big employer that we can just order to, and that’s government. As an example, just near where I live, there’s the Department of Agriculture, Department of Agrarian Reform, Bureau of Jail Management and Prisons, National Housing Authority, etc. There’s no reason these offices have to be in Metro Manila; heck for the DA and DAR it’s probably better to have their main offices closer to the farmlands. There’s also camps like Camp Crame and Camp Aguinaldo. I can see an argument for having the civilian police headquarters in the metro (but probably not smack-dab in the middle of EDSA), but why the military headquarters? Many of these government facilities aren’t in the more congested business districts, but the more we can reduce the overall population of Metro Manila, the better. And moving them to the provinces has the benefit of adding jobs to those areas too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infrastructure:&lt;/strong&gt; Obviously MM needs a lot more of everything: more trains, more train lines, bridges across Pasig River, etc. The focus should be on improving mass transportation options instead of more roads or routes, since those &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vox.com/2014/10/23/6994159/traffic-roads-induced-demand&#34;&gt;just incentivize people to drive more&lt;/a&gt;. We as a country are hopefully on a path to continue economic growth, so our infra needs to be better able to scale up with that growth, and that means mass transportation. This is already a well-known thing, I’m not saying anything new here, the bigger problem is that the governments take forever to implement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subway:&lt;/strong&gt; I am cautiously optimistic about the planned subway from Quezon City to Taguig. David is worried that it will likely be flooded a lot of the time, and that’s much more costly than just an equivalent above-ground rail line. I think the major difference is that the above-ground rail line would have more right of way issues so it may take longer to complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bikes:&lt;/strong&gt; It would be a big change culturally, but if we really want the city to be able to support larger populations, we have to promote usage of bikes. That means developing bike lanes and bike-friendly roads bike-friendly parking and having companies provide work lockers so people can change and not be smelly after biking to work. Having a bike culture would be a much more efficient use of road space and also improve the health of the population in general and be very eco-friendly. Much better than our current trend of more and more motorcycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mass transportation:&lt;/strong&gt; we need more, not less. As a lifelong commuter I cringe whenever I find private car owners complaining that PUVs are causing all of the traffic and there should be fewer of them on the street. Try commuting during the rush hours when it’s difficult to get a ride and see if you still have that sentiment. It’s true that PUV drivers need a lot more discipline, but the solution there is to revamp the business model of those services to avoid having the drivers behave that way. The boundary system has to be the single biggest cause of PUV traffic problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jeepney (and Bus) Modernization:&lt;/strong&gt; I support the goals of jeepney modernization, though in general I think the government is going about it the wrong way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when we lived at our grandmother’s house, our next-door neighbor was a jeepney driver. I like to think that he owned his vehicle (it was always parked at their house), but for all I know he was paying a daily boundary somehow. He ran the Project 2-3 route along Kamias/Anonas, and sometimes he’d recognize us kids when we get a ride on his jeep, and he’d refuse to accept our fare. There is a romanticized notion of the jeepney driver as the serial pull-up-by-your-bootstraps informal entrepreneur, symbolic of Filipino genius and creative expression with all their decorations, and I think such a thing would be fine in smaller municipalities. For a large, densely crowded beast like Metro Manila, it’s simply not an approach that scales, and it’s time to move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public transport is a public good&lt;/strong&gt;. I believe transport routes should be treated similar to services like water or power. A single service provider, chosen through a competitive bidding process, would serve each area or route/set of routes. If you’ve tried any of the good public transportation systems in other cities like Singapore or Hong Kong, you know this is how it works. Public transport routes are a centralized service, not run by individuals cowboys jostling with each other for riders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t propose to immediately replace existing jeepney and bus operators with such service providers. It’s ridiculous to think such a transition could be done in a one-time, big-time manner. I would choose a few pilot routes/areas where we can introduce the new service providers. They can initially be competing alongside the existing PUVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The service providers could propose the initial fare rate themselves as part of their bids. One of the criteria for the competitive bidding process would be that the rates must be reasonable. Competition with the existing routes would also hopefully keep the rates in line. Rate increases would be subject to approval by a regulatory commission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, each route/area being monopolized by a single service provider means each driver no longer needs to compete with other drivers on the next route. But we’ll need strict SLAs in place to make sure the service is being provided as expected. The franchise grant should impose certain requirements such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Euro-4 compliant engines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fixed salaries, benefits and no commissions for drivers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prioritize existing drivers of the same jeepney routes when hiring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;observance of fixed stops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimum of X vehicles in the field during lean hours and minimum of Y hours during rush hours (as defined by government - need to conduct studies on the optimum numbers for each route).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Penalties for traffic violations by their drivers (with some leeway)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And so on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other factors such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what kind of vehicles to use (maybe subject to branding guidelines and maintenance standards)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how much to pay the drivers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;can be left up to the service providers, for them to balance vis-a-vis their proposed rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would however prefer we get higher capacity vehicles than just the 20-22 passengers that jeepneys today can support. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking something like the public buses/shuttles used in Hong Kong or Singapore. I believe they are smaller than the city buses we have on EDSA, so they can navigate our narrower streets. Maybe prescribe a minimum passenger capacity for vehicles? Actually I would assume the economics are in favor of more capacity (since it means each trip can earn more money), so it might happen naturally. Of course not all routes would be able to support such buses, so maybe only where it makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this scheme, we may end up with transport fares slightly higher than what we have now. Probably closer to FX rates really. And honestly, it’s a bit anti-poor, but I think it’s something we have to live with. One of the big reasons the jeepney modernization plan is hard to pull off is because the current fares mean that drivers earn very little for a day’s work. At least this way the market determines the initial rates and the drivers don’t have to live in abject poverty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, we pilot the program on a few routes, and then we can observe the first few routes for a maybe 3-6 months. Are there enough vehicles servicing the route? Are drivers earning enough money? Has traffic worsened? Then adjust the parameters for the next set of routes. We should aim to strike a balance between low fares and reasonable income for the drivers and service providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the goals should be to make it attractive for existing drivers to switch over to working for the service providers. And also slowly wean people away from using jeeps. Same process could be applied to buses too. Franchise grants can be relatively short so that non performing suppliers can be replaced easily. Once the public gets used to the new service, we can phase out the old jeepneys on a per route basis. (Not all the old jeepney drivers will want to work for the service providers, alternative livelihood assistance may be needed for them)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Premium transportation options:&lt;/strong&gt; Senator Grace Poe (her again?) was derided recently for a suggestion to have “business class trains” in the MRT to encourage the upper class to take public transportation. Trying to do this in the MRT now is ridiculously impractical (which is why she was derided for the suggestion). However, I do agree that having premium transportation options available to the more affluent might be a good idea. It can still help to reduce the number of cars on the road. I’m especially fond of the P2P buses that were introduced to the Metro a few years back. They’re a lot more expensive than regular buses, but they’re comfortable and as long as it’s not rush hour, there’s not much of a queue. I often take a P2P bus where available. Maybe more routes are in order? Perhaps along the hopefully soon-to-be-finished North-South skyway?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Port congestion is also an issue&lt;/strong&gt; that contributes to the traffic as well. A lot of trucks are needed to carry the cargo offloaded in the port of Manila to the provinces. I would suggest developing other ports North and South of Metro Manila and diverting as much of the port traffic there as possible. I know we already have some existing nearby ports such as the port of Batangas, but AFAIK there’s still a lot of cargo traffic from outside Metro Manila passing through the port of Manila. The goal should be to minimize that. David also suggests developing freight rail lines from the port of Manila to provincial hubs. Freight rail can fast track cargo shipments instead of relying on trucks which add to traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional:&lt;/strong&gt; Another issue with Metro Manila is that it’s composed of different fiefdoms, er, cities. Each of them have their own jurisdictions and traffic rules and so on. This is unnecessary and contributes to the chaos. I would suggest &lt;strong&gt;having a centralized authority managing transportation issues&lt;/strong&gt; in MM. Something like how Transport for London manages transportation in the greater London area. This body would be responsible for things like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;managing service providers, rates, traffic rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;enforcement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;conducting studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;proposing solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traffic management duties of the MMDA can be absorbed by this new body. This requires taking away some autonomy from the local governments, so it requires legislation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stark reality is that no matter the denials, we are in the middle of mass transportation crisis in Metro Manila and will probably remain that way for the foreseeable future. We may get some short-term relief from some projects that may finish in the next couple of years (North-South Skyway, etc). But in the long term there is much, much more that we need to do to turn Metro Manila into a sustainable megacity. The idealist in me still hopes we can get our act together and somehow get there. Like I said, a reasonable amount of optimism is needed. We shall see, shan’t we?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/10/this-is-metro-manila/P_20181126_170127_hudebc1a09ce367cac7560877d90292e1b_861199_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Reddit PH: Software Dev Q&amp;A
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/reddit-ph-software-dev-qa/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 05:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2019/02/reddit-ph-software-dev-qa/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I had some free time the other day so I randomly decided to post in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Philippines/&#34;&gt;PH subreddit&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s regular afternoon &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Philippines/comments/arsxjg/afternoon_random_discussion_feb_18_2019/&#34;&gt;random discussion thread&lt;/a&gt;, asking for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Philippines/comments/arsxjg/afternoon_random_discussion_feb_18_2019/egpog87/&#34;&gt;questions about software development&lt;/a&gt;. I ended up typing some longish answers, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d copy them over to the blog in case anyone was interested. TBH I meant more like StackOverflow type questions with specific technical problems, but I ended up answering mostly career-related questions, which is fine, but disclaimer: I don&amp;rsquo;t claim to be an expert, these are just my opinions on things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Philippines/comments/arsxjg/afternoon_random_discussion_feb_18_2019/egpolbt/&#34;&gt;capybara_c0de&lt;/a&gt;: project/s junior devs should include in his/her portfolio?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve technical interviewed a lot of entry-level/junior level devs. Honestly any kind of project would probably be okay, as long as you&amp;rsquo;re able to explain what role you played, bonus points if you&amp;rsquo;re able to discuss technical decisions you made (why was this choice made, and why not this other one etc) or specific technical challenges you were able to overcome. That kind of stuff. Really, if you can demonstrate that you really worked on a project (and not just coasted by on teammates help etc), you&amp;rsquo;re already an above average interview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entry-level candidates might have more trouble since they often won&amp;rsquo;t have a portfolio, but the quality of candidates is a bit low locally, so if you can demonstrably do simple stuff like loops, recursion, stacks, etc you&amp;rsquo;re probably already an above average interview. Bigger companies will have written exams to filter out peeps who can&amp;rsquo;t do that though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More random technical interviewing tips, even though you didn&amp;rsquo;t ask for that: being able to communicate well is a big plus, mandatory even. Lack of confidence makes the interviewer worry that you don&amp;rsquo;t really know what you&amp;rsquo;re talking about. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll slip in something I know to be wrong &amp;ldquo;Diba pag cinall mo yan, ganito mangyayari?&amp;rdquo;, and see how the candidate reacts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Philippines/comments/arsxjg/afternoon_random_discussion_feb_18_2019/egpp2yr/&#34;&gt;veeequalseyeare&lt;/a&gt;: How many years of experience do you have? And what&amp;rsquo;s your basic salary?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do people keep asking about salary? That&amp;rsquo;s not really a programming or software dev question. I am a freelancing consultant at the moment, so I can&amp;rsquo;t really give a simple answer to that anyway (it&amp;rsquo;s almost always &amp;ldquo;it depends&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will answer the experience one - 15ish years in the industry (yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m old).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit: Also, there is a high range in the salaries of software devs in this country (not sure if the same elsewhere, probably), because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some people are better at selling themselves than others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some devs are way better than others (and thus are more valuable)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;each dev&amp;rsquo;s career path and growth is often unique, so it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to compare, especially once you rack up some years of experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i.e. for a given number of years of experience, the salary band will be quite wide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get that when you&amp;rsquo;re starting out, salary is a big deal, but honestly if you&amp;rsquo;re a decent enough programmer, you can get into any place with above average salary. You can grow your salary a bit faster by hopping jobs every so often, but too many hops looks bad on a resume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my advice is that once you get to a decent salary range that is good for you (i.e. you&amp;rsquo;re not starving), focus less on comparing yourself to other people, and more on increasing your own value and managing your work/life balance. Money isn&amp;rsquo;t everything, beyond basic survival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Philippines/comments/arsxjg/afternoon_random_discussion_feb_18_2019/egpqfdb/&#34;&gt;getmeoutofherealive&lt;/a&gt;: Anong advice ang maibibigay mo kapag gusto magcareer shift? Ex: IT Support to Development/Programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shifting careers from IT support isn&amp;rsquo;t an unreasonable proposition, but you need to already know your stuff before going in for interviews. You will also still need some basic level of programming knowledge. A lot of things you&amp;rsquo;ll need can be learned on the fly/on the job (like usage of specific languages or tools or libraries), but you need a good basic foundation to build on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I&amp;rsquo;m interviewing someone coming from a nonprogrammming background, I&amp;rsquo;ll basically be treating her as an entry-level candidate. You will need to be able to justify why I should hire you over say, a fresh grad who still remembers his java programming from his college days. The interviewer will need to know you&amp;rsquo;re not trying to BS your way into the position. Having some work you can show off (side projects or whatever) can be a big help. You can also cite anything you&amp;rsquo;re doing in your current domain that might show off some related skillset. Like, if you did some minor scripting to gather support statistics, something like that? IDK if IT support people do that kind of stuff. See my other interview tips in the other answer elsewhere in this thread too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Philippines/comments/arsxjg/afternoon_random_discussion_feb_18_2019/egpquyz/&#34;&gt;captainph&lt;/a&gt;: web services in web development, ELI5 please&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait, what do you mean? Web services are like web pages, except they&amp;rsquo;re endpoints that usually do only one thing and return some machine readable format like JSON or XML instead of HTML that can be rendered and viewed by a human in a browser. Basically you send them an HTTP request and they maybe do some processing and spit back an HTTP response that you consume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some types are simpler than others - REST-based web services are usually very simple for example, and can sometimes be invoked directly via the browser address bar. Some follow more complicated protocols (SOAP) that support things like authentication and signing and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web services are developed the same way as normal web pages, with the usual backend processing and stuff (but there are some frameworks to make this easier, especially for complicated protocols like SOAP), but the client program (the one calling the web services) does not have to be another web application. It can be a mobile app for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the typical usages would be third-party integration. For example, Philhealth I believe currently has some kind of e-Claims web services in development (maybe? IDK the current status), where the idea is to allow third-party systems to submit Philhealth claims electronically. The idea is that individual hospitals have their own medical records systems, those systems can send HTTP requests to the e-claims web services in order to for example check whether a patient is eligible for a claim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, sorry I know that explanation doesn&amp;rsquo;t really work for a 5-year old lol&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Philippines/comments/arsxjg/afternoon_random_discussion_feb_18_2019/egptmll/&#34;&gt;acequeen21&lt;/a&gt;: Do you have plans going abroad? Either work temporarily or move permanently. Why or why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah, I like living here, in spite of everything, and I&amp;rsquo;m programming avails me a good living naman. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked abroad on short stints (pinadala ng company), but TBH, I had never even considered leaving the country long-term, but I started looking into it after 2016. Hassle for me na ma-uproot and to try to start over elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Globe&#39;s Fair Use Policy and the &#34;Rotten Bananas&#34;, four years later
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/02/globes-fair-use-policy-and-the-rotten-bananas-four-years-after/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 01:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2018/02/globes-fair-use-policy-and-the-rotten-bananas-four-years-after/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;Around four years ago (give or take a few days), one of my many Twitter interactions with Globe Telecom&amp;rsquo;s CS account went a little bit viral due to them trying to justify their Fair Use Policy by calling 3% of their users &amp;ldquo;rotten bananas&amp;rdquo;. Apparently I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother writing on the blog about it back then, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;GiJBHdX&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/GiJBHdX&#34;&gt;View post on imgur.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exchange went a tiny bit viral on social media, with friends telling me about people I don&amp;rsquo;t know sharing the image of the conversation on Facebook and Twitter. (I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it was the exact same image above.). Even today, if you &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?client=firefox-b-ab&amp;amp;ei=QSl7Wp-HGcK40ASUmYWQBg&amp;amp;q=globe+%22rotten+bananas%22&amp;amp;oq=globe+%22rotten+bananas%22&amp;amp;gs_l=psy-ab.3...19552.21332.0.21630.2.2.0.0.0.0.107.213.0j2.2.0....0...1c.1.64.psy-ab..0.1.107...0i22i30k1.0.tqjY78J2On0&amp;amp;gfe_rd=cr&amp;amp;dcr=0&#34;&gt;Google ‘Globe &amp;ldquo;rotten bananas&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;‘ you still get &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fashionpulis.com/2014/02/talk2globe-refers-to-heavy-data-users.html&#34;&gt;a few relevant hits.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe the CS account eventually deleted the offending tweets, I can only see &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/431649435047583745&#34;&gt;my own tweets&lt;/a&gt; on the matter:&lt;/p&gt;


    On 
    &lt;a href=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2014/02/431649435047583745/&#34;&gt;&lt;time datetime=&#34;2014-02-07 04:43:39&#34;&gt;7 Feb 2014 4:43am&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    I wrote:
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/talk2GLOBE/&#34;&gt;@talk2GLOBE&lt;/a&gt; did you just call 3% of your customers rotten bananas? Saging lang may puso!&lt;/p&gt;

        






    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Globe Telecom no longer offers any plans with &amp;ldquo;unlimited data&amp;rdquo;, as far as I know. I feel like I can claim some nontrivial responsibility in that decision, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem like something to be proud of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I myself had resisted shifting to a new plan for a while (so I can carry over my unlimited data), but eventually had to shift to a 3gb capped plan because I wanted to get my mom a new phone on the cheap. They do offer unlimited data for their new fiber home broadband plans, for around 30% higher monthly fees than the capped plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;imgur-embed-pub&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; data-id=&#34;Cg5GI3G&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/Cg5GI3G&#34;&gt;View post on imgur.com&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//s.imgur.com/min/embed.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think about it, a 3gb bandwidth cap seems ridiculous in this day and age, but I&amp;rsquo;ve pretty much changed my behavior around it. I now very rarely watch Youtube or Facebook videos on the go for example. I prefer to watch stuff on the Desktop. (Phone screens are too tiny to appreciate most videos anyway.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going off on a slight tangent, our home broadband is now on a 50gb Globe fiber plan. Yes, I actually doubled-down on Globe despite all my problems with their customer service. In fact, even the migration of our Bayantel line over to Globe fiber was not without incident. Sadly, there is very little choice for high-speed coverage in our area. (I&amp;rsquo;m not inclined to try PLDT since I have a number of friends who also have poor customer service experience with them, and Converge isn&amp;rsquo;t available in our area.). We&amp;rsquo;ve only had the fiber service for a little more than a month, but it&amp;rsquo;s reasonably good so far. Some occasional slowdowns, but generally downloads are a lot faster. We have a bandwidth cap, but it&amp;rsquo;s at 600gb and there&amp;rsquo;s a mobile app that lets me monitor it. During the first month we only used less than 400gb, so I guess the cap is okay for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think overall we still have some of the worst internet service in the region. The poor quality of internet service in the Philippines has been &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/roytang/status/84881163134574592&#34;&gt;one of my all-time pet peeves&lt;/a&gt; about living in this country. Hopefully the promised third telco player to be introduced brings us some improvements in terms of higher bandwidth caps and speeds and better prices.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Sketching Daily
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 15:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a bit more free time recently, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been filling that time by starting up some hobbies (some old, some new). One of them has been sketching. I&amp;rsquo;ve been drawing things for as long as I remember &amp;ndash; I have elementary and high school notebooks with more doodles and x-men drawings than there are notes. And even at work, I often find other meeting participants checking out the random sketches I had been absently doing while other people were speaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started following this &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/sketchdaily&#34;&gt;subreddit SketchDaily&lt;/a&gt;. What they do is they have a bot post a daily theme (submitted by other users) and users post their sketches for others&amp;rsquo; comments. &amp;ldquo;Sketches&amp;rdquo; is a wide-ranging term here, submissions can be anything &amp;ndash; redditors will typically post sketches with a wide range of skillsets (some are beginners and some quite advanced) and mediums (some do real-life paper sketches or inked and colored drawings, others do digital stuff drawn on tablets or with photoshop).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you follow me on Instagram (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/roytang0400/&#34;&gt;@roytang0400&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s funny how I got that account, but that&amp;rsquo;s a story for another day), you know I&amp;rsquo;ve been posting my sketches for a bit more than a month now. I haven&amp;rsquo;t written a blog post in a while, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post about this and maybe show a bit of how I do my sketches. I&amp;rsquo;m not super talented or anything, although I like to think I&amp;rsquo;m not a beginner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For March 15th, the theme posted on r/SketchDaily was &amp;ldquo;Lots of Dinosaurs&amp;rdquo;. I usually try to relate the theme to a pop culture thing I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with &amp;ndash; something from movies, TV or video games. Since I&amp;rsquo;m a big Transformers fan, my first instinct was to do a drawing of the Dinobots. I&amp;rsquo;m not good enough yet to do one from scratch, so I usually search online for an image to use as reference. (I find that my sketches get a bit worse when I don&amp;rsquo;t use a reference)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the following image via Google Images, originally hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;http://kaiju-kingdom-hearts.wikia.com/wiki/Dinobots:&#34;&gt;http://kaiju-kingdom-hearts.wikia.com/wiki/Dinobots:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://vignette2.wikia.nocookie.net/kaiju-kingdom-hearts/images/3/3d/Dinobots_roar_by_kevinraganit-d5fx2sa.png/revision/latest?cb=20130130175814&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The five Dinobots (if you are ignorant) are Grimlock (center, T-Rex), Snarl (bottom left, Stegosaurus), Slag/Slug (bottom right, triceratops, he was renamed to Slug in later versions because apparently Slag had negative connotations somewhere), Sludge (top right, apatosaurus), and Swoop (top left, pteranodon)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually start by doing a light-pencil sketch of a rough outline and layout:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#88ad935342748c2fc90af1967ce88d6e-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_204514_hud5d95845c0897730f4408e4b6f3d35eb_789423_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;88ad935342748c2fc90af1967ce88d6e-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_204514.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;15 Mar 2016 3:39pm&#34;&gt;15 Mar 2016 3:39pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m drawing on a cheap sketchpad I bought for like 50 pesos using a 2B pencil. I usually just take pictures of my submissions using my cellphone camera, which explains the shadow near the bottom. I started out placing Grimlock&amp;rsquo;s head then placing the other Dinobots around him. It turned out that I had made Grimlock&amp;rsquo;s head a bit too big which meant I didn&amp;rsquo;t have room to place the other Dinobots exactly as they were in the reference image, I had to bunch them up closer (Sludge is mostly just a neck and head now), but that&amp;rsquo;s fine. Too lazy to start over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I have the initial light-pencil sketch, I draw in some heavier lines. I start with Grimlock in the center:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#14faea794ba25dbd0a77db6de50e46cb-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_210755_hu4a93ab3f911b11004ea0f6f637aa63f0_836561_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;14faea794ba25dbd0a77db6de50e46cb-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_210755.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;15 Mar 2016 3:39pm&#34;&gt;15 Mar 2016 3:39pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Snarl and Slag on either side:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#a810d46f7726c6af4a81eb740543a83a-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_213816_hud53ae180c1a19f20351f13d984d49fe6_1001878_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;a810d46f7726c6af4a81eb740543a83a-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_213816.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;15 Mar 2016 3:39pm&#34;&gt;15 Mar 2016 3:39pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the last two, Swoop and Sludge:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#e685b8a707a547e71bc1146eaf4bc3aa-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_215206_hu6ab6a54fc1b241a238e4494a1d9438df_903868_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;e685b8a707a547e71bc1146eaf4bc3aa-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_215206.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;15 Mar 2016 3:39pm&#34;&gt;15 Mar 2016 3:39pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, usually I&amp;rsquo;d stop at this stage and maybe polish a bit more (Grimlock probably needs an Autobot symbol on the chest) and just submit it to reddit already. But the problem with this sketch when I look at it, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell the Dinobots apart &amp;ndash; like in the image above, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell where Grimlock ends and Snarl begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So just this once, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try adding some colors to the sketch. I&amp;rsquo;d never done it before, but my mom was into the whole adult coloring book fad so she had some colored pencils lying around for me to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again I started with Grimlock:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#af7de5c06ab9e5f840218f96f39c0ce3-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_221453_huc857c3858d0463411b9493848cd95048_890822_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;af7de5c06ab9e5f840218f96f39c0ce3-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_221453.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;15 Mar 2016 3:39pm&#34;&gt;15 Mar 2016 3:39pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then the rest:&lt;/p&gt;











&lt;a href=&#34;#7cfcd9018672b2a845e6837892b1a731-lightbox&#34;&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_224636_hu5908af3cd29c2c62c93d107d1d5dd68d_945504_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;tn&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt; (Click to view full-size)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;lightbox&#34; id=&#34;7cfcd9018672b2a845e6837892b1a731-lightbox&#34; style=&#34;display: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_224636.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;lightbox_overlay&#34;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;time class=&#34;dt-published&#34; datetime=&#34;15 Mar 2016 3:39pm&#34;&gt;15 Mar 2016 3:39pm&lt;/time&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#_&#34;&gt;Close&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, it didn&amp;rsquo;t really improve telling the Dinobots apart by that much. Maybe only a little bit. At this point I&amp;rsquo;ve already spent way more time than I normally do on this (I was already on one and a half hours, most days it takes me less than half an hour), so the I went ahead and submitted the above image to reddit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above isn&amp;rsquo;t representative of what I do with all of the sketches. For one, this output is way more detailed than my usual ones. And the process varies slightly depending on what I&amp;rsquo;m drawing. I will usually always have the preliminary light-pencil sketch. Sometimes for drawing real-life people, I&amp;rsquo;ll want to do an outline trace, which means overlaying the paper over an image I want to draw (usually on the iPad) and lightly tracing the outline with pencil. It feels a bit like cheating, but real-life faces are hard enough without it. Maybe someday I won&amp;rsquo;t have to do them anymore (although I&amp;rsquo;ve only traced like 3 sketches I think). And as mentioned, I don&amp;rsquo;t usually do the coloring &amp;ndash; and I probably won&amp;rsquo;t do it again, takes too much time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure how far I&amp;rsquo;m taking this hobby. I have no ambitions of becoming a professional or anything (a friend once commented he was scrolling through his instagram feed with famous artists like Leinel Yu and one of my drawings was interspersed and surprised him LOL), but like life, I&amp;rsquo;ll just see how it goes I guess.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_204514_hud5d95845c0897730f4408e4b6f3d35eb_789423_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_210755_hu4a93ab3f911b11004ea0f6f637aa63f0_836561_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_213816_hud53ae180c1a19f20351f13d984d49fe6_1001878_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_215206_hu6ab6a54fc1b241a238e4494a1d9438df_903868_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_221453_huc857c3858d0463411b9493848cd95048_890822_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



&lt;img src=&#34;https://mirror.roytang.net/2016/03/sketching-daily/20160315_224636_hu5908af3cd29c2c62c93d107d1d5dd68d_945504_300x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34; /&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Scenes from a Quiz Night
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/03/scenes-from-a-quiz-night/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 16:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2013/03/scenes-from-a-quiz-night/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, March 20, 7:56pm&lt;/strong&gt; We were four of us walking down the barely lit passage on the side of the building. The guard had lazily pointed us to a large open door near the back of the building. The interior was a studio-type area and there was a group of three women dressed in white who had arrived ahead of us and we followed them up a narrow set of stairs to an elevated lounge area with chairs and tables. We recognized some of the faces already there so we knew we were in the right place. No, we weren&amp;rsquo;t there for some illicit meetup of any sort; we were there to participate in something a bit more geeky. We were here for a quiz night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quiz nights (or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pub_quiz&#34;&gt;pub quizzes&lt;/a&gt;, as they&amp;rsquo;re known in Britain) at their heart are simple affairs. You get a bunch of friends to form a team and you go to the event venue for a night of answering questions on various topics, competing with other teams. There&amp;rsquo;s usually food and alcohol involved too. This particular quiz night we were attending was Geekfight, a monthly event which was coming back from a three-month hiatus. Their questions usually revolved around pop culture and traditionally geeky exploits. That means you knowledge of the minutiae of movies, TV shows, comic books and other such channels of geek culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve arrived early since we didn&amp;rsquo;t know where the venue was and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to get lost. Aside from the organizers we are the only team already present. We jokingly said that maybe that meant we could win the event for once. I&amp;rsquo;ve been participating in quiz nights for more than three years now by my reckoning, but we&amp;rsquo;ve never finished first, the closest being a previous Geekfight where we tied for first place and I dropped the crucial tiebreaker question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re looking to change that tonight though. Each quiz night is usually divided into several rounds of questions, with each round following a certain category of questions. For Geekfight, the categories are announced ahead of time so we know that tonight&amp;rsquo;s questions will be all about movies and we figure we have a solid chance. Two more of our group arrive so that we hit the Geekfight maximum of six members per team. We order some pizza from the pizzeria out front since the venue doesn&amp;rsquo;t serve food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The place starts to fill in with other teams just as we&amp;rsquo;re finishing our pizza, though we don&amp;rsquo;t really mingle. &amp;ldquo;I feel like a lot of the people here know each other except for us,&amp;rdquo; one of us jokes, which starts a healthy discussion on our being introverts and our Myers-Briggs classifications. Still, we recognize many of the teams and attendees by face and by team name, and a few by name. A number of these players and teams also attend another of our regular haunts: quiz nights at Amici Greenhills which is held every first Thursday of the month. Amici&amp;rsquo;s question set is a bit wider and less involved with details as compared to Geekfight but still focused on pop culture, and the food is usually much better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It takes a while before all the teams are assembled (probably had the same trouble as us finding the place) so the event starts off a bit later than the 9pm call time. The organizers have a projector set up to show slides against the far side of the room. The host (a guy who looks like one of our ex-officemates) calls out the rules and categories. Each team is approached by a scorer and is given a small whiteboard and a marker to use to show their answers. The host is going to call out each question as they appear on the slides and give the teams some time usually around 30 seconds to scrawl an answer onto their boards. After some time the host counts down from 5 then asks the team to raise their boards. The host will then call out each answer (or not, depending on how lazy he&amp;rsquo;s feeling) before going to the next slide to show the answer. Each round will have ten such questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rounds one and two.&lt;/strong&gt; The event kicks off with a round on Sports Movies which gets us scratching our head over questions such as what team Tidwell played for in &lt;em&gt;Jerry Maguire&lt;/em&gt; 

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-1&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;
 and what Kevin Bacon movie has him recruiting basketball players in Africa &lt;a href=&#34;#a2&#34; name=&#34;q2&#34;&gt;

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-2&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-2&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;. Halfway through the round I predict that we&amp;rsquo;re going to get a &lt;em&gt;Dodgeball&lt;/em&gt; question and sure enough the very next slide asks us to name the gym opposite Average Joe&amp;rsquo;s in that movie 

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-3&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-3&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;
. The second round is on Science Fiction movies which leads to me struggling to remember the name of Emmet Brown&amp;rsquo;s dog in the year 1955 in the movie &lt;em&gt;Back to the Future&lt;/em&gt; 

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-4&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-4&#34;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;
 (it&amp;rsquo;s not Einstein!) and the technical name for the liquid metal that composed the T-1000 in &lt;em&gt;Terminator 2: Judgement Day&lt;/em&gt; 

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-5&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-5&#34;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike Geekfight and Amici which focus more on pop-culture topics, the first time we went to a quiz night was at a venue that tended towards more academic subjects &amp;ndash; which was how we found out about our team&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate weakness to geography and history questions. That was at the first establishment to start running quiz nights in Metro Manila: Murphy&amp;rsquo;s, an Irish pub in Makati which still runs their quiz nights weekly every Tuesdays. It&amp;rsquo;s still pretty fun and challenging, so we still go there every few weeks or so, but the best our group has done there was third place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rounds three and four.&lt;/strong&gt; Geekfight continued with a round on Gangster Movies, which sees us naming the lead character in &lt;em&gt;Scarface&lt;/em&gt; 

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-6&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-6&#34;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;
 trying to guess the two leads of the 1976 movie &lt;em&gt;Bitayin si Baby Ama&lt;/em&gt; 

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-7&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-7&#34;&gt;[7]&lt;/a&gt;
 and luckily one of knows the name of the movie where Brad Pitt plays famous outlaw Jesse James 

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-8&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-8&#34;&gt;[8]&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next round was a picture round, each slide showed a scene from a movie and we were to identify both the name of the place and the movie it appeared in (2 points each slide, so this round was worth twice as much as others!). The first question was a scene from the local movie &lt;em&gt;Ang Nawawala&lt;/em&gt; which by coincidence some of the people who worked on it were at Geekfight that night! When we were shown a shot of Luke Skywalker leaving behind his dead Uncle and Aunt, I wanted to write &amp;ldquo;Lars Water Farm&amp;rdquo; or something like that instead of Tatooine and it turns out that we did indeed have to be more specific (part of quiz night is knowing when to override your team!) I felt a bit redeemed later when I successfully named the Firehouse from &lt;em&gt;Ghostbusters&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breaktime!&lt;/strong&gt; After the first four rounds, it was halftime. We scored 26 points (out of a possible 50), which left us a sixth place out of 16 teams. Not bad, but certainly not good enough, we had to step it up. We took some time to vote on a category to joker. The joker was a common feature of the local quiz nights; it basically meant that each team gets to choose the category they&amp;rsquo;re most confident in and the team would earn double points for that particular category. Before my vote, it was split between Animated Movies and Rom-coms I just went with Rom-coms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rounds five and six.&lt;/strong&gt; Rom-coms happened to be the very next round too! We had to think about who played the lead roles in the remake of the Humphrey Bogart and Audrey Hepburn film &lt;em&gt;Sabrina&lt;/em&gt; 

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-9&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-9&#34;&gt;[9]&lt;/a&gt;
 and we had to fill in the &lt;em&gt;When Harry Met Sally&lt;/em&gt; quote &amp;ldquo;Waiter, there is too much pepper on my [blank]. But I would be proud to partake of your [blank]&amp;rdquo; 

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-10&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-10&#34;&gt;[10]&lt;/a&gt;
. We did fairly well in the joker round, only slightly worse than our best round which was the next round on War movies. The War movies round has us naming the ships in &lt;em&gt;Master and Commander: Far Side of the World&lt;/em&gt; 

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-11&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-11&#34;&gt;[11]&lt;/a&gt;
 and failing to identify the Oliver Stone war movie filmed in the Philippines 

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-12&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-12&#34;&gt;[12]&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rounds seven and eight.&lt;/strong&gt; The last two rounds were good for us so we just have to do well in the last two rounds (Fantasy and Animated Films). Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too hard right? You&amp;rsquo;d think so. The fantasy round had questions on old fantasy films we hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen such as &lt;em&gt;Willow&lt;/em&gt; and recent films we weren&amp;rsquo;t fond of like &lt;em&gt;Kingdom of Heaven&lt;/em&gt;. The animated round featured questions like who voiced Wreck-gar in the 1986 &lt;em&gt;Transformers&lt;/em&gt; movie 

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-13&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-13&#34;&gt;[13]&lt;/a&gt;
 and what was the name of the kart racing gaming in &lt;em&gt;Wreck-It-Ralph&lt;/em&gt; 

    


&lt;a href=&#34;#footnote-14&#34; id=&#34;footnotebase-14&#34;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;
 alongside questions on stuff we hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen like an obscure animated short that won some Oscar and a picture question asking us to identify which movie a character came from (we didn&amp;rsquo;t get the answer; it was, embarrassingly enough, &lt;em&gt;The Little Mermaid&lt;/em&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrapping up.&lt;/strong&gt; When all the rounds were done, we had score 29 points in the second half, with only one team scoring more points than us (30) in the second half. When we perform badly, we usually don&amp;rsquo;t bother waiting for the final rankings to be called out, but I felt like there was an outside chance of us actually winning here since most of the top scores were clustered together. It turns out that we finished with 55 points, just below the fifth-place team with 57 points, so it was the same rank we had in the first half. =/ Interestingly, the 1st and 2nd placers are tied, as are the 3rd and 4th placers, so an additional tie break question had to be done. (I&amp;rsquo;ve been there before!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah well, we&amp;rsquo;re used to not winning anyway. Yet we still keep coming back to quiz nights, Geekfight and Amici and Murphy&amp;rsquo;s. We enjoy the challenge I guess, and we love digging deep trying to find the answers to those trivia questions. Yes, we enjoy it even when we have trouble figuring them out. But next time we&amp;rsquo;re going to win for sure! (Or so I keep telling myself)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=============================&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might be the longest post I&amp;rsquo;ve ever written. Here are the answers to trivia questions marked in the post body:&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Pasmado
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/04/pasmado/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2008 04:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/04/pasmado/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pasmado&lt;/em&gt; is a term generally well-known among Filipinos. It refers to a condition of excessive sweating and/or trembling in the hands and/or feet. The concept is so well-known among Filipinos that it has developed several old wives&amp;rsquo; tales of its&amp;rsquo; own, such as the ever-popular solution of peeing on your hands first thing in the morning to get rid of the conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;em&gt;pasmado&lt;/em&gt;. Sometimes at least, especially when under stress or it&amp;rsquo;s really, really humid. The reason I got to thinking about it was that I finally realized it was affecting the way I play in Magic tournaments. After a few rounds of playing Magic, it always happens that the card sleeves start sticking to each other due to my sweaty hands. It&amp;rsquo;s quite a distraction and one my opponents even commented on my sweaty hands after the post-match handshake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about looking for a solution (one that didn&amp;rsquo;t involve pee), and did a bit of research on the concept of _pasmado _online. The difficult part was figuring out what the condition was called in English. I asked a few people and none could give any decisive answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My brother claimed the concept did not exist in Western medicine so there was no English term for it. Some thought that the condition was fictional and only exists in old wives&amp;rsquo; tales. Quoting a Pugad Baboy comic: &amp;ldquo;Kung totoo yung pasmado, ano sa English yun?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Edi pasmatic&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually I dug up a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.peyups.com/posts.khtml?mode=viewtopic&amp;amp;topic=16442&amp;amp;forum=37&amp;amp;start=90&#34;&gt;thread about pasmado on yehey.com &lt;/a&gt;that told me what the English medical term was: Palmar Hyperhidrosis. Sure enough, Wikipedia confirmed that &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyperhidrosis&#34;&gt;such a condition did exist &lt;/a&gt;. I even came across a website called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.curesweatypalms.com/Hyperhidrosis_Palmar.shtml&#34;&gt;CureSweatyPalms.com!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wikipedia entry cites several drugs that reduce hyperhidrosis and there&amp;rsquo;s even a surgery option for extreme cases. However, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend on medicine or god forbid surgery just so I could play better Magic. I&amp;rsquo;ve lived with this condition for as long as I can recall so I can tolerate it most of the time. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to instead to take up the simplest solution I could think of: I&amp;rsquo;m going to buy gloves.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>Killer-killer
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/02/killer-killer/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2008 08:02:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2008/02/killer-killer/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;During a recent out-of-town trip I observed that despite the abundance of digital entertainment available (what with all the NDS and PSP owners bringing the goods, not to mention some people bringing a Wii), some people still got together to play some face-to-face IRL games. I&amp;rsquo;m talking the types of games that are not easily translatable into digital format and will probably remain so for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One such game is known locally as &amp;ldquo;Killer-killer&amp;rdquo;. Obviously a local name due to the Filipino&amp;rsquo;s penchant for repeating words in a single term, I have no idea if it is known by other names elsewhere or if it exists outside this country at all. (As you can imagine, &amp;ldquo;Killer-killer&amp;rdquo; is not a very easy search term.) For the purposes of posterity, I will record the details of the game here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this game, a group of people sit around in a circular formation, such that each person can easily see each other&amp;rsquo;s face. A good number of participants would be around 6-8, although more can play with a few rules adjustments (we played with around 15 people on the night in question).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each player is given a role, usually written on a scrap of paper and drawn randomly. The players don&amp;rsquo;t know each others&amp;rsquo; roles. The following roles are available in the game:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Killer&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; the titular role obviously. The Killer&amp;rsquo;s objective is to assassinate a particular other role, usually named the &amp;ldquo;Judge&amp;rdquo;. The Killer kills people by winking at them silently, and tries to avoid getting caught by the Police. Other players who notice the Killer winking at them must declare that they have been killed. Once the Killer has killed his mark, the game ends and the killer wins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Judge&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; the assassination mark, his only objective in the game is to stay alive. If the Judge is killed, the Killer wins and the Policeman loses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Police&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; the law, his objective is to catch the Killer, either by catching him red-handed &amp;ldquo;killing&amp;rdquo; someone, or if the Killer attempts to &amp;ldquo;kill&amp;rdquo; the Police, the Police may immediately arrest him. Once the Police catches the Killer, the game ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Doctor&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; an important role, his objective is to &amp;ldquo;Heal&amp;rdquo; other people who have been &amp;ldquo;killed&amp;rdquo;, by winking at them as well. The person who has been healed usually declares something like &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m alive again!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Victim&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; other players are usually assigned randomly-named roles but have no gameplay significance; their only purpose is to delay the Killer in his hunt for the mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When playing with more people, the game can be balanced by adding more Killers and Policemen as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is best played with a group of people who know each other well and are comfortable staring into each other&amp;rsquo;s eyes. It&amp;rsquo;s a game of concentration, bluffing and deception that is probably close to impossible to accurately translate into a digital game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And because I just now noticed that WordPress now allows me to tag posts, I will tag this one with a term I coined just now: &amp;ldquo;meatspace-games&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 2020!&lt;/strong&gt; I found out there is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wink_murder&#34;&gt;Wikipedia entry&lt;/a&gt; about this game! (I checked the edit history, and the name &amp;ldquo;Killer-killer&amp;rdquo; was not part of the entry at the time that this post was written.)&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
        <item>
            <title>My Eyeglasses Belong To The Sea
</title>
            <link>https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/11/my-eyeglasses-belong-to-the-sea/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2004 09:30:02 +0000</pubDate>
            <author>hello@roytang.net (Roy Tang)</author>
            <guid>https://mirror.roytang.net/2004/11/my-eyeglasses-belong-to-the-sea/</guid>
            <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;In a fit of awe-inspiring common sense, I want swimming with my eyeglasses on. And, as expected when one makes such a gargantuan mistake, the Sea was aware of my folly. It sent its minions, one after another, to take my precious away from me. Again and again I bore their onslaught, as wave after wave came after me, yearning to knock me off my feet loosely planted upon the sandy earth some four and a half feet below water level. Finally, weary of the long battle, the Sea summons all its might. I did not see it coming, for my back was turned and I was celebrating my recent victories thinking the worst was over. I suddenly became aware of my 12-year-old adopted cousin looking behind me in abject horror. A gigantic wave had arisen out of nowhere, the only warning being the looming shadow that came at me from behind. I had no time to prepare for this savage assault, and the Mother of all Waves came upon me with all her might, finally knocking this proud yet weary warrior off his feet. I felt myself tumble underwater, my trunks almost torn off me in the fury of the crashing water. I reached out my arms in desperation, and my hands struck wet sand, letting me know in what direction to raise my head. When I finally surfaced again, my eyeglasses were gone, I had lost the battle. My eyeglasses belong to the Sea now.&lt;/p&gt;



            </description>
        </item>
    
    </channel>
  </rss>